import{_ as g,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as h,C as b,M as y,U as w,F as c,p,e as f,f as j,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},z={class:"poem-container"},A={class:"review"},N={class:"review-title"},x={class:"review-content"};function I(e,a,s,k,t,u){return i(),o("div",z,[n("div",A,[n("div",N,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",x,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const T=g(q,[["render",I],["__scopeId","data-v-08201079"]]),M=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"'ਅਠਾਰਵੀਂ ਸਦੀ ਦੇ ਅਖੀਰ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹੀਵੀਂ ਸਦੀ ਦੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਦੇਸੀ ਇਲਾਕਾ ਨਾਟਕੀ ਢੰਗ ਨਾਲ ਬਦਲ ਗਿਆ।' ਸਮਝਾਓ।","answer":"ਅਠਾਰ੍ਹਵੀਂ ਸਦੀ ਦੇ ਅਖੀਰ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹੀਵੀਂ ਸਦੀ ਦੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਦੇਸੀ ਇਲਾਕਾ ਨਾਟਕੀ ਢੰਗ ਨਾਲ ਬਦਲ ਗਿਆ। ਇਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ, ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਦੇ ਵੱਡੇ ਹਿੱਸੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੇਂਡੂ ਖੇਤਰ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹੇ ਸਨ। ਇਹ ਜ਼ਿਮੀਂਦਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਮਾਲਕੀ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਬੰਦ ਜ਼ਮੀਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਇਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹੇ ਮੈਦਾਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਂਝੀਆਂ ਜ਼ਮੀਨਾਂ ਸਨ। ਅਠਾਰ੍ਹਵੀਂ ਸਦੀ ਦੇ ਅੱਧ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ, ਐਨਕਲੋਜ਼ਰ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਨੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਫੈਲਿਆ, ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਲੈਂਡਸਕੇਪ ਨੂੰ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾ ਲਈ ਬਦਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ। 1750 ਅਤੇ 1850 ਦੇ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ, 6 ਮਿਲੀਅਨ ਏਕੜ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਨੂੰ ਘੇਰਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"ਇਸ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਸ਼ੱਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਗੋਵਿੰਦਾ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੇਲੇ ‘ਡਾਂਸਿੰਗ ਸਟਾਰ’ ਗਿਣਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਸੀ। ਮੋਟਾਪਾ ਆਉਣ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਕੁਝ ਸਮੇਂ ਲਈ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵੱਲ ਰੁਖ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਸੀ। ਪਰ ਹੁਣ ਇਕ ਵਾਰ ਫਿਰ ਤੋਂ ਉਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਚਾਏ ਗਰਮ’ ਵਿਚ  ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਠੁਮਕੇ ਲਗਾਉਂਦਾ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਏਗਾ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦਾ ਟਾਈਟਲ ਗੀਤ ਬੀਤੇ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਬੈਂਕਾਕ ਵਿਚ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ ਗੋਵਿੰਦਾ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਸੁਨੀਲ ਸ਼ੈਟੀ, ਈਸ਼ਾ ਦਿਓਲ ਅਤੇ ਸੇਲੀਨਾ ਜੇਤਲੀ ਨੇ ਵੀ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਲਿਆ। ਇਸ ਗੀਤ ਦੀ ਕੋਰੀਓਗਰਾਫੀ ਸ਼ਬੀਨਾ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਨ ਆਦਿਤਯ ਦੱਤ ਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ‘ਆਸ਼ਿਕ ਬਨਾਇਆ ਆਪ ਨੇ’ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਨ ਕਰ ਚੁੱਕਾ ਹੈ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਹਿੰਦੀ  ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦਾ  ‘ਡਾਂਸਿੰਗ ਸਟਾਰ’  ਕਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਗੋਵਿੰਦਾ  ਨੂੰ ਹਿੰਦੀ  ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦਾ  ‘ਡਾਂਸਿੰਗ ਸਟਾਰ’ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"What is the purpose of using Bayesian hierarchical models in analyzing areal data?","answer":"To describe the variability in the response variable as a function of covariates and random effects, assess the effects of explanatory variables, accommodate spatial autocorrelation, and quantify uncertainty in estimates."},{"question":"لخص المقال التالي: قِف بالقرب من حائط طويل أو عمود وارفع يدك أعلى ما يمكنك. اطلب من صديق قياس مكان وصول يدك ووضع علامة بالطباشير أو ما شابه، ثم اقفز بنفس تلك اليد مرفوعة واطلب من الصديق أن يحاول قياس مكان وصول أطراف أصابعك. اطرح قياسك الأصلي من قياس قفزتك، وهذا هو مقدار قفزتك العمودية الحالية. ستحتج لمتابعة قياساتك ومتى تم أخذها. دون الموعد الذي سجلت به القياسات والارتفاع الذي وصلت إليه. توجد عدة خيارات لمتابعة القياسات على حسب رغبتك. يمكنك استخدام ورقة أو الكمبيوتر أو هاتفك.  اجعل الأمر بسيطًا بمجرد تدوين أرقامك. اكتب أرقامك في مستند أو ملف وورد إلى كنت تفضل استخدام الكمبيوتر. تابع الأرقام على هاتفك في تطبيق الملاحظات أو تطبيقات الكتابة. يرجع عدد مرات قياسك لقفزتك إلى رغبتك الشخصية، ولكن القياس أسبوعيًا سيعطي اتساقًا ووقتًا للتحسن بين مرات القياس. إذا نسيت القياس في يومك المعتاد فقِس في أول مرة تأتيك فرصة بعدها..","answer":"حسناّ، هذا تلخيص للمقال 'قِس قفزتك العمودية الحالية. اختر طريقة لمتابعة تقدمك. خذ قياسات جديدة أسبوعيًا.'."},{"question":"童謡の「山寺のおしょうさん」で、和尚さんはどんな袋に猫をおしこんだと歌っているでしょう？","answer":"かんぶくろです。"},{"question":"(Uzwakala ngesankahlu engaphakathi.) Udlala ngesikhathi nje wenaLondiwe uma ucabanga ukuthi uzongena eyethu bazali bakho. Minangisaziqondisela izigwegwe nje lapha kunyoko.(Uzwakala engaphandle ngezwi elinokuhefuzela.)Enough is enough! Ngithi sekwanele-ke manje baba namanjeawukafuni wena ukuwuyeka lo mkhuba wakho wokudlala ngomame?Kungcono ngisale sengifa lapha kofela khona umame minakunokuba ngibekezelele la manyala. Ngiyasigqekeza futhi manje lesisicabha mina ngoba angivulelwa muntu.(Uzwakala engaphakathi) Sengathi ungake ulinge nje.Inkosi impela uyokubona okwabonwa ngumlisa mumbeowanyathela umthente engafake zingxabulela ezinyaweni.(UMaMlanduli usalokhu ekhala lapha ngaphakathi njengalokhusisamnetha nje isibhaxu.)(Uzwakala ngaphandle) Kodwa nawe mame uthatha kude kakhulu.Angazi nje ukuthi uncengeni kubaba kangaka njengalokhuekuhlukumeza kangaka ngalolu hlobo kodwa wena ujikeungambophisi. Abantu besilisa abenze nje badinga ukuboshwangempela. Kungagcini lapho futhi. Kuphinde kucelwe nencwadiyesivikelo emaphoyiseni ukuze ibenqabele ukwenza noma yini kuwengesihluku. Mina ukuba umuntu owenza njengobaba uganweyimina nje, bengingamgeza igilo libemhlophe qwa ngimkhombiseukuthi angisiyona neze into yokudlala. (Ngokushesha uLondiweaphumele phandle kwendlu nemfonomfono yakhe leyo ebizwangomakhalekhukhwini.)1. Uyazwelana yini nomlingiswa onguMemela mayelana nesigamekosokuboshwa kwakhe ngemuva kokushaya uChivenga? Yikuphi ongakwenzawena uma ungahle ubhekane nalesi simo?","answer":"Cha angizwelani naye ngoba ukulahlekelwa ngumsebenzi wokwakha umuzikaSaziwayo kwakungasho ukuthi kufanele abe nodlame kwabanye abantu.Ngingacela ukusebenza noChivenga noma ngiyozama elinye ikhono/itoho.NOMAYebo ngiyazwelana naye ngoba wazithola ehlupheka ngenkathi elahlekelwaikhasimende lakhe liqasha uChivenga esala engasasebenziNgingachazela umndeni wami ngengcindezi engibhekene nayo ukuze uqondeisimo esinzima engibhekene naso hleze bangicebise."},{"question":"カリマンタン島にある３つの国とは、マレーシア・インドネシアとどこでしょう？","answer":"ブルネイ･ダルサラーム国です。"},{"question":"Tüzel kişi tacirlerin tacir sıfatı nasıl sona erer?","answer":"Tüzel kişi tacirde, kural olarak tüzel kişiliğin son bulması ile nihayete erer ancak ancak tüzel kişilik derhal son verilmez tasfiye aşaması baslar durumun ticaret siciline terkini ve ilanı ile son bulur."},{"question":"Siapakah antara berikut BUKAN tokoh budaya Malaysia? Pilih jawapan yang betul dari pilihan berikut.  A. P Ramlee B. Sudirman Arshad C. Saloma D. Mas Selamat","answer":"Jawapan yang betul adalah D. Mas Selamat. P Ramlee, Sudirman dan Saloma merupakan penyanyi dan pelakon terkenal, manakala Mas Selamat merupakan suspek pengganas Singapura yang melarikan diri ke Malaysia tetapi berjaya ditangkap oleh polis."},{"question":"Moa ve mifameno sa mifanohitra sa tsy mifandray ny hevitra na tranga voaresaka amin'ireto fehezanteny roa manaraka ireto ?Fehezanteny voalohany: Mora sempotra i Tojo rehefa mihazakazaka.Fehezanteny faharoa : Tompon-daka maneran-tany amin'ny hazakazaka i Tojo. ","answer":"Mifanohitra ny fehezanteny roa satria tsy afaka ny ho tompon-daka maneran-tany i Tojo raha toa ka mora sempotra izy rehefa mihazakazaka. "},{"question":"Explain the following joke?person 1: Why was the broom late? person 2: It over swept!","answer":"Explanation: Brooms are for sweeping; one reason that people are late is because they over sleep. \\"Sleep\\" in the past tense is \\"slept” (everyday I sleep, yesterday I slept). “Slept” rhymes with swept (swept is sweep in the past-tense everyday I sweep, yesterday I swept). This joke is funny because the expected answer is “It over slept” not its rhyme, “It over swept.”"},{"question":"Vraag: Het kabinet Rutte viel aan het begin van de vrijdagavond 7 juli 2023. Het hoeveelste kabinet Rutte was dit?Antwoord:","answer":"Kabinet-Rutte IV."},{"question":"Ателектаз деген эмне ?","answer":"Ателектаз (гр. ateles - толук эмес, ektasis - керүү) - өпкө ткандарынын ыйлаакчаларында абанын такыр же жарым-жартылай жок болуп, көлөмүнүн кичирейип жыйрылышы.Организмде аба алмашуу негизинен өпкөнүн майда баштыкчаларында (альвеола) өтөт. Аба өтүшүнө тоскоол болуучу шарттардын натыйжасында абасыз калган альвеолдор кичиреет. Бала курсакта өсүү мезгилинде өпкө менен дем албагандыктан, альвеолдор жыйырылган абалда болот. Бала төрөлгөн учурда айрым себептерден (дем алуу кыймылынын начарлыгы, өпкөнүн аба түтүктөрүнүн бүтөлүп калуусу ж. б.) альвеолдорго аба барбай, алар жазылбай жыйрылган бойдон калат. Ателектаз өпкө сезгенгенде, анын кабына (плевра) суюктук толгондо, аба түтүктөрүнүн кысылуусунан же бүтөлүп калуусунан пайда болот."},{"question":"س229- من الذي لقب بأمير الشعراء ؟","answer":"ج229- أحمد شوقي"},{"question":"حط المنطق على جنب، و جاوب على السؤال ده: ازاى ندخل الفيل فى ازازة حاجة ساقعة؟","answer":"بما اننا حاطين المنطق على جنب، فممكن نقول ان اجابة السؤال ده هى: نخلى الفيل مش واخد باله و نزوقه جواها"},{"question":"arrow key-தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்","answer":"திசை விசை/திசை குறி"},{"question":"Какая из следующих планет находится ближе всего к Солнцу?A) ВенераB) МарсC) ЮпитерD) Уран","answer":"Правильный ответ: A) Венера. Венера — вторая планета от Солнца и считается самой горячей планетой в Солнечной системе из-за сильного парникового эффекта. Эта планета также известна своей яркой внешностью и часто называется \\"Утренней Звездой\\" или \\"Вечерней Звездой\\", так как её можно увидеть на небе ближе всего к Солнцу на рассвете или закате."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన గద్యానికి కొనసాగింపు రాయండి:ఉత్తమమైన ధర్మమందు ప్రీతి కలవాడా ! సారవంతమైన బుద్ధి కలవాడా ! మన వివాహం జరిగినరోజున నీవు నాకు ఇచ్చిన వరం అనే సత్యం ఉండగా అమిత – గుణవంతుడు, వంశవిస్తారకుడు అయిన పుత్రుడిని ఏ కారణం లేకుండానే కాదనటం తగునా ? (తగదని భావం). సత్యవ్రతుడవైన ఓ రాజా ! నూరు మంచినీటి బావులకంటే ఒక దిగుడుబావి మేలు. నూరు దిగుడు బావులకంటే ఒక యజ్ఞం మేలు. అటువంటి నూరు యజ్ఞాలకంటే ఒక పుత్రుడు మేలు. అటువంటి పుత్రులు నూరుమందికంటే ఒక సత్యవాక్యం మేలైనది.ఓ రాజా ! ఒక త్రాసులో వేయి అశ్వమేధ యాగాల ఫలాన్ని ఒకవైపునా, సత్యాన్ని . మాత్రమే మరోవైపునా ఉంచి తూచగా ముల్లు సత్యంవైపే మొగ్గు చూపుతుంది. తీరాలన్నింటినీ సేవించటం కానీ, వేదాలన్నింటినీ అధ్యయనం చేయటం కానీ సత్య వ్రతానికి సాటిరావు. ధర్మజ్ఞులైన మహర్షులు అన్ని ధర్మాలకంటే సత్యమే గొప్పదని ఎప్పుడూ అంటూ ఉంటారని గమనించాలి. కాబట్టి నిర్మలమైన మనసుతో సత్యం గొప్పదనాన్ని గ్రహించి, కణ్వమహర్షి ఆశ్రమంలో నీవు చేసిన ప్రతిజ్ఞను నెరవేర్చు. నీ కొడుకుపై దయఉంచు. క్షత్రియులలో ఉత్తముడైన విశ్వామిత్రునికే, దివ్యస్త్రీ అయిన మేనకకు జన్మించిన నేను అబద్ధములాడే అధర్మపరురాలను కాను.","answer":"శకుంతల మాటలను దుష్యంతుడు అంగీకరించలేదు. ఇట్లా బదులిచ్చాడు. ‘నేనెక్కడ ? నీవెక్కడ ? కుమారుడెక్కడ ? నేను నిన్ను ఇంతకు ముందెప్పుడూ కనీసం చూడనైనా లేదు. ‘ఆడవారి మాటలు అబద్దాల మూటలు’ అన్నట్లు ఇట్లా అసత్యాలు చెప్పటం నీకు తగునా ? (తగదని భావం). రూపంలోనూ, వయసులోనూ, బలంలోనూ సాటిలేనివాడుగా కనబడుతున్న. ఈ బాలుణ్ణి ‘నీ కొడుకు’ అని ఎంతో విరుద్ధంగా అందరూ నవ్వేటట్లు నాకు చూపటానికి తీసుకువచ్చావా ? ఇటువంటి వాస్తవ దూరమైన అంశాలను మేం అంగీకరించం. తగని మాటలు కట్టి పెట్టి నీవు నీ ఆశ్రమానికి తిరిగి వెళ్ళు అని దుష్యంతుడు పలకగా శకుంతల ఎంతో బాధతో ఇట్లా పలికింది."},{"question":"가을은 언제부터죠?9월 1일부터인가요 아님 입추인 오늘부터인가요?다음주에 가평가는데 이건 여름휴가일까요 가을휴가일까요?","answer":"기상학적으로는 보통 9∼11월을 가을이라고 하나 천문학적 기준으로 본다면 추분인 9월 22일을 가을의 시작으로 봅니다.\\"추분\\"은 한국과 중국, 일본 등 동아시아의 명절과 전통적인 날짜 중 하나로, 한 해의 가을 분기를 나타내는 기준점 중 하나입니다.​추분은 햇빛의 직접 비추는 위치가 적도에서 북쪽으로 이동하여 한 해의 절반이 되는 때로, 일반적으로 그레고리력 기준으로는 9월 22일에서 24일 사이에 해당합니다. 추분은 기온이 서서히 내리며 가을이 깊어지는 시기로서 농사의 수확을 준비하는 시점이기도 합니다."},{"question":"お笑いコンビ「オセロ」のメンバーは中島知子と誰でしょう？","answer":"松嶋尚美です。"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਕੇਤੇ ਲੈ ਲੈ ਮੁਕਰੁ ਪਾਹਿ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 5 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਬੇਅੰਤ ਜੀਵ (ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਪਦਾਰਥ) ਪਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਮੁਕਰ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ,\\""},{"question":"*أين يوجد تمثال الحرية ؟","answer":"نيويورك"},{"question":" Sheeg buurta Somaliya ugu dheer Magaalada iyo Gobolka ay ku taalo?","answer":" Buurta Soomaaliya ugu dheer waxay ku talaa magaalada Ceerigaabo ee Gobalka Sanaag."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa wadankii ugu horeeyey oo Afrikaan ah diyaarad lagu weeraro?","answer":"Wadankii ugu horeeyey oo Afrikaan ah diyaarad lagu weeraro (Duqeeyo) Waa dalka Soomaaliya."},{"question":"من هم المغضوب عليهم؟ ولماذ؟","answer":"\\tاليهود، لأنهم علموا الحق فتركوه وحادوا عنه على علم فاستحقوا غضب الله."},{"question":"\\"ජන\\" විරුද්ධ පදය කුමක්ද?","answer":"දුර්ජන කියන්නේ ජන කියන එකේ විරුද්ධ පදය නොවේ.එය යහජන යන වදනේ විරුද්ධ පදයයි.ජන යන්නෙහි විරුද්ධ පදයක් සෙවීම අසීරුය.ජන කියන්නෙ පොදු වචනය.ඒකට විරුද්ධ පදයක් නෑ.මේකට උපසර්ග යොදාගෙන වෙනත් පද හදාගන්න පුළුවන්.ජන > දන (පොදු වචන)සජ්ජන - දුර්ජනසුදන - දුදන"},{"question":"v","answer":"आवर्धक गिलासले प्रकाश किरणहरू झुकाउन घुमाउरो गिलास वा प्लास्टिक प्रयोग गर्दछ, वस्तुहरू वास्तवमा भन्दा ठूला देखिन्छन्।"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الذي لقب بأبو البشر من غير آدم؟","answer":"الجواب: نبي الله نوح عليه السلام."},{"question":"नेपालको पाथीभरा मन्दिर कसरी पुग्ने ?","answer":"काठमाडौं र विराटनगरबाट ताप्लेजुङ (सुकेटार) सीधा उडानहरू छन्। पाथीभरा मन्दिर पुग्न ८-९ घण्टाको पैदल यात्रा छ। काठमाडौं र विराटनगरबाट ताप्लेजुङसम्म सिधा सार्वजनिक बस सेवा पनि छ ।"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta ɗari ɗaya da ɗaya a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 101"},{"question":"ලොකයේ වැඩිම ජන ඝනත්වයක්‌ ඇති රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"ලොකයේ වැඩිම ජන ඝනත්වයක්‌ ඇති රට මොනාකෝ රාජ්‍යය වන්නේය. මොනාකෝ රාජ්‍යයේ නිල නාමය වනුයේ ප්‍රින්සිපැලිටි ඔෆ් මොනාකෝ යන්නය. මොනාකෝ යනු රටේ නම, මෙන්ම (එහි තිබෙන එකම නගරය වන) අගනුවරෙහි නමද වන්නේ ය. එය බදුවලින් තොර වූ කෙම්බිමක් ලෙස ප්‍රකටය. ජනගහනයෙන් බහුතරයක් එනම් 84% ක් පමණ ධනවත් විදේශිකයෝ වෙති. බොහෝ විට මෙම රට හඳුන්වනු ලබන්නේ යුරෝපයේ \\"ලාස් වේගා‍ස්\\" යනුවෙනි."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：加拿大歷史上的「英國北美法案」是什麼？","answer":"答案：英國北美法案是指1867年英國國會通過的一系列法案，將英國殖民地加拿大東、中、西部的分領地合併為加拿大聯邦。這一事件標誌著加拿大成為一個獨立的國家，並開始發展自己的政治體系。"},{"question":"Ìyá ìlù","answer":"Ìyá Ìlù Ìyá ìlù jẹ́ ìlù ilẹ̀ adúláwọ̀ tí wọ́n gbẹ́ gẹgẹ́ bí dígí tí wọ́n fi ń ka wákàtí láyé àtijọ́ , pàáv pàábjùlọ ní lẹ̀ Yorùbá. Wọ́n ma ń fi Ìyá ìlù sọ̀rọ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí eni wípé ènìyàn ni ó ń sọrọ̀ nígbà tí wọ́n bá lo ìwọ́hùn ènìyàn láti fi lu ìlù náà.Wọ́n gbẹ́-ẹ gẹ́gẹ́ bí dígí tí wọ́n fi ń ka wákàtí láyé àtijọ́, nígbà tí wọ́n fi awọ ewúrẹ́ bòó níwájú àti lẹ́yìn, tí wọ́n sì fi àwọn awọ tẹ́ẹ́rẹ́ ṣe okùn tí ó so àwọn awọ méjèèjì pọ̀ mọ́ ara wọn láàrín. Àwọn awọ tẹ́rẹ́ wọ̀nyí ni omílù yóò fọwọ́ kọ́ tí yóò sì ma fi apá fun mọ́ra áti lè fun ní irúfẹ́ ìwọ́hùn tí ó bá fẹ. Ẹni tí ó bàv jẹ́ Ààyàn tó bác yanjú yóò lè lo ìlù náà láti fibsọ ohun kóhun tó bá fẹ́. Ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwon ìyá ìlù ló ma ń sọ̀rọ̀ bí ènìyàn. Àmọ́, ó dá lóri bí onílù bá ṣe lùú. Lára àwọn ìlù tí wòn fara jọ ìyá ìlù tí wọ́n fi gẹgẹ́ bí dígí tí wọ́n fi mń ka wákàtí láyé àtijọ́ náà wà ní agbàègbè ilẹ̀ Éṣíà, ṣùgbọ́n wọn kìí lòó láti fi sọ̀rọ̀ bí ti ilẹ̀ Adúláwọ̀. Àmọ́ ṣá wọ́n ma ń lo ìlù idakka láti fi gbe orin lẹ́sẹ̀."},{"question":"ශාක මගින් අවශෝෂණය කරන වායු වර්ගය කුමක්ද?","answer":" කාබන් ඩයොක්සයිඩ්"},{"question":"வினா:சிங்கப்பூரின் பழைய பெயர்?","answer":"விடை: டெமாஸெக்"},{"question":"Nawa ne yawan al'ummar Sudan ta Kudu a shekarar 2021?","answer":"Kimanin miliyan 11"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਙੰਙਾ ਙਿਆਨੁ ਨਹੀ ਮੁਖ ਬਾਤਉ ॥ਅਨਿਕ ਜੁਗਤਿ ਸਾਸਤ੍ਰ ਕਰਿ ਭਾਤਉ ॥ਙਿਆਨੀ ਸੋਇ ਜਾ ਕੈ ਦ੍ਰਿੜ ਸੋਊ ॥ਕਹਤ ਸੁਨਤ ਕਛੁ ਜੋਗੁ ਨ ਹੋਊ ॥ਙਿਆਨੀ ਰਹਤ ਆਗਿਆ ਦ੍ਰਿੜੁ ਜਾ ਕੈ ॥ਉਸਨ ਸੀਤ ਸਮਸਰਿ ਸਭ ਤਾ ਕੈ ॥ਙਿਆਨੀ ਤਤੁ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਬੀਚਾਰੀ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਜਾ ਕਉ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਧਾਰੀ ॥੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 251 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਨਿਰੀਆਂ ਮੂੰਹ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਨਾਲ, ਨਿਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਮਿਲਾਪ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਆਖਣ ਸੁਣਨ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਮਿਲਾਪ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ।   ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਅਨੇਕ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀਆਂ ਜੁਗਤੀਆਂ ਵਰਤਿਆਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਜਾਣ-ਪਛਾਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਉਹੀ ਜਾਣ-ਪਛਾਣ ਪਾਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਪੱਕਾ ਨਿਵਾਸ ਬਣੇ । ਨਿਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਮਿਲਾਪ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਆਖਣ ਸੁਣਨ ਨਾਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਮਿਲਾਪ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ । ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਪੱਕੀ ਟਿਕੀ ਰਹੇ, ਉਹੀ ਅਸਲ ਗਿਆਨੀ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਰਾ ਦੁਖ-ਸੁਖ ਇਕ-ਸਮਾਨ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਜੇਹੜਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਜਗਤ-ਦੇ-ਮੂਲ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਿਚਾਰਵਾਨ ਬਣ ਜਾਵੇ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਬਣਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰੇ।੫।\\""},{"question":"*كم قمرا تابعا للأرض ؟","answer":"قمر واحد"},{"question":"Cad é an cheist le haghaidh: \\"Lonnaithe i ndeisceart an Aigéin Chiúin, tá sé suite go geografach in oirthear na hOileáin Mhálaigh, lena gcuirtear san áireamh é uaireanta mar chuid d'Oileáin Mhór na hOileáin Intí-Ostaire.\\"? Is é an t-ábhar ná an Ghuine Nua.","answer":"is é an tabhar \\"Cá bhfuil an t-oileán Nua-Ghuine?\\""},{"question":"Hãy chọn câu trả lời đúng nhất cho câu hỏi sau:Tổng nào sau đây chia hết cho 7.A. 49 + 70     B. 14 + 51     C. 7 + 134     D. 10 + 16","answer":"Lời giảiTheo tính chất chia hết của một tổng: Ta có 49 chia hết cho 7 và 70 chia hết cho 7 nên 49 + 70 chia hết cho 7.Chọn đáp án A."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai diurap dengan daun katang-katang\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang panas hati hendak berkelahi"},{"question":"La domanda: Quanti stati USA hanno meno di 1 milione di abitanti?","answer":"La risposta è 6."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berikut: Gula pada sebatang kayu, budak suka menjilatnya.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah lollipop. "},{"question":"देवी सीताको जन्मस्थल कुन हो ?","answer":"देवी सीताको जन्मस्थल जनकपुर, नेपाल हो"},{"question":"శ్రీ కృష్ణదేవ రాయలు గురించి రాయండి.","answer":"శ్రీకృష్ణదేవ రాయలు (1471 జనవరి 17 – 1529 అక్టోబరు 17) విజయనగర చక్రవర్తి. ఇతను 1509 ఫిబ్రవరి 4 న తన ఇరవై సంవత్సరాల వయసులో విజయనగర సింహాసనాన్ని అధిష్ఠించాడు. రాయల పాలనలో విజయనగర సామ్రాజ్యము అత్యున్నతస్థితికి చేరుకున్నది. కృష్ణరాయలను తెలుగు, కన్నడ ప్రజలు భారతదేశాన్ని పాలించిన గొప్ప చక్రవర్తులలో ఒకడిగా అభిమానిస్తారు. ఆంధ్ర భోజుడుగా, సాహితీ సమరాంగణ సార్వభౌముడిగా, కన్నడ రాజ్య రమారమణగా అతడు కీర్తించబడినాడు. శ్రీకృష్ణదేవరాయలు సాళువ నరసనాయకుడి వద్ద మహాదండనాయకుడుగా పనిచేసిన తుళువ నరసనాయకుని మూడవ కుమారుడు. నరసనాయకుడు పెనుకొండలో ఉండగా, రెండవ భార్య నాగలాంబకు జన్మించాడు. రాయలు తల్లి నాగలాంబ గండికోటను పాలించిన పెమ్మసాని నాయకులు ఆడపడచు. ఈయన పాలనను గురించిన సమాచారము పోర్చుగీసు సందర్శకులు డొమింగో పేస్, న్యూనిజ్‌ ల రచనల వలన తెలియుచున్నది. రాయలకు ప్రధాన మంత్రి తిమ్మరుసు. శ్రీకృష్ణదేవరాయలు సింహాసనం అధిష్ఠించడానికి తిమ్మరుసు చాలా దోహదపదడినాడు. కృష్ణరాయలు తిమ్మరుసును పితృసమానునిగా గౌరవించి \\"అప్పాజీ\\" (తండ్రిగారు) అని పిలిచేవాడు. ఇతను ఇరవై సంవత్సరాల వయసులో 1509 ఫిబ్రవరి 4 న విజయనగర సింహాసనాన్ని అధిష్ఠించాడు. ఇతని పట్టాభిషేకానికి అడ్డురానున్న అచ్యుత రాయలు నూ, వీర నరసింహ రాయలు నూ, అనుచరులనూ తిమ్మరుసు సుదూరంలో ఉన్న దుర్గములలో బంధించాడు."},{"question":"ÌGBÉYÀWÓ ÌṢẸ̀ǸBÁYÉ LÁÀÁRÍN ÀWỌN Ẹ̀YÀ ÌGBÒ","answer":"ÌGBÉYÀWÓ ÌṢẸ̀ǸBÁYÉ ni wọ́n ń pè ní \\"Igba Ukwu\\" ní ilẹ̀ Ìgbò. Ní apá ìlà oòrùn ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà, ìgbéyàwó kìí ṣe ìsopọ̀ láàárín ọ̀dọ́bìnrin àti ọ̀dọ́mọkùnrin tó fẹ́ di ọkọ àti aya níkan ṣùgbọ́n ojúṣe àwọn òbí, àwọn ẹbí àti àwọn ará àdúgbò. Ìdí nìyí tí ìkọ̀sílẹ̀ fi ṣọ̀wọ́n láàárín wọn.[1]lẹ́yìn tí ọkùnrin bá ti rí obìnrin tí yóò fi ṣe aya, ohun àkọ́kọ́ tí yóò ṣe ni pé kí ó fi tó àwọn òbí rẹ̀ létí. Ètò mọ̀mí-n-mọ̀-ẹ́ ní oríṣìíríṣìí ìgbésẹ̀ nínú ìgbéyàwó Ìgbò.Nínú ìgbésẹ̀ àkọ́kọ́ yìí ni ọkùnrin tí yóò fẹ́ ìyàwó yóò ti lọ yọjú sí bàbá ìyàwó tàbí ẹbí rè (ìyàwó) kan, baba rẹ̀ ni yóò sìn-ín lọ. Ní àkókò fífi ojú gán-án-ní baba ìyàwó yìí, tí ó sábà máa ń wáyé ní ìrọ̀lẹ́, bàbá ọkọ yóò sọ ìdí tí wọ́n fi wá rí wọn. Àwọn òbí ìyàwó yóò gbà wọ́n tọwọ́tẹsẹ̀ ṣùgbọ́n wọn kò ní fún wọn ní ìdáhùn pàtó sí ohun tí wọ́n bá wà."},{"question":"\\" સૂપડું સવા લાખનું \\" લોકગીત લખો.","answer":"સૂપડું સવા લાખનું, ઝાટકો રે ઝાટકો           દાણા એટલા દાણા, પાણા એટલા પાણા                          દાણા દાણા   મૈયરિયાના                          પાણા પાણા સાસરિયાનાસૂપડું સવા લાખનું, ઝાટકો રે ઝાટકોબોલો નવતર વહુ તમને સસરા ગમે કેવા?                              ઝૂલે  બેસી  ઝૂલે એવા                              એને કાંઈ ન લેવા દેવા                              મને  સસરા ગમે એવાસૂપડું સવા લાખનું, ઝાટકો રે ઝાટકોબોલો નવતર વહુ તમારાં સાસુ છે કેવા?                             તીખાં તમતમતાં  જાણે                             લાલ-લીલા મરચાં જેવા                             મારા સાસુજી  છે એવાસૂપડું સવા લાખનું, ઝાટકો રે ઝાટકોબોલો નવતર વહુ તમને નણદી ગમે કેવા?                           ફરતાં ફરતાં  ફેરફુદરડી                           જાય હવામાં ઉડતા જેવા                           મને  નણદી  ગમે  એવાસૂપડું સવા લાખનું, ઝાટકો રે ઝાટકોબોલો નવતર વહુ તમારા પરણ્યાં છે કેવા?                           ભોળા   ભોળા  ભટ્ટ  ને                           બેઠાં હોય ગણપતિ જેવા                           મારા  પરણ્યાં  છે  એવાસૂપડું સવા લાખનું, ઝાટકો રે ઝાટકો           દાણા એટલા દાણા, પાણા એટલા પાણા                          દાણા દાણા   મૈયરિયાના                          પાણા પાણા સાસરિયાના\\t\\tસૂપડું સવા લાખનું, ઝાટકો રે ઝાટકો"},{"question":"بعد از تیرماه چه ماهی است؟","answer":"مردادماه، که ماه پنجم سال شمسی است"},{"question":"పరిశ్రమల వర్గీకరణను వివరించండి.","answer":"పరిశ్రమలను సాధారణముగా దిగువ విధాలుగా వర్గీకరించవచ్చు.1) ప్రాథమిక పరిశ్రమలు : ఈ పరిశ్రమ ప్రకృతిపై ఆధారపడి, ప్రకృతి సహాయముతో వస్తువులను ఉత్పత్తి చేస్తుంది. ఉదా : వ్యవసాయము, చేపలు పట్టుట, అటవీకరణ మొదలైనవి.2) ప్రజనన పరిశ్రమలు : ఈ పరిశ్రమలు వంశ క్రమానికి చెందిన కొన్ని జాతి మొక్కలను, పశువులను, పక్షులను పునరుత్పత్తి చేసి, వాటిని అమ్మడం ద్వారా లాభాన్ని ఆర్జిస్తాయి. ఉదా : నర్సరీలు, కోళ్ళ పరిశ్రమ, పట్టు పురుగుల పరిశ్రమ.3) ఉద్గ్రహణ పరిశ్రమలు: ప్రకృతి వనరుల నుంచి వస్తువులను వెలికితీసే కార్యకలాపాలతో ముడిపడివున్న పరిశ్రమలను ఉద్గ్రహణ పరిశ్రమలు అంటారు. ఉదా : ఖనిజాల త్రవ్వకము, బొగ్గు, ఇనుప ఖనిజము మొదలైనవి. గనుల నుంచి వెలికితీయడము మొదలైనవి.4) వస్తు తయారీ పరిశ్రమలు : ముడిపదార్థాలు లేదా సగం తయారైన వస్తువుల నుంచి పూర్తిగా తయారైన వస్తువులుగా ఉత్పత్తిచేసే వాటిని వస్తు తయారీ పరిశ్రమలు అంటారు. ఉదా : ఇనుము – ఉక్కు, యంత్ర పరికరాలు, సిమెంటు మొదలైనవి.5) వస్తు నిర్మాణ పరిశ్రమలు : రోడ్లు, వంతెనలు, భవనాలు, ప్రాజెక్టులు మొదలైనవాటి నిర్మాణాన్ని చేపట్టే పరిశ్రమలను వస్తు నిర్మాణ పరిశ్రమలుగా చెప్పవచ్చును.6) సేవారంగ పరిశ్రమలు : ప్రత్యక్షముగా గాని, పరోక్షముగా గాని ప్రజలకు ఆవశ్యకమైన సేవలను అందజేసే ప్రజోపయోగ సంస్థలను సేవా పరిశ్రమలు అంటారు. ఉదా : హోటల్ పరిశ్రమ, టూరిజమ్ పరిశ్రమ మొదలైనవి."},{"question":"オリコンのシングルチャートで初めて「デビュー曲初登場1位」となった、近藤真彦のヒット曲は何でしょう？","answer":"『スニーカーぶる～す』"},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত প্রশ্নটি পড়ুন এবং প্রশ্নের জন্য একটি উপযুক্ত প্রসঙ্গ প্রদান করুন।বর্তমানে সংযুক্ত আরব আমিরাতের মোট জনসংখ্যা কত?","answer":"সংযুক্ত আরব আমিরাতের লোকসংখ্যা প্রায় ৮২ লক্ষ।২০১৪ সালের তথ্য অনুযায়ী এখানে বসবাসকারীদের মধ্যে ভারতীয় বংশোদ্ভূতরা সবচেয়ে বেশি রয়েছেন। দেশটতে প্রায় ২৬ লক্ষ ভারতীয় রয়েছেন। এছাড়া ১২ লক্ষ পাকিস্তানী রয়েছেন এবং ১২ লক্ষ বাংলাদেশী রয়েছেন। স্থানীয় জনগোষ্ঠীর সংখ্যা ১১ লক্ষ। এছাড়াও অন্যান্য কিছু দেশের লোকজনও এখানে বসবাস করেন।"},{"question":"السؤال: كم كان عمر الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم عندما تزوج من السيدة خديجة ؟","answer":"الإجابة: 25 سنة"},{"question":" Iza no nanoratra ny boky mitondra ny lohateny hoe « Ny fanagasiana »1- E.D Andriamalala2- DOX3- Iharilanto Patrick Andriamangatiana","answer":"1- E.D Andriamalala no nanoratra ny boky « Ny fanagasiana ». Ny taona 1975 no nivoahan’ny boky. Miompana amin’ny fomba fitondrana ny firenena ny votoantiny."},{"question":"Иерархия деген эмне?","answer":"Иерархия-кандайдыр бир предметтердин, буюмдардын, адамдардын, концепциялардын “жогоркудан” “төмөнкүгө” иретке келтирилген системасы."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la capital de Zacatecas?","answer":"La capital es Zacatecas y tiene 1 490 668 de habitantes."},{"question":"Unsa ang tawag sa tawo nga naay kahadlok sa gagmay na espasyo?","answer":"Ang tawag sa tawo nga naay kahadlok sa gagmay na espasyo kay claustrophobic."},{"question":"Eyi jẹ Aroko nipa Yí Yára bi Ojú-ọjọ́ ti nyí padà nitori Èérí Àyíká. Aroko: Ẹlẹkọ-ìjìnlẹ̀ ṣe àkiyesi pe enia ndá kún yí yára bi ojú-ọjọ́ ti nyi padà nitori èérí-àyíká.  Ojú-ọjọ́ ti nyí padà lati ìgbà ti aláyé ti dá ayé, ṣùgbọ́n àyípadà ojú-ọjọ́ ni ayé òde òní yára ju ti ìgbà àtijọ́ lọ.Yorùbá sọ wi pé “Ogun à sọ tẹ́lẹ̀, ki i pa arọ tó bá gbọ́n”. Àsìkò tó lati fi etí si ìkìlọ̀ Ẹlẹkọ-ìjìnlẹ̀ lóri yí yára bi ojú-ọjọ́ ti nyi padà. Àwọn Ẹlẹkọ-ìjìnlẹ̀ ńké ìbòsí nipa ohun ti èérí àyíká ndá kún gbi gbóná àgbáyé àti ki ènìyàn ṣe àtúnṣe, lati din ìgbóná kù. Ìgbà gbogbo ni àwọn Ẹlẹkọ-ìjìnlẹ̀ Àyíká nṣe àlàyé yi ni Àjọ Ìfohùnṣọ̀kan Ìpínlẹ̀ Àgbáyé.Lára ohun ti o ndá kún èérí àyíká, Ẹlẹkọ-ìjìnlẹ̀ tọ́ka si ọkọ̀, ẹ̀rọ mọ̀nà-mọ́ná, ẹ̀rọ-ilé-iṣẹ́, ṣ̀ugbọ́n èyí ti ó burú jù ni àwọn ohun ti wọ́n fi ike ṣe bi i: igò-ike, àpò-ike, ọ̀rá-ike, ike-ìṣeré àti bẹ́ ẹ̀ bẹ́ ẹ̀ lọ gẹ́gẹ́ bi ohun ti o ndá kún yi yára bi ojú-ọjọ́ ti nyi padà.Ewé, ìwé tàbi páálí ti a kó sọnù, wúlò fún àyiká ju ọ̀rá ati ike igbàlódé lọ.  Bi wọ́n bá da àwọn ohun ti wọ́n fi ike ṣe dànù si ààtàn tàbi si odò, ki i jẹrà bi ewé. Bi wọn da ewé si ilẹ́, yio da ilẹ́ padà lai ni ewu fún ekòló, igbin àti àwọn kòkòrò kékeré yókù. Bi wọn da ewé, ìwé tàbi páálí si inú omi/odò, kò léwu fún ẹja àti ohun ẹlẹmi inú omi/odò, bi ti ọ̀rá àti ike igbàlódé to léwu fún ẹja àti ẹranko inú odò.Àwọn ohun ti a lè ṣe lati fi etí si ìkìlọ̀ àwọn Ẹlẹkọ-ìjìnlẹ̀, ni ki a din li lo ọ̀rá ike àti ohun ti a fi ike ṣe kù bi a kò bá lè da dúró pátápátá.  Ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ orílẹ̀-èdè ni ìlú Òyìnbó ló ti ṣe òfin lati din li lò ike kù, àwọn miran ti bẹ̀rẹ̀ si gba owó fún àpò-ike ni ọjá lati jẹ́ ki àwọn enia lo àpò àlòtúnlò.  Bi ó bá ṣe kókó ki á pọ́n oúnjẹ, a lè lo ewé fi pọ́n,  jú ọ̀rá tàbi ike lọ.  Ki a fi páálí tàbi apẹ̀rẹ̀ ọparun kó ẹrù, lo àpò àlòtúnlò lati ra ọjà, ka lo ìkòkò alámọ̀ lati ṣe oúnjẹ tàbi tọ́jú oúnjẹ kó lè gbóná, àti ki a din li lo ike kù yio din yi yára bi ojú-ọjọ́ ti nyí padà kù.Lára àtúnṣe ti ìjọba lè ṣe, ni ki awon olòṣè̀lú ṣe òfin lati din èérí kù, ìpèsè ilé iṣẹ́ ti ó lè sọ àwọn ohun ti a fi ike ṣe di àlòtúnlò àti ki kó ẹ̀gbin ni àsìkò.Ohun ti gbogbo ará ilu,́ pàtàki àwọn ọ̀dọ́ tún lè ṣe, ni ṣi ṣa ọ̀rá tàbi ike omi àti ohun ti wọn fi ike ṣe, ti o ti dá èérí rẹpẹtẹ si inú odò àti àyíká kúrò.  Gbi gbin igi àti ṣe ètò fún àyè ti omi lè wọ́ si ni ìgbà òjò na a yio din ìgbóná àgbáyé kù.Ibeere: Gẹgẹbi Aroko yi, kini àwọn nkan ti o buru ju lara awon ohun ti o ndá kún èérí àyíká?","answer":"Gẹgẹbi Aroko yi, àwọn nkan ti o buru ju  lára àwọn ohun ti o ndá kún èérí àyíká ni àwọn ohun ti wọ́n fi ike ṣe bi i: igò-ike, àpò-ike, ọ̀rá-ike, ike-ìṣeré àti bẹ́ ẹ̀ bẹ́ ẹ̀ lọ."},{"question":"Marlon Brando naGeorge C Scott vakaramba chii?","answer":"Vose Marlon Brando naGeorge C. Scott vakaramba nemufaro kubvuma maAcademy Awards panguva yebasa ravo rakasiyana.1. Marlon Brando: Muna 1973, Marlon Brando akakunda Academy Award yeBest Actor nokuda kwebasa rake saVito Corleone mu \\"The Godfather.\\" Nekudaro, akaramba kubvuma Oscar senzira yekupikisa kuratidzwa kwevanhu vekuAmerica muindasitiri yemafirimu uye kubatwa kwavo nehurumende yeUS. Panzvimbo yekuenda kumabiko emubairo, akatumira mumiriri weNative America uye mutambi anonzi Sacheen Littlefeather kuti arambe mubairo panzvimbo yake.2. George C. Scott: Muna 1971, George C. Scott akahwina Mubayiro weAcademy for Best Actor nokuda kwebasa rake mu \\"Patton,\\" kwaakaratidza General George S. Patton munguva yeHondo Yenyika II. Scott akanga ajekesa pamberi pemhemberero iyi kuti haaizogamuchira Oscar, sezvo aifunga kuti mutambo wemubairo waiva \\"mutambo wemaawa maviri wenyama\\" uye aisabvumirana nepfungwa yevatambi vanokwikwidzana. Pasinei nekukunda, haana kuenda kumhemberero yekugamuchira mubairo.Zvose izvi zviitiko zvakakosha munhoroondo yeOscar semienzaniso isingawanzo yevatambi vari kuramba mubairo wepamusoro."},{"question":"Quand la comète de Halley reviendra-t-elle ?","answer":"Elle repasse près du soleil tous les 76 ans environ et devrait réapparaître dans notre ciel en 2062 - son dernier passage date de 1986. Les astronomes connaissent bien son parcours : Halley tourne autour du Soleil en suivant une trajectoire très allongée qui l'entraîne jusqu'aux confins du Système solaire puis la fait revenir inlassablement dans les parages de la Terre et du Soleil, depuis au moins des millénaires."},{"question":"Йоттошкон тамгалар деген эмне?","answer":" Кыргыз тилинде 4 йоттошкон тамга бар.А л а р: е, ё, ю, я. Бул тамгалар экиден тыбышты билдирет:е = й + э;    ё = й + о;     ю = й + у;     я = й + а. "},{"question":"Tôi không có thời gian nấu ăn sáng cho bé tại nhà nên hay mua bánh mì, xúc xích ở cổng trường, nhưng lo không an toàn thực phẩm. Nên cho con ăn sáng thế nào?","answer":"Nhiều phụ huynh không thể chuẩn bị bữa sáng đúng nghĩa cho con đến trường, đây là một thực tế. Ngoài ra, cũng không ít người cho rằng bữa sáng là bữa phụ nên ăn qua loa, điều này hoàn toàn sai lầm.Bữa sáng sau khoảng thời gian dài 10-12 giờ kể từ bữa ăn tối, cung cấp dinh dưỡng, năng lượng để bắt đầu ngày học tập và làm việc hiệu quả. Vì vậy bữa sáng được coi là bữa quan trọng nhất trong ngày.Bạn cho con ăn sáng bằng những thực phẩm bán ở cổng trường như bánh mì, bánh ngọt, thịt xiên nướng, xúc xích rán, bánh rán... là hoàn toàn không nên. Những thực phẩm này không đảm bảo vệ sinh, phụ huynh cũng không kiểm soát được liệu con có ăn thật hay không."},{"question":"Madagasikara dia nosy hita ao amin'ny ranomasim-be an'ny Indiana. Valio eny sa tsia.","answer":"Eny, Madagasikara dia anisan'ireo nosy hita amin'ny ranomasim-be an'ny Indiana, ary izy no nosy lehibe indrindra amin'ireo nosy hita ao."},{"question":"இதை அடிப்படையாகக் கொண்ட ஒரு கட்டுரையை எழுதுங்கள் \\"உங்கள் முழங்கைகளை உயர்த்தும் போது உங்கள் ஆதிக்கம் செலுத்தும் கையை கீழே திருப்புங்கள். உங்கள் முழு உடலையும் சுழற்றும் போது உங்கள் முன் முழங்காலை உள்ளே வளைக்கவும். உங்கள் முழங்கைகளை 90 டிகிரி கோணத்தில் வளைத்து, இலக்கை நோக்கி சுழற்றுங்கள்\\".  ","answer":"கட்டுரை:இருப்பில் இருந்து, உங்கள் முன்னங்கை தரையில் இணையாக இருக்கும் வரை உங்கள் ஆதிக்கம் செலுத்தும் முழங்கையை உயர்த்தவும். உங்கள் மணிக்கட்டு இயற்கையாகவே கீழ்நோக்கி திரும்பட்டும், இதனால் உங்கள் முட்டிகள் தரையை நோக்கி இருக்கும். உங்கள் எதிரிக்கு உங்கள் குத்து சமிக்ஞைகளைத் தவிர்ப்பதற்காக உங்கள் முழு மார்பையும் நகர்த்தாமல் இதை விரைவாகச் செய்யுங்கள். நீங்கள் ஒரு கொக்கி உங்கள் ஆதிக்கம் அல்லது ஆதிக்கம் அல்லாத கையில் தூக்கி முடியும். உங்கள் மற்ற கையால் இந்த குத்து வீசினால், உங்கள் ஆதிக்கம் இல்லாத மணிக்கட்டை கீழே திருப்பி, முழங்கையை உயர்த்தவும். இந்த கொக்கி நேரடியான குத்துவை விட வீச அதிக நேரம் எடுக்கும், ஆனால் சரியாகப் பயன்படுத்தினால் அது மிகவும் சக்தி வாய்ந்தது. உங்கள் எதிரி உங்களுக்கு மிக அருகில் இருக்கும்போது அவர்களை சமநிலையிலிருந்து தள்ளுவதற்கு கொக்கிகளை வீசுங்கள். ஒரு நல்ல கொக்கி உங்கள் எதிரியை கீழே தள்ள அதிக வாய்ப்பு உள்ளது, நீங்கள் அவர்கள் எதிர்பார்க்கவில்லை ஒரு கோணத்தில் உங்கள் எதிரி தாக்கும் என்பதால். அதிகபட்ச சக்திக்கான சிறிய சுழற்சி தேவைப்படுகிறது. உங்கள் குத்துக்களுக்குப் பின்னால் சில எடையைச் சேர்க்க, உங்கள் முன் கால்களை கீழே வளைத்து, உங்கள் உடலை நோக்கி நீங்கள் சுருண்டுபோவது போல் வளைத்துக்கொள்ளுங்கள். உங்கள் எதிரியை விட்டு விலகிச் செல்வது போல் உங்கள் இடுப்பு உங்கள் முழங்காலுக்குப் பின்னால் செல்லட்டும். இதை செய்யும்போது உங்கள் கைகளை நகர்த்த வேண்டாம். இந்த இயக்கத்தின் முடிவில் உங்கள் ஆதிக்கம் மிக்க கை நேரடியாக உங்கள் தலையின் பின்னால் இருக்க வேண்டும். உங்கள் ஆதிக்கம் இல்லாத கையால் ஒரு கொக்கி வீசும் அறிவுறுத்தலை மாற்றியமைக்கவும்; உங்கள் முதுகெலும்பை உள்நோக்கி வளைத்து, உங்கள் உடலை உங்களிடமிருந்து சற்று விலக்கி வைக்கவும். உங்கள் முழு உடலையும் உங்கள் இலக்கை நோக்கி சுழற்றும் போது ஒரு வளைந்த முழங்கையை பராமரிக்கவும். உங்கள் முன் கால் திறக்க போது உங்கள் பின் கால் உள்நோக்கி சுழற்று இலக்கு வரை. உங்கள் கை உங்கள் இடுப்பைப் பின்தொடர்ந்து உங்கள் எதிரியை உங்கள் நடுத்தர முழங்காலால் அடிக்கட்டும். சரியாக செய்தால், உங்கள் முழு உடலும் ஒரு சக்கரம் போல முன்னோக்கி சுழலும். உங்கள் ஆதிக்கம் இல்லாத கையை கொண்டு ஒரு கொக்கிக்கு, நீங்கள் வேறு திசையில் இருந்து திருப்புகிறீர்கள் மற்றும் உங்கள் ஆதிக்கம் இல்லாத கால் பயன்படுத்தி உங்கள் உடலை சுழற்றுகிறீர்கள் என்பதைத் தவிர, அறிவுறுத்தல் அடிப்படையில் ஒன்றே."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina amin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\" Amidy amin’olotsotra izay manambola ka afaka hitatana azy ny orinasa, izany hoe, alain’ny fanjakana ny volany niasa tao ka izay tianilay olona nividy azy hitatanany ny orinasa no ataony, ka tsy afa-mitsabaka eo itsony ny fajakana fa manaramaso fotsiny sisa azony atao.\\"","answer":"Ity ny fanambarana miaraka amin'ireo hadisoana voahitsy:\\" Amidy amin’ny olon-tsotra izay manam-bola ka afaka hitantana azy ny orin’asa, izany hoe, alain’ny fanjakana ny volany niasa tao ka izay tian’ilay olona nividy azy hitantanany ny orinasa no ataony, ka tsy afa-mitsabaka eo intsony ny fanjakana fa manara-maso fotsiny sisa azony atao.\\""},{"question":"How did the French Revolution impact the monarchy?","answer":"The French Revolution led to the abolition of the absolute monarchy, resulting in the execution of King Louis XVI and the establishment of the First French Republic in 1792."},{"question":"நிகழ்கலை வடிவங்கள் – அவை நிகழும் இடங்கள் – அவற்றின் ஒப்பனைகள் – சிறப்பும் பழைமையும் – இத்தகைய மக்கள் கலைகள் அருகிவருவதற்கான காரணங்கள் – அவற்றை வளர்த்தெடுக்க நாம் செய்ய வேண்டுவன – இவை குறித்து நாளிதழுக்கான தலையங்கம் எழுதுக.","answer":"நிகழ்கலை வடிவங்கள் நிலைக்குமா?! – கண்ணுக்குக் காட்சியையும் சிந்தைக்குக் கருத்தினையும் தருவன. கருத்துடன் கலைத்திறனை நோக்காகக் கொண்டு காலவெள்ளத்தைக் கடந்து நிற்பன. ஆடல், பாடல், இசை, நடிப்பு ஒப்பனை உரையாடல் வழியாக மக்களை மகிழ்வடையச் செய்வன. சமூகப் பண்பாட்டுத்தளத்தின் கருத்துக் கருவூலமாக விளங்குவன. நுட்பமான உணர்வுகளின் உறைவிடமாக இருப்பன. அவை யாவை? அவை தாம் மக்கள் பண்பாட்டின் பதிவுகளான நிகழ்கலைகள்.சிற்றூர் மக்களின் வாழ்வியல் நிகழ்வுகளில் பிரித்துப் பார்க்க இயலாக் கூறுகளாகத் திகழ்வை நிகழ்கலைகள். இவை மக்களுக்கு மகிழ்ச்சியெனும் கனி கொடுத்துக் கவலையைப் போக்குகின்றன. சமுதாய நிகழ்வுகளின் ஆவணங்களாகவும் செய்திகளைத் தரும் ஊடகங்களாகவும் திகழ்கின்றன. பழந்தமிழ் மக்களின் கலை, அழகியல், புதுமை ஆகியவற்றின் எச்சங்களை அறிவதற்குத் தற்காலத்தில் நிகழ்த்தப்படும் கலைகள் துணை செய்கின்றன.நிகழ்கலைகள் ஊரக மக்களின் வாழ்வில் இரண்டறக் கலந்திருக்கின்றன. இவை கற்றோராலும் மற்றோராலும் விரும்பப்படும் கலைகளாக உள்ளன. உழைப்பாளிகளின் உணர்வுகளாக உள்ளன. மக்களின் எண்ண வெளிப்பாடாக, வாழ்க்கையைக் காட்டும் கண்ணாடியாக, மக்களின் சமய வழிபாட்டிலும் வாழ்வியல் நிகழ்வுகளிலும் பிரிக்க முடியாத பண்பாட்டுக் கூறுகளாக விளங்குகின்றன.நிகழ்கலைகளை வளரச் செய்வோம். என்றும் அழியாமல் நிலைக்கச் செய்வோம்."},{"question":"புதுமைப்பித்தனின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"வேதாந்திகள் கைக்குள் சிக்காத கடவுள் மாதிரிதான் நான் பிறப்பித்துவிட்டவைகளும். அவை உங்கள் அளவுகோல்களுக்குள் அடைபடாதிருந்தால் நானும் பொறுப்பாளியல்ல, நான் பிறப்பித்து விளையாடவிட்ட ஜீவராசிகளும் பொறுப்பாளிகளல்ல; உங்கள் அளவுகோல்களைத்தான் என் கதைகளின் அருகில் வைத்து அளந்து பார்த்துக்கொள்கிறீர்கள் என்று உங்களுக்குச் சொல்லிவிட விரும்புகிறேன்."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - I sina ungdoms- och juniorår representerade Surový Slovakien vid U18-VM 1999 och vid JVM både 2000 och 2001. U18-VM arrangerades för första gången 1999, i Tyskland. Slovakien tog brons och Surový noterades för tre poäng på sju matcher (ett mål, två assist). Vid JVM 2000","answer":"slutade Slovakien sist i sin grupp och tvingades kvala mot Ukraina för att behålla sin plats i JVM. Efter att båda nationer vunnit varsin match, spelades en 10 minuter lång avgörande match där Slovakien till slut vann efter straffläggning. Surový gick poänglös under turneringen. Han blev sedan uttagen att spela JVM 2001 i Ryssland. Slovakien lyckades ta sig till slutspel, men blev omgående utslagna av Finland med 3–1 i kvartsfinal. På sju matcher stod Surový för fyra poäng (ett mål, fyra assist)."},{"question":"كم مرة حج رسول الله؟\\t","answer":"مرة واحدة"},{"question":"Nước chanh có dùng để giải rượu được không?","answer":"Chanh tươi là phương pháp giải rượu truyền thống, hiệu quả. Trường hợp bị bệnh tiêu hóa, bạn có thể thêm gừng, mật ong, muối, sữa để giảm độ chua và tăng hương vị.Ví dụ, thái một củ gừng tươi khoảng 60 g thành từng lát mỏng cho vào một ly trà kèm một lát chanh. Vị gừng nóng có tác dụng chống say rượu. Ngoài ra, có thể cho thêm một thìa mật ong vào nước trà gừng nóng. Bên cạnh đó, uống nước chanh hoặc cam pha mật ong, khi tỉnh dậy sẽ thấy tỉnh táo và ít khát nước hơn.Hoặc có thể lấy một quả chanh thái lát mỏng hoặc vắt lấy nước cốt chanh pha vào một chút nước ấm rồi thêm đường."},{"question":"Macdanta Loo Yaqaano Zinc-ka.","answer":"Zinc wuxuu kor u qaadaa koritaanka iyo kobcidda caadiga ah. Wuxuu caawiyaaraysashada nabarrada, wuxuu joogteeyaa habkadifaaca jirka oo caafimaad qaba wuxuu kaloogacan ka geystaa ka hortegga shubanka carruurta yar yar."},{"question":"Aiza no tanan-dehibe be velarana indrindra ao amin'ny kontinenta Eoropeanina?","answer":"I Londres no tanan-dehibe be velarana indrindra ao amin'ny kontinenta Eoropeanina."},{"question":"什么是人工智能奴役人类的概念？","answer":"答：人工智能奴役人类的概念是指在科幻作品或未来学说中，当人工智能发展到一定程度，超过人类智慧并开始控制或奴役人类的情形。"},{"question":"Tómi Ọdúnsì","answer":"Tomi Odunsi tí wọ́n bí ní ọjọ́ Kẹrìnlélógún oṣù Karùn-ún ọdún 1987 jẹ́ òṣèré orí-ìtàgé, olórin, òńkọrin tí gbogbo ènìyàn mọ̀ sí Ṣaléwá nínú eré onípele ọlọ́sọ̀ọ̀sẹ̀ ti Tinsel.Wọ́n bí Tómi ní ọjọ́ Kẹrìnlélógún oṣù Karùn-ún ọdún 1987 ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn. Ó lọ sílé ẹ̀kọ́ Yunifásitì Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó níbi tí ó ti kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ gboyè nínú ìmọ̀ ẹ̀dá-èdè (linguistics) àti èdè ilẹ̀ Adúláwọ̀, tí ó sì mú èdè Yorùbá ní iṣẹ́ àṣàyàn. She premiered her debut single, \\"I Wan Blow\\", in April 2013 and performed it at the Oriental Hotel in August 2013.Ó jẹ́ olùdásílẹ̀ CGT Media Ltd, African entertainment and media company."},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:મુશ્કેલીથી મેળવી શકાય તેવું","answer":"દુષ્પ્રાપ્ય"},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Robert H. Grubbs para a química?","answer":"Robert H. Grubbs recebeu o Prêmio Nobel de Química em 2005 por suas contribuições para o desenvolvimento da metátese de olefinas, uma importante reação na síntese orgânica."},{"question":"ضد یخ چه عملی در رادیاتور انجام می دهد؟","answer":"مایع ضد یخ علاوه بر آنکه از یخ زدگی آب در سرما جلوگیری می کند، در به تاخیر اندازی نقطه جوش آب نیز تاثیر مهم دارد. عدم استفاده از ضد یخ در تابستان می تواند منجر به جوش آوردن زودتر موتور شود. ضدیخ همچنین در جلوگیری از زنگ زدگی رادیاتور و قطعات سیستم خنک کاری موثر است."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _ :\\"Jamba mangery amoron-tevana _\\" .","answer":"\\"Jamba  mangery amoro-tevana  ka latsaka alohan'ny tainy.\\" ."},{"question":"එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ මූලස්ථානය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ කොහෙද?","answer":"එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයේ මූලස්ථානය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ ජපානයේ ටෝකියෝ නුවරෙහිය."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada wang abang saya, tak ada wang abang paya\\"?","answer":" Ia bermaksud orang yang disukai apabila seseorang itu kaya atau berharta sahaja."},{"question":"Wyjaśnij znaczenie powiedzenia: \\"Fortuna kołem się toczy.\\"","answer":"Jasne, oto wyjaśnienie. \\"Fortuna kołem się toczy\\" to stare przysłowie, które sięga do mitologii rzymskiej, w której Fortuna była boginią przeznaczenia. Bardzo często jej postać była przedstawiana właśnie z kołem, które wprawione w ruch toczy się tak długo, aż nie podziałają na niego siły zewnętrzne. Jest to bardzo mądre powiedzenie, które uświadamia nam, że przeznaczenie jest cały czas w „ruchu”. Nasz los może w każdej chwili ulec zmianie. Okresy szczęśliwe są przeplatane nieszczęściami i odwrotnie. Jedyne, czego możemy być pewni, to zmiana. "},{"question":"Ысытуу : муздатуу(А) кууруу : кайнатуу(Б) жутуу : ичүү(В) кирдетүү : тазалоо(Г) ырдоо : бийлөөСуроо: кайсы вариант тура?","answer":"Жооп: (В) варианты туура.Суроого жооп бериш үчүн мындайча ой жүгүрттүк.Жогорудагы сөздөрдүн баары кыймыл – аракетти билдирет. Демек, ысытуу:мыздатуу кыймыл-аракетти билдирген, толук антоним сөздөр. (А), (Г) вариантындагы сөздөр бири-бирине карама-каршы сөздөр боло албайт. (Б) вариантында болсо жутуу жана ичүү деген сөздөрдүн кандайдыр бир маанилик катышы болгону менен бул сөздөр антоним боло алышпайт. Ошондуктан, бир гана туура вариант – (В) варианты."},{"question":"मानकीकरण\\" (Standardization) ","answer":"\\"मानकीकरण\\" (Standardization) हे डेटा प्रक्रिया आहे ज्याच्यामध्ये डेटा प्रमाणाच्या मूल्यांच्या वरिनेंट्समध्ये स्थितितल्या वाचनीयतेत आणि मूल्यांतरितीत लागू केली जाते, ज्यामुळे त्याच्या संरेखित प्रक्रिया किंवदंती वाचनीयतेच्या संकेतांना मिळते.मानकीकरणचा मुख्य उद्दिष्ट तो आहे की डेटा नॉर्मल प्रमाणे (standard scale) वाचण्याची क्रिया करणे, ज्यामुळे डेटा डेटा प्रमाणे 0 म्हणजे मान्य असल्याचे प्रमाणित केले जाते, आणि सामान्यवर्ती मूल्यांतरितीच्या परिपाटीला असल्याची सांकेतिक साथी दिली जाते.मानकीकरणच्या प्रक्रियेमध्ये प्रमुखपणे दोन प्रकारच्या मूल्यांतरिती वापरल्या जातात:माध्य तपासणी (Mean Normalization): डेटा या प्रमाणाच्या मूल्यांतरितीत डेटा या प्रमाणाच्या सर्व मूल्यांच्या माध्य अथवा सर्व मूल्यांच्या वरिनेंट्समध्ये वेग जतन करण्याचा क्रिया आहे. हे प्रक्रिया डेटा तपासण्यात वापरल्या जातात जेणेकरून डेटा या प्रमाणाच्या मूल्यांतरितीमध्ये कोणत्याही अस्थित्याची विशिष्ट चिन्हे किंवदंती असल्याचे प्रमाणित करतो.मॉक्सिममम एंड मिनिमम स्केलिंग (MinMax Scaling): इथे डेटा या प्रमाणाच्या मूल्यांच्या वरिनेंट्समध्ये वेग जतन करण्याचा क्रिया आहे, परंतु ती वेग जतन केली जाते की डेटा या प्रमाणाच्या मूल्यांच्या वरिनेंट्स 0 आणि 1 यात्रेसीमित होतात.मानकीकरणच्या प्रक्रियेच्या वापराने डेटा प्रमाणाच्या वरिनेंट्ससाठी वाचनीयता देण्यात मदतील असू शकते, डेटा प्रमाणांमध्ये विचाराच्या अंशाची माध्यस्थता बचावून ठेवण्यास मदतील आहे."},{"question":"පහත ගීතයේ තේරුම පහදන්න.හන්තානට පායන හඳ ලස්සනයිද කියන්න ....මා නොදකින ඒ පුරහඳඔබට හැකිය දකින්න ....අඳුරු ලලා වහිනා කලසරසවි බිම තෙමෙන්න ....කුඩේ යටින් ඔබ යන කලඑපා තනිය දැනෙන්න ....ලතා මඬුලු අත වනාවිඑපා අහක බලන්න ....මා ගැන මතකය ගුලි කරමහවැලියට දමන්න ....","answer":"සැබෑ ප්‍රේමය වූ කලී හිමිකර ගැනීමම නොවෙයි .... එය හුදෙක් ආධ්‍යාත්මික බැඳීමක් වටා ගෙතුණු ; අනෙකාගේ සුවය ; අනෙකාගේ සුඛය මුල් කොටගෙන පිදෙන සොඳුරු ආත්මීය පූජාවකි ...මෙම ගීතය තුළින් ධම්මික බණ්ඩායන් පෙන්වා දෙන්නේ එකී ප්‍රේමගත කැඩපතෙහි දිස්වන පාරිශුද්ධ වූ ප්‍රේම පූජාවක ප්‍රතිබිම්භයයි ....මීට වස්තුවිෂය වූයේද සත්‍ය සිදුවීමකි ...එය වරෙක ධම්මිකයන් විසින්ම මුහුණ දුන්නකි .... මෙතැන් සිට අපිද එය දකිමු ; විඳිමු ....සිය උපකාරක පන්තියේ විවේක කාලය තුළදී හදිසියේම ගුරුවරයාගේ නෙතු සොරා ගන්නේ අපූරු දසුනකි ... එයනම් , එක බත් පත බෙදාගෙන ; නොයෙක් උසුළු විසුළු පාමින් ; බත් කන ; කවන තරුණයෙකු සහ තරුණියකගේ දසුනකි ....නොයෙක් කරුණු කාරණා මත සිතමින් .. මොවුන් දෙදෙනා ඉඳුරාම පෙමින් බැඳුණු යුවළක් විය යුතුයැයි ගුරුවරයා හිතින් නිර්ණයක යෙදිණි ...පසුව දින , සති ගෙවී ගොස් කාලයාගේ ඇවෑමෙන් මොවුන්ද උ.පෙළ විභාගයට මුහුණ දුන් අතර ඔය සිදුවීම ද ගුරුවරයාට අමතකව ගියේය ....-------------------------------------දිනක් නඟරයේදී මෙම ගුරුවරයාට හදිසියේ තරුණයෙකු මුණගැසෙයි ....\\" sir ට මාව මතකද ...!? \\"මොහොතක් සිතා බැලූ කල ගුරුවරයාට මොහු පිළිබඳ මතකයට නැඟෙයි ....' ඔව් ...මේ ඔහු තමයි ... එදා එක බත් පත අනා කමින් සිය ප්‍රියාවිය සමඟ ආදරයෙන් මුකුළු පෑ ඒ තරුණයා මොහුයි ... 'Sir : ඉතින් කොහොමද ?... දැන් මොකද කරන්නේ දරුවෝ ...!? කෝ දැන් අර ඉස්සර බත් කවා ගත්තු ගෑනු ළමයා ආ ....!!??තරුණයා : එයා දැන් campus එකේ sir...දැන් අපේ සම්බන්ධය නෑ ...Sir : මොකක් ...!? ඒ මොකද ඒ ...!? ඇයි ගෑනු දරුවා වෙනස් වුනාවත්ද campus ගියාට පස්සේ ...!?තරුණයා : අනේ නෑ sir...!! එයා එහෙම කෙනෙක් නෙවෙයි .... ගොඩක් ....ගොඩක් ....හොඳ කෙනෙක් .....අපි දෙන්නම campus යන්න තමයි ආශා කළේ .... ඒත් මට ඒ හීනෙ හැබෑවක් කර ගන්න බැරි වුනානෙ sir...එත් ,. එහෙමයි කියලා මට එයාගෙ සතුට නැති කරන්න බෑ ... එයා මට වඩා ගොඩක් ඉහළ ,.. ගොඩක් දුර යන්න පුළුවන් කෙනෙක් .... ඉතින් ,.. මං එයා එක්ක ඉන්නවා කියන්නේ එයාගෙ ගමනට බාධාවක් ....අන්න ඒ නිසා ඉතින් කොච්චර අමාරු වුනත් ..... කොහොමින් හරි මේ හිත හදාගෙන මං එයාගෙන් දුරස් වුනා ...ඒ එයාගෙ සතුට වෙනුවෙන් ... මට වඩා උගත් හොඳ කෙනෙක් එයාට ලැබෙයි .... එයා වෙනුවෙන් එයාගෙ අනාගතය වෙනුවෙන් ඉතින් මං මගේ ආදරය පූජා කළා sir....ඔය වචන ටික ඇහෙද්දිම ගුරුවරයාට හිතුනලු අදටත් අධම ආදරවන්තයන් මැද මෙහෙව් සොඳුරු චරිතත් ඉන්නවනේ කියලා .... ඒ නැඟුණු සිතිවිලි කැටි කිරීම තුළින් තමයි මේ ගීතය බිහි වෙන්නේ ....\\" හන්තානට පායන හඳ ලස්සනයි ද කියන්න ....මා නොදකින ඒ පුරහඳඔබට හැකිය දකින්න .... \\"අපි දෙන්නා එකට පාඩම් කළේ ; සරසවියට එන්න හිතාගනනේ ..... ඒත් මට ඒක අහිමි හීනයක් වුනා .... හැබැයි මට සතුටුයි ... ඔයා අද ඒ හීනෙ හැබෑ කරගෙන ....මට අහිමි ඒ සොඳුරු හන්තාන සඳ .... අද ඔයා දකිනවා ; විඳිනවා ...ඉතින් කියන්න .... ඒ සඳ ලස්සන ද ...!? හැබෑ වුණු ඔයාගේ හීනෙ සුන්දරද ...!?\\" අඳුරු ලලා වහිනා කලසරසවි බිම තෙමෙන්න ....කුඩේ යටින් ඔබ යන කලඑපා තනිය දැනෙන්න ...\\"\\" ලතා මඬුලු අත වනාවිඑපා අහක බලන්න ....මා ගැන මතකය ගුලි කරමහවැලියට දමන්න .... \\"සරසවිය යනු සැබැවින්ම ප්‍රේම පාරාදීසයකි .... එහි සරන්නන් අතරතුර ප්‍රේමාතුරයන් නොසිටින්නේ කලාතුරකිනි ....මෙහි ,...' හතර වටින් කළුවර කරගෙන මන්දාරම් වැහි ඇද වැටෙනා ; සරසවි බිම තෙමෙනා මොහොතේ ..... කුඩය යටින් යනෙන නුඹට තනියක් නොදැනේවා ' යැයි කෙරෙන ප්‍රාර්ථනය තුළින්ම මෙකී ප්‍රේමවන්තයාගේ ආත්මීය පූජාවේ උත්තම බව විශද වෙයි ....එසේම ,....සරසවිය පුරා රැඳි තුරු ලතා , .. රුක් ගොමු , ... තණ ඇතිලිරි ..... ආලවන්ත කම් පිබිදීමට තෝතැන්නකි ....අතරතුර සැදි ලතා මණ්ඩප .... පෙම්වතුනට හුරු ; නුහුරු ආලනුරා දඟකම් පෑමට ඇරයුම් කරන්නා සේ බලා සිටියි ...ඉතින් නුඹ මා ගැන සොවින් තැවි තැවී නොසිට ; මා පිළිබඳ ඇති සියලූම වූ මතකයන් පොදි බැඳ ..... සරසවිය අසලින් ගලන මහවැලි නදියට දමන්න ....අනතුරුව නුඹට හිමි ලෝකයේ සොඳුරුතා විඳින්න ....නුඹට හිතැති උගත් ....ආදරණීය පෙම්වතෙකු හා ඔය සොඳුරු ලතා මඬුලු වල සරන්න ..... හීන් හිරි පොද වැස්සේ එක කුඩයක මුවා වෙලා සොඳුරු මිහිරි සුව විඳින්න ..... මට උරුම නැති ලෝකයේ කිරුළු පලඳින්න .... ඒ ලස්සන දුර ගමනට මගෙන් ආසිරි ....------------------------------------තම ප්‍රියයා හෝ ප්‍රියාවිය තමන්ට අහිමි වූ කල සාහසිකව හැසිරෙනා උමතු දනන් වෙසෙනා ලොවක ...... මෙවැනි බෝසත් චරිත පිළිබඳ අපි කුමක් කියමුද ...!?? සිතමුද ...!?ප්‍රේමයේ නිසි අරුත දන්නා මෙවැනි උන් ළඟ සැබැවින්ම අප ප්‍රේමයට දුහුනන් නොවේද .....!?( සිතීම ඔබට පවරමි... )"},{"question":"ભારતીય હેરિટેજ ગુજરાતી ભોજન","answer":"ગુજરાતી ફૂડ કલ્ચરના ચાર આધારસ્તંભકાઠિયાવાડી ભોજનસુરતી ભોજનઆમદાવાડી ભોજનકચ્છી ભોજન"},{"question":"સ્ક્વિડ ગેમ્સ નેટફ્લિક્સ શ્રેણીના કલાકારોની યાદી બનાવો","answer":"લી જંગ-જેપાર્ક હે-સૂજંગ હો-યેઓનઓ યેઓંગ-સુવાઈ હા-જૂનઅનુપમ ત્રિપાઠીકિમ જૂ-ર્યોંગ"},{"question":"Sheeg magaca saddexan ee halgame Xalane, meesha uu ku geeriyooday iyo   sanadkii  uu geeriyooday? ","answer":" Waxa uu ahaa sanadkii 1960kii."},{"question":"புத்தரின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"ஆசையே துன்பத்தின் அடிப்படை. பௌத்தத்தில், ஆசையும் அறியாமையும் துன்பத்தின் வேரில் உள்ளது என்று கூறப்படுகிறது. ஆசை என்பதன் மூலம், பௌத்தர்கள் ஏங்குதல் இன்பம், பொருள் பொருட்கள் மற்றும் அழியாமை ஆகியவற்றைக் குறிப்பிடுகின்றனர், இவை அனைத்தும் ஒருபோதும் திருப்தி அடைய முடியாத தேவைகள். இதன் விளைவாக, அவற்றை விரும்புவது துன்பத்தை மட்டுமே தரும் என்பதே இதன் பொருள்."},{"question":"Qual o significado de \\"Chutar o balde?\\"","answer":"Significa descontrolar-se, tendo atitudes erradas."},{"question":"Inty misy apahan-dahatsoratra:Ny nosikelin' Ampasy dia nosim-pasika fotsy tsy voahitsakitsaky ny olona raha tsy indraindray ihany. Ahitana zavamaniry, ka isan' izany ny bararata. Tokony ho 10 km miala an' i Belo amin' ny moron' ny reniranon' i Tsiribihina ity toerana fanaovana ny lanonana ity.Manomeza fanontaniana azo apetraka momba io ampahan-dahatsoratra io.","answer":"Indro misy fanontaniana azo apetraka momba io ampahan-dahatsoratra io: Tahaka ny ahoana izany nosikelin'Ampasy izany?"},{"question":"Cé hé Eileen Gray? ","answer":"Ailtire agus dearthóir troscán Éireannach ab ea Kathleen Eileen Moray Gray (9 Lúnasa 1878 – 31 Deireadh Fómhair 1976). Ceannródaí i ngluaiseacht ailtireachta an Nua-Aoiseachais ba ea í. Bhí Gray ar dhuine de na dearthóirí agus na hailtirí ba mhó tionchar sa 20ú haois. In Inis Córthaidh, i gContae Loch Garman, a rugadh í. D'fhás sí aníos ansin agus i Londain. Rinne sí staidéir ar an ealaín i Londain (scoil Slade) agus ansin i bPáras (scoil Julien). Sa Fhrainc a chaith sí an chuid ba mhó dá saol mar dhuine fásta. Bhí sí ina cónaí san árasán céanna i bPáras (21 rue Bonaparte, 6ú arrondissement) ó 1907 go dtí lá a báis sa bhliain 1976, in aois a 98 bliana. Bhí Gray ar dhuine de phríomhcheannairí na gluaiseachta deartha nua-aimseartha i dtús na 20ú haoise. Dhear sí troscán laicir ar dtús. Thosaigh sí ag obair le foirmeacha ailtireachta i ndeireadh na 1920idí. Bhí cur chuige nua aici maidir le cruth, líne, úsáid dathanna, ábhair agus uigeachtaí."},{"question":"Ayat 1: Dia ialah bapa saudara pemuzik Tal Bachman dan bapa Ryder Bachman. Ayat 2: Dia ialah bapa saudara kepada pemuzik Tal Bachman dan bapa kepada Ryder Bachman. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan maksud yang sama? ","answer":"Ya."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Tối 28/8 (13/7 âm lịch), khuôn viên chùa Phước Duyên ở phường Hương Long, TP Huế chật kín phật tử về tham dự lễ Vu Lan do nhà chùa tổ chức. Trong đêm lễ, các phật tử đã cùng nhau tụng kinh Vu Lan báo hiếu, tưởng nhớ công ơn của những đấng sinh thành.Vu Lan báo hiếu là một trong những nghi lễ quan trọng của ","answer":"những người theo đạo Phật. Lễ được tổ chức vào rằm tháng 7 hàng năm, xuất phát từ sự tích Bồ tát Mục Kiền Liên đại hiếu cứu mẹ khỏi kiếp ngạ quỷ bằng cách nghe lời Phật dạy.Rằm tháng 7 có thể nói là tháng đẹp nhất trong năm khi những người con học theo hiếu lễ của Mục Kiền Liên tôn giả hướng về cha mẹ, đánh dấu chư tăng kết thúc 3 tháng an cư tỏa sáng công hạnh."},{"question":"Yimuphi umbuzo othi: \\"I-gravy iyisosi, ngokuvamile eyenziwe ngejusi eliphuma ngokwemvelo enyameni noma emifino lapho iphekwa\\".\\"? Isihloko sithi uGravy.","answer":"\\"Isenziwa ngani isoso? Hangazi\\""},{"question":"Waxaad sheegta noocyada cabsida foobiyada (Phobias) Sababaha keeno iyo dadka u nugul ?","answer":"Foobiyadu waa xanuun maskaxeed, leh dareen cabsiyeed ama baqdin joogta ah. dadka qaba xanuunka foobiyada waxay leeyihiin waxyaalo badan oo ka danbeeya in xanuunkan ku dhaco, dadka qaarkood waxay yeeshaan astaamo ay kamid yihiin cabsi daran, argagax joogta ah iyo feejignaan. cabsida haleesha bukaanada la ildaran xanuunkan waxay noqon kartaa mid ku xiran waqtiyo gaar ah, goobo gaar ah ama walxo gaar ah oo bukaanku si gaara uga qabo cabsi kuwaasoo ku sababaya inuu qofku foobiyo ka qaado waxyaalahaas.Saamaynta xanuunka foobiyadu ku yeelato dadka waxay noqon kartaa mid iska caadi ah ama mid khatar ah oo bukaanka garsiisa xaalad halis ah, dadka qaba foobiyada waxay qaarkood ogaadaan in xaladoodu tahay xaalad maskaxeed ama jiro maskaxeed haysa balse waxba kama qaban karaan.Astaamaha laga dhaxlo xanuunka foobiyada waxay saamayn ku yeelan kartaa qofka shaqadiisa, waxbarashadiisa, iyo noloshiisa gaarka ah ama xataa nolosha qoyskiiska.Maxaa sababa cabsida ama Foobiyada?  Waxaa la aamin sanyahay in xanuunkan lakala dhaxli karo, waxaa kaloo xanuunkan sababi kara xaalado kale oo la xiriira deegaanka qofku ku noolyahay. marxaladaha murugada iyo walwalka wata oo qofku soo dhex galo, deegaanka aan nadaafadiisu wacnayn oo qofku badanaa joogo, meelaha jooga sare leh oo qofku ku badnaado, qaniinyada xayawaanada iyo cayayaanka qaarkood, dhamaan qodobadaas aya noqon kara kuwa sababa foobiyada.waxaa jiri kara dad badan oo caafimaadkoodu taam yahay oo hadana waxyaalaha qaarkood ka qaba foobiyo, saan horay usoo sheegnayna xaaladaha foobiyadu waa kala duwanaan karaan, dadka shilalka gala ama madaxa ay jugi kasoo gaarto ayaa kamid ah kuwa u nugul cudurka foobiyada.Noocyada Foobiyada:Waxaa jira oo ila hada bahda caafimadku ogyihiin boqolaal nooc oo foobiya ah balse waxaan halkaan kusoo bandhigaynaa kuwa ugu caansan uguna waxyeelada wayn ee dadka ku dhaca.Agoraphobia: waa cabsi uu qofku ka cabsado meelaha qaarkood iyo xaaladaha uusan qofku ka baxsan karin. dadka qaba xaaladan waxay ka cabsadaan inay ku dhex jiraan meel dad badan joogaan ama inay guriga banaanka uga baxaan, waxay necebyihiin inay xaafadooda ka baxaan oo banaanka aadaan, sidoo kale ma jecla inay bulshada dhex galaan. dadka qaba xaaladan, qaarkood waxay lakulmi karaan xaalado deg deg ah sida inay suuxaan ama in xaaladooda caafimaad halis gasho, waxay arintaan ku dhici kartaa markay la kulmaan waxyaalaha ay foobiyada ka qabaan.Social Phobia: dad badan ayaa waxay necbaan karaan xaalado gaara ama waxyaalo gaara,balse hadii la rabo in shayga lagu qeexo inuu yahay Foobiya run ah, waa in cabsida oo ah shayga koowaad ee furaha u ah xanuunka foobiyadu ay noqota mid qofka noloshiisa maalin laha ah si toosa ula xiriirta, waa inay noqotaa mid maalin walba joogta ah. taas ayaa si gaara loo oran karaa Social Phobia.Glossophobia: wuxuu qofku cabsi ka qabaa inuu dadka hortooda wax ka sheego, siiba in qofku dad badan hortood soo istaago wax sheego waa shay ku adag dadka qaba foobiyada noocaan ah.Acrophobia: dadka qaba noocaan waxay necebyihiin inay joogaan meelaha jooga sare leh sida buuraha, guryaha dhaa dheer, iyo buundooyinka iyo diyaaradaha. calaamadaha dadkaan lagu garto waxaa kamid ah naxdin joogto ah markay meelahaan yimaadaan, wareer ama dawakhaad, dhidid, iyo dareen ah in qofku markaas dhimanayo ama uu miyir daboolmayo.Astaamaha FoobiyadaAstaamaha ugu caansan uguna badan ee noocyada kala duwan ee foobiyada waxaa kamid ah: Argagax ama naxdin, wadna garaac, neefsashada oo dhib noqota, hadalka oo deg deg qofka uga soo baxa, ama hadalka oo qofka ka xirma, afka oo qallala, lallabo, cadaadiska dhiiga oo siyaada, jirka oo gariira, xabad xanuun, dawakhaad ama madax wareer, dhidid, iwm.Yaa khatar ugu jira FoobiyadaWaxaa la aaminsanyahay in dadka walidkood ama faracoodii hore uu qabay foobiyada inay kujiraan khatarta ugu badan ee cudurkaan ugu dhici karo. sidoo kale waxyaalaha kale ee qofka galin kara xaalad halis u ah inuu foobiyo qaado waxaa kamid ah, da’da, xaalada dhaqaale iyo midda bulsho ee qofka, sidoo kale waxaa la aaminsanyahay in kala duwanaanshaha jinsiga dadku ay leedahay saamaynteeda gaarka ah. tusaale ahaan dumarku waxay si gara foobiyo ugu qabaan xayawaanada. caruurta iyo dadka xaaladooda dhaqaale hoosayso waxay ayaguna foobiya badanaa ku qabaan bulshada inay ku dhex jiraan, halka raguna ay badanaa foobiya ka qaadaan dhakhaatiirta ilkaha iyo ilka gashiga ama ilka badalida.Sidee looga hortagi karaa Cabsida/foobiyada:Cudur walba wuxuu leeyahay kahortag kaasoo ka fiicnaan kara dawaynta. cudurka foobiyada oo noqon kara mararka qaarkood xaalad caadiya oo dadku la noolaan karaan, mararka qaarkoodna noqon kara xaalad halis ah waxaa looga hortagi karaa ayadoo qofku iska ilaaliyo waxyaalaha qofka ku kicinaya foobiyada ee aan kasoo sheekaynay.waxaa kaloo looga hortagi karaa ayadoo qofku ku xirnaado Allah subxaanu watacaalaa sababtoo ah qofka Allah ku xiran waajibaadkiisana ilalaiya wuxuu mar walba ku sugnaadaa amaanada Rabbi."},{"question":"Sheeg shanta Nabi ee Ulul-Casmiga laysku yiraahdo?","answer":"Shanta Nabi ee Ulul-Casmiga laysku yiraahdo  waxay kala yihiin.1- Nabi Nuux (Cs),2- Nabi Ibrahim (Cs).3- Nabi Muuse (Cs).4- Nabi Ciise (Cs),5- Nabi Muxamed Scw."},{"question":"Арзыкан, сизге биз күйгөнАрманым айттым бир жүргөн (Барпы).Суроо: Бул ырдан ат атоочту тап","answer":"Жооп: сизге, биз"},{"question":"Explain the concept of amortized analysis.","answer":"Amortized analysis involves averaging the time or space complexity over a sequence of operations to determine the average performance, providing a more accurate representation of the overall efficiency."},{"question":"Tuliskan sebuah karangan yang bertajuk 'Langkah-Langkah Memartabatka Bahasa Malaysia'","answer":"      'Bahasa jiwa bangsa', itulah frasa yang paling sesuai untuk melambangkan signifikan sesuatu bahasa kepada bangsa-bangsa di Malaysia. Pelbagai polemik telah dibangkitkan sejak akhir-akhir ini bagi membicarakan identiti bahasa Malaysia sebagai bahasa kebangsaan bagi sebuah rumpun bernama Malaysia. Bahasa Malaysia telah diadaptasikan daripada frasa asal 'Bahasa Melayu' yang disifatkan berjiwa perkauman sekaligus tidak relevan dengan Gagasan 1 Malaysia. Namun begitu, apakah inisiatif yang perlu dilaksanakan demi memartabatkan bahasa Malaysia dalam kalangan masyarakat?      Langkah-langkah yang patut diambil termasuklah menggesa semua urusan rasmi dan surat-menyurat di semua jabatan kerajaan diimplimentasikan dalam bahasa ibunda. Mutakhir ini, jabatan-jabatan kerajaan lebih gemar memilih bahasa Inggeris yang dianggap berdarjat tinggi berbanding bahasa Malaysia untuk digunakan dalam urusan syarikat mereka. Sifat nafsi yang menggunung dalam jiwa mereka wajar diibaratkan seperti kacang lupakan kulit kerana mereka persis mengenepikan sebuah bahasa yang telah mendewasakan pemikiran mereka. Oleh itu, pihak-pihak ini haruslah menjaga martabat bahasa Malaysia supaya tidak hilang ditelan zaman.      Selain itu, idea Pengajaran dan Pembelajaran Sains dan Matematik dalam Bahasa Inggeris (PPSMI) juga harus dilupuskan. Sifat dominan bahasa Inggeris dalam kehidupan kita tidak harus dinafikan, tetapi langkah ini dilihat berpotensi memadamkan kegemilangan bahasa Malaysia di peringkat lokal. Jika teras pentarbiahan turut dilaksanakan dalam bahasa asing, tidak mustahil pada satu era nanti, generasi akan datang tidak mengenali lagi perkataan 'Melayu'. Ironinya, usaha Memartabatkan Bahasa Malaysia dan Memperkasakan Bahasa Inggeris (MBMMBI) dilihat sangat proaktif sebagai mangkin yang efektif demi membejat kemelut bahasa yang sedang dihadapi Malaysia kini.      Sementelahan pula, kewujudan Sekolah Jenis Kebangsaan (SJK) Cina dan Tamil juga tidak harus dikerling enteng berikutan perkara tersebut berkemampuan memperkasakan bahasa Cina dan bahasa Tamil lantas menjatuhkan darjat bahasa ibunda di sekolah-sekolah berkenaan. Jika dilihat dari perspektif berbeza, hal ini dapat menimbulkan nafsi perkauman bahkan tidak sejajar dengan penerapan 1Malaysia dalam kalangan masyarakat. Maka, polemik ini mungkin tidak dapat mencapai objektif kemenjadian bahasa sebagai agen perpaduan yang utuh bagi semua rakyat di negara ini. Tuntasnya, pihak-pihak yang berwajib seperti Dewan Bahasa dan Pustaka (DBP) harus berfikir secara kreatif dan kritis demi menaikkan imej bahasa ibunda secara holistik.        Di samping itu, bagi mengukuhkan kedudukan bahasa Malaysia dalam sanubari rakyat rencaman golongan, DBP harus melaksanakan pelbagai aktiviti yang menggapai minat umum terhadap keindahan bahasa Malaysia. Aktiviti seperti Sayembara Pidato Antarabangsa anjuran Kementerian Kebudayaan, Kesenian, Warisan dan Pelancongan dengan usahasama Radio Televisyen Malaysia (RTM) baru-baru ini dilihat sebagai anjakan paradigma yang berpotensi memperkenalkan bahasa kebangsaan di peringkat dunia. Deduksinya, langkah yang sama harus diambil DBP untuk mewujudkan 'jiwa bahasa' dalam kalangan rakyat.     Mendepani arus globalisasi kini, pelbagai perubahan serta modifikasi yang sudah dilaksanakan terhadap bahasa Malaysia asal sehingga terbentuk bahasa rojak. Lihat sahaja di kiri dan kanan jalan raya serta di bangunan-bangunan pencakar langit, banyak papan tanda memaparkan penggunaan bahasa rojak. Perkara ini tidak patut dibiarkan berlarutan kerana keupayaannya untuk mencemarkan bahasa adalah tinggi. Pihak Berkuasa Tempatan (PBT) tidak harus berpeluk tubuh dan mendiamkan diri, sebaliknya perlu mengambil tindakan Undang-undang bagi menyedarkan pihak berkenaan bahawa bahasa Malaysia bukanlah sebuah wadah mainan komersial. Oleh itu, 'pidana bahasa' ini perlu dibejat bagi mewujudkan rakyat kontemporari yang berpegang teguh dengan bahasa ibunda.      Konklusinya, semua pihak haruslah menggembleng sinergi untuk meledakkan darjat bahasa Malaysia sebagai bahasa rasmi dalam semua urusan harian, selain status utamanya sebagai bahasa kebangsaan. Janganlah kita menjadi manusia yang khusyuk menyelami sungai pemodenan dengan mementingkan bahasa asing sebaliknya menidakkan kebolehan bahasa Malaysia untuk membawa kita ke mata dunia. Pepatah Melayu ada menyebut, \\"yang kurik itu kendi, yang merah itu saga, yang baik itu budi, yang indah itu bahasa\\". Oleh hal yang demikian, marilah kita berpijak di bumi yang nyata dengan menjaga bahasa kebangsaan supaya kekal nirmala dan 'tak lapuk dek hujan, tak lekang dek panas'."},{"question":"Sheeg Kumuu Ahaa Ninkii Ey U Kireysteen Rasuulka (NNKH) Iyo Abuu-Bakar Rc Inuu Jidka Tuso Markii Ey U Hijroonaayeen Madiina?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Dal Aqoonkii La’oran Jiray Cabdullaahi Bin Ariiqadh."},{"question":"« Nandeha lavitra ny resaka ka tonga tany amin’izay tsy tokony ho henon’ny zaza tsy ampy taona. Maro anefa ireo zanak’i zoky izay voa manomboka hiala sakana teo nanatrika anay na tsy dia nihaino be ny resakay aza. »Inona no mety fiafaran’ny tantara :A. Najanona ny resaka dia novaina haingana.B. Notohizana ihany ny resaka.","answer":"Ny valiny A. \\"Nandeha lavitra ny resaka ka tonga tany amin’izay tsy tokony ho henon’ny zaza tsy ampy taona. Maro anefa ireo zanak’i zoky izay voa manomboka hiala sakana teo nanatrika anay na tsy dia nihaino be ny resakay aza.\\" dia fara-tantara mety hitranga kokoa."},{"question":" کارکوونکی په ښه توګه د کار په ترسره کولو ، د محصوالتو د کیفیت ښه والي او نوښتونو په ترسره کولو تشويقېږي ؟","answer":"ځواب: ۱ – د تحسین نامې اعطا کول ۲ – د تقديرنامې اعطا کول ۳ – د مالي مکافاتو ورکول ۴ – د مډال ، نښان او لقب ورکول"},{"question":"Awọn ọba Amosun yari fun igbimọ Oloye Kemta, wọn lawọn o ki i ṣe baalẹ, Tẹjuoṣo naa loun ṣi ni Olu Orile-Kemta","answer":"Latari bi igbimọ Oloye Kemta(Kemta Council Of Chiefs) nipinlẹ Ogun, ṣe ni awọn ti yọ Ọba Adetokunbọ Tẹjuoṣo nipo baalẹ tawọn fi i jẹ, ti wọn tun ni awọn baalẹ marundinlọgọrin ti Sẹnetọ Ibikunle Amosun sọ di ọba lọdun 2019 ki i ṣe ọba, awọn tọrọ naa kan ti koro oju si bi wọn ṣe pe wọn ni baalẹ, wọn lọba alade lawọn.Ṣe igbimọ oloye ni Kemta ti fi atẹjade sita lọsẹ to kọja, ninu eyi ti wọn ti ni awọn ti yọ Tẹjuoṣo, baalẹ Adabọnyin, l’Orile-Kemta, nipo baalẹ, bẹẹ ni kẹnikẹni ma ṣe pe e lọba tabi Olu Orile Kemta to n pe ara ẹ, nitori baalẹ lawọn fi i jẹ ki Amosun too sọ oun atawọn yooku rẹ dọba lọdun 2019.Awọn oloye Kemta fi kun un pe ijọba Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun gbe igbimọ oluwadii iyansipo awọn ọba naa kalẹ, wọn si ri i pe ọna ti wọn gba yan wọn ko tọna, ijọba si paṣẹ pe ki wọn pada sipo baalẹ, ki wọn yee pe ara wọn lọba mọ.Nigba to n sọrọ lori ohun tawọn Kemta fi sita yii, ọkan ninu awọn ọba ti Amosun yan naa, Ọba Tanimọwo Fọlarin, Olu Ijẹbu Muṣin to tun jẹ akọwe awọn ọba marundinlọgọrin naa, sọ lorukọ awọn ọba yooku pe awọn ko ba ma sọrọ, to ba jẹ ti Adabọnyin tawọn ọlọpaa mu nitori ẹsun jibiti nikan ni. Wọn ni ṣugbọn bawọn oloye Kemta ṣe n pe awọn ni baalẹ lẹyin tawọn ti di ọba ko ṣee dakẹ si, ohun to jẹ kawọn fesi niyẹn.Ọba Tanimọwo ti sọ pe ọjọ kẹtala, oṣu karun-un, ọdun 2019, ni Amosun ti sọ awọn di ọba, tawọn kuro nipo baalẹ.Wọn ni ọjọ kẹfa, oṣu keji, ọdun 2020, ni kootu paṣẹ pe ki ọrọ wa bo ṣe wa tẹlẹ (status quo), eyi to tumọ si pe bo ṣe wa latigba tawọn ti jọba, titi digba ti kootu yoo fi gbe idajọ mi-in jade. Wọn ni ko tumọ si pe kawọn pada sipo baalẹ.  ALAROYE pe Tẹjuoṣo ti wọn lawọn yọ loye, lori foonu laaarọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ojọ kẹwaa, oṣu karun-un yii, lati gbọ ero rẹ nipa iyọnipo naa, bayii lọkunrin naa wi.‘’ Aimọkan lo n da wọn laaamu, nibo ni wọn ti lagbara lati yọ mi loye, nigba tijọba ti gbe ote le wọn lati ọdun 2017, pe ki wọn ma da si ọrọ ọba ati yiyan baalẹ mọ nipinlẹ Ogun, emi dẹ jọba ni 2019.‘’Awọn kọ ni wọn fi mi jọba o, awọn dẹ kọ ni wọn fi mi jẹ baalẹ. Ogboni ni wọn, ile Ogboni la mọ wọn si, ko si nnkan to n jẹ Traditional Council kankan nibi kan.‘’ Emi ṣi ni Olu Orile Kemta, Adabọnyin, ẹnikan ko yọ mi loye’’Nipa ibi ti ẹsun jibiti ibasun ti wọn fi kan an de duro, Adetokunbọ ṣalaye pe ko sohun to n jẹ ẹsun jibiti lọrọ oun. O ni awọn kan ni wọn bẹrẹ ọtẹ naa lati tabuku oun lawujọ, ati lati jẹ koun dakẹ lori Ilẹ Olominira Yoruba toun n polongo ẹ kiri."},{"question":"请问“步步生莲花”这句话是什么意思？","answer":"这句话是用来形容女子步态轻盈姿，每一步都像莲花般娇艳，每一步都能开出美丽的花朵。"},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து முட்டை மசாலா மேகி செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:3 பாக்கெட் மேகி நூடுல்ஸ்5 முட்டை2 பெரிய வெங்காயம்4 தக்காளி1 அல்லது 2 பச்சை மிளகாய்3 பூண்டு பல்1 இஞ்சி துண்டு1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சீரகம்1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி மல்லி தூள்1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி கரம் மசாலா¼ மேஜைக்கரண்டி மஞ்சள் தூள்3 பாக்கெட் மேகி மசாலாதேவையான அளவு மிளகாய் தூள்தேவையான அளவு உப்புதேவையான அளவு ண்ணெய்சிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லி","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் வெங்காயம், தக்காளி, பச்சை மிளகாய், மற்றும் கொத்தமல்லியை நறுக்கி, இஞ்சி பூண்டை பேஸ்ட் ஆக்கி வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. அடுத்து ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் முட்டைகளை வேக வைப்பதற்கு தேவையான அளவு தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி பின்பு முட்டைகளை அதில் போட்டு அதை சுமார் 10 லிருந்து 12 நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும்.3. 10 நிமிடத்திற்கு பின் அடுப்பை அணைத்து விட்டு முட்டைகளை எடுத்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து சிறிது நேரம் ஆற விட்டு பின்பு அதன் கூடை உரித்து அதை ஒரு கத்தியின் மூலம் சிறு சிறு துண்டுகளாக நறுக்கி ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.4. இப்பொழுது ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.5. எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் அதில் ஒரு மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு சீரகத்தை போட்டு அதை சுமார் அரை நிமிடம் வரை வறுக்கவும்.6. அரை நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் வெங்காயத்தை போட்டு வெங்காயம் கண்ணாடி பதம் வரும் வரை அதை வதக்கவும்.7. வெங்காயம் கண்ணாடி பதம் வந்ததும் அதில் நாம் பொடியாக நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் தக்காளி, பச்சை மிளகாய், செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட், மற்றும் தேவையான அளவு உப்பு சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விட்டு தக்காளி நன்கு மசியும் வரை வதக்கவும்.8. தக்காளி நன்கு மசிந்தவுடன் அதில் மல்லி தூள், மஞ்சள் தூள், கரம் மசாலா, மற்றும் அவரவர் விருப்பத்திற்கேற்ப மிளகாய் தூளை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விட்டு சுமார் ஒரு நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும்.9. ஒரு நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அதில் மேகி மசாலாவை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.10. பின்பு அதில் சுமார் ரெண்டரை கப் அளவு தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி அதை நன்கு கலந்து விட்டு அதை சுமார் ஒரு நிமிடம் வரை கொதிக்க விடவும்.11. ஒரு நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அதில் மேகி துண்டுகளை எடுத்து உடைத்து போட்டு அது மசாலாவோடு ஓட்டுமாறு அதை நன்கு கலந்து விட்டு மேகி முக்கால் பாகம் வேகும் வரை வேக விடவும்.12. மேகி முக்கால் பாகம் வெந்ததும் அதில் நாம் வேக வைத்து நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் முட்டைகளை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கிளறி விட்டு சுமார் 2 லிருந்து 3 நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும்.13. 3 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அதில் சிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லியை தூவி ஒரு கிளறு கிளறி அதை அப்படியே எடுத்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.14. பின்னர் அதே பாத்திரத்தில் ஒரு முட்டையை உடைத்து ஊற்றி அதை ஆப் பாயிலாக இருக்கும்போது அதை எடுத்து நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் மேகி மீது பக்குவமாக வைத்து அதை சுட சுட பரிமாறவும்.15. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் மிகவும் அட்டகாசமான முட்டை மசாலா மேகி தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து சுவைத்து மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"Çörek otu yağı saça direk uygulanır mı?","answer":"Çörek otu yağı sağlıklı yağ kategorisinde olup genellikle bitkisel yağın kullanıldığı alanlarda kullanılabilir. Diğer yandan çörek otu yağı kozmetik olarak, cilt ve saça direkt uygulanabilir."},{"question":"Indro misy lahatsoratra:Hoy ny talen’ny sekoly: « Teo aloha dia nikasa hanatanteraka hetsika ihany izahay, saingy noho ny tsy fahampian’ny enti-manana sy ny fahalalana dia tsy lasa lavitra, fa hatramin’ny nampidirana ny fandaharan’asa “mpianatra iray, hazo iray” tato amin’ny sekoly dia nahazo fiofanana sahaza anay miaraka amin'ny fitaovana ary koa ny zavamaniry izahay. Eo ihany koa ity toeram-pambolena ity izay ampiasaina amin’ny fikojakojana ireo zava-maniry tanora izay ho ampiasaina amin’ny fambolen-kazo any aoriana. Tsy mbola nahita an’izany mihitsy izahay ary tsy sahy nieritreritra an’izany akory. Tsy toy ny hitako teo aloha fa ity dia azo tsapain-tanana sy mivaingana. Mino aho fa ho afaka handroso bebe kokoa isika izao ary hiezaka hanome hasina ity hetsika ity amin'ny alàlan'ny fikojakojana sy ny fanaraha-maso… »Efa nahazo zana-kazo hafa tamin’ny alàlan’ny mpamatsy vola hafa ny sekoly, ankoatra ny efa azony teo aloha. Mampanantena fampandrosoana manome famporisihana ity hetsika ity eny anivon’ilay distrika, eny fa any amin’ireo distrika hafa aza, izay heverina ho fanombohana ihany.Inona no olan'ny sekoly teo aloha?","answer":"Ny tsy fahampiana fitaovana sy ny fahalalana no olan'ny sekoly teo aloha ka nanakana azy hanatanteaka hetsika."},{"question":" வினா: வெந்தய கீரையின் மருத்துவக் குணங்களைக் குறிப்பிடுக","answer":" விடை :வெந்தய கீரையின் மருத்துவக் குணங்கள்:-வெந்தயம் என்பது மெத்தி என்ற பெயரில் இந்தியாவில் அழைக்கப்படுகிறது. அதன் விதைகள் மற்றும் அதன் இலைகள் நிறைய மருத்துவக் குணங்கள் வாய்ந்ததாக உள்ளது. நமது உடம்பை குளிர்ச்சியாக வைப்பதற்கு வெந்தயம் மிகவும் உதவி புரிகிறது. இது எந்த ஒரு சூழ்நிலைக்கும் ஏற்ற படி வளரும் மருத்துவக் குணம் வாய்ந்த மூலிகை செடியாகும்.வெந்தய கீரை புதிய பாலூட்டும் தாய்மார்களுக்கு பால் உற்பத்தியை அதிகரிக்கிறது. பிரசவ வலி மற்றும் மாதவிடாய் காலங்களில் ஏற்படும் வலிகளை குறைக்கிறது. மேலும் வயிற்றில் ஏற்படும் அலர்ஜி, குடல் அலர்ஜி குடல் அல்சர் போன்றவற்றை தடுப்பதோடு இரத்தத்தில் கொலஸ்ட்ரால் அளவை குறைக்கிறது. கெட்ட சுவாசத்தைத் தடுக்கிறது. இத்தகைய வெந்தயத்தின் மருத்துவப் பயன்கள் குறித்து இந்த பதிவில் தெரிந்துக் கொள்ளலாம். மேலும் வெந்தயக் கீரைகள் இரும்புச்சத்துப் பொருட்களை அதிக அளவில் கொண்டு உள்ளன. இந்த இரும்புச் சத்துப் உடலில் ஏற்படும் ரத்தசோகையை வராமல் தடுப்பதோடு உடலுக்குச்  சிறந்த நோய் எதிர்ப்பு சக்தியை வழங்குகின்றன.வெந்தயக் கீரையைப் பொடியாக நறுக்கி வதக்கி இரண்டு டம்ளர் தண்ணீர் விட்டு ஒரு டம்ளர் அளவிற்குச் காய்ச்சி, காலை மாலை குடித்து வர நெஞ்சுவலி பூரணமாகக் குணமாகும். உடல் சூடு அதிகமாக இருப்பவர்கள் வெந்தயக் கீரை சாப்பிடலாம். இதன் குளுர்ச்சி தன்மை உடல் சூட்டை குறைத்து குளிர்ச்சியை கொடுக்கும்.கபம், சளி உள்ளவர்கள் வெந்தயக் கீரை சாப்பிட்டால் விரைவாகக் குணமடையலாம். வெந்தயக் கீரையை வேகவைத்து, வெண்ணெயில் வதக்கிச் சாப்பிட்டால், பித்தத்தினால் வரும் மயக்கம் சரியாகும். பத்து கிராம் வெந்தயத்தை நெய்யில் வறுத்துச் சிறிதளவு சோம்பு, உப்பு சேர்த்து அரைத்து மோரில் கரைத்து சாப்பிட வயிற்றுப் போக்கு தீரும்.வெந்தயக் கீரைகளைத் தினசரி உணவில் சேர்ப்பது உடலில் ஏற்படும் புரதக்குறைபாட்டை போக்கி வலிமை சேர்க்கும். மேலும் கண்பார்வைக் குறைவு நோய்கள் இருப்பவர்கள் வெந்தயக் கீரையைத் தொடர்ந்து சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால் கண்பார்வை அதிகரிக்கும். மேலும் வெந்தயக் கீரை நரம்பு தளர்ச்சியில் இருந்து மீண்டுவர உதவும். அதனால் நரம்பு தளர்ச்சி உள்ளவர்களுக்கு இது ஓர் சிறந்த மருந்தாகும்."},{"question":"Na mitologia nórdica quem é Jord?","answer":"É a deusa guardiã de Midgard, a terra média e reino dos humanos."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny tsipelina amin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Mifatotra ny famonkarana sy ny fahaleovatena amin’ny isambatan’olona sy amin’ny firenena\\"","answer":"Ity ny fanambarana miaraka amin'ireo hadisoana voahitsy:\\"Mifatotra ny famokarana sy ny fahaleovan-tena amin’ny isam-batan’olona sy amin’ny firenena\\""},{"question":"மனித உடலில் அயோடின் குறைவால் ஏற்படுவது?","answer":"குறிப்பாக கடலுணவு உண்ணப்படாத உள்நாட்டுப் பகுதிகளிலும் வறண்ட புவிநடுவரை நாடுகளிலும் அயோடின் குறைபாடு மீத்தைராயிடியத்தை உருவாக்குகிறது. இது அயர்வு, கழுத்துக்கழலை, உள ஒடுக்கம், உள இறுக்கம், எடைகூடுதல், தாழ்ந்த அடிப்படை உடல் வெப்பநிலைபோன்ற அறிகுறிகளைத் தோற்றுவிக்கிறது."},{"question":"１９９８年デビュー。うし君とかえる君をあやつり、ブラック＆シュールな笑いを提供する芸人は？","answer":"パペットマペットです。"},{"question":"Berikan jawapan kepada soalan yang rumit ini: Pemuzik dan komposer Amerika manakah yang menjadi pemuzik jemputan dalam album Manhattan Blues Project oleh Steve Hunter?","answer":"Philip Aaberg"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：印度歷史上的「莫臥兒帝國」是哪位統治者建立的？","answer":"答案：印度歷史上的莫臥兒帝國是由巴布爾（Babur）建立的。巴布爾是中亞的一位君主，他成功征服印度並建立了莫臥兒帝國，該帝國在亞洲歷史上佔據重要地位。"},{"question":"Nibi ti kọsitọọmu at’onifayawọ ti n bara wọn ja ni wọn ti yinbọn pa ọmọọlewe kan ni Badagry","answer":"Ibanujẹ ati ọfọ nla ti ṣẹlẹ sawọn mọlẹbi akẹkọọ ọmọ ọdun mejidinlogun kan, Alade Ọba. Nibi tawọn aṣọbode atawọn onifayawọ ti n ba ara wọn ja ni ibọn tawọn kọsitọọmu n yin ti lọọ ba ọmọ ọhun, to si dagbere faye loju ẹsẹ.Gẹgẹ bi Ajọ Akoroyinjọ ilẹ wa, NAN, ṣe sọ, ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide to kọja yii, niṣẹlẹ naa waye. Wọn ni nibi ti eruku ija ti sọ lala, ti ọta ibọn n fo kaakiri, ni aṣita ibọn ti da ẹmi ọmọ naa legbodo lẹsẹkẹsẹ.Wọn ṣalaye pe awọn agbofinro to wa ninu ikọ JBPT (Joint Border Patrol Team) eyi to ni ṣọja, awọn aṣọbode ati awọn imigireṣọn ninu, ni wọn n patiroolu lọjọ buruku ọhun, bi wọn ṣe n lọ ni wọn n bọ lagbegbe Irosu, nitosi ibi tawọn ọlọpaa ti n yẹ iwe ọkọ wo ni Sawa, ni bọda Owode-Apa, Badagry, wọn n wa awọn onifayawọ to fẹẹ ko irẹsi tijọba ti fofin de kọja, lati mu wọn.Bi wọn ti n ṣe eyi lọwọ ni wọn lawọn ọdọ kan lagbegbe naa ko ara wọn jọ, wọn si lọọ ba ikọ JBPT pe ki wọn kuro laduugbo awọn, wọn lawọn o le gba kawọn agbofinro naa ṣiṣẹ ti wọn ba wa ọhun lọdọ awọn.Ọrọ yii lo dariwo laarin awọn ọdọ ọhun, tawọn kọsitọọmu fi bẹrẹ si i yinbọn kaakiri lai bikita, ibẹ si ni ọta ibọn kan ti lọọ ba Alade Ọba nibi to duro si, to si ṣeku pa a loju ẹsẹ, lawọn agbofinro ba gbe oku rẹ si mọto wọn, wọn fẹẹ maa gbe e lọ.A gbọ pe ileewe girama Kankou Secondary School, lọmọ naa n lọ, ipele kẹta agba (SS3) lo wa, ọdun yii ni iba pari ẹkọ rẹ nileewe ọhun.Iṣẹlẹ yii la gbọ pe o mu kawọn ọdọ to ku gbana jẹ, ti wọn si bẹrẹ si i sun taya laarin titi, wọn lawọn o ni i gba ki wọn gbe oku ọmọ ohun lọ.Nigba ti ọrọ yii to ọga ṣọja ileeṣẹ ologun 243 Recce Battalion, to wa n’Ibẹrẹko, Ọgagun Nicholas Rume, leti, oun atawọn ṣọja to ko sodi waa ba wọn da si i, awọn aṣọbode naa si yọnda oku naa fawọn mọlẹbi oloogbe ọhun.Ọgbẹni David Aladeotan to niṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣoju oun sọ pe oko agbọn ni oloogbe naa ti n bọ, ko si lara awọn ti wọn n fa wahala rara ti ibọn fi ba a.O ni, “Pẹlu bawọn agbaagba atawọn olori agbegbe naa ṣe sọ fawọn kọsitọọmu pe ko si irẹsi ajeji kankan laduugbo awọn, sibẹ wọn kọ, wọn ko gba, afigba ti wọn fibọn ṣọṣẹ yii, bẹẹ wọn ko ri irẹsi kankan mu.O ni nigba ti wọn ko ri irẹsi ti wọn lawọn n wa ni wọn tun bẹrẹ si i mu ọkada tawọn eeyan gbe siwaju ile wọn, wọn fẹsun kan wọn pe wọn n lo ọkada naa fun iṣẹ fayawọ ni, eyi lo mu kawọn ọdọ ati ẹgbẹ ọlọkada yari fawọn agbofinro naa.Ṣugbọn Alukoro ileeṣẹ kọsitọọmu, kọmandi ti ẹnubode Sẹmẹ, Ọgbẹni Abdullahi Hussain, ni bẹẹ kọ lọrọ ọhun ri, o lawọn onifayawọ kan ti wọn gba ọna ẹlẹsẹ ninu igbo ni wọn ṣakọlu sawọn kọsitọọmu niluu Irolu, latari bawọn ṣe gbegi dina fun wọn nigba ti wọn n fi ọkada ṣe fayawọ irẹsi tijọba fofin de.O lawọn yii naa ni wọn lọọ pe awọn ọdọ bii aadoje lati waa ba awọn agbofinro ja, wọn bẹrẹ si i ju okuta, igi ati awọn nnkan ija mi-in lu mọto kọsitọọmu ati awọn agbofinro naa. O nigba ti wọn gbiyanju lati dana sun mọto ijọba ọhun lawọn kọsitọọmu bẹrẹ si i yinbọn soke lati le wọn sa, ti ọta ibọn si lọọ ba olori awọn onifayawọ ọhun.O ni irọ lawọn to pe oloogbe naa lọmọ ileewe n pa, ki i ṣe oko lo ti n bọ, ọkan lara awọn onifayawọ ni, aarin wọn lo duro si.Hussain ni omi alaafia agbegbe naa ti n toro."},{"question":"கேள்வி : “நற்றிணை“ - நூல் குறிப்பு தருக.","answer":"பதில் :    நற்றிணை :நற்றிணை என்பது தமிழ் இலக்கியத்தில் எட்டுத்தொகை என்ற சங்க இலக்கிய வகைப்பாட்டினுள் காணப்படும் ஒரு நூலாகும். இந்நூல் தனிப்பாடல்களாகப் பலராலும் பாடப்பட்டுப் பின்னர்த் தொகுக்கப்பட்டது. எட்டுத்தொகை நூல்கள் இவையெனக் குறிப்பிடும் பழைய வெண்பாவில் முதலிடம் பெற்றுத்திகழ்வது நற்றிணை ஆகும். எட்டுத்தொகை நூல்களில் \\"நல்\\" என்ற அடைமொழி பெற்ற நூல் (நல்+திணை) இதுவேயாகும். இதனை நற்றிணை நானூறு என்றும் தூதின் வழிகாட்டி என்றும் (வாப் பறை விரும்பினைஆயினும், தூச் சிறை - பாடல் எண்.54) கூறுவர். இந்நூலில் கடவுள் வாழ்த்தோடு 401 பாடல்கள் ஆசிரியப்பாவில் அமைந்துள்ளன. அவைகளில் பெரும்பான்மையானவை 9 அடி முதல் 12 அடிகள் கொண்ட பாடல்களாக அமைந்துள்ளன. இந்நூலைத் தொகுத்தவர் யாரென அறியப்படவில்லை என்றாலும் தொகுப்பித்தவன் பன்னாடு தந்த பாண்டியன் மாறன் வழுதி ஆவார். நற்றிணைப் பாடல்கள் அனைத்தும் அகப்பொருள் அமையப் பெற்ற பாடல்களாம். நற்றிணையில் 7 அடிகள் கொண்ட பாடலும் 13 அடிகள் கொண்ட பாடல்களும் இடம்பெற்றுள்ளன என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கதாகும்.7 அடிகளில் அமைந்த பாடல்கள் - 18 அடிகளில் அமைந்த பாடல்கள் - 19 அடிகளில் அமைந்த பாடல்கள் - 10610 அடிகளில் அமைந்த பாடல்கள் - 9611 அடிகளில் அமைந்த பாடல்கள் - 11012 அடிகளில் அமைந்த பாடல்கள் - 7713 அடிகளில் அமைந்த பாடல்கள் - 8234-ஆவது பாடல் கிடைக்கவில்லை.பாடியோர்நற்றிணையில் உள்ள 401 பாடல்களை 275 புலவர்கள் பாடியுள்ளனர். குறுந்தொகைப் புலவர்கள் போலவே நற்றிணைப் புலவர்களும் பாடலில் இடம்பெற்றுள்ள தொடர்களால் பெயர் பெற்றுள்ளனர் என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கதாகும். சான்றாக : வண்ணப்புறக் கந்தத்தனார்மலையனார்தனிமகனார்,விழிக்கட் பேதைப் பெருங்கண்ணனார்தும்பிசேர்க்கீரனார்தேய்புரிப் பழங்கயிற்றினார்மடல் பாடிய மாதங்கீரனார்என்ற எழுவராவர். மேலும் 59 பாடல்களைப் பாடிய புலவர்களின் பெயர்கள் காணப்படவில்லை. இந்நூலில் உள்ள நானூறு பாடல்களில் 234 ஆம் பாடலும் 385 ஆம் பாடலின் ஒரு பகுதியும் கிடைக்கப்பெறவில்லை. இந்நூலினைத் திணை அடிப்படையில் ஆராயும்போது,குறிஞ்சித் திணைப் பாடல்கள்-132பாலைத் திணைப் பாடல்கள்-104நெய்தல் திணைப் பாடல்கள்-102மருதத் திணைப் பாடல்கள்-32முல்லைத் திணைப் பாடல்கள்-30 அமைந்துள்ளன.நற்றிணை காட்டும் வாழ்க்கைநற்றிணைப் பாடல்கள் வாயிலாக அக்கால மக்களிடம் பரவிக்கிடந்த பழக்க வழக்கங்களை அறியலாம். தலைவன் பிரிவால் வாடும் தலைவி, தன்தலைவனின் வரவைச் சுவரில் கோடிட்டுக் கணக்கிடும் பழக்கமும் காதலன் வரவைப் பல்லி கத்தும் ஓசையை வைத்துச் சகுனம் பார்க்கும் வழக்கமும் அக்காலமக்களிடம் இருந்த நம்பிக்கையைக் காட்டுகிறது. மேலும் மகளிர் காற்பந்து விளையாடும் வழக்கமும் இருந்ததை அறியமுடிகிறது. பிற்காலத்தில் சிறந்து விளங்கிய \\"தூது\\" என்ற சிற்றிலக்கியத்திற்கு வழிகாட்டியாகக் குருவி, கிளி, நாரை ஆகியவற்றைத் தூதுவிடும் பாங்கையும் நற்றிணையில் காணலாம். மேலும் மன்னர்களின் ஆட்சிச் சிறப்பு, கொடைத்திறம், மன்னர்களைப் பின்பற்றி மக்கள் வாழ்ந்த அறவாழ்வு ஆகியவற்றை அறியவும் நற்றிணைப் பாடல்கள் துணை செய்கின்றன."},{"question":"Manana teny mikotorana ianaoisarOmeo ary teny marina :","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"sira\\""},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa 3-Saddex waxyabod aya si dagdag u badali kara?","answer":"Maalin Wanaagsan dhamaan Saddex waxyaabood ayaa si deg-deg ah u bedeli kara jawiga dumarka, farxadna u keeni kara:-1. In lagu yiraahdo Waa ku Jeclahay2. Markay dukaamaysanayso in loo sameeyo 50% discount ‘qiime dhimis’3. In sawirkeedu helo Like iyo Comments badan ."},{"question":" Sheeg Dowladii Ugu Horeysay Ee Soo Saarta Sokorta?","answer":"Dowladdii Ugu Horeysay Ee Soo Saarta Sokorta Waa Dowladda Kuuba \\"Cuba\\"."},{"question":"Quem inventou a fotografia?","answer":"A primeira fotografia moderna reconhecida é uma imagem produzida  pelo francês Joseph Nicéphore Niépce. Em 1834 Hércules Florence, pintor franco-brasileiro e inventor isolado da fotografia no Brasil, cunhou a palavra “photographie” para a técnica, pelo menos quatro anos antes de John Herschel cunhar a palavra inglesa “photography”."},{"question":"Inona no vola ofisialin'ny Vondrona Eoropeana?","answer":" Ny euro no vola ofisialin'ny Vondrona Eoropeana (UE), ampiasain'ny ankamaroan'ny firenena mpikambana ao aminy. Ity vola tokana ity dia nampidirina tamin'ny 1999 mba hanatsorana ny varotra sy hanamafisana ny fampidirana ara-toekarena ao anatin'ny EU."},{"question":"ටොනේඩෝ කාලගුණ තත්වයක් ඇතිවීම සඳහා බලපාන , වලාකුළු වර්ගය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ටොනේඩෝ කාලගුණ තත්වයක් ඇතිවීම සඳහා බලපාන , වලාකුළු වර්ගය වන්නෙ කැටි වැහි වලාකුළු වර්ගයයි."},{"question":"Inona ary izany : mihiratra tsy mahita azy, mikimpy vao mahita azy ?","answer":"Torimaso no ikimpiana vao mahita azy."},{"question":"ماأسم المضيق الذي يربط البحر الاسود ببحر مرمره ؟","answer":"مضيق البسفور."},{"question":"Ẹyin Fulani, ẹ yee gbe ninu igbo, ẹ maa bọ nigboro-Oluwoo","answer":"Oluwoo ti ilu Iwo, Ọba Abdulrosheed Adewale Akanbi, ti fẹsun kan awọn aṣaaju ilẹ Yoruka kan pe awọn ni wọn wa nidii ilu ogun to n dun lemọlemọ lorileede yii bayii.Ninu atẹjade kan to fi sita lọ̣̣̣jọ Aiku, Sannde lo ti sọ pe ṣe lawọn eeyan naa n ṣe bẹẹ fun iwa imọtara-ẹni nikan ati nitori ohun ti wọn fẹẹ da ninu oṣelu.O ni ọrọ wahala eto aabo ti orileede yii, paapaa, lapa Guusu Iwọ-Oorun, n koju bayii ko ṣẹyin ọrọ idibo ipo aarẹ ti ọdun 2023.Ọba Akanbi ṣalaye pe “A mọ awọn aṣaaju Yoruba yi wọn n lulu ọtẹ bayii, nitori oṣelu si ni. Gbogbo rẹ ko ṣẹyin bi wọn ṣe n ro pe ẹnikan fẹẹ dupo aarẹ, ti wọn ko si fẹ ki ẹni naa debẹ.“Wọn mọ pe ilẹ Yoruba ni aarẹ yoo ti wa lọdun 2023, wọn ko si fẹ ko ṣe e ṣe, ẹni ti wọn si n tori rẹ da wahala silẹ gan-an ko ti i sọ pe oun fẹẹ di aarẹ, ki lo wa fa ikorira gan an?“Emi o ni i laju silẹ ki ẹnikẹni dana ogun lorileede yii, gbogbo awọn ti wọn si n pete ogun nilẹ Yoruba, paapaa, niluu Eko, ko ni i ni ẹyin rere”Oluwoo ke si awọn agbofinro lati dọdẹ ẹnikẹni to ba n huwa janduku lorileede yii; yala ọmọ Yoruba tabi Fulani, ki wọn si gbe wọn lọ sile-ẹjọ lona to tọ.Bakan naa lo rọ awọn Fulani lati ran ijọba lọwọ lati ṣawari awọn ti wọn ba jẹ ọdaran laaarin wọn. O ni ki wọn yee gbe ninu igbo, ki wọn maa bọ laaarin ilu.O tun ke sijọba lati gbe eto ilanilọyẹ kalẹ fawọn Fulani lori ọna igbalode ti wọn le gba maa sin maaluu wọn, ko ma baa si wahala mọ pẹlu awọn agbẹ ilẹ Yoruba."},{"question":" வினா : ஹோமோ சேபியன்ஸைத் தவிர, ‘ஹோமோ’ இனத்தின் கீழ் உள்ள மற்ற இரண்டு இனங்கள் யாவை?","answer":"விடை: ஹோமோ ஹாபிலிஸ் மற்றும் ஹோமோ எரெக்டஸ்."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"banyak akal\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Maksudnya ialah banyak helah. Contoh ayat: Leman banyak akal apabila diminta membayar hutangnya."},{"question":"સર્બિયન ઇતિહાસ","answer":"સર્બિયન મુખ્યત્વે સર્બ્સ દ્વારા ઉપયોગમાં લેવામાં આવતી સર્બો-ક્રોએશિયન ભાષાની પ્રમાણિત વિવિધતા છે.તે સર્બિયાની સત્તાવાર અને રાષ્ટ્રીય ભાષા છે, બોસ્નીયા અને હર્ઝેગોવિનાની ત્રણ સત્તાવાર ભાષાઓમાંની એક અને મોન્ટેનેગ્રો અને કોસોવોમાં સહ-સત્તાવાર છે.તે ક્રોએશિયા, ઉત્તર મેસેડોનિયા, રોમાનિયા, હંગેરી, સ્લોવાકિયા અને ચેક રિપબ્લિકમાં માન્યતા પ્રાપ્ત લઘુમતી ભાષા છે.સ્ટાન્ડર્ડ સર્બિયન સર્બો-ક્રોએશિયન, શ્ટોકાવિયનની સૌથી વ્યાપક બોલી પર આધારિત છે, જે સ્ટાન્ડર્ડ ક્રોએશિયન, બોસ્નિયન અને મોન્ટેનેગ્રિન જાતો [૧ 14] નો પણ આધાર છે અને તેથી ક્રોટ્સ, બોસ્નીઆક્સ, સર્બ્સ અને મોન્ટેનેગ્રિન્સની સામાન્ય ભાષા વિશેની ઘોષણા2017 માં જારી કરવામાં આવી હતી. સર્બ્સ દ્વારા બોલાતી અન્ય બોલી દક્ષિણપૂર્વ સર્બિયામાં ટોરલકિયન છે, જે મેસેડોનિયન અને બલ્ગેરિયનમાં સંક્રમિત છે.\\""},{"question":"Zer da globalizazioaren ondorio ekonomikoa herrialde garatugabeetan?","answer":"Globalizazioaren ondorio ekonomikoa herrialde garatugabeetan anitzekoa da. Batetik, merkatu berriak irekitzen dira eta teknologia berriak sartzen dira. Bestetik, lehiakortasuna handitzen da eta jatorrizko industria batzuk kaltetu daitezke."},{"question":"Madaxa Lalbaad: Xuquuqda, Xorriyaadka Aasaasiga Ah Ee Qofka Iyo Xaddidaadooda.","answer":"Madaxa Lalbaad: Xuquuqda, Xorriyaadka Aasaasiga Ah Ee Qofka Iyo Xaddidaadooda.Qodobka 17aad. Xorriyadda Diinta iyo Caqiiddada. (1) Qof kastaa wuxuu xor u yahay in uu ku dhaqmo dantiisa.(2) Diin aan ahayn Islaamka laguma faain karo Jamhuuriyadda Federaalka Soomaaliya. Qodobka 18aad. Xorriyadda Ra'yiga iyo Afkaarta.(1) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay in uu yeesho, soo bandhigo ra'yigiüsa iyo in uu doono, inuu helo o0 gudbiyo ra'yigiüisa, xog ama afkaar si kastaba.(2) Xorriyatu qoolka waxaa kar mid, xorriyadda hadalka, saxaafadda iyo wax walba oo soo gelaya warbaahinta clektaroonikada iyo internet-ka.(3) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay in uu muujyo hal'abuurkiisa faneed, xorriyaddisa aqooneed iyo xorriyadda cilmi-baarista. Qodobka 19aad. Xurmada Hoyga (1) Qofna gurigisa ama meeshii kale ce isaga u gaar ah lama geli karo, lama baari karo, lamana basaasi karo amar garsoore oo sababaysan la'aantiis.(2) Waxaa wajitb ah in amarka garsooraha si toos ah loogu akhriyo degganaha hoyga, baarahana waxaa ka reeban ku xadgudubka sharciga.Qodobka 20aad. Xorriyadda Kulanka, Bannaanbaxa, Cabashada iyo Codsi-wadareedka.(1) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay in uu abaabulo, kana qaybglo kulammo ama bannaabax oo si xasilooni ah cabasho loogu muujinayo, iyada oo aan oggolaansho loo bahnayn. (2) Qof kastaa wuxuu xaq u leeyahay inuu cabasho qoraal ah u gudbiyo hay'adaha Dawladda.Qodobka 21aad. Xorriyadda Isu-socodka iyo Degitaanka(1) Qof kasta oo si sharci ah ku deggan dhulka Jamhuuriyaddu wuxuu xaq u leeyahay in uu si xor ah u degi karo, ugu dhex-socon karo meel kasta oo dalka ka mid ah, kana bixi karo.(2) Muwaaddin kasta wuxuu xaq u leeyahay soo-gelidda iyo joogitaanka waddanka iyo inuu helo Baasabboo.Qodobka 22aad. Xaqa Ka-qaybgalka Siyaasadda.(1) Muwaaddin kastaa wuxuu xaqu leeyahay in uu ka qayb-qaato arrimaha guud ce dadweynaha. Xaqa kan waxaa ka mid ah: (a) Inuu samaysan karo ama ka mid noqon karo xisbi siyaasadeed, kana qayb-qaadan karo hawlihisa; (b) In xisbi siyaasadecd gudihisa looga dooran karo jago kasta.(2) Muwaaddin kasta po buuxtya shoruudaha sharciga tilmaamayo wuxuu xaq u leeyahay inuu wax doorto, lana doorto.(3) Xuaquuqda ku xusan faqradaha iyo ce qodobkan waa in loogu dhaqmaa si waafaqsan Dastuurkan iyo sharci Baarlamaanka Federalka."},{"question":"Apakah bahasa rasmi Malaysia?","answer":"bahasa Melayu"},{"question":"Indil péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Daldi potoxlu gìsee'k waakëram, daldi indi aw sëllu wu duuf.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Daldi potoxlu gìsee'k waakëram, daldi indi aw sëllu wu duuf.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Daldi: ADVpotoxlu: VERBgìse: VERBe'k: ADPwaakëram: NOUN,: PUNCTdaldi: ADVindi: VERBaw: DETsëllu: NOUNwu: PRONduuf: ADJ.: PUNCT"},{"question":"மனிதனின் மார்பில் உள்ள விலா எலும்பின் எண்ணிக்கை எவ்வளவு ?","answer":"பெரும்பாலான மக்கள் 12 ஜோடி விலா எலும்புகளுடன் பிறந்தவர்கள், மொத்தம் 24."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Apa akan manis jika anda minum minuman yang manis, dan makan makanan yang manis?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah kencing manis."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--कामापुरता मामा","answer":"आपले काम करून घेईपर्यंत गोड गोड बोलणे."},{"question":"Коменскийдин ою боюнча тарбиялоонун системасы кандай болууга тийиш?а)Тандалган адамдар үчүнб)Аристократтык жоболор үчүнв)Коомдун демократиялык болушу үчүнг)Акылдуулар жана акылсыздар үчүн","answer":"Тураа жообу:в)Коомдун демократиялык болушу үчүн"},{"question":"\\"ധാരാളം വിനോദസഞ്ചാരികളെ ആകർഷിക്കുന്ന പ്രകൃതിസൗഹൃദ ടൂറിസം പദ്ധതിയാണ് ഗവിയിലുള്ളത്. ഇവിടെയെത്തുന്ന സന്ദർശകരിൽ ഭൂരിഭാഗവും പ്രകൃതിസ്‌നേഹികളോ സാഹസിക പ്രേമികളോ ആണ്. ഗവിയെ ലോകത്തിലെ മുൻനിര പ്രകൃതി സൗഹൃദ ടൂറിസം കേന്ദ്രങ്ങളിലൊന്നായി ഉൾപ്പെടുത്തിയതോടെ പ്രശസ്ത ടൂറിസം കമ്പനിയായ അലിസ്റ്റർ ഇന്റർനാഷണൽ, സന്ദർശകരുടെ ഒഴുക്കും വർധിക്കുകയാണ്. ഇന്ത്യയിൽ തീർച്ചയായും കണ്ടിരിക്കേണ്ട സ്ഥലങ്ങളിലൊന്ന് എന്ന പദവിയും ഗവി നേടിയിട്ടുണ്ട്. \\" മുകളിൽ പറഞ്ഞ ഭാഗം ഏത് സ്ഥലത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് സംസാരിക്കുന്നത്?","answer":"മുകളിൽ സൂചിപ്പിച്ച ഭാഗം ഇന്ത്യയിൽ സ്ഥിതി ചെയ്യുന്ന ഗവി എന്ന സ്ഥലത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് സംസാരിക്കുന്നത്."},{"question":"சென்னைப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் முதல் தமிழிப்பேராசிரியர் யார் ?","answer":"சென்னைப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தின் முதல் தமிழிப்பேராசிரியர் ரா.பி. சேதுப்பிள்ளை. இவர் ஒரு தமிழறிஞர், எழுத்தாளர், வழக்குரைஞர், மேடைப்பேச்சாளர். இவர் தமிழில் சொற்பொழிவு ஆற்றுவதிலும், உரைநடை எழுதுவதிலும் மிகவும் பெயர் பெற்றவர். இனிய உரைச் செய்யுள் எனக் குறிப்பிடும் அளவுக்கு அவரது உரைநடை இனிமை வாய்ந்தது எனப் பலரும் பாராட்டியுள்ளனர். உரைநடையில் அடுக்குமொழியையும், செய்யுள்களுக்கே உரிய எதுகை, மோனை என்பவற்றையும் உரைநடைக்குள் கொண்டு வந்தவர் இவரே எனப்படுகின்றது."},{"question":"ರಾಯಲ್ ಚಾಲೆಂಜರ್ಸ್ ಬೆಂಗಳೂರು (ಆರ್ ಸಿ ಬೀ) ಕರ್ನಾಟಕದ ಬೆಂಗಳೂರು ಮೂಲದ ಫ್ರಾಂಚೈಸಿ ಕ್ರಿಕೆಟ್ ತಂಡವಾಗಿದ್ದು, ಇಂಡಿಯನ್ ಪ್ರೀಮಿಯರ್ ಲೀಗ್ (ಐಪಿಎಲ್) ನಲ್ಲಿ ಸ್ಪರ್ಧಿಸುತ್ತದೆ. ತಂಡವನ್ನು 2008 ರಲ್ಲಿ ಸ್ಥಾಪಿಸಲಾಯಿತು ಮತ್ತು ಯುನೈಟೆಡ್ ಸ್ಪಿರಿಟ್ಸ್ ಲಿಮಿಟೆಡ್ ಒಡೆತನದಲ್ಲಿದೆ. ಆರ್ ಸಿ ಬೀ ಎಂದಿಗೂ ಐಪಿಎಲ್ ಪ್ರಶಸ್ತಿಯನ್ನು ಗೆದ್ದಿಲ್ಲ, ಆದರೆ ಅವರು 2009 ಮತ್ತು 2016 ರಲ್ಲಿ ಎರಡು ಬಾರಿ ಫೈನಲ್ ತಲುಪಿದ್ದಾರೆ. ಅವರು ಐಪಿಎಲ್ ನಲ್ಲಿ ಅತ್ಯಂತ ಜನಪ್ರಿಯ ತಂಡಗಳಲ್ಲಿ ಒಂದಾಗಿದೆ ಮತ್ತು ಹೆಚ್ಚಿನ ಅಭಿಮಾನಿಗಳನ್ನು ಹೊಂದಿದ್ದಾರೆ.ಮೇಲಿನ ಲೇಖನವನ್ನು ಪರಿಗಣಿಸಿ ಈ ಪ್ರಶ್ನೆ ಉತ್ತರಿಸಿ:ರಾಯಲ್ ಚಾಲೆಂಜರ್ಸ್ ಬೆಂಗಳೂರು ಎಷ್ಟು ಬಾರಿ ಐಪಿಎಲ್ ಫೈನಲ್ ತಲುಪಿದೆ?","answer":"ರಾಯಲ್ ಚಾಲೆಂಜರ್ಸ್ ಬೆಂಗಳೂರು ತಂಡ ಎರಡು ಬಾರಿ, 2009 ಮತ್ತು 2016ರಲ್ಲಿ ಐಪಿಎಲ್ ಫೈನಲ್ ತಲುಪಿದೆ."},{"question":"અમૃત ઘાયલની \\"જવાય છે\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"એવુંય ખેલ ખેલમાં ખેલી જવાય છે,હોતી નથી હવા અને ફેલી જવાય છે.ઊંઘી જવાય છે કદી આમ જ ટહેલતાં,ક્યારેક ઊંઘમાંય ટહેલી જવાય છે.આવી ગયો છું હું ય ગળે દોસ્તી થકી,લંબાવે કોઈ હાથ તો ઠેલી જવાય છે.બલિહારી છે બધીય ગુલાબી સ્મરણ તણી,આંખો કરું છું બંધ, બહેલી જવાય છે.મળતી રહે સહાય નશીલી નજરની તો,આંટીઘૂંટી સફરની ઉકેલી જવાય છે.લાગે છે થાક એવો કે ક્યારેક વાટમાં,સમજી હવાને ભીંત અઢેલી જવાય છે.‘ઘાયલ’, ભર્યો છે એટલો પૂરો કરો પ્રથમ,અહીંયાં અધૂરો જામ ના મેલી જવાય છે."},{"question":"ਜਰਮਨ ਆਰਥਿਕਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਬੁਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਿਤ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਸੰਕਟ ਨੂੰ ਦੂਰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਹਿਟਲਰ ਨੇ ਕੀ ਕੀਤਾ?","answer":"ਜਰਮਨੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਤਾਨਾਸ਼ਾਹੀ ਸਥਾਪਤ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ, ਉਸਨੇ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਪੁਨਰ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਵੱਲ ਵੱਡੇ ਕਦਮ ਚੁੱਕੇ।ਹਿਟਲਰ ਨੇ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਰਿਕਵਰੀ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਮੇਵਾਰੀ ਅਰਥ ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰੀ ਹਜਾਲਮਾਰ ਸਚਟ ਨੂੰ ਸੌਂਪੀ, ਜਿਸਦਾ ਉਦੇਸ਼ ਰਾਜ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਫੰਡ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੰਮ-ਸਿਰਜਣ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਪੂਰਾ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਅਤੇ ਪੂਰਾ ਰੁਜ਼ਗਾਰ ਦੇਣਾ ਸੀ।ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ ਨੀਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਵੀ ਹਿਟਲਰ ਨੇ ਤੇਜ਼ੀ ਨਾਲ ਸਫਲਤਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਸਨੇ 1933 ਵਿੱਚ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਲੀਗ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਕੱਢ ਲਿਆ, 1936 ਵਿੱਚ ਰਾਈਨਲੈਂਡ ਉੱਤੇ ਮੁੜ ਕਬਜ਼ਾ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਅਤੇ 1938 ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਲੋਕ, ਇੱਕ ਸਾਮਰਾਜ ਅਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਨੇਤਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਅਰੇ ਹੇਠ ਆਸਟ੍ਰੀਆ ਅਤੇ ਜਰਮਨੀ ਨੂੰ ਏਕੀਕ੍ਰਿਤ ਕੀਤਾ।ਫਿਰ ਉਸਨੇ ਚੈਕੋਸਲੋਵਾਕੀਆ ਤੋਂ ਜਰਮਨ ਬੋਲਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਸੁਡੈਂਟਨਲੈਂਡ ਨੂੰ ਜਿੱਤਣ ਲਈ ਅੱਗੇ ਵਧਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਪੂਰੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਨੂੰ ਲੁੱਟ ਲਿਆ। ਇਸ ਸਭ ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਦਾ ਬੇਲੋੜਾ ਸਮਰਥਨ ਸੀ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਵਰਸੇਲਜ਼ ਦੇ ਫੈਸਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਕਠੋਰ ਸਮਝਿਆ ਸੀ। ਦੇਸ਼-ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਤੇਜ਼ ਸਫਲਤਾਵਾਂ ਦੇਸ਼ ਦੀ ਕਿਸਮਤ ਨੂੰ ਉਲਟਾਉਂਦੀਆਂ ਜਾਪਦੀਆਂ ਸਨ।ਹਿਟਲਰ ਨੇ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਸੰਕਟ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਨਿਕਲਣ ਦੇ ਰਾਹ ਵਜੋਂ ਯੁੱਧ ਨੂੰ ਚੁਣਿਆ। ਖੇਤਰ ਦੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸਰੋਤ ਇਕੱਠੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾਣੇ ਸਨ। ਸਤੰਬਰ 1939 ਵਿੱਚ ਜਰਮਨੀ ਨੇ ਪੋਲੈਂਡ ਉੱਤੇ ਹਮਲਾ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਫਰਾਂਸ ਅਤੇ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਨਾਲ ਜੰਗ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ਸਤੰਬਰ 1940 ਵਿੱਚ, ਜਰਮਨੀ, ਇਟਲੀ ਅਤੇ ਜਾਪਾਨ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਇੱਕ ਤ੍ਰਿਪੱਖੀ ਸਮਝੌਤਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ, ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਹਿਟਲਰ ਦੇ ਅੰਤਰਰਾਸ਼ਟਰੀ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਦੇ ਦਾਅਵੇ ਨੂੰ ਮਜ਼ਬੂਤ ​​ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।ਹਿਟਲਰ ਹੁਣ ਪੂਰਬੀ ਯੂਰਪ ਨੂੰ ਜਿੱਤਣ ਦੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਲੰਬੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੇ ਉਦੇਸ਼ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਅੱਗੇ ਵਧਿਆ। ਉਹ ਜਰਮਨਾਂ ਲਈ ਭੋਜਨ ਸਪਲਾਈ ਅਤੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਦੀ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ਨੂੰ ਯਕੀਨੀ ਬਣਾਉਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਸੀ। ਉਸਨੇ ਜੂਨ 1941 ਵਿੱਚ ਸੋਵੀਅਤ ਯੂਨੀਅਨ ਉੱਤੇ ਹਮਲਾ ਕੀਤਾ। ਇਸ ਇਤਿਹਾਸਕ ਗਲਤੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਿਟਲਰ ਨੇ ਜਰਮਨ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਮੋਰਚੇ ਨੂੰ ਬ੍ਰਿਟਿਸ਼ ਹਵਾਈ ਬੰਬਾਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਪੂਰਬੀ ਮੋਰਚੇ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਕਤੀਸ਼ਾਲੀ ਸੋਵੀਅਤ ਫੌਜਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕੀਤਾ।"},{"question":"Nội dung chính của bài Buổi học cuối cùng Ngữ văn lớp 7 là gì?","answer":"Văn bản “Buổi học cuối cùng” mang đến cho người đọc những suy nghĩ hồn nhiên và tâm sự còn ngây thơ nhưng vô cùng xúc động của một chú bé vùng An-dát. Diễn biến trong buổi học cuối cùng đã để lại những dấu ấn sâu đậm trong lòng người đọc."},{"question":"مصر کے دار الحکومت قاہرہ کے بارے میں کچھ بتایں۔","answer":"قاہرہ مصر کا دار الحکومت اور افریقہ، عرب دنیا اور مشرق وسطیٰ میں سب سے بڑا شہری مجموعہ ہے۔ قاہرہ کبری میٹروپولیٹن علاقہ، جس کی آبادی 21.9 ملین ہے، آبادی کے لحاظ سے دنیا کا بارہواں بڑا میگا شہر ہے۔ قاہرہ کا تعلق قدیم مصر سے ہے، کیونکہ اہرامات جیزہ اور قدیم شہر ممفس اور عين شمس اس کے جغرافیائی علاقے میں واقع ہیں۔ نیل ڈیلٹا کے قریب واقع، شہر سب سے پہلے فسطاط کے طور پر آباد ہوا، ایک بستی جس کی بنیاد مسلمانوں کی فتح مصر کے بعد 640ء میں ایک موجودہ قدیم رومی قلعے، بابلیون کے ساتھ رکھی گئی تھی۔ دولت فاطمیہ کے تحت 969ء میں قریب ہی ایک نئے شہر القاہرہ کی بنیاد رکھی گئی۔ اس نے بعد میں ایوبی سلطنت اور سلطنت مملوک (مصر) ادوار (بارہویں-سولہویں صدی) کے دوران میں فسطاط کو مرکزی شہری مرکز کے طور پر پیچھے چھوڑ دیا۔ قاہرہ طویل عرصے سے اس خطے کی سیاسی اور ثقافتی زندگی کا مرکز رہا ہے، اور اسلامی فن تعمیر کی پیش رفت کی وجہ سے اسے \\"ہزار میناروں کا شہر\\" کا عنوان دیا گیا ہے۔ قاہرہ کے تاریخی مرکز (قاہرہ المعز) کو 1979ء میں یونیسکو عالمی ثقافتی ورثہ کا درجہ دیا گیا۔ عالمگیریت اور عالمی شہر تحقیق نیٹ ورک کے مطابق قاہرہ کو \\"بیٹا +\\" درجہ بندی کے ساتھ عالمی شہر سمجھا جاتا ہے۔آج، قاہرہ میں عرب دنیا کی سب سے قدیم اور سب سے بڑی سنیما اور موسیقی کی صنعت ہے، نیز دنیا کا دوسرا قدیم ترین اعلیٰ تعلیم کا ادارہ، جامعہ الازہر بھی یہیں واقع ہے۔ بہت سے بین الاقوامی میڈیا، کاروباری اداروں اور تنظیموں کے علاقائی ہیڈ کوارٹر شہر میں ہیں۔ عرب لیگ کا صدر دفتر قاہرہ میں اپنے زیادہ تر وجود میں رہا ہے۔453 مربع کلومیٹر (175 مربع میل) پر پھیلا ہوا 10 ملین سے زیادہ آبادی کے ساتھ، قاہرہ مصر کا سب سے بڑا شہر ہے۔ مزید 9.5 ملین باشندے شہر کے قریب رہتے ہیں۔ قاہرہ، بہت سے دوسرے شہروں کی طرح، آلودگی اور ٹریفک کی اعلیٰ سطح کے مسائل کا شکار ہے۔ قاہرہ میٹرو، جو 1987ء میں کھولی گئی، افریقہ کا سب سے پرانا میٹرو نظام ہے اور اس کا شمار دنیا کے پندرہ مصروف ترین نظاموں میں ہوتا ہے، جس میں سالانہ 1 بلین مسافروں کی سواری ہوتی ہے۔ قاہرہ کی معیشت 2005ء میں مشرق وسطیٰ میں پہلے نمبر پر تھی اور فارن پالیسی (رسالہ) کے 2010ء گلوبل سٹیز انڈیکس میں عالمی سطح پر 43 ویں نمبر پر ہے۔"},{"question":"Манас эпосу 📚 1903-жылы экспедицияда манасчынын (Кенжекаранын) үнүн тарыхта биринчи жолу тасмага түшүрүп алган инсана) Б. В. Смирнов б) А. Н. Бернштамв) Е. Д. Поливанов г) А. Г. Белинский","answer":"г) А. Г. Белинский"},{"question":"Jawablah pertanyaan berdasarkan artikel cerita di bawah ini.Artikel:Di dekat Liang Benau dan hilir Sungai Sajau, Hidup seorang anak muda, Layis namanya. Jika anak kota mengambil makanan langsung dari meja, Layis berbeda cerita. Bersama Samsul, ayahnya, tiap hari ia menjelajah hutan belantara: Berburu, Meramu.Pada tahun 2018, Datanglah para ilmuwan membawa rasa penasaran. Melompatlah mereka dari perahunya setelah melewati sungai berbuaya. Pradiptajati Kusuma salah satunya. Beliau mempelajari DNA. Rantai dalam tubuh kita yang menyimpan rekaman asal-usul manusia. Ada pula Steve Lansing dari Amerika. Beliau yang meneliti budaya, tentang apa yang manusia cipta dan kebiasaannya.Punan Batu menyambut hangat semua peneliti yang terlibat. Bercakap-cakap sampai akrab. Berbulan bercengkerama, hingga saling percaya. Hingga tiba saat, ilmuwan menyampaikan niat. \\"Aku ingin meneliti kalian semua\\", kata ilmuwan. \\"Untuk apa?\\", Punan Batu bertanya. \\"Untuk menambah pengetahuan tentang asal-usul manusia dan kesehatan, Supaya terwakilkan, suku-suku yang kerap terabaikan.\\"Ilmuwan bertanya-tanya, \\"Apa kiranya bisa jadi balasan?\\". Yang tak terduga terucapkan dalam doa yang Punan Batu panjatkan, \\"Bantulah kami menjaga hutan.\\"Kehidupan Punan Batu sekarang diungkapkan. Diceritakanlah kepada para ilmuwan itu kisah-kisah yang pilu. Tentang babi hutan, buruan kesukaan yang sudah jarang kelihatan. Tentang kematian, bayi sungsang dan ibu melahirkan. Tentang layanan kesehatan yang belum bisa jadi langganan. Tentang hutan yang terancam jadi kenangan. Siapa yang diberi harus memikirkan balas budi.Akhirnya, ilmuwan mengucap janji. Tak di atas kertas, tapi tetap sepenuh hati. \\"Baiklah, aku akan berusaha membantu kalian\\". Di dekat Liang Benaudan hilir Sungai Sajau Jarum suntik menembus pembuluh darah, mengambil cairan merah. Berpindah cairan ke tabung sementara hingga saatnya penelitian DNA. Bersama perburuan tak kenal lelah, ilmuwan melacak wilayah jelajah. Mata memandang lebih dalam, telinganya mendengar lebih tajam: Mengobservasi. Ternyata Punan Batu unik dan berbeda: - Tidak punya jejak Austronesia- Berbeda bahasanya- Unik simbol komunikasinya- Merdu aliran musiknya- Dan luas wilayah jejaknyaDiungkapkan bahwa Punan Batu adalah pemburu terakhir di Kalimantan.Ilmuwan teringat bahwa ada kata sepakat. Setelah penuh berusaha, bertemulah mereka dengan yang berkepedulian sama. Mereka meyakinkan pemimpin negara untuk melestarikan hutan belantara.Di dekat Liang Benau, dan hilir Sungai Sajau. Babi-babi kembali. Daging di atas piring bersama ubi kariting. Layis belajar hukum, meski tak ikut kurikulum. Itulah harapannya. Pada 2 Juni 2023,  Punan Batu diterima sebagai suku berbeda. Perjuangan menjaga hutan lebih dekat dengan kenyataan.Pertanyaan:Apakah pesan moral dari kisah di atas?Jawaban:","answer":"Pesan moral dari kisah di atas adalah mengenai bagaimana ilmu pengetahuan bisa menumbuhkan harapan. Ilmu pengetahuan bukan cuma soal penemuan, melainkan juga tentang kebaikan dan saling membantu antara sesama manusia."},{"question":"Makoɗi kayan aiki ne naA)sassaƙaB)jimaC)ƙiraD)wanzanci","answer":"C.Domin Kora kaifin wuka, garms, fortanya d-s."},{"question":"Kekere lohun to ṣẹlẹ yii lẹgbẹẹ eyi to n bọ- Tunde Bakare","answer":"Oludasilẹ ati adari ijọ Latter Rain Assembly tẹlẹ, to ti porukọ da si Citadel Church bayii, Pasitọ Tunde Bakare, ti sọ pe bii ọmọde meji n ṣere ni iwọde tawọn ọdọ ṣe ta ko awọn ọlọpaa SARS laipẹ yii, aifararọ ati biba dukia jẹ to ṣẹlẹ lẹyin iwọde naa maa jẹ lẹgbẹẹ rogbodiyan to n rọ dẹdẹ lori orilẹ-ede yii, afi ti ijọba atawọn oloṣelu ba jawọ ninu aapọn ti ko yọ bayii, ti wọn tete da omi ila ka’na lai fakoko ṣofo mọ.Ọsan ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii ni ojiṣẹ Ọlọrun yii sọrọ naa ninu ikede pataki kan to ṣe lẹyin isin ọjọ isinmi rẹ. Bakare ni o ti gbọdọ han gbangba si awọn alagbara orilẹ-ede yii pe ko si iye ihalẹ, ifiyajẹni, idunkooko mọ ni ati ikoni-ni-papa-mọra to le bomi pana ẹhonu ati ikanra to wa lọkan awọn ọmọ Naijiria lasiko yii, o ni ara ti kan araalu de gongo gidi ni.‘‘Ibọn yin le le wọn kuro ni titi, ṣugbọn ibọn yin ko le le ibinu ati ẹhonu to wa lookan aya wọn kuro. Ipenija ta a ni latari bi wọn ṣe n ṣejọba raurau lorileede yii lo fa a tara awọn eeyan fi gbẹkan, ti wọn ko si bikita lati ja funra wọn mọ.’’O ṣalaye pe ijọba ti pẹ ju, aṣeju ati aṣetẹ ti wọ ọ, lẹnu bi wọn ko ṣe pese awọn nnkan koṣeemani bii ina ẹlẹntiriiki, omi, oju ọna to ja geere, ile ati ọrọ aje to dara fawọn araalu. Iru ifarada tawọn eeyan ni latọjọ yii wa ti sọnu bayii, ko sẹni tọrọ ilu yii tẹ lọrun mọ, tori iya ki i ṣe omi ọbẹ.O ni orileede tawọn baba nla wa ja fun kọ niyi, ki i ṣe ipo ti wọn reti pe ki Naijiria wa lo wa yii, ko si sigba ti nnkan ko ni i burẹkẹ si i bo ba n lọ bo ṣe n lọ yii.Ni ipari ọrọ rẹ, Bakare, to ti figba kan du ipo igbakeji aarẹ orileede yii pẹlu Aarẹ Buhari ri sọ pe imọran oun si ijọba apapọ ni pe ki wọn ma ṣe duro lori awọn ibeere marun-un tawọn ọdọ ti taari siwaju wọn nikan, ṣugbọn ki wọn tete gbe igbesẹ lati ṣatunto eto bi awọn awọn ọlọpaa ilẹ wa ṣe n ṣiṣẹ latoke delẹ.O tun ni kijọba wadii awọn to wa lẹyin bi awọn ṣọja ṣe yinbọn lu awọn to ṣewọde ni Lẹkki lọjọ Iṣẹgun to kọja yii, ki wọn si fiya to tọ jẹ wọn labẹ ofin, tori igbesẹ buruku tawọn ṣọja naa gbe lo tanna ran gbogbo ifẹhonu han ati biba dukia jẹ to kọ ti ko dawọ duro yii.O kilọ pe ni bayii, bi ayipada rere ko ba bẹrẹ si i waye latọdọ awọn onṣejọba wa lati Abuja, titi de awọn ipinlẹ, o da oun loju pe ohun to ṣi wa lẹyin ọfa maa ju oje lọ, afaimọ ni ki rukerudo to lagbara ko ni i ṣẹlẹ."},{"question":"எந்நான்கை உள்ளடக்கியது ஒரு மொழியின் இலக்கணம் என்று தமிழ்நடைக் கையேடு குறிப்பிடுகிறது?","answer":"ஒரு மொழியில் அடிப்படை அறிவு என்பது அந்த மொழியில் உள்ள எழுத்துகளையும் சொற்களையும் அவற்றின் பொருளையும் வாக்கிய அமைப்புகளையும் சேர்ந்திருப்பதே. மேலே குறிப்பிட்ட நான்கையும் உள்ளடக்கியது ஒரு மொழியின் இலக்கணம் என்கிறது தமிழ் நடைக் கையேடு."},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Ny marina toy ny afo ka _.\\"","answer":"\\"raha kobonina mandoro\\""},{"question":"Ndechipi chishandiso chekurapa chakagadzirwa naSanctorius muna 1612?","answer":"Chishandiso chekurapa chakagadzirwa naSanctorius muna 1612 ndiyo \\"thermoscope.\\" Sanctorius, chiremba wekuItaly, akagadzira iyo thermoscope seyekutanga vhezheni yethermometer. Iyo thermoscope yakabvumira kutarisa kwekuchinja kwekushisa uye kusiyana kwemuviri wevarwere. Nepo iyo thermoscope pachayo yakanga isina chikero chenhamba, yakaratidza danho rekutanga mukugadzirwa kwemidziyo yekuyeresa tembiricha uye yakaita basa mukusimudzira kunzwisisa kwekurapa kwekushanduka kwekushisa kwemuviri."},{"question":"મને જીવવિજ્ઞાન વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"જીવવિજ્ઞાન એ જીવન અને જીવતંત્રના બંધારણ, કાર્યશૈલી, વિકાસ, ઉત્ક્રાંતિ, વિતરણ, ઓળખ અને વર્ગીકરણ સંબંધીત કુદરતી વિજ્ઞાન છે.આધુનિક જીવવિજ્ઞાન વિવિધ શાખાઓ ધરાવતું ઘણું જ વિસ્તૃત વિજ્ઞાન છે. લેટિન ભાષામાં \\"જીવવિજ્ઞાન\\" એવો શબ્દ પ્રયોગ સૌ પ્રથમ વખત ઈ.સ. 1736માં કાર્લ લિનૌશ નામના સ્વિડીશ વૈજ્ઞાનિકે કર્યો હતો. જો કે ભારતીય ઉપખંડ, ચીન, મેસોપોટેમીયા, ઇજિપ્ત વગેરેની પ્રાચીન સભ્યતાઓમાં આ જ શાસ્ત્ર સાથે સંબંધીત એવા વિવિધ શાસ્ત્રોનો 'કુદરતના તત્વજ્ઞાન' તરીકે અભ્યાસ થયેલો જ હતો. આધુનિક જીવવિજ્ઞાને તે જ્ઞાનમાં પુષ્કળ વિકાસ સાધ્યો છે. તદ્‍ઉપરાંત, આધુનિક જીવવિજ્ઞાન અને તેના કુદરતના અભ્યાસના વલણનાં મૂળ છેક પ્રાચીન ગ્રીસના ઔષધીય અભ્યાસ સમેતનાં વિવિધ સંશોધનો સુધી પહોંચે છે.એન્તોન વાન લ્યુવેનહોક દ્વારા સુક્ષ્મદર્શક યંત્રમાં સુધારાઓ પછી તો જીવવિજ્ઞાન શાખાનો ઝડપી વિકાસ થયો છે. આ પછી જ, એટલે કે 19મી સદીની શરૂઆતમાં, ઘણાં જીવવિજ્ઞાનીઓએ કોષનાં મધ્યવર્તી મહત્વ તરફ અંગૂલીનિર્દેશ કર્યો હતો. પછી 1838માં જીવતંત્રનાં બંધારણનો પાયાનો એકમ કોષ છે એવા વૈશ્વિક વિચારનો ઉદ્ભવ અને પ્રચાર થયો."},{"question":"Hãy chọn đáp án đúng nhất cho câu hỏi sau:Hình chữ nhật có bao nhiêu trục đối xứng:A. 1B. 2C. 3D. 4","answer":"Trả lời:Hình chữ nhật có 2 trục đối xứng.Đáp án cần chọn là: B"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਅਗਮ ਰੂਪ ਕਾ ਮਨ ਮਹਿ ਥਾਨਾ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ਕਿਨੈ ਵਿਰਲੈ ਜਾਨਾ ॥੧॥ਸਹਜ ਕਥਾ ਕੇ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਕੁੰਟਾ ॥ਜਿਸਹਿ ਪਰਾਪਤਿ ਤਿਸੁ ਲੈ ਭੁੰਚਾ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਅਨਹਤ ਬਾਣੀ ਥਾਨੁ ਨਿਰਾਲਾ ॥ਤਾ ਕੀ ਧੁਨਿ ਮੋਹੇ ਗੋਪਾਲਾ ॥੨॥ਤਹ ਸਹਜ ਅਖਾਰੇ ਅਨੇਕ ਅਨੰਤਾ ॥ਪਾਰਬ੍ਰਹਮ ਕੇ ਸੰਗੀ ਸੰਤਾ ॥੩॥ਹਰਖ ਅਨੰਤ ਸੋਗ ਨਹੀ ਬੀਆ ॥ਸੋ ਘਰੁ ਗੁਰਿ ਨਾਨਕ ਕਉ ਦੀਆ ॥੪॥੩੫॥੧੦੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 186 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਜਿਸ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੇ ਚਸ਼ਮੇ ਜਾਰੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ) ਉਸ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਅਪਹੰੁਚ ਸਰੂਪ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਿਵਾਸ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । (ਪਰ) ਕਿਸੇ ਵਿਰਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ (ਇਹ ਭੇਤ) ਸਮਝਿਆ ਹੈ ।੧। ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਦਾ ਲੇਖ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ) ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਤੇ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੇ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਦੇ ਚਸ਼ਮਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। (ਜਿਥੇ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਤੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਦੇ ਚਸ਼ਮੇ ਚੱਲ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ) ਉਹ ਹਿਰਦਾ-ਥਾਂ ਇਕ-ਰਸ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਅਨੋਖਾ (ਸੁੰਦਰ) ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਦੀ ਜੁੜੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਉਤੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਭੀ) ਮੋਹਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਜਿਥੇ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੇ ਚਸ਼ਮੇ ਜਾਰੀ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ) ਉਥੇ (ਉਸ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕੇ ਹੋਏ)ਸੰਤ ਜਨ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਦੇ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਤੇ ਬੇਅੰਤ ਅਖਾੜੇ ਰਚੀ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਨ ।੩।(ਉਸ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ) ਬੇਅੰਤ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ ਹੀ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ ਬਣੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਕਿਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਚਿੰਤਾ-ਫ਼ਿਕਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੋਂਹਦਾ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਟਿਕਾਣਾ (ਮੈਨੂੰ) ਨਾਨਕ ਨੂੰ (ਭੀ) ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਿਆ ਹੈ ।੪।੩੫।੧੦੪।\\""},{"question":"डाल्टन के परमाणु सिद्धांत का कौन सा अभिधारणा द्रव्यमान संरक्षण के नियम का परिणाम है?","answer":"डाल्टन के परमाणु सिद्धांत का अभिधारणा जो द्रव्यमान के संरक्षण के नियम का परिणाम है - किसी दिए गए यौगिक में परमाणुओं की सापेक्ष संख्या और प्रकार स्थिर होते हैं। रासायनिक प्रतिक्रिया में परमाणुओं को न तो बनाया जा सकता है और न ही नष्ट किया जा सकता है।"},{"question":"வினா: எண்வகை மெய்பாடுகளை இலக்கியச் சான்றுடன் விளக்குக.","answer":"விடை:நகை :ஈட்டுபுகழ் நந்தி பாணநீ எங்கையர் தம்வீட்டிருந்து பாட விடிவளவும்…….எனும் பாடல்களில் பாணனின் குரலை தலைவி எள்ளி நகையாடுகிறாள்.நீ இரவு முழுவதும் பாடியதை என் தாய் பேய் என்றாள், பிறர் நரி என்றார், தோழி நாய் என்றாள். ஆனால் நானோ நீ என்றேன்.அழுகை :ஐயோ எனின் யான் புலி அஞ்சுவலேஅணைத்தனன் கொளினே அகன் மார்பு……என்ற பாடலடிகளில் காட்டில் புலியோடு போராடி இறந்த தலைவனைப் பற்றி தலைவி துயரம் கொள்வதாக உள்ளது.தலைவன் உடலைப் பார்த்து ஐயோ என்று கதறினால், புலி வந்துவிடுமோ என்று அஞ்சுகிறாள்.தூக்கிச் செல்லலாம் என்றால் ‘உனக்கு அகன்ற மார்பு உன்னைத் தூக்க இயலாது’ என்று துன்புறுகிறாள்.இளிவரல் (சிறுமை) :தொடர்ப்படு ஞமலியின் இடர்ப்படுத்து இரீஇயகேளல் கேளிர் வேளாண் சிறுபதம்……என்ற பாடலில் சேரனுக்கு ஏற்பட்ட சிறுமையை எண்ணிப் பாடுவதாக அமைகிறது. நாயைச் சங்கிலியால் கட்டி வைத்து துன்புறுத்தியது போல என்னைத் துன்புறுத்தினர். சிறையிலிட்ட உன் உதவியால் வந்த தண்ணீரை நான் இரந்து உண்ணமாட்டேன்.மருட்கை (வியப்பு) :அமரரர்க்கு அரசன் தமர்வந்து ஈண்டி அவள்காதல் கொழுநனைக் காட்டி….எனும் வரும் பாடல் அடிகளில் கண்ணகி கோவலனோடு சென்ற காட்சி வியப்பை ஏற்படுத்துகிறது. இந்திரன் கோவலனோடு வந்து பத்தினியாகிய கண்ணகியை விண்ணுக்கு அழைத்துச் சென்ற வியப்பான காட்சி.அச்சம் :மையல் வேழம் மடங்கலின் எதிர்தரஉய்வு இடம் அறியேம்…..எனும் இப்பாடலில் அச்சம் வெளிப்படுகிறது. மதம் பிடித்த யானை மரங்களை முறித்தது; கார்மேகம் இடிப்பது போல் முழங்கியது. உயிர் பிழைப்பதற்கு வேறு இடம் இல்லாமல் மகளிர்தம் கை வளையல் ஒலிக்க மயில் போல் நடுங்கி நின்றார்கள்.பெருமிதம் (பெருமை) :உறுசுடர் வாளோடு ஒருகால் விலங்கினசிறு சுடர் முற்பேர் இருளாங் கண்டாய்…..இப்பாடலில் தனியொரு வீரன் பெரும் படையை எதிர்த்த பெருமையை விளக்குகிறது. ஒளிமிக்க வேலினையும், தேன் நிறைந்த மாலையும் உடைய வேந்தனே! வாளுடன் பெரும் படையைத் தடுப்பேன். அப்பெரும்படை சிறுவிளக்கின் முன் இருள் ஓடுவது போல் ஓடும்.வெகுளி (சினம்) :உறுதுப்பு அஞ்சாது, உடல் சினம் செருக்கிச்சிறுசொல் சொல்லிய சினங்கெழு வேந்தரைஎன்ற பாடல் அடிகளில் நெடுஞ்செழியனின் சினம் கூறப்படுகிறது. தன்னை இளையவன் என்று எள்ளிய வேந்தர்களை சிதறி ஓடச் செய்து முரசையும் கைப்பற்றுவேன் என்று செழியன் சினங்கொள்கிறார்.உவகை (மகிழ்ச்சி) :மண்டல மதியமன்ன மாசறு முகத்தினாளுந்திண்டிறன் மருகன் ……இப்பாடலில் மழை மேகத்தைக் கண்ட மயில் போல மகிழ்ச்சி காணப்படுகிறது. குந்தி தன் திறன் மிக்க மருமகன் கண்ணனைக் கண்ட காட்சி வெள்ளலைகள் நிறைந்த நீலக் கடலின் நீரை முகந்து வரும் மேகத்தைக் கண்ட தோகை மயில் போல மகிழ்ந்து வரவேற்றாள்."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en esta categoría: Películas.","answer":"¿Qué edad tiene Ellen DeGeneres? Ella tiene 63 años."},{"question":"*ما اللقب الذي أطلق على زوجات الرسول ؟","answer":"أمهات المؤمنين"},{"question":"Adivina la siguiente advinanza: Tengo una gran sombrilla y  me buscan por sabrosa, pero atención, ten cuidado que puedo ser venenosa.","answer":"La respuesta a la adivinanza es: La seta (hongo)"},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en esta categoría: Deportes.","answer":"¿Cuándo ganó Derrick Jeter su segunda Serie Mundial? En 1998."},{"question":"\\"වියදම් කිරීමට අකමැති\\"  යන්නට වඩාත්ම ගැලපෙන කෙටි පදය කුමක්ද? (ඔබට භාවිතා  කල හැක්කේ එක වචනයක් පමණි)","answer":"\\"මසුරු\\" වඩාතම ගැලපෙන තනි පදයයි."},{"question":"\\"පරිගණකයේ පියා\\" ලෙස හඳුන්වන්නේ කවුද?","answer":"චාල්ස් බැබේජ්"},{"question":"కుటుంబవ్యవస్థ బాగా కొనసాగాలంటే మనమేం చేయాలి?","answer":"ఉమ్మడి కుటుంబం, వృష్టి కుటుంబం మేలు కలయికతో సమానత్వం, ఆర్థిక స్వాతంత్ర్యం, వ్యక్తి స్వేచ్ఛకు భంగం రాని ఏడంగా, ఆధిపత్యాల పోరులేని విధంగా, ప్రేమానురాగాలు, విలువలు, మానవ సంబంధాలు అంతస్సూత్రంగా గల ఒక కొత్త కుటుంబ వ్యవస్థను తీర్చిదిద్దుకోవాలి.ఏ కుటుంబంలో ఉన్నప్పటికీ కుటుంబ భావనలు, పిల్లలకు వివరించి చెప్పాలి. పెద్దల బలాన్ని పొందాలి. బలగాన్ని పెంపొందించుకోవాలి. యాంత్రికత తగ్గాలి. మానవ శక్తి, యుక్తి నైపుణ్యాలు మన వారసత్వ సంపదను పెంచేలా ఉపయోగపడాలి. సమస్యలను పరస్పరం ఆలోచించుకొని పరిష్కరించుకోవాలి. బాధ్యతలు పంచుకోవడం వల్ల యజమాని భారం తగ్గుతుంది. యంత్రశక్తి మీద ఆధారపడి బద్ధకస్తులు కాకూడదు.కుటుంబ సభ్యులు సుఖాల్నీ, సంతోషాల్నీ, కష్టాల్నీ, బాధల్నీ పరస్పరం పంచుకోవాలి. ఆర్థిక సంబంధాలు, వ్యక్తిగత స్వార్థం, హక్కులు కంటె, మన బాధ్యతలు, మానవ సంబంధాలు ముఖ్యమనీ, అవి మన మనుగడకు ఆధారమనీ తెలుసుకోవాలి.మనం చేసే పని ఏదయినా, మన సంస్కృతిని, వారసత్వాన్ని, దేశ ఔన్నత్యాన్నీ, ఇబ్బడి ముబ్బడిగా పెంచి, వారసులను ఉత్తేజితులను చేసే విధంగా ఉండాలి. అందుకు సమష్టి లేదా వ్యష్టి కుటుంబ వ్యవస్థలు దోహదం చేయాలి. ‘ఇల్లే ఇలలో స్వర్గం’ అని గుర్తించాలి. సమాజానికి కుటుంబం వెన్నెముక. మంచి కుటుంబ వ్యవస్థకై అందరూ కృషి చేయాలి."},{"question":"Dáhùn ìbéèrè tó tẹ̀ lé e yìí: tani ẹni tí ó jẹ́ kọmíṣọ́nnà ìdìbò àkọ́kọ́ ní pakistan?","answer":"FM Khan ni."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. බෝ මළුවේ මල් සුවඳක පැටලීඅම්මා පෙව් කිරි සුවඳ ගලා එන්නේසුපුරුදු උණුහුමකට සිත ඈඳීගේ දොර සෙල්ලම් පිටිය මතක් වෙන්නේදං බෝවිටියා කැලේ මැදින්එන්න හිතයි නුඹ ළඟට සැණින්","answer":"බෝ මළුවේ මල් සුවඳක පැටලීඅම්මා පෙව් කිරි සුවඳ ගලා එන්නේසුපුරුදු උණුහුමකට සිත ඈඳීගේ දොර සෙල්ලම් පිටිය මතක් වෙන්නේදං බෝවිටියා කැලේ මැදින්එන්න හිතයි නුඹ ළඟට සැණින්එතෙර කරන්නම් හතර වරිගයමසංසාරේ යන මේ ගමනේචුට්ටක් සෙල්ලම් කරලා එන්නදපුරුදු යහළුවන් හා සැණිනේඑහෙම ගියත් ඒ අය පොඩි සාදූකියා කියන විට වැඳ වැටිලාකොහොමද අම්මේ ඔට්ටු දුවන්නේවෙල් ඉපනැල්ලේ පැන නටලාභවයෙන් භවයේ පෙරුම් පුරා මමබවුන් වඩා උපදින වාරේදිනයක මතුදා හතර වරිගයමඑතෙර කරන්නම් සංසාරේඉන් පසු ඇවිදින් අම්මේ ඔබ ළඟඉන්නම් කිරි සුවඳේ එතිලාකොහොමද අම්මේ එහෙම කරන්නේඅම්මත් සසරින් එතෙර වෙලාසනත් නන්දසිරිප්‍රණීත් අභයසුන්දරසනත් නන්දසිරි"},{"question":"GOGOLDHIGGA GUURKAGUURKA IYO MOWQIFKA DIINTA.","answer":"FAA'IIDOOYINKA GUURKAGuurku waxa uu leeyahay shan faa' iido oo kala ah:.-1-Ubad kaa hara:-Faa' iidooyinka guurka tan ugu horreysaa waa sidii laguheli halaa ubad, si aanay tafiirta dadku u dabar go'in. Ubad dhalistu waa inay yeelataa afar ulajeeddo oo kala ha:--Inaad ku doontid raallinimada Eebbe, maadaama aad gacan ka geysanaysid siday tafiirta dadku kusii socon lahayd.-Inaad ku doontid raallinimada Rasuulka (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam)kol haddaad ku kaalmeyneysid siduu ummadaha kale tirada ummaddiisa ugu faani lahaa.-In Eebbe ku siiyo ubad khayr qaba oo kuu soo duceeya kolka aad dhimatid.-Inaad ku doontid shafeeco kolka ilmo yari kuu saqiro.2-Dhufays aad ka gashid Shaydaanka: -Guurku waxa uu kaa oodaa meeluhuu shaydaanku kaasoo gelayey, mar hadday wuxuu xaaraan ku raadi ku lahaa rugtaada kuu yaallaan iyago0 xalaal ah. Qofku hadduusan Eebbe ku lahaa rugtaada kuu yaallaan iyagoo xalaal ah. Qofku hadduusan Eebbe ka cabsi iyo iimaan ku hubaysnayn, rabitaankiisa kacsi ayaa hor kaca, haddii markaasi aanu helin guur xalaal ah, siduu dembi isaga ilaaliyaa way adag tahay.3-Qalbigoo kuu dega iyo laabtoo kuu qabowda: Shaqo tay naftu u jeceshahay haddaan loo helin waqti nasasho, waa lagu daalayaa dabeetana la'iska deynayaa. Haddaba maxaad ka oran lahayd hadday shaqadaasi tahay taqwada Eebbe ooy iyada iyo naftuba isdiidayaan!. Saacadaha uu ninku ku hawlan yahay cibaadada Alle iyo camalka adduunyo, waxaa habboon inuu dhexgashado waqti uu xaaskiisa kula baashaalo, si qalbigu ugu dego, laabtu ugu qabowdo firfircoonaanna uga qaado.4-Hawshii guriga oo hoggaankeedii kaa wareego: Ninka oo ka xorooba maamulka guriga sida hagaajintiisa, xaaqistiisa, goglistiisa, cunto karinta iyo diyaarinta, alaab dhaqista, suuq kasoo adeegga, iwm., waxay siisaa waqti dheeraad ah oo uu ku shaqaysto, wax ku barto, Eebbena ku caabudo. Rasuulkeenna suubban (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) waxa uu xadiis uu soo saaray Tirmidi ku leeyahay: (Midkiin ha yeesho qalbi Eebbe ku mahadin og, carrab Eebbe xusid badan iyo haweeney mu'minad suubban ahoo Aakhiradiisa ku kaalmeysa). Haddaba dumarka looma guursado oo qura in adduunyada lagu raaxaysto, carruurna laga daadiyo, balse yoolka ugu muhiimsani waxa weeye inay kuu abuuraan waqti iyo jawi aad Eebbe ku caabuddid.5-Nafta ood kula dagaallantid daryeelka qoyska: Nafta ood ku jara-bartidqaadista mas'uuliyadda reerka, daryeelkiisa, gudashada waajibka kaasaaran xaaskaaga, dabeecaddeeda 00d ugu samirtid, dhib wixii kaaga yimaada ood u dulqaadatid, hanuuninteeda ood u hawlgashid, dadaal aad u gashid sidaad marasho iyo masruuf xalaal ah ugu keeni lahayd, carruurta ood ku tarbiyeysid waddada toosan, iwm.Waxaas 0o dhami waxay kamid yihiin faa'iidooyinka guurka, tiyoo weliba ajar iyo xasanaad Eebbe kaa siinayo. Nabigeennu (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) waxa uu xadiis ku leeyahay: (War hooya gebigiin waxaad tihiin QawsaarrO, qawsaar walibana waxa uu mas'uul ka yahay wixii la raaciyey). Waxaa la sheegay in raggii hore ee suusuubbanaa mid kamid ahi uu niman walaalihii ah ooy jihaad ku wada jireen weydiiyey: (Ma garanaysaan shaqada aynu hadda hayno mid inooga ajar badan?). Markaas bay yiraahdeen: (Ma garanayno). Suu yiri: (Anaa garanaya). Markey weydiiyeenna waxa uu ugu jawaabay: (Nin sabool ahoo ciyaal leh, ha yeeshee aan cidna wax weydiisan, o0 intuu cawa-barkii toosay 00 reerka indha-indheeyey arkay carruurtiisii oo hurudda cawradoodunabannaan tahay, dabeetana ku huwiyey go'ii uu keligii dhar ka lahaa, kaas baa naga camal wanaagsan)."},{"question":"வினா: ஆறில் ஒரு பங்கு நாவலாசிரியர் யார்? ","answer":"விடை:   பாரதியார்1.  பாரதி, தமிழ்க் கவிதையிலும் உரைநடையிலும் சிறப்பான புலமை கொண்டு, நவீன தமிழ்க் கவிதைக்கு    முன்னோடியாகத் திகழ்ந்தார்.2.  தமிழ், தமிழர் நலன், இந்திய விடுதலை, பெண் விடுதலை, சாதி மறுப்பு, பல்வேறு சமயங்கள் குறித்து      கவிதைகளும் கட்டுரைகளும் எழுதியுள்ளார். 3.  தம் எழுத்துகள் மூலமாக மக்கள் மனதில் விடுதலை உணர்வை ஊட்டியவர். 4.  எட்டப்ப நாயக்கர் மன்னர் இவருடைய கவித்திறனை மெச்சி, கலைமகள் எனப் பாெருள்படும் பாரதி      என்ற பட்டம் வழங்கினார்.5.   பாரதியாரின் நூல்கள் தமிழ்நாடு மாநில அரசினால் 1949-ஆம் ஆண்டில் நாட்டுடைமை ஆக்கப்பட்டன. 6.  இந்தியாவிலேயே முதன்முதலாக நாட்டுடைமை ஆக்கப்பட்ட இலக்கியம் பாரதியாருடையதாகும்."},{"question":"આ પર આધારિત એક લેખ લખો \\" 1 થી 2 વાક્યોથી શરૂ કરો તમારા શિક્ષકને પત્ર શું છે તે જણાવો. તમારા શિક્ષકને તેમના વિશે તમે શું પ્રશંસા કરો છો તેના થોડા ઉદાહરણો આપો. તમારા પત્રના શરીરને ફરીથી આભાર માનતા સમાપ્ત કરો. \\"  લેખઃ","answer":"આ તમારા શિક્ષકને પત્રમાંથી શું અપેક્ષા રાખશે તે જણાવશે. તમારા શિક્ષકનો આભાર માનવો કહો, \\"હું તમને આ પત્ર લખું છું કે હું તમારા વર્ગમાં કેટલો ખુશ છું કારણ કે તમે શ્રેષ્ઠ શિક્ષક છો. આ વર્ષ મુશ્કેલ રહ્યું છે, પરંતુ તમે મને મારા શ્રેષ્ઠ પ્રયાસ કરવામાં મદદ કરી. તમારા શિક્ષકને બતાવવા માટે શ્રેષ્ઠ ઉદાહરણો પસંદ કરો તમારા પત્રને વધુ વ્યક્તિગત બનાવવા માટે, ચોક્કસ બનો અને તેમને જણાવો કે તેમની ક્રિયાઓ તમને કેવી રીતે લાગે છે. તમે લખી શકો છો, \\"શાળા પછી તમે મને ટ્યુશન આપતા સમયની હું પ્રશંસા કરું છું. મને લાગ્યું કે હું ક્યારેય ગુણાકારને સમજી શકતો નથી, પણ તમે મને ક્યારેય છોડતા નથી. હું એટલો ખુશ છું કે તમે મારા શિક્ષક છો! જો તમને શું કહેવું તે નક્કી કરવામાં મુશ્કેલી આવી રહી છે, તો સ્ક્રેચ પેપરની શીટ લો અને કેટલાક મગજનો તોફાન કરો. તમારા શિક્ષકને તમે શા માટે પસંદ કરો છો, તેમણે તમને કેટલી વાર મદદ કરી છે અથવા તમે તેમની પાસેથી શું શીખ્યા છો તે લખો. ૧૧. યહોવાહના સાક્ષીઓ માટે શું કરવું જરૂરી છે? 1 થી 3 વાક્યો લખો જે તમે કહ્યું છે તે સારાંશ આપે છે. તમારા શિક્ષકને યાદ કરાવો કે તેમણે તમારા માટે જે કર્યું છે તેની તમે પ્રશંસા કરો છો. તમે કહી શકો છો, \\"આ વર્ષે એક મહાન શિક્ષક હોવા બદલ આભાર. હું ખૂબ જ ખુશ છું કે હું તમારા વર્ગમાં છું. હું આશા રાખું છું કે તમારી પાસે અદ્ભુત ઉનાળો છે!"},{"question":"Ebuka indodana yakhe esinguthuqasana nje.Uzibonele-ke mfana wami lokho ebesikhuluma ngakho.Okungikhalisa kakhulu ukungabikhona kukaPhindisiwe. Bengifunaukuzwa ukuthi lolu daba ubeyoluphendula athini ikakhulu indabakaZiphozonke ngoba phela lo mlisa uyibhedlile.Phela ngenye indaba lena kaZiphozonke. Kwamina ingifocozaumbombo. Kangazi nokuthi ngingayiqala ngiyithini ukuyixoxa.Sekufanele uthathe isinqumo manje Thamsanqa. Konkekusezandleni zakho.Ubukhona bukamakoti bekungeke kwasiguqula isimo sezinto.Okwesibili bekufanele ulale phansi ungavumeli ukucinaniswayigwebu lentukuthelo kuze kubhoboke ithumba.Lolu daba aluluncane njengoba bengicabanga. Khona nginakhoukusolasola ukuthi kungenzeka lesi sitifiketi yilezi okuthiwaziyathengwa. Kukhona into ayifunayo lo Nkululeko.Uma usenokungabaza ndodana kukuwe lokho. Umbuzo wamikuwena munye vo, uthini ngale nkulumo engiyitshelwe ngumkakholuqobo ukuthi savumelana ngingamoneli umuzi?Kangenziwa kanjena mina. Kufanele ngiqonde ngqo kwaMakhungabangichazele kahle ngale nto, izinkomo zami ngifuna bazibeke la.(Ekhomba intende yesandla sakhe sangakwesokunxele.)Baze bangamahumusha abantu madoda. Kusho khona ukuthikwenziwa ibhizinisi?1. Chaza isizathu sokuba khona komlingiswa onguKholekile kulo mdlalo.","answer":"Isizathu sokuba khona kukaKholekile ukugqamisa ukuthi kukhona abantu othingabangani kanti bangamaxoki njengoba uPhindisiwe emethemba uKholekileemxoxela ngazo zonke izinkinga zakhe nobunzima abhekene nabo kantiuKholekile uthunywe nguNkululeko ukuthi asenge izindaba kuPhindisiweokwaholela ekutheni iqhinga likaNkululeko lokufuna imali liphumelele."},{"question":"තත්‍ර‍මජ්ඣත්තතාව  චෛතසිකය ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"චිත්ත චෛතසිකයෝ ඒ ඒ කෘත්‍යයන් සිදු කරමින් සමූහ වශයෙන් උපදින්නෝ ය. එකිනෙකින් වෙන් නො කළ හැකි සේ බැඳී උපදනා වූ ධර්ම රාශියක් ඇති සෑම ධර්මයකට ම වෙන් වූ කෘත්‍යයක් ද ඇත්තේ ය. සියල්ල ම එක්වීමෙන් සිදුවන සර්වසාධාරණ කෘත්‍යයක් ද ඇත්තේ ය. මිනිසුන් සමූහයක් එක් වී ගෙයක් සාදන කල්හි ගල් ගෙන ඒම, බදාම ඇනීම, ගල් බැඳීම යනාදි කෘත්‍යයන් ඒ ඒ අය විසින් වෙන වෙන ම කරනු ලැබේ. සැම දෙන ම කරන ක්‍රියා සියල්ලේ ම එක්වීමෙන් ගෙය තැනීම නමැති ක්‍රියාව වේ. එමෙන් චිත්ත චෛතසික පිණ්ඩයක ඇති ධර්මයන් විසින් වෙන් වෙන් වශයෙන් සිදු කර කෘත්‍ය රාශියක් ද ඇත්තේ ය. සමූහයට ම අයත් වූ ප්‍ර‍ධාන කෘත්‍යයක් ද ඇත්තේ ය. සාමූහික කෘත්‍යය නම් දීම් ගැනීම් ආදිය ය. දෙදෙනකු විසින් එක් ව බරක් ඔසවා ගෙන යෑමේ දී ඒ දෙදෙනාගෙන් එකකු වේගයෙන් යන්නටත් එකකු සෙමෙන් යන්නටත් සූදානම් වුව හොත් ඔවුන් දෙදෙනාට ඒ බර ගෙන යා හැකි නො වන්නේ ය. එය ගෙන යා හැකි වීමට නම් දෙදෙනා විසින් ම සම ව ගමන් කළ යුතු ය. එමෙන් ම එක් සාමූහික ක්‍රියාවක් සිදු කිරීම් වශයෙන් පහළ වන්නා වූ චිත්ත චෛතසික පිණ්ඩයක තම තමා විසින් වෙන් වශයෙන් සිදු කරන ක්‍රියාවන්ගේ වේග සමත්වයක් තිබිය යුතුය. සිදු කරන ප්‍ර‍ධාන කෘත්‍යයට ගැලපෙන පරිදි ධර්මයන් ගේ වේග සමත්වය නොහොත් වේගයන් සම කරන ධර්මය තත්‍ර‍මජ්ඣත්තතාව ය. ධර්මයන් ගේ සමත්වය ශෝභන සිත්වල පමණක් නොව අශෝභන සිත්වලද තිබිය යුතුය. එහෙත් තත්‍ර‍මජ්ඣත්තතාව චෛතසිකය අශෝභන සිත්වල ලැබෙන බවක් දක්වා නැත. එබැවින් මෙය තේරුම් ගැනීමට දුෂ්කර තැනෙකි. මේ චෛතසිකය ධම්මසංගණිය උද්ධරණය කොට දක්වා නැත. මෙය යේවාපනක වශයෙන් දේශිත චෛතසිකයෙකි."},{"question":"\\"لوليتا، حبّي\\" هى مسرحيّة غنائية مبنيّة على رواية \\"لوليتا\\" التى كتبها أيّ مؤلف؟","answer":"رواية \\"لوليتا\\"  كتبها فلاديمير فلاديميروفيتش نابوكوف."},{"question":"மதுரையிலுள்ள தூண் மண்டபம் எவ்வளவு உயரம் கொண்டது?(அ) 45 அடி(ஆ) 90 அடி(இ) 135 அடி(ஈ) 180 அடி","answer":"பதில்: (ஆ) 90 அடி"},{"question":"ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਉਪ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਸੁਖਬੀਰ ਬਾਦਲ ਨੇ ਟਿੱਪਣੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਕਿ ਤਤਕਾਲੀ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਤਾਂ ਖ਼ੁਦ ਸਿੱਖ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਕਤਲੇਆਮ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰਸਾਨੀ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਸਨ। ਇਸ ਬਿਆਨ ਉੱਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਸੀਬੀਆਈ ਨੂੰ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਨੋਟਿਸ ਲੈਣ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਮਰਹੂਮ ਰਾਜੀਵ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਦੇ ਰੋਲ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਕੀਤੀ।ਦੂਜੇ ਪਾਸੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਕੈਪਟਨ ਅਮਰਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਜਦਦੀਸ਼ ਟਾਇਟਲਰ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਨੂੰ ਰੱਦ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਸਭ ਸੱਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।ਟਾਈਮਜ਼ ਆਫ਼ ਇੰਡੀਆ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਖ਼ਬਰ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ਿਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਜੋ ਗੂਗਲ 'ਤੇ ਟਰੈਂਡ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਖ਼ਬਰ 'ਤੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਦਿਲਚਸਪ ਟਿੱਪਣੀਆਂ ਕੀਤੀਆ ਹਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਟਿੱਪਣੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਕੁੱਝ ਅਸੀਂ ਇੱਥੇ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਾਂ:ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਨਾਮ ਵਰਤਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਨੇ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਕਿ ਅਮਰਿੰਦਰ ਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਸਭ ਨੂੰ ਨਕਾਰਨਗੇ ਹੀ, ਉਹ ਭਲਾ ਕਿਉਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਨਕਾਰਨਗੇ? ਪਰ ਸੁਖਬੀਰ ਬਾਦਲ ਹੁਣ ਕਿਉਂ ਬੋਲ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ? ਦਸ ਸਾਲ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹਿੰਦਿਆਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਕਿਉਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਵਾਈ ਜਾਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਮਨਮੋਹਨ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਣ ਦਿੱਤੀ?ਪਿਅੰਕੀ ਬੈਨਰਜੀ ਨੇ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਖੁਸ਼ੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸਿੱਖਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਵਾਪਰੀਆਂ 1984 ਦੀਆਂ ਮੰਦਭਾਗੀਆਂ ਘਟਨਾਵਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਸਮਝੌਤਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਵਧ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਗੱਲ ਤਕਲੀਫ਼ ਦਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸੁਖਬੀਰ ਵਰਗੇ ਆਗੂ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਲਾਭ ਲਈ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਭਾਵਨਾਵਾਂ ਭੜਕਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਅਮਰਿੰਦਰ ਵਰਗੇ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਬਿਆਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਨਕਾਰ ਦਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਅਸੀਂ ਇੱਕ ਵਾਰ ਸਹਿਮਤ ਕਿਉਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਦੰਗੇ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਨੇ ਕਰਵਾਏ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਆਗੂਆਂ ਨੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਿਗਰਾਨੀ ਕੀਤੀ। ਹੁਣ, ਇਸ ਗੱਲ ਨਾਲ ਕੀ ਫ਼ਰਕ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਕਿ ਰਾਜੀਵ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਉੱਤਰੀ ਕਿ ਦੱਖਣੀ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਘੁੰਮ ਕੇ ਇਹ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਜਾਂ ਘਰ ਬੈਠ ਕੇ ਅਪਡੇਟ ਲਈ।ਕੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੇ ਵਾਲੇ ਇੱਕ ਸ਼ਖਸ਼ ਨੇ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਗੱਲ ਦੀ ਸੀਬੀਆਈ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਂਚ ਕਰਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਬਾਦਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਨੂੰ ਨਸ਼ੇੜੀ ਸੂਬਾ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਹੈ। ਇੰਨਾ ਕੋਲ ਐਨਾ ਪੈਸਾ, ਵਪਾਰ ਕਿੱਥੋਂ ਆਇਆ ਤੇ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਜੁਰਮ ਨੂੰ ਉਤਸ਼ਾਹਿਤ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਕੀਤਾ।ਬਰਿਜ ਵਾਈ ਨੇ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਕਿ ਇੱਕ ਦਹਾਕੇ ਤੱਕ ਗੁਜਰਾਤ ਦੰਗੇ ਵਰਤੇ। ਉਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਐਨਡੀਏ 1984 ਨੂੰ ਮਰਨ ਦੇਵੇਗਾ ਤੇ ਐਮਰਜੈਂਸੀ ਦਾ ਸਮਾਂ ਯਾਦ ਕਰਵਾਉਂਦਾ ਰਹੇਗਾ। ਇਹ ਤਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਤੱਖ ਹੈ ਕਿ 1984 ਕਿਤੇ ਵੱਡਾ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਦੇਸ ਵਿਆਪੀ ਕਤਲੇਆਮ ਸੀ।ਅਭਿਸ਼ੇਕ ਨੇ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਕਿ ਕੀ ਸੁਖਬੀਰ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਰਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਂਦੀ? ਇੱਕ ਸਿੱਖ ਨੇ ਉਸੇ ਦੀ ਜਾਨ ਲਈ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਰਾਖੀ ਲਈ ਉਹ ਜ਼ਿੰਮੇਵਾਰ ਸੀ। ਇੰਦਰਾ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਨੂੰ ਸਲਾਹ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਦਸਤੇ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਸਿੱਖ ਹਟਾ ਦੇਵੇ।","answer":"ਜਗਦੀਸ਼ ਟਾਈਟਲਰ ਨੇ ਇੱਕ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਨਿਊਜ਼ ਚੈਨਲ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਕਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਹ 1984 ਦੇ ਸਿੱਖ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਦੰਗਿਆਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਤਤਕਾਲੀ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਰਾਜੀਵ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਨਾਲ ਬਚਾਅ ਕਾਰਜਾਂ ਦਾ ਜਾਇਜ਼ਾ ਲੈਣ ਦਿੱਲੀ ਦੇ ਕਈ ਇਲਾਕਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਗਏ ਸਨ।"},{"question":"ગુજરાતની પ્રસિદ્ધ હસ્તકળાઓ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"ભરતગુંથણ કામમાટીકામબાંધણીકાષ્ટકામપટોળાજરીકામઘરેણાબીડ વર્કવારલી ચિત્રકળા"},{"question":"5x^7 – 6x^5 + 7x – 6 బహుపది పరిమాణం ఎంత?","answer":"7"},{"question":"மணத்தக்காளி கீரையின் மருத்துவ பயன்கள் யாவை?","answer":" மணத்தக்காளி கீரையின் மருத்துவ பயன்கள்:-கீரைகளில் பல வகைகள் உள்ளன. அவற்றில் ஒன்று தான் மணத்தக்காளி கீரை. இந்த கீரையின் தண்டு, இலை, காய், பழம் போன்ற அனைத்துமே சமையலில் மட்டுமின்றி, மருத்துவத்திலும் பயன்படுகிறது.வாய்ப்புண் உள்ளவர்கள், மணத்தக்காளி கீரையை தொடர்ந்து சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால், வாய்ப்புண் மட்டுமின்றி, வயிற்றுப்புண்ணும் குணமாகும். ஏனெனில் வாய்ப்புண்  உள்ளவர்களுக்கு வயிற்றுப்புண்ணும் இருக்கும். மலச்சிக்கலால் அவஸ்தைப்படுபவர்கள், மணத்தக்காளி கீரையை சாப்பிட்டால், இப்பிரச்சனையில் இருந்து விடுபடலாம். தொண்டை கரகரப்பு உள்ளவர்களுக்கு இந்த கீரை விரைவில் நிவாரணம் அளிக்கும். எனவே வாரம் இரண்டு முறை இந்த கீரையை உணவில் சேர்த்து வந்தால், தொண்டை கரகரப்பு ஏற்படுவதைத் தடுக்கலாம். செரிமான பிரச்சனை உள்ளவர்கள், மணத்தக்காளி கீரையை சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால், உடலுக்கு வேண்டிய சத்துக்கள் கிடைப்பதுடன், செரிமான பிரச்சனையும்  நீங்கிவிடும். உடல் வெப்பம் அதிகம் இருந்தால், மணத்தக்காளி கீரையை சமைத்து சாப்பிட்டு வர, உடல் வெப்பம் தணியும். காசநோய் உள்ளவர்கள் இந்த கீரையின் பழத்தை  தினமும் சாப்பிடுவது நல்லது. காய்ச்சல் வந்தால், கை கால் போன்றவை வலி எடுக்கும். இத்தகைய வலியையும், காய்ச்சலையும் போக்க இந்த கீரையை சாப்பிடுவது சிறந்தது. சருமத்தில் அலர்ஜி, வெயில் கட்டி போன்றவை இருந்தால், அப்போது மணத்தக்காளியின் சாற்றினை பிரச்சனை உள்ள இடத்தில் தடவினால், விரைவில்  குணமாகும்.மணத்தக்காளி கீரையானது இருதயத்தின் செயல்பாட்டை அதிகரிக்கும். களைப்பை நீக்கி நல்ல உறக்கத்தைக் கொடுக்கும். மணத்தக்காளியானது மலச்சிக்கலிலிருந்து நிவாரணம் அளிக்கும். கண்பார்வை தெளிவு பெறும்.வயிற்றில் உள்ள பூச்சிகளை வெளியேற்றும் தன்மை கொண்டது   மணத்தக்காளி. மணத்தக்காளியின் வேரானது மலச்சிக்கலை நீக்கும் மருந்துகளில் சேர்க்கப்படுகிறது.கீரையுடன் தேங்காய் சேர்த்து கூட்டு போல செய்து சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால் குடல் புண், மற்றும் சிறுநீர்ப்பை எரிச்சல் போன்ற பிரச்சனைகள் நீங்கும். மணத்தக்காளி வற்றலானது வாந்தியைப் போக்கி பசியை ஏற்படுத்தும்.உடற்சூடு அதிகம் கொண்டவர்கள் மணத்தக்காளி கீரையை உணவில் சேர்த்து கொண்டால் உடற்சூடு குறையும். காச நோயால் பாதிக்கப்பட்டவர்கள் மணத்தக்காளி பழத்தை சாப்பிடுவது நல்லது."},{"question":"ජීවීන්ගේ පැවත්මට ජලය වැදගත් වන්නේ ඇයි?","answer":"මූලික හේතු කිහිපයක් නිසා  ජලය ජීවීන්ගේ පැවත්මට ඉතා  වැදගත් වේ:1. ද්‍රාවක ගුණ: ජලය විශිෂ්ට ද්‍රාවකයකි, එයින් අදහස් කරන්නේ බොහෝ  ද්‍රව්‍ය එහි දිය විය හැකි බවයි. මෙම ගුණාංගය ජීවීන්ගේ පෝෂ්‍ය පදාර්ථ හා අපද්‍රව්‍ය ප්‍රවාහනය ඇතුළුව ජීවිතයට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය විවිධ ජෛව රසායනික ප්‍රතික්‍රියා  සඳහා  පහසුකම් සලසයි.2. රසායනික ප්‍රතික්‍රියා : ජල විච්ඡේදනය සහ ඝනීභවනය ඇතුළු බොහෝ ජෛව රසායනික ප්‍රතික්‍රියා සඳහා ජලය සම්බන්ධ වේ. සජීවී ජීවීන්ගේ අණු බිඳවැටීම සහ ගොඩනැගීම යන දෙකෙහිම එය අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වේ.3. උෂ්ණත්ව නියාමනය: ජලයට ඉහළ නිශ්චිත තාප ධාරිතාවක් ඇති අතර එමඟින් තාපය සෙමෙන් අවශෝෂණය කර මුදා හැරීමට ඉඩ සලසයි. මෙම ගුණාංගය පරිසරයේ සහ ජීවීන් තුළ උෂ්ණත්වය ස්ථාවර කිරීමට උපකාරී වන අතර එය ජීවයට හිතකර වේ.4. ජීව විද්‍යාත්මක මාධ්‍යය: ජීව විද්‍යාත්මක ක්‍රියාවලීන් සඳහා මාධ්‍යයක් ලෙස ජලය ක්‍රියා කරයි. උදාහරණයක් ලෙස, සෛල තුළ, පරිවෘත්තීය රසායනික ප්රතික්රියා බොහොමයක් සිදු වන පරිසරය සපයයි.5. ප්‍රවාහනය: ජලය බොහෝ ජීවීන්ගේ සංසරණ පද්ධතියේ ප්‍රධාන අංගයක් වන අතර, පෝෂ්‍ය පදාර්ථ, වායූන් සහ අපද්‍රව්‍ය ප්‍රවාහනය පහසු කරයි.6. භෞතික ව්‍යුහය සහ ආධාරක: බොහෝ ජීවීන් තම භෞතික ව්‍යුහය සඳහා ජලය මත රඳා පවතී. නිදසුනක් ලෙස, ශාක ව්යුහය පවත්වා ගැනීම සඳහා ඔවුන්ගේ සෛල තුළ ජල පීඩනය භාවිතා කරයි.7. වාසස්ථාන: ජල කඳන් යනු ජලජ ජීවීන් සඳහා අවශ්‍ය පරිසරය සපයමින් විශාල වන ජීවීන් සමූහයකට අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වාසස්ථාන වේ.ජලයෙහි ඇති අද්විතීය ගුණාංග - එහි ද්‍රාව්‍ය හැකියාවන්, ඉහළ තාප ධාරිතාව සහ රසායනික ප්‍රතික්‍රියා වල එහි භූමිකාව වැනි - එය පෘථිවියේ ජීවයේ පැවැත්මට සහ ව්‍යාප්තිය සඳහා  අත්‍යවශ්‍ය වේ."},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 「新語・流行語大賞」は今年あったことや流行したことの中から、その年を代表することばを選びます。東京で1日、選ばれた10のことばが発表されました。1番になったのは、プロ野球で56本のホームランを打ったヤクルトの村上宗隆選手の活躍を表す「村神様」でした。SNSやニュースなどいろいろなところで使われました。ほかには、元総理大臣が銃で撃たれて亡くなったことに関係する「国葬儀」や「宗教２世」が選ばれました。ウクライナへの連帯を表すために読み方を変えたウクライナの首都「キーウ」、いろいろな物の値段が上がっていくのに円安が続く「悪い円安」なども選ばれました。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。"},{"question":"कृपया रिक्त स्थानों को पूरा करें: \\"स्कूल में खेलकूद का महत्व __________ है, क्योंकि यह __________ और __________ को बढ़ावा देता है.\\"","answer":"पूर्ण लिखित वाक्य यह है: \\"स्कूल में खेलकूद का महत्व बहुत है, क्योंकि यह स्वास्थ्य और सामूहिकता को बढ़ावा देता है.\\""},{"question":"Kayeefi nla! Niluu Ifọn, ara san pa maaluu meje","answer":"Fun igba akọkọ niluu Ifọn Ọṣun, maaluu meje ni ara nla to san lasiko ojo nla kan to rọ loru mọjumọ oni pa.Abule kan ti wọn n pe ni Elepo Village, nijọba ibilẹ Orolu niṣẹlẹ naa ti ṣẹlẹ.Ibi ti awọn Fulani darandaran ko awọn maaluu ọhun pamọ si lẹyin ti wọn fi wọn jẹko tan ni ara ti san pa wọn.Nigba ti awọn oniroyin pe Olufọn tiluu Ifọn Orolu, Ọba Almaroof Magbagbeọla, lori foonu lati fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ, kabiyesi sọ pe awọn yoo pe pada."},{"question":"Di manakah pengisytiharan kemerdekaan diadakan?","answer":"Dataran Merdeka"},{"question":"\\"欧•亨利式的结尾\\"是指美国作家欧•亨利的短篇小说结局","answer":"出乎意料、耐人寻味"},{"question":"வினா : எரிசோடா என்ப்படுவது ","answer":"விடை : சோடியம் ஹைட்ராக்சைடு"},{"question":"வினா:பகத் சிங் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"விடை:பகத் சிங் (செப்டம்பர் 28, 1907[1] – மார்ச் 23, 1931 இந்தியாவின் விடுதலைப் போராட்ட வீரரும் இந்திய விடுதலை இயக்கத்தில் ஒரு முக்கிய புரட்சியாளரும் ஆவார். இக்காரணத்துக்காக இவர் சாஹீது பகத் சிங் என அழைக்கப்பட்டார் (சாஹீது என்பது மாவீரர் எனப் பொருள்படும்). இவர் இந்தியாவின் முதலாவது மார்க்சியவாதி எனவும் சில வரலாற்றாசிரியர்களால் குறிப்பிடப்படுவதுண்டு.இந்தியாவின் பிரித்தானிய ஆட்சிக்கெதிராகப் போராடிய குடும்பமொன்றில் பிறந்த பகத் சிங் இளம் வயதிலேயே ஐரோப்பிய புரட்சி இயக்கங்களைப் படிக்க ஆரம்பித்து பொதுவுடமைக் கொள்கைகளில் ஈர்க்கப்பட்டார். பல புரட்சி இயக்கங்களுடன் தொடர்புகளை ஏற்படுத்திக் கொண்டார். விரைவிலேயே இந்துஸ்தான் குடியரசு அமைப்பு என்ற புரட்சி அமைப்பின் தலைவர்களில் ஒருவரானார். 63 நாட்கள் சிறைவாசத்தில் இருந்தபோது இந்தியக் கைதிகளுக்கு ஏனைய பிரித்தானியக் கைதிகளுடன் சம உரிமை பெறுவதற்காக உண்ணாநோன்பு இருந்ததில் இவரது செல்வாக்கு மக்களிடையே அதிகரித்தது. முதுபெரும் காங்கிரஸ் தலைவர் லாலா லஜபதி ராய் என்பவரின் இறப்புக்குக் காரணமாயிருந்த காவலதிகாரியைச் சுட்டுக் கொன்ற குற்றத்திற்காக பகத் சிங் 24வது அகவையில் தூக்கிலிடப்பட்டார். இந்நிகழ்வானது மேலும் பல இளைஞர்களை இந்திய விடுதலைப் போராட்டத்தில் ஈடுபடவும் சோசலிசக் கொள்கைகள் இந்தியாவில் பரவவும் வழிவகுத்தது. பகத் சிங் தூக்கில் இடுவதுற்கு முன் தன் தந்தைக்கு நான் ஏன் கடவுள் மறுப்பு கொண்டவனாக மாறினேன் என்பதை கடிதம் மூலம் தெரிவித்தார். தமிழில் அப்புத்தகம் நான் ஏன் நாத்திகன் ஆனேன் என்ற பெயரில் ப. ஜீவானந்தம் என்பவரால் மொழி பெயர்க்கப்பட்டது.மேற்கோள் தனி நபர்களைக் கொல்வது எளிது, ஆனால் உங்களால் கருத்துகளைக் கொல்ல முடியாது."},{"question":"Rukunan Insha’i?","answer":"Abin da ake nufi da rukuni a nan shi ne sashe. Zamowar insha’i gajeren rubutu bai hana shi samun sassa ba domin ya samu cika. Insha’i yana da rukunai guda uku kamar haka:Gabatarwa.Gundari jawabi.Kammalawa.Abun so ne insha’i ya samu waɗannan sassa guda uku, rashin samun ɗaya daga cikin su ya mai she da wannan insha’i naƙasasshe"},{"question":"إذا رفعت كتابا عن طاولة ثم أعدته إلى مكانه؛ فإنك لا تبذل شغلا لأن:(أ) الدفع يساوي صفر (ب) الإزاحة تساوي صفر(ج) القوة المبذولة تساوي صفر (د) الطاقة المبذولة تساوي صفر","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة (ب) الإزاحة تساوي صفر"},{"question":"Waa maxay Haa ?","answer":"Haaa waa jawaab uugu fudud."},{"question":"أين تقع مدينة العين ؟","answer":"الإمارات"},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: An san Saudiyya da faffadan hamada da suka hada da Rub' al Khali. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"ドイツ語で「黒い森」という意味をもつ、ドイツ南部に広がる森林地帯のことを何というでしょう?","answer":"シュバルツバルト"},{"question":"පාරු කවියක් සඳහා උදාහරණයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"පාරු කවියක් සඳහා උදාහරණයක් පහත දැක්වේ.\\"සීරුව ඔබට කණු නො ම සිටුවා මහතවාරුව ඇතුව දිය පිට තැනු ගෙයක් ඇතමාරුව තැනින් තැන මඩු ගෙන ගමන් යතපාරුව වැනි ගෙයක් මේ මුළු ලොවේ නැත\\""},{"question":"Hatagi ko ug listahan sa mga pamaagi sa pagtuon ug pagtukar sa guitara para sa mga baguhan?","answer":"Ang mga pamaagi sa pagtuon ug pagtukar sa guitara para sa mga baguhan kay:1. Pili ug kanta na nakasaulo kana2. Tan-awa ang mga chords na gigamit sa kanta. Mas maayo kung sayon ra ang mga chords parehas sa A, C, D, G, E, Em, Am. 2. Tun-a ang mga porma sa chords 3.  Praktisa gamit ang kanta ug ang mga chords na imong gitun-an"},{"question":"Tarjamahkeun kalimah ieu tina basa Sunda kana basa Indonésia:Hobi kuring diajar basa asing sareng ayeuna kuring resep diajar Jerman.","answer":"Terjemahan: Hobi saya adalah belajar bahasa asing dan saat ini saya senang belajar bahasa Jerman."},{"question":"Ireto misy fanambarana:“Namita ny asako ara-potoana aho.” sy \\"Tsy vitako ny mamita ny tetikasa alohan'ny fe-potoana.\\"Mifanindra-teny ve ireo ?","answer":"Tsia, tsy mifanindra-teny ireo fanambarana ireo. Ny iray miresaka fahavitana ny asa fa ny iray kosa miresaka tsy fahavitana asa."},{"question":"Bu metin hangi önemli olayla ilgilidir: Hilderik (460lar - 533) Geç Antik Çağ'da Kuzey Afrika'daki Vandallar ve Alanların sondan bir önceki kralıdır. Vandal Krallığı, 534'te devrilmiş olsa da, o olayda kilit bir rol oynamıştır.","answer":"534'te devrilmiş"},{"question":"Hãy chọn câu sai.A. Một số chia hết cho 9 thì số đó chia hết cho 3B. Một số chia hết cho 3 thì số đó chia hết cho 9C. Một số chia hết cho 10 thì số đó chia hết cho 5D. Một số chia hết cho 45 thì số đó chia hết cho 9","answer":"Lời giảiCâu B sai vì: Một số chia hết cho 3 thì chưa chắc đã chia hết cho 9. Ví dụ 3 chia hết cho 3 nhưng 3 không chia hết cho 9.Chọn đáp án B."},{"question":"సంస్థాపన పత్రం అంటే ఏమిటి ? అందులోని క్లాజులను పేర్కొనండి.","answer":"భారత కంపెనీల చట్టము క్రింద నమోదైన అన్ని కంపెనీలకు ఆవశ్యకమైన పత్రము సంస్థాపన పత్రము. సంస్థాపనా పత్రమనే పునాది మీదనే కంపెనీ అనే భవనము నిర్మాణము అవుతుంది. ఈ పత్రము కంపెనీ అధికార ఎల్లలను, కంపెనీ వ్యవహారాలకు హద్దులను ఏర్పాటు చేస్తుంది. కంపెనీ ధ్యేయాలను, అధికారాలను, కార్యకలాపాలను వాటాదారులు, ఋణదాతలు, కంపెనీతో ప్రత్యక్షముగా సంబంధమున్న ప్రతివారికి ఖచ్చితముగా తెలియపరచడమే ఈ పత్రము ముఖ్య ఉద్దేశ్యము. కనుక దీనిని కంపెనీ రాజ్యాంగము అంటారు.ఈ పత్రము కంపెనీకి, బయటవారికి గల సంబంధాలను నిర్వచిస్తుంది. ఈ పత్రములో పొందుపరిచిన వ్యవహారాలు, నిర్వచించిన అధికారాలను, నిర్ణయించిన సంబంధాలను అతిక్రమించి ఏ కంపెనీ నడుచుకోవడానికి వీలులేదు. అలా నడుచుకుంటే ఆ వ్యవహారాలు, అధికారాలు, సంబంధాలు న్యాయవిరుద్ధము అవుతాయి. అవి చెల్లుబాటు కావు:దీనిని పేరాలుగా విభజించి, వరుసగా సంఖ్యలు వేసి ముద్రించవలెను. పబ్లిక్ కంపెనీ అయితే ఏడుగురు, ప్రైవేటు కంపెనీ అయితే ఇద్దరు సాక్షి సమక్షములో ఈ పత్రాల మీద సంతకాలు చేయవలెను. సంతకము చేసిన ప్రతి వ్యక్తి కనీసం ఒక వాటానైనా తీసుకొనవలెను.సంస్థాపనా పత్రములోని క్లాజులు.1) నామధేయపు క్లాజు : ఈ క్లాజులో కంపెనీ పూర్తి పేరు వ్రాయవలెను. పబ్లిక్ కంపెనీ అయితే పేరు చివర ‘లిమిటెడ్’, ప్రైవేటు కంపెనీ అయితే పేరు చివర ‘ప్రైవేటు లిమిటెడ్’ అనే పదములు ఉండాలి. కంపెనీ ఏ పేరునైనా పెట్టుకోవచ్చుగాని అంతకముందు స్థాపితమైన మరొక కంపెనీ పేరును పోలిగాని, సమీపములోగాని ఉండరాదు. అంతేగాక అవాంఛనీయమైన పేర్లు, చట్టముచే బహిష్కరింపబడిన పేర్లు కంపెనీకి పెట్టరాదు.2) కంపెనీ స్థానపు క్లాజు : కంపెనీ రిజిష్టర్డ్ ఆఫీసు ఏ రాష్ట్రములో ఉన్నదో ఆ రాష్ట్రము పేరు ఈ క్లాజులో తెలిపాలి. కంపెనీతో ఉత్తర ప్రత్యుత్తరాలు జరపడానికి కార్యాలయ చిరునామా అవసరము. కంపెనీ నమోదు సమయములో గాని, నమోదు అయిన 30 రోజులలోపు కార్యాలయపు చిరునామాను రిజిస్ట్రారుకు3) ధ్యేయాల క్లాజు : ఇది అతి ప్రధానమైన క్లాజు. ఇందులో కంపెనీ ధ్యేయాలు, అధికారాలు, వ్యాపార వ్యవహారాల పరిధి స్పష్టముగా పేర్కొనబడి ఉంటాయి. న్యాయపూరితమైన ఎన్ని ధ్యేయాలనైనా ఇందులో చేర్చవచ్చును. వాటినన్నింటిని కంపెనీ చేపట్టనవసరం లేదు. ఈ క్లాజులో చేర్చని కార్యకలాపాలను, ధ్యేయాలను అతిక్రమించి ఏ పని చేయరాదు. అలా చేస్తే అవి న్యాయవిరుద్ధము అవుతాయి.4) ఋణబాధ్యత క్లాజు : కంపెనీ వాటాదారుల యొక్క స్వభావాన్ని ఈ క్లాజులో వ్రాయవలెను. వాటాదారుల ఋణబాధ్యత వారు తీసుకున్న వాటాల విలువ మేరకు పరిమితమని తెలియజేస్తుంది. ఒకవేళ వాటాలో కొంత మొత్తము చెల్లిస్తే, వారి ఋణబాధ్యత ఆ చెల్లించని మొత్తానికే పరిమితము అవుతుంది.5) మూలధనపు క్లాజు : ఎంత మూలధనాన్ని జారీ చేయడానికి అనుమతి కావలెనో ఈ క్లాజులో తెలియజేస్తారు. దీనిని అధీకృత మూలధనము, నమోదు మూలధనము అంటారు. ఈ మూలధనాన్ని ఎన్ని వాటాలుగా విభజించినారు, వాటా విలువ ఎంతో తెలియపరచవలెను.6) వ్యవస్థాపన – చందాల క్లాజు : తాము కంపెనీని స్థాపించడానికి ఒక సంస్థగా ఏర్పడినట్లు, తమ పేర్లకు ఎదురుగా ఉన్న వాటాలను తీసుకోవడానికి ఒప్పుకున్నట్లు ఒక ప్రకటన ద్వారా ఈ క్లాజులో తెలియజేయాలి. వారందరూ సాక్షి సమక్షములో సంతకాలు చేయాలి."},{"question":"கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள கேள்விக்குச் சரியான பதிலளி:சாரநாத் கல்தூணில் செதுக்கப்படாத விலங்கு?1. மான் 2. யானை3. சிங்கம்4. குதிரை","answer":"விடை: 1. மான் . இந்தியாவின் புகழ் பெற்ற சக்கரவர்த்தியான அசோகர், சில ஸ்தூபிகளையும் தூணையும் 'சாரநாத்' எனும் இடத்தில் நிறுவினார். இதில் உள்ள அசோகச் சக்கரம்தான் இந்தியத் தேசியக் கொடியையும் அலங்கரிக்கிறது. அசோகச்சக்கரத்தின் அருகில் நான்கு பக்கமும் சிங்கம், குதிரை, எருது, யானை ஆகியவற்றின் உருவங்கள் உள்ளன. இந்தத் தூணில் உள்ள நான்கு சிங்கங்கள்தான் இந்தியாவின் தேசியச் சின்னமாக உள்ளது."},{"question":"கேள்வி:முகமது கஜினி இந்தியாவின் மீது படையெடுத்து வந்ததற்கு காரணம் என்ன ?","answer":"பதில்:முகமது கஜினி செல்வத்தைப் பெறவும்,  இஸ்லாத்தைப் பரப்பவும் இந்தியாவின் மீது படையெடுத்தார். இந்தியாவின் மீது படையெடுப்பது மத்திய ஆசியாவில் தனது சக்தியை நிரூபிக்க அவரது வழியாகும், மேலும் அவர் தனது சக்தியை நிரூபித்து இந்தியாவை ஆக்கிரமித்து தனது பேரரசை விரிவுபடுத்த விரும்பினார். "},{"question":" Em qual cidade está o monumento Coliseu, também conhecido como Anfiteatro Flaviano?","answer":"Em Roma."},{"question":"सरला, अर्जुन र ईशा तीन साथी हुन् जो घुम्न मन पराउँछन्। सरलाले १५ देशको भ्रमण गरिसकेकी छिन् भने अर्जुनले १० देशको भ्रमण गरिसकेका छन् । ईशाले ८ देशको भ्रमण गरिसकेकी छिन् । माथिका भनाइहरूबाट के अनुमान लगाउन सकिन्छ?क) सरलाले अर्जुनभन्दा धेरै देशको भ्रमण गरेकी छिन् ।ख) एमिलीले सबैभन्दा धेरै देशको भ्रमण गरेकी छिन्।ग) अर्जुनले ईशाभन्दा कम देशको भ्रमण गरेका छन्।घ) सरलाले ईशाभन्दा कम देशको भ्रमण गरेकी छिन् ।","answer":"सहि उत्तर हो \\"क) सरलाले अर्जुनभन्दा धेरै देशको भ्रमण गरेकी छिन्\\" ।"},{"question":"Yaa ugu soo hor islaamay reer Madiina?","answer":"Waxaa ugu soo hor islaamay Sacad binu saruura."},{"question":" Sheeg Kal-Kaalisadii Ugu Horeeyey Islaamka","answer":" Waxay Eheed Kuceybatu Al Aslaamiyah."},{"question":"Apakah kesan terhadap sesebuah negara sekiranya rusuhan berlaku dan tidak dapat dikawal?","answer":"Rusuhan yang tidak terkawal akan enjejaskan kestabilan politik, ekonomi, dan sosial sesebuah negara. Suasana akan menjadi huru-hara dan menjejaskan keamanan. Ia akan menyebabkan berlakunya pergaduhan yang akan mungkin akan menyebabkan kecederaan atau kematian. Ini akan menjejaskan keselamatan dalam negeri. Akibatnya, fenomena ini akan menakutkan pelabur asing dan pelancong luar untuk datang. Ini akan embuka ruang dan kesempatan kepada kuasa asing untuk campur tangan dalam politik negara dan memudahkan penjajahan kuasa asing."},{"question":"Quais são as cores da bandeira da Espanha?","answer":"A bandeira da Espanha é formada por duas faixas vermelhas e uma faixa amarela. Cor vermelha: tem como significado principal a coragem e sacrifício do povo espanhol. Cor amarela: remete às riquezas presentes no território espanhol. O amarelo, enquanto simbologia local, também remete à nobreza espanhola."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk biskut Cheese Cadbury sebagai biskut raya? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan-bahan : 180 gm mentega, 80 gm shortening, 90 gm gula icing, 1 biji kuning telur, 1 sudu makan esen vanila, 70 gm cream cheeseBahan B : 400 gm tepung gandum, 80 gm tepung jagungBahan C : 1 botol coklat Cadbury – 200 pcs, Putih telur untuk sapuCara membuatnya :1. Pukul bahan A hingga sebati dan kembang.2. Masukkan bahan B. Gaul rata.3. Rehatkan selama 15-30 minit di dalam peti sejuk untuk senang terap.4. Potong/terap mengikut saiz dan ketebalan lebih kurang coklat Cadbury dan bakar dalam oven yang telah dipanaskan terlebih dahulu selama 15 minit dengan suhu 150-160’C,5. Kemudian bakar selama 20 minit menggunakan api atas bawah.Note : 5 minit terakhir itu untuk pusingkan tray untuk pembakaran sekata.6. Biarkan biskut sejuk. Sapu sedikit putih telur. Letakkan Cadbury.7. Bakar lagi 5 minit hingga bawah dan keliling biskut kelihatan perang, guna api atas-bawah, rak paling bawah.8. Sejukkan atas redai sebelum disimpan dalam bekas kedap udara berlayerkan baking paper (untuk serap lebihan minyak)."},{"question":"Kílódé tí Ìjọba àpapọ̀ fí wọ́gilé N-Power fún ìgbà díẹ̀?","answer":"O to milọnu kan eeyan to ti padanu isẹ wọn kete ti ìjọba apapọ kede pe awọn ti wọgile eto ìjọba N-Power to n pese fun araalu.Eto ìjọba N-Power ni ijọba da silẹ lasiko eto isejọba Aarẹ ana, Mohammadu Buhari lati gbe ogun ti airisẹ awọn ọdọ, ti wọn si n san ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgbọn naira fun awọn ọdọ naa ni owo oṣu wọn.Ọdun meje sẹyin ni ijọba apapọ da eto silẹ lati gbe ogun ti bi awọn ọdọ ko ṣe ri isẹ lorilẹede Naijiria.Minisita fun igbayegbaju araalu, Betta Edu lo kede ọrọ naa lasiko to n kopa ninu ifọrọwerọ kan to ṣe pẹlu ileeṣẹ tẹlẹfisan TVC lana salaye pe ijọba gbe igbesẹ yii lati ṣe iwadi lori bi awọn olori eto ṣe na owo ijọba.Bakan naa ni Minisita bu ẹnu atẹlu bi awọn ọdọ kan ṣe kuna lati ṣe ojuṣe won lori eto ti ijọba pese ti pupọ si gba owo ijọba nikan sapo.“A ni lati pada si N-Power lati ṣe atunṣe ati lati mọ isoro to n da lamu. Bayii, a wogile fun igba diẹ lati le ṣe iwadi to jina lori bi wọn ṣe n na owo ti ijọba pese fun eto N-Power.“A fẹ mọ iye awọn eeyan ti wọn n jẹ anfani yii lọwọlọwọ bayii, iye awọn ti a jẹ lowo ati iye ti ajẹ wọn, A fẹ ṣe atunṣe nla si eto N-Power, a si fẹ ko kari;e ati oko.“Ọpọ igba ni a ma kesi ile ẹkọ ti a fi awọn ọdọ yii, sugbọn wọn ko si nibẹ, bẹẹni wọn sọ pe a jẹ awọn ni owo oṣu mẹjọ si mẹsan an.“O to ida ọgọrin ọdọ ti wọn ṣe isẹ kankan bayii sugbọn wọn fẹ gba owo oṣu lọwọ ijọba”Bawo ni N-Power ṣe waye?Ọjọ kẹjọ oṣu kẹfa ọdun 2016 ni ijọba apapọ gbe eto N-Power kalẹ lati tan isoro airisẹ ati lati pese iranlọwọ fun awọn ọdọ lorilẹede Naijiria.Awọn ọdọ lati ọdun Mejidinogun si ọdun marundinlogoji lo ni anfani si eto yii.Ọdun meji ni ijọba yoo fi san owo fun awọn ọdọ ti wọn ba gba sisẹ.Ijọba pin eto naa si isọri mẹfa; N-Teach, N-Health, N-Agro, N-Build, N-Creative ati N-Tech."},{"question":"ගෝණපතිරාව වැව ගැන කියන්න.","answer":"ධාතුසේන රජතුමාට මල් සැපයූ තැනැත්තා හැදින්වූයේ කඩඉම් රාල යනුවෙනි. ඔහුගේ ගම කඩඉම්ගල. ඔහු ගෙන එන මල් අතරේ ලස්සන රතු නෙළුම් මල් තිබුණා. එක යායට මල් පිපී ඇති මල් බලන්නට රජතුමාට ආසා හිතුණා. රජතුමා කාටත් රහසේ කඩඉම් රාලගේ ගමට ගියා. මල් පිපුණු වතුර පිරි වළ දුටුවා. ඒ වෙලාවේ වතුර වළෙන් වතුර බිබී උන් ගෝණා නාද කළා. නෙත දුටු සුන්දර දසුනත් කණ වැකුණු නාදයත් නිසා රජතුමා බොහෝ සේ ප්‍රීතියට පත් වුණා. රජතුමා ඒ ඉසව්වේ වැවක් තනන්නට කල්පනා කළා. ඒ කටයුත්ත කඩඉම් රාලට පැවරුවා. ඔහු ඒ රාජකාරිය අකුරටම ඉටු කළා. හැමදාම වැව අසල ගෝණුන් ප්‍රතිරාව නැංවූ නිසා වැවට ගෝණපතිරාව වැව නමින් කටවහර පුරුදු වුණා."},{"question":"Question: Which of the following is not a natural resource?a. Soilb. Waterc. Electricityd. Air","answer":"Answer: (c)Electricity is not a natural resource. It is a manmade resource i.e., a form of energy that is not found in nature but can be produced artificially, by man. Whereas air, soil and water are all natural resources."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'ikan dalam keroncong'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sudah tertangkap atau terperangkap (tidak dapat ditolong lagi)"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'pilih kasih'? Berikan satu contoh ayat.","answer":"Simpulan bahasa ini bermaksud berat sebelah.Contoh ayat: Semasa membesarkan anak-anak, ayah tidak pernah mengamalkan sikap pilih kasih."},{"question":"नेपालमा मोमो खानेकुरा के हो ?","answer":"‘मस्ट खानै पर्ने’ नेपाली परिकार मोमो तिब्बतबाट आएको भनिन्छ जसलाई नेवारी व्यापारीहरूले नेपाल ल्याएका थिए। कुखुराको मासु, मटन, बफ ग्रेटेड पनीर, चीज वा तरकारी प्रयोग गरेर तयार। मोमोहरू मुख्यतया बाफमा पकाइन्छ भने, तिनीहरू पनि भुटेका हुन्छन्, झोल मोमोस भनिने सूपमा छोडिन्छन् वा चाटको रूपमा तयार हुन्छन्। यो सम्भवतः स्वदेशी र विदेशी पर्यटकहरूले रमाइलो र स्वाद लिने नेपालको सबैभन्दा लोकप्रिय फास्ट फूड डिश हो।"},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Manao tsinontsinona ireo mponina ao Texas ireo aho; mpamono olona avokoa izy ireo.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Eny, fanambarana maneho fankahalana ity fanambarana ity satria tsy ara-drariny no iantsoana ireo mponina ao Texas ho mpamono olona avokoa. "},{"question":"问：在科研行业中，什么是同行评议？","answer":"答：同行评议是一种由专家对研究成果进行质量评估的过程，以保证科研成果的质量和可靠性。"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന വാക്യം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക:  1981 മുതൽ അദ്ദേഹം തന്റെ പുസ്തകങ്ങളുടെ പകർപ്പവകാശ തുകയുടെ ഒരു പങ്ക് കൊൽക്കത്തയിലെ തെരുവുകളിൽ ജീവിക്കുന്ന കുട്ടികൾക്ക് സഹായമെത്തിക്കുന്ന സിറ്റി ഓഫ് ജോയ് ഫൗണ്ടേഷന് നൽകിപ്പോരുന്നു. ഫ്രാൻ‍സിൽ രജിസ്റ്റർ ചെയ്തിട്ടുള്ള ഈ സംഘടനയുടെ ഔദ്യോഗികനാമം Action pour les enfants des lépreux de Calcutta എന്നാണ്. \\"Five Past Midnight in Bhopal\\" എന്ന പുസ്തകത്തിന്റെ പകർപ്പവകാശത്തുക","answer":"ഭോപ്പാൽ ദുരന്തത്തിന് ഇരകളായവരുടെ ചികിത്സയ്ക്കായി ഭോപ്പാലിലെ സംഭാവനാ ക്ലിനിക്കിന് അദ്ദേഹം നൽകിവരുന്നു."},{"question":"ਸਮਾਜ-ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰ ਨੂੰ ਕੀ ਸਮਝਣ ਲਈ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਿਰਭਰ ਰਹਿਣਾ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਸਮਾਜ-ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰ ਨੂੰ ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਸਮਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਝਣ ਦੇ ਲਈ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਿਰਭਰ ਰਹਿਣਾ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Halako ireo mpiasan'ny teknolojia ireo; sahiran-tsaina izy rehetra.\\" Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay fanambarana?","answer":"Eny, kabary fankahalana ity fanambarana ity satria tsy mety ny fampifandraisana ireo mpiasa teknolojia rehetra amin'ny fahasahiranana ara-tsaina."},{"question":"வகைப்பாட்டியலின் தந்தைஎன  அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார்?","answer":"விடை :கார்ல் லின்னேயஸ்"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga :\\"Lehibe nangataka : ny miloa-bava mora ihany, fa _\\"","answer":"\\"Lehibe nangataka: ny miloa-bava mora ihany fa ny mamerin-tanana tsy mahazo no henatra.\\""},{"question":"බලු පැටියෙකු පුහුණු කිරීමට හොඳම ක්‍රමය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඔබ දැන් බලු පැටියෙකු හදා වඩා ගත්තා, සුභ පැතුම්! බලු පැටවුන් සාර්ථකව ගෙදර-දුම්රිය හෝ පෝට්ටි-දුම්රිය කිරීමට බොහෝ ක්රම තිබේ. පළමුව, පෝෂණය, විවේකය, සෙල්ලම් කිරීම සහ බඳුන් වේලාවන් සඳහා දැඩි කාලසටහනක් පවත්වා ගැනීම සඳහා ඉවසිලිවන්තව හා කඩිසරව සිටීම වැදගත් වේ. මෙය ඔබේ බලු පැටියා පැමිණි මොහොතේම ආරම්භ විය යුතුය, මෙය ඔවුන්ව සහ ඔබව සාර්ථකත්වය සඳහා සකසනු ඇත. දෙවනුව, පළමු සති කිහිපය තුළ හදිසි අනතුරු සිදු වන විට, ඔබේ බලු පැටියාට ඉවසිලිවන්තව හා කාරුණික වීමට මතක තබා ගන්න. මෙය නිවසේ අධිකාරී පුද්ගලයා ලෙස ඔබ කෙරෙහි ගැඹුරු විශ්වාසයක් වර්ධනය කරයි. සාමාන්‍යයෙන්, බලු පැටවුන් අවදියෙන්, ක්‍රීඩා කරන වේලාවෙන් සහ සෑම ආහාර වේලකටම පසු ආරක්ෂිත ප්‍රදේශයකට පිටතට යාමට ඉඩ දිය යුතුය. ක්‍රීඩා කරන වේලාව සමඟ බඳුන් කාලය පටලවා නොගැනීම වැදගත් වන අතර ඔබේ බලු පැටියා සමීපව නිරීක්ෂණය නොකරන්නේ නම් කූඩයක හෝ දොරටු සහිත ප්‍රදේශයක ආරක්ෂිතව තබා ඇත. ඔබේ බලු පැටියා බඳුනකට යා යුතු බව ඔබ දන්නේ කෙසේද? බොහෝ බලු පැටවුන් බඳුනකට යාමට අවශ්‍ය වූ විට බිම ආඝ්‍රාණය කිරීමට පටන් ගනී, එබැවින් මෙය ගෘහස්ථව සිදුවන බව ඔබ දුටුවහොත්, ඉක්මනින් ඔබේ බලු පැටියා එළිමහනට හෝ පුහුණු පෑඩ් වෙත ගෙන යන්න. හොඳින් කරන ලද කාර්යයක් සඳහා ඔබේ බලු පැටියාට බොහෝ පැසසුම් ලබා දීම වැදගත් වේ. සමහර බලු පැටවුන් සඳහා, කුඩා සංග්‍රහයක් ලබා දෙන අතරම ඔවුන්ගේ පවුලේ සාමාජිකයාගේ වාචික ප්‍රශංසාව ඔබේ බලු පැටියා සුදුසු ප්‍රදේශයට බඳුනකට යෑම ඔවුන්ට සහ ඔබට ඉතා හොඳ දෙයක් බවට සම්බන්ධ කර ගැනීමට උපකාරී වේ."},{"question":"ਸਵਾਲਃ ਕੰਪਿਊਟਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ਤਾਵਾਂ ਕੀ ਹਨ?","answer":"ਜਵਾਬਃ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿ ਅਸੀਂ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਕੰਪਿਊਟਰ ਇੱਕ ਬਹੁਤ ਲਾਭਦਾਇਕ ਮਸ਼ੀਨ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੀਆਂਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ਤਾਵਾਂ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਹਨ :ਰਫ਼ਤਾਰ ,ਸ਼ੁੱਧਤਾ ,ਇਕਾਗਰਤਾ ,ਬਹੁਗੁਣਤਾ ,ਆਟੋਮੇਸ਼ਨ ,ਭੰਡਾਰਨ ੧. ਰਫ਼ਤਾਰ -ਕੰਪਿਊਟਰ ਤੇਜ਼ ਰਫ਼ਤਾਰ ਨਾਲ਼ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। ਜਿਹੜੀਆਂ ਗਣਨਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਸੀ ਕਈ ਘੰਟੇ ਲਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਾਂ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਇਹ ਕੁਝ ਹੀ' ਸਕਿੰਟਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਮਾਂ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਜਾਣ ਕੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਹੈਰਾਨੀ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ ਕਿ ਇੱਕ ਕੰਪਿਊਟਰ ਇੱਕ ਸਕਿੰਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਈ ਲੱਖਾਂ ਹਿਦਾਇਤਾਂ ਤੇ ਅਮਲ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ।੨. ਸ਼ੁੱਧਤਾ - ਕੰਪਿਊਟਰ ਦੀ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੁੱਧਤਾ ਦਾ ਮਾਪ-ਦੰਡ ਬਹੁਤ ਉੱਚਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਇਹ ਹਰ ਗਣਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਮਾਪ-ਦੰਡ ਨਾਲ਼ ਹੀ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ੩. ਇਕਾਗਰਤਾ -ਕੰਪਿਊਟਰ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਥਕਾਵਟ, ਧਿਆਨ ਭਟਕਣਾ ਅਤੇ ਕੰਮ ਦਾ ਬੋਝ ਆਦਿ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ। ਇਹ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਕੋਈ ਗ਼ਲਤੀ ਕਿੱਤਿਆਂ ਘੰਟਿਆਂ ਬੱਧੀ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪. ਬਹੁਗੁਣਤਾ -ਇਸਦਾ ਭਾਵ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇੱਕੋ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਸਮਰੱਥਾ। ਜਦੋਂ ਅਸੀਂ ਕੰਪਿਊਟਰ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋ' ਗਣਨਾਵਾਂ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਾਂ, ਉਸੇ ਸਮੇਂ_ਹੀ ਅਸੀਂ ਕੰਪਿਊਟਰ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋ' ਵਸਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਰਿਕਾਰਡ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਅਤੇ ਖ਼ਰੀਦ-ਫਰੋਖ਼ਤ  ਦੇ ਬਿੱਲ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਵੀ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਨਾਲ਼ ਹੀ ਗਾਣੇ ਵੀ ਸੁਣ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਾਂ।੫. ਆਟੋਮੇਸ਼ਨ -ਜੇਕਰ ਇੱਕ ਵਾਰ ਕੰਪਿਊਟਰ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਹਿਦਾਇਤ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਜਾਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਦਖ਼ਲ-ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ੀ ਤੋ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਉਸ ਹਿਦਾਇਤ ਤੇ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਹਿਦਾਇਤ ਦੀ ਪੂਰਤੀ ਹੋਣ ਤੱਕ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ।ਜਦ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹਿਦਾਇਤ ਨੂੰ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕੋਈ ਲੌਜਿਕਲ (ਤਾਰਕਿਕ) ਹਿਦਾਇਤ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਉਕਤ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਕਰ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੬. ਭੰਡਾਰਨ -ਕੰਪਿਊਟਰ ਦੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਮੈਮਰੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਇਹ ਡਾਟਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਟੋਰ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਡਾਟਾ ਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਸੈਕੰਡਰੀ ਸਟੋਰੇਜ ਉਪਕਰਨ, ਜਿਵੇ ਕਿ ਸੀ.ਡੀ., ਡੀ.ਵੀ.ਡੀ., ਯੂ.ਐੱਸ.ਬੀ. ਅਤੇ ਪੈੱਨ ਡਰਾਈਵ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਨਾਲ਼ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਕੰਪਿਊਟਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਲਿਜਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Qual das alternativas menciona apenas símbolos nacionais?a) Bandeira insígnia da presidência, bandeira nacional, brasão, hinos e selob) Bandeira nacional, armas nacionais, hino nacional e selo nacionalc) Bandeira nacional, brasão, hino nacional e hino da independênciad) Bandeira nacional, cores nacionais, hino nacional e hino da independênciae) Bandeira insígnia da presidência, brasão flora e fauna e hinos","answer":"Alternativa b: Bandeira nacional, armas nacionais, hino nacional e selo nacional.Os Símbolos Nacionais são: a bandeira nacional, as armas nacionais ou brasão da república, o selo nacional e o hino nacional. Implementados pela Lei n° 5.700, de 1º de setembro de 1971, juntos, eles representam a união do nosso país."},{"question":"Su'aasha 2aad Hanka sare halkee ayuu ka soo burqadaa? ","answer":"Han ka sare (himmada sare) booskeedu iyo halka ay dagan tahay waa qalbiga, xubnaha kalena waxay fuliyaan wixii himmad ah oo qalbigaas kasoo fula, qofkuna himmadiisa wuxuu ku gaaraa oo ku helaa darajo uusan ficilkiisa ku gaarin.  Bal xadiiskan dhuux: - اَ   أن النبي  عن سهل بن حنيف    الشهه َ اللَّه َلَأَ س ْنَ قال : ( م ٍ ب َةَد َ قْ ص د ُ ب هَ لهغ (1909( اش ه  ) رواه مسلم َ ى ف ر َلَ ع َ ات َ م ْ إ ن َ اء  و َدَهُّ الش َ از ل َنَ م ُاللَّه((Qofkii Alle waydiista shahaado si dhab ahna wu weydiista, Alle waa gaarsiiyaa qofkaas darajada shuhadada, waloow gogoshiisaba haku naf baxee)).  Bal xadiiskanna aan dhuuxno, si ay inoo ku caddaato qiimaha ay leedahay inuu qofku han sare yeesho.  عن ابن عباس   عن رسول الله   :فيما يرويه عن ربه تبارك وتعالى قال  (إن الله كتب الحسنات والسيئات، ثم بين ذلك، فمن هم بحسنة فلم يعملها كتبها الله عنده حسنة كاملة..................... ) رواه البخاري و مسسلم . ((Alle wuxuu qoray xasanaadka iyo xumaanta, kadibna waa cadeeyay, qofkii ku hammiya khayr inuu sameeyo, goortaasna aan samyn, Alle wuxu u qoraa xasano dhamays tiran ) . Labadaan xadiis waxaynu ka faa'iidaysanaynaa arimahan soocodada: - - Qof walba hammigiisa meeshuu dhigo weeye, qofkii han sare leh, hankiisaasi wuxuu gaarsiinayaa, shay uusan ficilkiisu gaarsiin karin. - Qofka hankiisu sareeyo Alle wuxuu ka dalbadaa wax weyn, Allena wuu siiyaa qofkaas wuxuu ka dalbaday niyadiisa ayuuna ku siiyaa."},{"question":"يوم ترجف الراجفة.. شنو  المقصود بالراجفة؟","answer":"\\tالنفخة اللولى اللي كيموت فيها جميع الخلائق."},{"question":"Magaca Wadankii Ugu Danbeeyey Ee Xurnimo Qaata Qaarada Asia?","answer":" Wadanka Loo-Yaqaano East Timor, Wuxuuna Ka Go’ay Wadanka Indonesia."},{"question":"தேசிய அறிவியல் தினம் எப்போது கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது?","answer":"தேசிய அறிவியல் தினம் பிப்ரவரி 28தேசிய அறிவியல் நாள் (National Science Day) இந்தியாவில் பெப்ரவரி 28 ஆம் நாளில் ஆண்டு தோறும் கொண்டாடப்பட்டு வருகிறது.தேசத்தலைவர்கள் மற்றும் தியாகிகளைக் கொண்டாடுவது போல அறிவியல் மேதைகளும் போற்றப்பட வேண்டும் என்ற கருத்தின் அடிப்படையில் 1987 - ஆம் ஆண்டு இந்தத் தேசிய அறிவியல் நாள் இந்திய அரசால் அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டது.ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் ஒரு குறிக்கோளை அடிப்படையாக கொண்டு இந்நாள் கொண்டாடப்படுகிறது.[1] 2013-ம் ஆண்டிற்காக, \\"மரபணு மாற்றப்பட்ட பயிர்களும் உணவு பாதுகாப்பும்\\" (Genetically Modified Crops and Food Security) குறித்த கொள்கையை வலியுறுத்தப்படுகிறது.[2]வரலாறுஇந்த தினம் கொண்டாடப்படும் வரலாறு மற்றைய தினங்களைப் போல அல்லாமல் வழக்கத்துக்கு மாறானது ஆகும். பொதுவாக தேசத்தலைவர்களின் பிறந்த மற்றும் நினைவு நாட்களே சிறப்பு நாட்களாக அறிவிக்கப்படும். இந்த இரண்டு வகையிலும் அல்லாமல் இந்திய மண்ணில் பிறந்து உலகம் போற்றும் வகையில் பல அரிய கண்டுபிடிப்புகளை ஆராய்ந்து வெளியிட்டவரும் சிறந்த இயற்பியல் மேதையுமான சர். சி. வி ராமன் தன்னுடைய நோபல் பரிசு பெற்ற ஆராய்ச்சி முடிவை வெளியிட்ட பிப்ரவரி 28 ம் தேதி தேசிய அறிவியல் தினம் என அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது.[3]சர். சி. வி. இராமன் தனது புகழ்பெற்ற ராமன் விளைவை (Raman Effect) இந்நாளிலேயே கண்டுபிடித்தார். இந்தக் கண்டுபிடிப்பு உலகளாவிய பெருமையை இந்தியாவிற்குப் பெற்றுத் தந்ததுடன் உயரிய விருதான நோபல் பரிசும் (1930) இவருக்கு கிடைத்தது. அந்நிகழ்வின் நினைவாகவும் அறிவியல் என்பது அடித்தட்டு மக்களையும் சென்றடைய வேண்டும் என்ற நோக்கோடும் இந்திய அரசு இந்நாளைத் தேசிய அறிவியல் நாளாகப் பிரகடனப்படுத்தியது.நோக்கம்எந்த ஒரு நாகரீகத்திற்கும் அடிப்படையான அறிவியலின் சிறப்பை இளம் தலைமுறை மாணவர்களுக்கு கூறும் வகையிலும், நாட்டின் அனைத்து பகுதிகளிலும் பல புதிய அறிவியல் சிந்தனைகளைக் கண்டறிவதும்,. அதனை தகுந்த முறையில் பயன்பாட்டிற்கு கொண்டுவரவும், புதிய கண்டுபிடிப்புகளை வரவேற்பதுமே அறிவியல் அறிஞர்களுக்கு நாம் செலுத்தும் உண்மையான நன்றிக்கடன் என்பதை உணரச் செய்வதே இந்நாளின் நோக்கமாகும்."},{"question":"No contexto da biologia, explique o significado de Neurotransmissores.","answer":"Neurotransmissores são substâncias químicas liberadas pelos neurônios para transmitir sinais entre células nervosas. Eles desempenham um papel crucial na comunicação entre células nervosas no sistema nervoso, influenciando o humor, comportamento e funções corporais."},{"question":"වීසති වස්තුක සක්ඛාය දිට්ඨිය යනු කුමක්ද , සූතානුසාරයෙන් පෙන්වා දෙන්න","answer":"පංචස්කන්ධයෙන්...රූපය මමය, රූපය මගේය, තමා තුළ රූපය ඇත, රූපය තුළ තමා ඇත.. යන්නෙන් රූපය සම්බන්ධවසතරාකාර වේ.. ඒ ආකාරයෙන් වේදනා සංඥා සංස්කාර විඤ්ඤාණ පිළිබඳවත් වෙන වෙනම...ඒ ආකරයට ගත් විට (4*5) 20 ආකාර වේ.රහත් මඟින් ප්‍රාහණය වේ.... - නකුල පිතු සූත්‍රය -"},{"question":"Nitori Sunday Igboho, Oluwoo bẹ Buhari, o lo ti kẹkọọ pe Naijiria ko ṣe e pin","answer":"Oluwoo ti ilu Iwo, Ọba Abdulrosheed Adewale Akanbi, ti rawọ ẹbẹ si Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari lati sinmi lilepa Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ, ẹni ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho, kaakiri.Ninu lẹta kan ti Akọwe iroyin Oluwoo, Alli Ibraheem, kọ ranṣẹ si Buhari lorukọ Kabiesi ni Oluwoo ti sọ pe ọmọde ki i mọ ẹkọ ọ jẹ ko ma ra a lọwọ ni ọrọ wahala ti Igboho ko ara rẹ si yii.O ni ọpọlọpọ ori-ade lo gba a nimọran nigba to bẹrẹ ijijagbara rẹ pe dandan ni ki Orileede Oodua da duro, ṣugbọn to kọ eti ikun si imọran awọn agba.Oluwoo ṣalaye pe pẹlu bi gbogbo nnkan ṣe waa da bayii, Sunday Igboho ti kẹkọọ pe Naijiria ko ṣee pin si wẹwẹ lasiko ti a wa yii, ati pe ko sẹni to le doju ija kọ ijọba.Kabiesi sọ siwaju pe “Gẹgẹ bii Musulumi, gbogbo wa la mọ pe ọjọ idariji ni ọjọ Jimọh jẹ, idi niyi ti mo fi n bẹ Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari lati fori jin Sunday Adeyẹmọ.“A kilọ fun un to. Ẹni to ba mọ itan wahala to mu ẹmi awọn eeyan bii Moshood Kaṣimawo Ọlawale Abiọla ati Kensaro Wiwa lọ yoo mọ pe ninu iṣọkan ni agbara wa wa.“Sunday Adeyemo di gbajugbaja nipasẹ jija fun awọn ti wọn ba fọwọ ọla gba loju lawujọ, mo si maa n ba a sọrọ nigbakuugba ti mo ba gbọ ohunkohun nipa rẹ. O wa si aafin mi lọdun 2018, mo si gba a nimọran, ṣugbọn ko mọ iyatọ laarin didoju ija kọ ijọba ati jija fun ẹya ẹni.“O to asiko kan to bẹrẹ si i bu gbogbo eeyan, mo wa lara awọn to kọkọ fẹsun kan nitori ipolongo ki orileede yii wa lọkan ti mo n ṣe. Gẹgẹ bii baba, mo ti dariji i, mo wa n bẹ Aarẹ Buhari pe ko foriji ọmọ wa ologo yii.“Ope ni ninu nnkan to jẹ mọ tijọba. Ẹbun pataki lo jẹ fun iran Yoruba. O ti ṣeleri lati feti si imọran wa. Mo bẹ Aarẹ lati paṣẹ fun awọn agbofinro lati tuukanna lẹyin ọrun rẹ. Mo gbagbọ pe ṣiṣe bẹẹ yoo tun mu ki iṣọkan Naijiria tẹsiwaju. Mo ṣeleri lati mu Igboho wa fun ipade alaafia nitori oju rẹ ti ri to, yoo si maa kiyesi ihuwasi rẹ latoni lọ.”Oluwoo wa gboṣuba fun Buhari lori ọna to n gba lati gbogun ti iwa igbesunmọmi ati awọn iwa janduku lorileede yii pẹlu bo ṣe n mu idagbasoke ba gbogbo ẹkajẹka."},{"question":"Sheeg qaaradaha loo yaqaano Adduunka Gaboobay ama Duqoobay?","answer":"Qaarada Adunka gaboobay loo yaqaano waa:1- Qaaradda Africa.2- Qaaradda Asia.3- Qaaradda Yurub."},{"question":"Pada pendapat anda, jelaskan ciri pemimpin yang mampumelonjakkan kecemerlangan negara ke persada dunia","answer":"Jawapan:F1 Pemimpin yang mempunyai wawasan yang jelasH1 Mampu berfikir dalam pelbagai pendekatan bagi mencari alternatifH2 Oleh itu, mampu menyelesaikan setiap permasalahan dengan berkesanC Contohnya, pemimpin yang mempunyai cita-cita untuk memajukan negaraInf Pemimpin yang berwawasan akan sentiasa memastikan cara terbaik untuk mencapai apa yang diingini.F2 Pemimpin yang bertanggungjawabH1 Tahu tanggungjawab yang perlu dilaksanakan demi kesejahteraan rakyatC Contohnya, mengutamakan kebajikan rakyatH2 Oleh itu, rakyat dapat hidup dengan aman dan sejahteraInf Pemimpin mempunyai tanggungjawab yang besar untuk memastikan kemakmuran negara."},{"question":"Onde foram produzidas as primeiras animações de computador?","answer":"Laboratório Rutherford Appleton"},{"question":"අලගු තැබීම යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ලොකු ද්‍රවය ගොඩක් එකින් එක ගනන් කරනකොට ගනන් වරදිනවට පැත්තකින් තියන අගය. උදාහරණයක් විදියට ලොකු පොල් ගොඩක් ගනන් කරන කොට ගෙඩි 100ක් ගනන් කරලා එක පොලයක් පැත්තකින් තියනවා. ඒවා තමයි අලගු තියපු ගොඩ. අන්තිමට ඒ ගොඩේ ගෙඩි ගනන 100න් ගුණ කරලා  ඔක්කොම ගෙඩි ගාන සොයාගන්න පුලුවන්."},{"question":"Viết biểu thức đại số biểu thị:a) Tích của tổng x và y với hiệu của x và y;b) Ba phẩy mười bốn nhân với bình phương của r.","answer":"Lời giải:a) Biểu thị đại số biểu thị tổng x và y là: x + y.Biểu thị đại số biểu thị hiệu của x và y là: x - y.Biểu thức đại số biểu thị tích của tổng x và y với hiệu của x và y là: (x + y)(x - y).b) Biểu thức đại số biểu thị ba phẩy mười bốn nhân với bình phương của r là: 3,14r2."},{"question":"Qual é a flor nacional do Japão?","answer":"Crisântemo"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నకు జవాబు ఇవ్వండి:  ఇప్పుడు పాకిస్థాన్‌లో ఏ సింధు నాగరికత ఉంది?","answer":"హరప్పన్"},{"question":"Đưa ra một tiêu đề cho đoạn văn bản sau: Hoạt động kinh doanh tại khu vực đồng euro đang giảm nhanh do nhu cầu yếu đi đáng kể, làm tăng xác suất suy thoái tại đây.Hôm 6/11, chỉ số nhà quản trị mua hàng (PMI) tháng 10 của eurozone do S&P Global công bố chỉ đạt 46,5 điểm. Số liệu này thấp hơn rất nhiều so với 47,2 của tháng 9 và cũng là thấp nhất kể từ tháng 11/2020, khi các lệnh phong tỏa vì Covid-19 siết chặt kinh tế khu vực này.PMI dưới 50 cho thấy hoạt động sản xuất co lại. Đây là tháng thứ 5 liên tiếp PMI của eurozone dưới 50.Tuần trước, số liệu chính thức cũng cho thấy GDP khu vực này giảm 0,1% trong quý III. Eurozone đang bước vào quý cuối năm với triển vọng không mấy khả quan. GDP khu vực này đã giảm 3 trong 4 quý gần nhất.\\"PMI công bố hôm nay khẳng định các số liệu sơ bộ là đúng, khớp với dự báo của chúng tôi rằng GDP eurozone sẽ tiếp tục co lại trong quý IV. Triển vọng có vẻ rất yếu. Số đơn hàng mới đang xuống thấp nhất kể từ tháng 9/2012, nếu không tính các tháng đầu đại dịch. Xuất khẩu cũng đặc biệt yếu\\", Adrian Prettejohn tại Capital Economics cho biết.","answer":"Nỗi lo suy thoái tại eurozone ngày càng lớn"},{"question":"-حيوان يضرب به في الروى فيقال أروى من …؟","answer":"-ضب"},{"question":"অনুগ্রহ করে নিম্নলিখিত বাক্যাংশটি সম্পূর্ণ করুন :১৯১৫ সালে রুশ ককেসাস সেনাবাহিনী পূর্ব আনাতোলিয়ায় অগ্রসর অব্যাহত রাখে। উসমানীয় সরকার স্থানীয় জাতিগত আর্মেনীয়দের স্থানান্তর শুরু করে। ফলশ্রুতিতে প্রায় ১.৫ মিলিয়নের মত আর্মেনীয় মৃত্যুবরণ করেছিল যা","answer":"আর্মেনীয় গণহত্যা বলে পরিচিত। এছাড়াও গ্রিক ও এসিরিয়ান সংখ্যালঘুদের বিরুদ্ধেও বড় আকারের হত্যাকান্ডের ঘটনা ঘটেছে।"},{"question":"Iya Gebu gbe ọmọ ọsẹ mẹta silẹ fọkọ ẹ, lo ba sa lọ l’Aparadija","answer":"Gabriel Ayọmide Ojo ni baba rẹ sọ ọ nigba ti wọn bi i lọdun mẹrin sẹyin, iyẹn ọmọkunrin kekere ti ẹ n wo aworan rẹ yii. Ṣugbọn Gebu lawọn eeyan n pe e laduugbo wọn l’Aparadija.O gbajumọ bii iṣana ẹlẹẹta, nitori ohun meji kọ, nitori pe ọsẹ mẹta pere lo wa ti iya rẹ ti gbe e silẹ fun baba ẹ, to sa lọ bamubamu.Kọlawọle Ojo ni baba rẹ n jẹ, Ruth lorukọ iya to bi i. Alaye ti baba ti ẹ n wo yii ṣe f’ALAROYE ni pe Iya to bi Ruth lo waa mu un kuro nile oun nigba ti ọmọ to bi foun ṣẹṣẹ pe ọmọ ọsẹ mẹta pere.O loun lọọ wa ohun ti iyawo oun yoo jẹ lọjọ naa ni, koun too de loun ko ba a nile mọ pẹlu iya rẹ to waa wo o koun too jade nile. O ni Gebu ti wọn faṣọ we lori bẹẹdi nikan loun ba nibẹ, loun ba bẹrẹ si i wa iyawo oun ati iya rẹ kiri.Baba Gebu sọ pe, ‘‘Mo wa wọn dele wọn, mi o ba wọn, wọn ti sa lọ. Mo daamu titi, mi o gburoo wọn mọ titi doni, emi ni mo n da tọju ọmọ yii, nitori mi o niyaa ati baba mọ. Ọdọ ẹgbọn mi ti mi o ba dẹ tun mu un lọ ko ṣee ṣe, nitori ile tiwọn naa ti kun’’Akọroyin wa beere idi ẹ ti iya iyawo yoo fi waa mu ọmọ rẹ nile ọkọ, ti wọn si yọnda ọmọ ikoko bẹẹ fun baba rẹ lai wẹyin wo o mọ. Ohun to fi da wa lohun ni pe‘‘Iya ẹ ko fẹ ko fẹ mi latilẹ. Iṣẹ awọn to n gbẹ sọkawee, gọta, fandeṣan ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ ni mo n ṣe. Iya iyawo mi loun ko nifẹẹ si iṣẹ naa nitori mi o le ri ṣe nibẹ, oun ko si le fọmọ fẹni ti ko ni nnkan kan.‘‘Ọmọ ẹ ti lọkọ kan tẹlẹ ko too fẹmi, Hausa lọkunrin yẹn, iyawo mi bimọ kan fun un, ọmọkunrin lo bi fun Hausa yẹn naa. Iya ẹ naa lo lọọ mu un kuro nibẹ, ṣugbọn wọn ko fọmọ silẹ fun Mọla, wọn gbe ọmọ wọn lọ. Ọmọ temi ni wọn fi silẹ ti wọn kuro laduugbo fun mi.‘‘Ọmọ yii maa pe ọdun mẹrin nipari ọdun yii, ko lọ sileewe, nitori mi o rowo ran an lọ. Lẹsinni ti wọn ti n san fifti Naira lojumọ ni mo n mu un lọ tẹlẹ, nigba ti Koro dẹ ti de lawọn iyẹn ti kogba wọle, ko lọ sibi kankan mọ bayii.‘‘Ko rọ mi lọrun lati maa tọju ẹ, nitori mi o ki i riṣẹ ṣe deede. Bi mo fẹẹ lọọ tọ lasan, a jọ n lọ ni, nigba ti ko sẹni ti mo fẹẹ fi i silẹ fun. Bi mo ṣe n lọọ gbẹ koto kiri naa ni mo n mu un lọ.‘‘Mo n bẹ awọn ọmọ Naijiria ki wọn ṣaanu mi lati tọju ọmọ yii. Awọn eeyan ti ju taya si mi lọrun ri ni Sango, wọn ni mo ji i gbe ni, abi bawo ni mo ṣe n gbe ọmọ kekere bẹẹ kiri lai si iya rẹ nibẹ.‘‘Mo n fẹ iranlọwọ lati le mu un lọ sileewe, to ba n wa nibẹ, emi naa aa raaye ṣe daadaa. Mi o lowo lọwọ ti mo le fi fẹyawo mi-in to le ba mi tọju ẹ, atijẹ-atimu gan-an nira fun mi. Kawọn eeyan jọwọ, ran mi lọwọ, kọmọ mi kawe bi emi o tiẹ ka’’ALAROYE ba Gebu naa sọrọ, ọmọ to kẹtan naa gbo lohun bii ọjẹ, ọrọ da lẹnu rẹ ṣaka, bo tilẹ jẹ pe ai ri itọju jẹ ko kere pupọ si ọjọ ori rẹ, niṣe lo da bii ọmọ ọdun meji pere. A beere pe nibo niya rẹ wa, o ni iya oun ti lọ. Gbogbo bawọn eeyan ṣe n kọja lọ lọmọ yii n ki wọn, bẹẹ lawọn iyẹn naa n sa a, ti wọn ki i bii pe agbalagba ẹgbẹ wọn ni.Nigba ta a beere pe ṣe ki i ṣe ai ri itọju to naa lo sọ ẹsẹ rẹ di kẹrẹbutu bẹẹ, obinrin kan to n ṣe bii iya fun un (Ọmọ yii maa n duro lọdọ rẹ nigba mi-in ti baba rẹ ba wa jijẹ mimu lọ), lo dahun pe aanu Ọlọrun gan-an lo jẹ ko dide rin. O ni Gebu ko rin titi to fi pe ọmọ ọdun mẹta, nigba to si jaja dide ti ẹsẹ rẹ ṣe kẹrẹbutu, ẹru n dupẹ lawọn fi ọrọ naa ṣe, ko kuku sowo ti wọn yoo fi lọọ ba a tun ẹsẹ ṣe lọsibitu, ọmọ to jẹ bo ṣe ti dagba to yii, wọn ko ti i dako rẹ, atọtọ lo n gbe kiri titi dọla.Koda, baba rẹ ko ni i foonu ni ka wi gẹgẹ bi obinrin naa ṣe wi (Baba Gebu funra ẹ naa si sọ bẹẹ), nitori batiri ko jẹ ki foonu to n lo gbadun. Ọpọ igba ti akọroyin wa n pe e ko too lọ sile rẹ ni foonu naa ki i wọle, ti obinrin to n ba a gba Gebu sọdọ la bẹrẹ si i pe ko too di pe a dele wọn.Bi ẹnikẹni ba fẹẹ ṣaanu Gebu lati lọ sileewe, tabi to fẹẹ ran baba rẹ lọwọ lati maa rọwọ mu lọ sẹnu, ko si tun le maa tọju ọmọ naa si i, eyi ni nọmba asunwọn ti tọhun le fowo si: 0169538111, Oluwarotimi Ọladele Ọlatokunbọ , GT Bank.Eni to ba si fẹẹ pe e lati ridi ododo le pe sori nọmba rẹ yii 09098380761 tabi 08032054735."},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, awọn oṣiṣẹ Sifu Difẹnsi meji ku sinu ijamba ọkọ l’Ondo","answer":"Meji ninu awọn oṣiṣẹ ajọ Sifu Difẹnsi ẹka tipinlẹ Ondo, ni wọn ku, ti ẹni kan si tun fara pa ninu ijamba ọkọ kan to waye lalẹ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọgbọnjọ oṣu yii.Awakọ bọọsi elero meje to gbe awọn ẹsọ alaabo ọhun ni wọn lo padanu ijanu ọkọ rẹ loju ọna marosẹ Ọrẹ si Ondo lasiko ti wọn n bọ lati ibi ariya isinku kan ti wọn lọọ ṣe l’Okitipupa.Wọn ní bi ọkọ bọọsi naa ti wọgbo mọ awakọ yii lọwọ lo ti takiti wọ inu koto nla kan to wa lẹgbẹẹ ọna, leyii to ṣokunfa iku meji ninu awọn eeyaan ọhun loju ẹsẹ, ti ẹni kan ninu wọn si tun farapa yannayanna.Wọn ti gbe ẹni to ṣeṣe ninu wọn lọ sileewosan ẹkọṣẹ iṣegun to wa niluu Ondo, nibi to ti n gba itọju lasiko ta a fi n ko iroyin yii jọ.Alukoro ajọ naa nipinlẹ Ondo, Olufẹmi Ọmọle, fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ fun akọroyin wa, o ni ọga agba patapata fun ajọ ọhun nipinlẹ Ondo, Ọgbẹni Okoro Eweka, naa ti ba ẹbi awọn to ku ọhun kẹdun."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Những rạp chiếu phim trong mơ","answer":"\\"Rạp chiếu phim\\" dã chiến, chắp cánh ước mơ con trẻ Anh Hồ Hoàng Liêm (33 tuổi) là một người con của Đà Nẵng. Suốt 13 năm liền anh lấy sức trẻ của mình để đem đến ánh đèn, bộ phim hoạt hình hay đơn giản là những món đồ chơi con trẻ... đến với những ngọn núi cao, nơi mà những đoàn từ thiện \\"ngại\\" lui tới. Kể về những rạp chiếu phim trên vùng cao, anh Liêm hồ hởi: \\"Trong một lần chúng tôi lắp điện mặt trời miễn phí cho bà con tại vùng núi Nam Trà My của tỉnh Quảng Nam, các em nhỏ ở đây đã tròn xoe mắt nhìn vào những tòa nhà cao tầng, những chiếc xe máy trong điện thoại của tôi một cách ngạc nhiên. Có em còn hỏi đó là cái gì?\\". Sự ngây ngô, đôi mắt hồn nhiên háo hức về một thành thị xa hoa tấp nập trong chiếc điện thoại của anh Liêm như một thế giới cổ tích mà các em nhỏ vùng cao ao ước được một lần nhìn thấy. Chính những câu hỏi ngây thơ đầy hi vọng của bọn trẻ đã gợi lên trong lòng anh Liêm miền ký ức lúc anh còn thơ dại. Anh Liêm tâm sự: \\"Ngày còn nhỏ, tôi mê hoạt hình lắm. Tom&Jerry, Vịt Donal... hay những bộ phim cổ tích về lòng nhân hậu, về chàng hoàng tử và công chúa... nhưng vì lúc đó gia đình nghèo quá nên thường phải xem trộm tivi nhà hàng xóm. Bây giờ thấy các em tôi như thấy mình của những ngày trước, vì vậy ngày trước tôi thích gì tôi sẽ cho các em thứ đó\\". Và cũng chính từ lúc đó, anh Liêm đã khởi lên một ý niệm sẽ mang phim hoạt hình từ vùng đồng bằng đến với những \\"mầm non\\" ở vùng núi cao. Giây phút các em nhỏ ở trường Dân tộc bán trú Vừ A Dính ở xã Trà Dơn, huyện Nam Trà My, tỉnh Quảng Nam nhìn thấy màn hình chiếu 120 inch bừng sáng với những bộ phim hoạt hình là lần đầu tiên anh Liêm thấy mình hạnh phúc đến vậy. Xã Trà Dơn là vùng núi cao, còn nghèo khó có nơi còn chưa có điện. Khi nhìn thấy những bộ phim hoạt hình chuyển động trên màn hình, cả điểm trường lặng yên lắng nghe từng âm thanh đang vang vọng núi đồi. Tại vùng núi làng Canh Tiến, xã Canh Liên, Quy Nhơn, Bình Định, anh Liêm cho biết: \\"Đây là vùng núi nghèo của tỉnh Bình Định, có nơi còn chưa có điện. Khi tôi kể câu chuyện này cho mọi người, không một ai tin rằng tại tỉnh Bình Định lại có nơi chưa có điện. Các thầy cô giáo đang công tác tại đây cho biết 13 năm rồi chưa có một đoàn từ thiện nào ghé thăm vì ngại đường xa, cách trở\\". Chính vì vậy, khi đoàn thiện nguyện của anh Liêm vận chuyển các thiết bị của rạp chiếu phim lên đến đây, các thầy cô đã mừng rỡ không ngừng. Tuy nhiên, để có điện phát máy chiếu, các thành viên trong đội từ thiện phải băng rừng 19 tiếng đồng hồ mới đến được với vùng núi này. Khi ánh đèn bừng lên, cả một làng Canh Tiến túm tụm nhìn ngắm ánh đèn với ánh mắt say sưa vui mừng. \\"Chúng tôi lớn lên với những quà từ thiện\\" Anh Liêm sinh ra và lớn lên khi Đà Nẵng còn là một vùng quê nghèo. Từ nhỏ anh đã phải trải qua thời gian cơ cực cùng gia đình. Chính vì vậy, ngay khi còn ngồi trên ghế giảng đường đại học anh Liêm đã mủi lòng trước những mảnh đời bất hạnh mà anh gặp phải. \\"Chúng tôi lớn lên với những phần quà từ thiện, những ngày xếp hàng nhận quà từ các mạnh thường quân tôi đã tự nhủ với lòng sau này khi lớn lên sẽ là người phát quà cho mọi người. Chính ý nghĩ đó, đã thúc đẩy tôi thực hiện các chuyến tình nguyện đến vùng sâu vùng xa, giúp đỡ những gia đình giống tôi ngày còn nhỏ\\", anh Liêm kể. Từ năm 2009, anh Liêm cùng các bạn học của mình cùng nhau lập nên nhóm thiện nguyện Nụ Cười Hồng với mong muốn góp một phần sức trẻ đến với những hoàn cảnh khó khăn. Hằng ngày, ngoài giờ học, anh và mọi người thường tổ chức các buổi nhạc đường phố vừa bán kẹo vừa hát để mọi người vừa thương thức vừa ủng hộ cho nhóm bằng việc mua kẹo. Toàn bộ số tiền thu được, nhóm đều dành để mua mỳ tôm, bánh kẹo... và hỗ trợ tiền hàng tháng cho cụ già neo đơn, trẻ em mồ côi. Dần dần khi đã ra trường đi làm, anh nghĩ đến những việc lớn hơn như lắp hệ thống điện mặt trời cho người dân vùng núi, nấu bữa cơm có thịt cho trẻ em tại các điểm trường vùng cao. Ngoài ra, vào mùa đông nhóm của anh Liêm còn thực hiện dự án trao 2.000 áo ấm cho người dân vùng biên giới. Không những vậy, câu lạc bộ của anh Liêm cũng lắp đặt những trạm pin mặt trời ở 16 điểm khác, thắp sáng cho nhiều điểm trường và thôn bản ở Quảng Nam, Quảng Trị, Kom Tum, Gia Lai, Quy Nhơn... Cô Trà Thị Thu - giáo viên điểm trường Tắk Pổ, huyện Nam Trà My, tỉnh Quảng Nam không khỏi xúc động cho biết từ ngày có bộ thiết bị máy chiếu mà nhóm anh Liêm bàn giao, việc soạn giáo án của các thầy cô cũng dễ dàng và sinh động hơn. Những ngày trước, các thầy cô phải lặn lội đến từng nhà để vận động các em nhỏ đến trường nhưng từ ngày có máy chiếu, các em nhỏ tự động đến trường để mỗi cuối tuần được xem phim hoạt hình hay cổ tích từ rạp chiếu phim của anh Liêm. Cho đến nay, anh Liêm đã mang được 3 \\"rạp chiếu phim\\" đến 2 điểm trường của vùng núi Nam Trà My, tỉnh Quảng Nam và tỉnh Bình Định cho trẻ em vùng cao. Hiện anh đang lên kế hoạch cho 2 \\"rạp chiếu phim\\" tại tỉnh Hà Giang và Gia Lai trong tháng 8, 9 sắp tới."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو أكثر فريق فوزًا في دوري أبطال أوروبا؟","answer":"الإجابة: ريال مدريد "},{"question":"RAG MAXAA LAGU RAACAA?","answer":"RAG MAXAA LAGU RAACAA?Ragga iyo dumarku way ku kala duwan yihiin marka laga eego sifooyinka la'isku doorto xilliga guurka. Rasuulkeennu (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) waa kii yiri : (Naag waxa loo guursadaa maalkeeda, quruxdeeda, sharafteeda iyo diinteeda), taasi oo ina tusaysa in maalka iyo quruxdu ay 50% ka yihiin sababaha dumarka loo guursado, ha yeeshee kolkay arrintu joogto ninka isagu doonaya inuu guursado, qimeyntiisu taa ka duwan.Diinteenna Islaamku waxa ay xaddidday laba shardi oo haddii ninka lagahelo ay tahay in markaa inanta uu soodoontay loo guuriyo, labadaasi shardi oo kala ah; Din iyo Dabeecad. Rasuulka suubbani (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) waxa uu xadiis ku leeyahay: (Hadduu idin yimaado nimaad diintiisa iyo dabeecaddiisa u bogtaan u guuriya, haddii kale xumaan iyo dhibaato weyn baa dhulka ka dhacaysa). Xadiiska waxaad ka garan kartaa in dabeecadda qofku aanay ku xirnayn diintiisa, maxaa yeelay si kasta oo qofku uu diinta u yaqaan, haddana dabeecad wanaagga, degganaanta iyo qabowga iyo waa loo kala dhashaa dabeecad xumida, xanaaq dhowaanta iyo kulaylka joogtada ah.Rasuulku (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) kuma aanu soo hadal qaadin xadiiskiisa qurux iyo maal looga baahan yahay ragga guurdoonka ah toona.Haddaba sababtu waxa weeyaan, aynu ku horreeyno quruxda eh, ninka raggaah waxaa qurux ugu filan ragannimadiisa, oo kol hadduu waxgarad yahay, geesi yahay, caqli iyo kartina leeyahay, waxay ila tahay qurux ay dumar ku raacaan00 u harsani ma jirto. Dhanka kale, marka diinta Islaamka laga hadlayo, maalkukamid ma aha shuruudaha guurdoonka lagu xiray. Ninkii din (aqoon iyo kudhagan) iyo dabeecad wanaag isku darsada, Eebbe asagaa xagga maalka ka kafaalad qaaday. Waxana taasi marqaati ka ah Aayadda oranaysa: (Haddaysabool yihiin eebbe asagaa deeqdiisa ku hodminaya)."},{"question":"Asian Games 2023 October 3 Live Updates: Medal Rush! Parul Chaudhary Wins 5000m Gold, 1 Silver, and 2 Bronze in Athletics","answer":"Asian Games 2023, October 3 Live Updates: It's a medal rush. Parul Chaudhary has clinched India's 14th gold medal at the Asian Games 2023. The Indian charge in athletics is on at the Asian Games 2023. Vithya Ramraj has won a bronze in the women's 400-meter hurdles. Earlier, India was assured of three medals in squash: Saurav Ghosal (men's singles), Dipika Pallikal/Harinder Pal Singh (mixed doubles), and Abhay Singh/Anahat Singh (mixed doubles). India's move towards 100 medals at the Asian Games 2023 started with some solid showings by archers and boxers on Tuesday. In boxing, Olympic medalist Lovlina Borgohain assured India at least a silver medal by entering the women's 75kg final, while Preeti bowed out with a bronze medal in the women's 54kg. Indian archers were the stars of the day, securing at least three medals in compound events. Ojas Pravin and Abhishek Verma set up an all-Indian final in the men's compound individual event. This will be India's first-ever individual gold medal in archery at the Asian Games. Jyoti Surekha Vennam is in the final of the women's compound individual archery event. India earned its first medal of the day through canoeing, where Arjun Singh and Sunil Singh Salam finished third in the men's canoe double 1000m event."},{"question":"ஆற்றங்கரை படிவு என்றால் என்ன? அவற்றின் பயன்கள் யாவை?","answer":"• தமிழ்நாட்டில் மழைக்காலங்களில் பெறும் நீரைச் சேமித்து வைக்கும் நீர் மேலாண்மை அமைப்புகள் இருந்தன.• வெள்ளச் சமவெளி என்பது ஆற்றின் நீரோட்ட வழியில் இயற்கை உருவாக்கிய காப்பரண். ஆற்றில் வெள்ளம் கரைபுரண்டு வரும் காலங்களில் அடித்து வரப்படும் பொருள்கள் ஆற்றின் ஓரங்களில் படிந்துவிடும்.• இது ஆற்றங்கரைப்படிவு எனப்படும். இதில் படிகின்ற பொருள்களால் ஆற்றுச் சமவெளியில் அடர்த்தியான மணலாலும் மற்றும் சேற்றினாலும் அடுக்குப் படிவம் உருவாகும்.• அப்படிவம் வெள்ளப் பெருக்குக் காலங்களில் நீரை உறிஞ்சுவதால் வெள்ளப்பெருக்கு ஏற்படுவது குறையும், நீர் மாசடைவதைத் தடுக்கும், மண் அரிப்பைத் தடுக்கும், வறட்சிக் காலங்களில் நீர்மட்டம் குறைந்துவிடாமல் பாதுகாக்கும். உபரிநீர்க் கால்வாய்களும் வெள்ளக்காலங்களில் உதவியாக இருக்கும்."},{"question":"Kalau seorang, dia sendiri tahu. Bila berdua pula, dua-dua mesti tahu. Tapi kalau bertiga, tiada yang tahu kecuali orang yang buat. Kalau berempat pula, lagilah tak tahu. Apa dia tu?","answer":"Kentut"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga:\\"Ratsy vintana toy ny saka,_\\"","answer":"\\"Ratsy vintana toy ny saka,ka be vohoka vao ato hoe mamosavy\\""},{"question":"අක්කරයට රූඩ් කීයද","answer":"අක්කරයට රූඩ් 4"},{"question":"Qual o significado de \\"Dar uma de João sem braço?\\"","answer":"Significa fingir-se desentendido."},{"question":"2月14日に10作品が発売された、『ドンキーコング』『ゼビウス』など懐かしいソフトを、ゲームボーイアドバンスで復刻していくゲームシリーズは何でしょう？","answer":"ファミコンミニです。"},{"question":"කොන්ෆියුසියස් කවුද?","answer":"කොන්ෆියුසියස් යනු පුරාණ චීන ගුරුවරයෙකු, දාර්ශනිකයෙකු සහ දේශපාලන න්‍යායාචාර්යවරයෙකු වූ අතර, ඔහුගේ අදහස් චීන, කොරියානු, ජපන් සහ වියට්නාම චින්තනයට සහ ජීවිතයට ගැඹුරින් බලපා ඇත."},{"question":"Sheeg immisa magac ayuu leeyahay Qur’aanka?.","answer":"Wuxuu leeyahay  ilaa 15 magac. Waxayna Kala Yihiin1. Qur’aan,2. Furqaan,3. Tansiil,4. Dikri,5. Kitab,6. Nuur,7. Hudaa,8. Hanuun,9. Raxma,10. Shifaa,11. Mowcida,12. Caziiz,13. Mubaarak,14. Bashiir,15. Nadiir."},{"question":"O que caracteriza o signo chinês de Dragão?","answer":"Com uma personalidade forte, é uma pessoa sonhadora e medrosa. Encantadora, inteligente e resistente. Ora é esforçada demais, ora preguiçosa. Gosta de brigar e o orgulho a faz sentir dificuldades para voltar atrás e assumir erros e derrotas. É romântica e fiel. É forte, rude e gosta de estar no topo."},{"question":"Generate a headline for the following text: nRais Samia Suluhu anakabiliwa na kibarua kigumu cha kuinua hali ya uchumi iliyodorora huku kilio miongoni mwa wananchi, wadau na wanasiasa ndani na nje ya Bunge,chama na serikali kikiwa kunyauka kwa sekta binafsi yenye mchango mkubwa katika maendeleo ya Tanzania. Toka aingie madarakani mwezi Machi mwaka huu Rais Samia amekuwa akikemea watendaji pamoja na utaratibu wa ukusanyaji wa mapato kwa njia ya vikosi maalumu,matumizi ya nguvu dhidi ya wafanyabiashara na kile anachokiita utumwa wa kisheria ambao umekuwa kiini cha kuharibu biashara, uwekeza,pamoja na kudorora kwa shughuli za uchumi na ajira kwa ujumla. Wataalamu wa biashara na uchumi wanakubaliana kuwa kilio cha wananchi wa taifa hilo kipo katika kodi, tozo kubwa, vikwazo vya mamlaka za biashara kuchangia mazingira mabaya  ya uendeshaji, miradi ya muda mrefu, zabuni kupewa kampuni nyingi za nje, kampuni za ndani kutengwa katika zabuni na taasisi za serikali kuchukua fursa za miradi za sekta binafsi, wingi wa taasisi zenye dhamana ya kutoa leseni na kusimamia biashara, mzigo wa madeni ya serikali kwa wakandarasi wa ndani ni baadhi ya sababu ya kusinyaa hali ya uchumi. Ni katika kipindi cha miaka mitano iliyopita mdororo umezikabili sekta za benki, hoteli, habari, kilimo, masoko, kupomoroka biashara za nje, kampuni kupunguza wafanyakazi kutokana na hali mbaya ya uchumi, huku baadhi zikiendeleza zoezi hilo na kuzalisha tatizo la ajira nchini humo na kuifanya serikali ya Samia kukabiliwa na mtihani mkubwa kutatua changamoto tajwa. Mei 22 mwaka huu Waziri wa Viwanda na biashara, Profesa Kitila Mkumbo wakati akiomba wabunge kupitisha bajeti ya wizara yake 2021/2022, alilieleza Bunge la nchi hiyo kuwa mauzo bidhaa za Tanzania katika soko la India yalipungua kutoka dola za Marekani milioni 867.70 mwaka 2019 hadi dola za Marekani milioni 528.60 mwaka 2020 sawa na upungufu wa asilimia 39.1. Pia alieleza kupungua mauzo ya nje ya bidhaa za kahawa,maua,alizeti,madini na ufuta. Vilevile alieleza kuwa mauzo ya bidhaa katika soko la Japan nayo yalipungua kwa kiasi cha dola za Marekani 1,258.40 mwaka 2019 hadi dola milioni 1,089.50 mwaka 2020, ikiwa ni ishara ya kutetereka uchumi wa nchi hiyo, huku serikali ikifanya jitihada kupata mkopo Shirika la Fedha Duniani ambalo limeafiki na kutoa sharti kuwa lazima takwimu za ugonjwa virusi vya corona ziwekwe wazi. Kwa kipindi cha miaka mitano takribani Benki 15 zilifunga shughuli zake na kuwa pigo kwa sekta binafsi,biashara na uchumi. Chini ya sheria za Benki na taasisi za fedha ya mwaka 2006 na marekebisho ya kanuni zake za mwaka 2012, ambayo inainisha kuwa kiwango cha chini cha mtaji wa kuanzisha taasisi ya fedha ni shilingi bilioni 5 na shilingi bilioni 15 kwa benki za kibiashara. Wataalamu wa masuala ya benki wamemwambia mwandishi wa makala haya kuwa kuwa mtaji wa benki unaposhuka huokolewa kwa njia za wamiliki au wanahisa kuongeza kiwango cha mtaji ya taasisi yao. Njia nyingine ni Benki kuungana na kuunganisha mtaji na kuungana kuwa taasisi moja. Hadi hapo swali analojiuliza mwananchi wa kawaida ni kwanini benki zilishuka mitaji? Je chanzo kilikuwa makosa ya uendeshaji au hali mbaya ya uchumi? Lakini sababu kuu ya kushuka mtaji zipo katika ripoti zao za kupata hasara kwa vipindi kadhaa mfululizo. Ripoti kadhaa za mabenki zimetaja mikopo isiyolipika na mzunguko hafifu wa fedha ni kiini cha kuporomoka sekta hiyo. Kuwa na mzunguko mdogo wa fedha mitaani kunaharibu mwenendo wa biashara za watu kwani hawana fedha mifukoni na sekta ya ajira inaathirika. Kwa hiyo wataalamu wa masuala ya fedha wanasisitiza kuwa hili ni eneo muhimu ambalo mkuu wa nchi itampasa alitazame kwa kina kwa kutumia matumizi ya sheria na busara pia. Gerard Nyerere ni mtaalamu wa masuala ya teknolojia na biashara anazitaja sekta za kimkakati, kwa mfano madini, utalii, kilimo ni maeneo ambayo yanapaswa kuimarishwa na ndiyo chanzo kikubwa cha ajira. Kilimo kupatiwa wataalamu wa kutosha, Maafisa Ugani maeneo yote ya kilimo, tafiti za mbegu bora na benki za TADB na TIB kufungua milango kwa wakulima wadogo watakaodhaminiwa na Halmashauri zao kupitia Mabaraza ya Kata kitaamarisha sekta za ufugaji na uvuvi kwa masoko ya ndani na nje. Mkakati mwingine ni vyuo vya elimu na ujuzi wa ujuzi wa vijana wa Tanzania kwa sababu ni changamoto kubwa kupata fursa za ajira katika sekta za viwanda. Aidha, anaonya suala la uchumi wa kidigitali lililozungumzwa na Rais Samia katika mkutano wake na Vijana Juni 15 mwaka huu wa 2021 jijini Mwanza, licha ya teknolojia kutoepukika, lakini serikali ya Tanzania inashauriwa kuwekeza katika elimu ya uchumi huo,miundombinu na usimamizi mzima wa mwenendo wa biashara hiyo ikiwemo rekodi za miamala ya kidigitali na kutoza kodi. Kwa sasa China ndiye mmiliki mkubwa wa miundombinu ya uchumi wa kidigitali na ni tishio kwa sarafu kama Dola na Euro. Gabriel Mwang'onda ni mshauri wa uchumi na biashara amemwambia mwandishi wa makala haya kuwa namna bora ya kuimarisha sekta binafsi ziko nne; kwanza ni Rais Samia kutochoka kukutana na wafanyabiashara mara kwa mara, kwa sababu wao ndio wanajua shida zinazowakabili. \\"Wafanyabiashara walishatoa mapendekezo na muongozo ambao ni suluhu ya matatizo mengi yanayowakabili ili kukwamua hali ya biashara na uchumi, mpaka sasa ni sehemu ndogo ambayo imetekelezwa na serikali. Kwa hiyo Rais aongeze kasi ya utekelezaji wa mapendekezo yaliyotolewa na Wafanyabiashara kwa sababu kuna mambo mengi mazuri yanayoweza kustawisha biashara na sekta binafsi. Tatu, ni muhimu kuongeza ujazo wa fedha katika mzunguko kiuchumi, hili anaweza kulitekeleza kwa kuanza kulipa madeni ya watu wenye kandarasi mbalimbali serikalini ambao bado hawajalipwa stahiki zao, Nne, ni vyema sekta binafsi inayomilikiwa na Watanzania kupewa kipaumbele kwenye zabuni hususani kwenye ujenzi kwa sababu asilimia kubwa ya bajeti ya Tanzania huishia kwenye ujenzi lakini wanufaika wakubwa wa hizo zabuni ni kampuni za nje, hii inadhoofisha ukuaji wa sekta binafsi ya Watanzania. Tano, kuendelea kupunguza tozo na kodi mbalimbali ili Wafanyabiashara waweze kuvutiwa kufanya biashara. Pia ni muhimu kuendelea kutoza kodi kubwa bidhaa zinazotoka nje ili zinazozalishwa ndani zipate soko na kukuza sekta binafsi,\\" ameeleza Bw. Mwang'onda. Mchambuzi wa masuala ya maendeleo na kukabiliana na umasikini Dkt. Marcossy Albanie, amesisitiza kuwa sekta binafsi inahitaji kufunguliwa milango ya mikopo na mitaji,kukubali ukweli kuwa biashara inahitaji usimamizi wa kulea si holela wala udhibiti wakati wa ukusanyaji wa kodi pamoja na kuweka mazingira wezeshi ya sera na sheria ya kufanya biashara na kuvuitia uwekezaji. Lipo jingine kubwa la kufanya mabadiliko wa sheria ya mapato ili kufufua biashara, ni lazima serikali ya Rais Samia ikubali kupunguza mamlaka za kutoa leseni na kusimamia biashara, litakuwa jambo lenye afya zaidi ikiwa itaanzishwa mamlaka au bodi moja yenye dhamana ya masuala hayo kuliko mbili za sasa. Mfanyabiashara anakutana rundo la mamlaka nyingi zenye dhamana na zote anatakiwa kulipia ada. Ni mzigo.","answer":"Sure, here's a headline for the given text - Siku 100 za Rais Samia Suluhu: Fahamu njia zinazoweza kukwamua hali ya uchumi na biashara Tanzania"},{"question":"Алмамбеттин ысымын ким койгон, ал төрөлгөндө канча күн жер титиреп тургана) кыргыз дубана, 70 күн б) белгисиз дубана 69 күнв) ата-энеси, 71 күнг) Эсенкан, 77 күн","answer":"Алмамбеттин ысымын кыргыз дубана койгон, ал төрөлгөндө 70 күн жер титиреп турган. Туура жообу А варианты болот. "},{"question":"Susieti faktus ir atsakyti į tai: Koks vaidmuo šios amerikiečių aktorės ir komikės vaidinusios NBC serijose \\"The Office\\", kuris taip pat buvo pristatytas „Redeeming Rainbow“?","answer":"Erin Hannon"},{"question":"Me kalmar: \\"stone\\" ke nufi a harshen Hausa?","answer":" Kalmar \\"stone\\" na nufin \\"dutse\\" a harshen Hausa"},{"question":"ජාත්‍යන්තර පොලිසියේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ කොහේද? ","answer":"ජාත්‍යන්තර පොලිසියේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ ප්‍රංශයේය."},{"question":"意大利的倫巴第區的首府在哪裡？","answer":"在米蘭。"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਤਿ ਬਚਨ ਸਾਧੂ ਉਪਦੇਸ ॥ਸਤਿ ਤੇ ਜਨ ਜਾ ਕੈ ਰਿਦੈ ਪ੍ਰਵੇਸ ॥ਸਤਿ ਨਿਰਤਿ ਬੂਝੈ ਜੇ ਕੋਇ ॥ਨਾਮੁ ਜਪਤ ਤਾ ਕੀ ਗਤਿ ਹੋਇ ॥ਆਪਿ ਸਤਿ ਕੀਆ ਸਭੁ ਸਤਿ ॥ਆਪੇ ਜਾਨੈ ਅਪਨੀ ਮਿਤਿ ਗਤਿ ॥ਜਿਸ ਕੀ ਸ੍ਰਿਸਟਿ ਸੁ ਕਰਣੈਹਾਰੁ ॥ਅਵਰ ਨ ਬੂਝਿ ਕਰਤ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥ਕਰਤੇ ਕੀ ਮਿਤਿ ਨ ਜਾਨੈ ਕੀਆ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਜੋ ਤਿਸੁ ਭਾਵੈ ਸੋ ਵਰਤੀਆ ॥੭॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 284 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਉਪਦੇਸ਼ ਅਟੱਲ ਬਚਨ ਹਨ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ (ਇਸ ਉਪਦੇਸ਼ ਦਾ) ਪ੍ਰਵੇਸ਼ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਭੀ ਅਟੱਲ (ਭਾਵ, ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਰਹਿਤ) ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਨਾਮ ਜਪ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਉੱਚੀ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਜਗਤ ਭੀ ਸੱਚ ਮੁੱਚ ਹੋਂਦ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪਣੀ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਤੇ ਮਰਯਾਦਾ ਆਪ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਜਿਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਜਗਤ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਆਪ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਬਨਾਉਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਜਗਤ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਿਆਲ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਾਲਾ (ਭੀ) ਨਾਹ ਸਮਝੋ ।ਕਰਤਾਰ (ਦੀ ਬਜ਼ੁਰਗੀ) ਦਾ ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ਾ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਬੰਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਾ ਸਕਦਾ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਉਹੀ ਕੁਝ ਵਰਤਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੭।\\""},{"question":"I wonder పాడేరు మండలంలో నిర్మించిన మొదటి బ్యాంకు ఏది.Help me answer this question with \\"Yes\\" or \\"No\\" or \\"None\\" if none of the first two answers apply.Here's what I found on the internet:Topic: పోర్చుగల్Article: పోర్చుగల్ (అధికార నామము పోర్చుగీస్ రిపబ్లిక్) [note 1] ఐరోపాలోని ఐబీరియా ద్వీపకల్పంలోని ఒక దేశం. నైఋతి ఐరోపా లో ఉన్న పోర్చుగల్ అట్లాంటిక్ మహాసముద్రానికి తూర్పు మరియు ఉత్తర దిశలలో స్పెయిన్ఉంది. దీనికి లిస్బన్ రాజధాని.అట్లాంటిక్ ద్వీపసముహాలోని స్వయంప్రతిపత్తి కలిగిన అజోరెస్ మరియు మడియేరా ద్వీపాలు వాటి ప్రాంతీయ ప్రభుత్వ నిర్వహణ చేస్తూ దేశంలో భాగంగా ఉన్నాయి.[3]పోర్చుగల్ ఒక అభివృద్ధి చెందిన దేశము. పోర్చుగల్ ఐక్యరాజ్య సమితి (1955 నుండి), ఐరోపా సమాఖ్య, నాటో మరియు ఓఈసీడీ లలో సభ్యదేశంగా ఉంది.15వ శతాబ్దంలో భారత దేశం చేరే నావిక మార్గాన్ని కనుక్కోవడంలో పోర్చుగల్ దేశస్థులు ముందున్నారు. ఆ దేశస్థుడైన వాస్కో డ గామా (Vasco da Gama) 1498లో ఐరోపా నుండి భారతదేశానికి నేరుగా సముద్రమార్గాన్ని కనుగొన్నాడు. వాస్కోడిగామా బృందము మొట్టమొదట కాలికట్లో కాలుమోపింది. 16వ శతాబ్దంలో పోర్చుగీసు వర్తకులు గోవాలో స్థావరం ఏర్పరచుకొన్నారు. కొద్దికాలంలోనే, 1510లో అఫోన్సో డి ఆల్బుకరెక్ గోవాను స్వాధీనపరుచుకుని అధికారాన్ని బలవంతంగా హస్తగతం చేసుకొన్నాడు. 1531లో దమన్‌ను, ఆ తర్వాత దియును పోర్చుగీసువారు ఆక్రమించారు. 1539లో గుజరాతు సుల్తాను ద్వారా దమన్ అధికారికంగా పోర్చుగీసువారికి అప్పగింపబడింది. పోర్చుగీసువారు గోవాను స్వాధీనపరుచుకున్న 450 ఏండ్ల తరువాత, 1961లో డిసెంబరు 19న భారత ప్రభుత్వం గోవా, దమన్, దియులను తన అధీనంలోకి తీసుకొన్నది[4][5]. కానీ పోర్చుగల్ ప్రభుత్వం 1974 వరకు వీటిపై భారతదేశపు అధిపత్యాన్ని అంగీకరించలేదు. అలాగే దాద్రా నగరు హవేలీ కూడా 1779 నుండి 1954లో భారతదేశము స్వాధీనము చేసుకునే వరకు పోర్చుగీస్ కాలనీగా ఉంది.పోర్చుగల్ ఇబెరియన్ ద్వీపకల్పంలో అత్యంత పురాతన రాష్ట్రంగా ఉంది మరియు పురాతన యూరోపియన్ దేశాలలో ఒకటిగా ఉంది. దాని భూభాగంలో నిరంతరం మాననవనివాసితంగా ఉంది. పూర్వ చారిత్రకు పూర్వం నుండి కాలాల తరువాత ఆక్రమించబడింది. ప్రీ-సెల్ట్స్, సెల్ట్స్, కార్తగినియన్లు మరియు రోమన్లు ​​విసిగోత్స్ మరియు స్యూబి జర్మానిక్ ప్రజల దండయాత్రలు జరిగాయి.క్రీ.శ. 711 లో ఐబీరియన్ ద్వీపకల్పాన్ని ఆక్రమించిన ముస్లిం మూర్సుకు వ్యతిరేకంగా పోర్చుగల్ క్రిస్టియన్ రీకోనక్స్‌టా తరువాతపోర్చుగల్ స్థాపించబడింది. \\" సావో మమేడే యుద్ధం \\" తరువాత అపోన్సో హెన్రిక్స్ నేతృత్వంలోని పోర్చుగీస్ దళాలు అతని తల్లి థెరెస్సా పోర్చుగల్ నేతృత్వంలోని దళాలను ఓడించగా పోర్చుగల్ కౌంటీ దాని సార్వభౌమత్వాన్ని...నిలుపుకు0ది. ","answer":"None"},{"question":"लुम्बिनीमा मनाइने \\"बुद्ध जयन्ती\\" पर्वसँग सम्बन्धित सांस्कृतिक प्रचलन र विश्वासहरू वर्णन गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"बुद्ध जयन्तीमा भगवान बुद्धको जन्म, बुद्धत्व र मृत्युको उत्सव मनाइन्छ र प्रार्थना, भेटी र दीप प्रज्वलन समावेश गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Aara san pa maaluu meje niluu Alla","answer":"Aara san pa maaluu meje, Fulani darandaran meji fara pa nigba ti ojo n rọ niluu Alla, nijọba ibilẹ Isin, nipinlẹ Kwara.ALAROYE gbọ pe awọn Fulani darandaran ni wọn n da ẹran kiri lati ilu kan si ekeji, nigba ti wọn de ilu Alla, ti wọn si n lọ si Oke-Ọdẹ, ni ojo bẹrẹ si i rọ, ni wọn ba fara pamọ sinu oko kan to wa nitosi wọn, afi bi aara ṣe bẹrẹ si i san, nigba ti wọn yoo si fi mọ ohun to n ṣẹlẹ,  maaluu meje ti ku, awọn Fulani mejeeji si fara pa yannayanna.Ẹlẹyin ju aanu kan lo ri wọn, to si lọọ sọ fun awọn araalu, eyi lo mu ki Ọba Alala ti ilu Alla, fi Ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ naa to DPO ọlọpaa Oke-Onigbin ati awọn Fulani to wa ni agbegbe naa leti fun igbeṣẹ to yẹ.Wọn gbe ọkan lara awọn Fulani to fara pa lọ si ileewosan Awoye, niluu Oro, o si n gba itọju lasiko ta a fi n kọ iroyin yii. Ọsunitu kan niluu Igbaja ni wọn gbe ẹni kejiNinu ipade ti wọn ṣe laafin Ọba Alla pẹlu awọn Fulani, wọn fẹnuko pe ki ẹni to ni maaluu lọọ tọju awọn Fulani to fara pa, tori pe amuwa Ọlọrun ni."},{"question":"පහත මාතෘකා ව ඇති කතාව ලියා  දක්වන්න. (ඉඟිය: මෙය රසවාහිනීයේ එන කතාවකි)මුවපැටියාගේ කථාව.","answer":"සිංහලද්වීපයෙහි උද්දලොලක නම් එක් සිත්කළු විහාරයක් විය. ඒ විහාරය සමීපයෙහි බොහෝ මුවෝ හා ඌරෝ වසති. එකල්හි එක් වැදි ගමක වැදි පුතෙක් මේ වනයෙහි, බොහෝ මුවන් හා ඌරන් දැක එක් දිනක් වනයෙහි එක් පැත්තක කොටුවක් සාදා වනයෙහි කෙළවර කොළ අතු බැඳ දුනු කලප් රැගෙන මුවන්ගේ පැමිණීම බලමින් කොටුවෙහි සිටියේය.ඉක්බිති මුවෙක් එහි ගොදුරු ගෙන පැන් බොන්නට තොටට යන්නේ එම විහාරයෙහි බණ අසනු සඳහා ඝෝෂා කළ ශබ්දය අසා දික්කළ ගෙලින්, උස් කළ කනින් හා බිම නොතබන ලද දකුණු පාදයෙන් යුතුව දම් දෙසන භික්‍ෂුවගේ කට හඬෙහි නිමිති ගෙන සිටියේය.2. එකෙණෙහි වැද්දා එක පහරින්ම විද මරණයට පත් කෙළේය. ඉක්බිති ඒ මුවා කළුරිය කොට එම වෙහෙර වැසි අභය හිමියන්ගේ නැගණියගේ කුසෙහි පිළිසිඳගෙන දසමස් ඇවෑමෙන් මවු කුසින් බිහිවී පිළිවෙළින් වැඩෙන්නේ සත් වයස් ඇත්තෙක් විය. මවුපියවරු ඒ දරුවා අභය හිමියන් ළඟට ගෙන ගියාහුය. හේ නොබෝ කලකින් පැවිදි කරවීය. ඒ කුමරා පෙර මුව දිවියෙහි දී කරන ලද දහම් දෙසුම්හි බලයෙන් කර අගදීම රහත් බවට පැමිණියේය. ඔහුගේ මයිලණුවන් වන හිමියෝ අවබෝධ කළ පඤ්චාභිඥා අෂ්ට සමාපත්ති ඇත්තෝ නමුදු රහත් බව් නොලැබුවෝය. ඉක්බිති එක් දිනක් සාමණේරයන් වහන්සේ උදෑසනම උපාධ්‍යාය ස්ථවිරයන් වහන්සේ කරා ගියහ. ඉක්බිති උපාධ්‍යායයන් වහන්සේ අත ඔසවා සඳ මඬල පිරිමදිමින් සිටියේය. සාමණේරතෙම ස්වාමීනි, මෙය රැකීම සුදුසුය කීයේය. ස්ථවිරයන් වහන්සේ සාමණේර තැන අගපල රහත් බවට පත් බව නොම දැන ඔහුගේ වචනය මෙනෙහි නොකළහ. ඉක්බිති සාමණේර තෙම සෘද්ධියෙන් දහසක් චන්‍ද්‍ර‍යන් ගෙන හැර පා තෙරුන් වහන්සේට දක්වා ස්වාමීනි, චන්‍ද්‍ර‍යන් දහසක් ලක්‍ෂයක් ගෙන හැර පෑම අමාරු නොවේ. යමෙක් එකම තෘෂ්ණාව අත හරීද එයම ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨය වැදගත් යයි සලකමන් මෙසේ කීයේය.3. යම් නැණහීන මිනිසෙක් ඉවුරෙහි සිට මහමුහුද දැක මහ මුහුද දැක්කෙමි යි කියයිද?4. මෙවැනිම මහණ තමා ළඟ ඇති කෙලෙස් පහකොට නොහැර එකාන්තයෙන් අභිඥා බලය ලබා ගෙන,5. කෙලෙස් නොනසා කෙලෙස් නැසුයෙමියි හඟීද (හේ) තෘෂ්ණා නමැති දාසකමින් යුක්ත වූයේ නො මිදීම පවතී.6. ඉතා නිශ්‍ර‍ක වූ, ක්‍ෂෙම නොවූ බියජනක වූ අත්හැර නොයන්නා වූ තෘෂ්ණාව යමෙක් ඉවත් කෙරේද හේ මරුගේ බැඳුම්වලින් නිදහස් වූවා වේ.7. මෙය අසා ස්ථවිරයන් වහන්සේ එදිනම රහත් වූ සේක. ඉක්බිති දෙවැනි දින තෙරුන්ගේ නැගණියෝ සාමණේරයන් වහන්සේත් සමග තෙරුන්ට ආරාධනාවක් කළහ. ස්ථවිරයන් වහන්සේ සොහොයුරියට මෙසේ වදාළහ.උපාසිකාව තී විසින් අද බොහෝ මහණුන්දෑ දැක සිත පැහැදිය යුතුය. එහෙත් (ආහාර) කොටස දෙදෙනාට පමණක් විය යුතු යයි ඇය යවා පෙරවරු සමයෙහි හැඳ පොරවාගෙන පා සිවුරු ගෙන මහණුන්දෑ තිස් දහසක් සමග වැඩම කළහ. ඇය එය දැක මාමාට හා බෑණාට පමණක් ආසන පැනවූවාය. ඒ ආසන උන්වහන්සේලාගේ ආනුභාවයෙන් තිස් දහසක් පමණ විය. උන්වහන්සේලාගේම ආනුභාවයෙන් ඇගේ ගෙය ද විශාල විය. භික්‍ෂූහු පැමිණි පැමිණි අසුන්වල වැඩ හුන්හ. ඒ දෙදෙනා වහන්සේට පිළියෙල කරන ලද සුපව්‍යාඤ්ජනාදිය ඒ තිස් දහසක් පමණ භික්‍ෂූන්ට සෑහිණ. වළඳා අවසානයෙහි ඒ උවසිය අනුමෙවෙනි බණ සඳහා සාමණේරයන්ගේ පාත්‍ර‍ය ගත්තාය. ඒ හෙරණුන්දෑ ද උන්වහන්සේලාගේ මැද අභිවෘද්ධිය වඩවමින් මිහිරි වදන් පිට කරමින් ධර්‍මය දෙසූහ. දෙසුන් අවසන මවුපියන් මුල් කොට කුල පන්සියයක් සෝවාන් පෙලෙහි පිහිට වූහ. බොහෝ දෙනාට ධර්‍ම දේශනාව සාර්‍ථක වූවාය.8. දහම් දෙසන විට වන සත්තු ද ඒ ශබ්දයේ නිමිත්ත පමණක් ලැබගෙන මිනිස් සැප හා නිවන් සැප ලබති. බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ කෙරෙහි යොදවන ලද ශ්‍ර‍ද්‍ධාව ඇති අය බණ අසා බුදුරජාණන් වහන්සේ විසින් දේශනා කරන ලද වර්‍ණනාවට සුදුසු දෙව් විමන්වල නො ඇලේද (ඇලේමැයි)"},{"question":"Kíni orúkọ Yunifásítì àkọ́kọ́ ní orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà? ","answer":"Yunifásítì ti ìlú Ìbàdàn. "},{"question":"Альпака тууралуу айтып берчи..","answer":"Альпака - бул Анд тоолорунда жашаган, эң акылдуу жана жүндөрү жумшак болгон жаныбар. Жүнү да дүйнөдө кымбат болуп эсептелинет."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा सोप्या शब्दात अर्थ सांगा खाईन तर तुपाशी नाहीतर उपाशी","answer":"परिस्थितीशी जुळवून न घेता हट्टीपणाने वागणारा."},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Bulgarie nékk","answer":"Réwum Bulgarie mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Europe"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪਉੜੀ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਵਡੀ ਹੈ ਹਰਿ ਕੀਰਤਨੁ ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਵਡੀ ਹੈ ਜਾ ਨਿਆਉ ਹੈ ਧਰਮ ਕਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਵਡੀ ਹੈ ਜਾ ਫਲੁ ਹੈ ਜੀਅ ਕਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਵਡੀ ਹੈ ਜਾ ਨ ਸੁਣਈ ਕਹਿਆ ਚੁਗਲ ਕਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਵਡੀ ਹੈ ਅਪੁਛਿਆ ਦਾਨੁ ਦੇਵਕਾ ॥੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 84 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਸ ਹਰੀ ਦਾ ਧਰਮ ਦਾ ਨਿਆਂ ਹੈ, ਉਸਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਤੇ ਉਸਦਾ ਕੀਰਤਨ ਕਰਨਾ—ਇਹੋ (ਜੀਵ ਲਈ) ਵੱਡੀ (ਕਰਣੀ) ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਹਰੀ ਦਾ ਧਰਮ ਦਾ ਨਿਆਂ ਹੈ, ਉਸਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਤੇ ਉਸਦਾ ਕੀਰਤਨ ਕਰਨਾ—ਇਹੋ (ਜੀਵ ਲਈ) ਵੱਡੀ (ਕਰਣੀ) ਹੈ ਹਰੀ ਦੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਕਰਨੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਚੰਗਾ ਕੰਮ ਹੈ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਜੀਵ ਦਾ (ਅਸਲੀ) ਫਲ (ਹੀ ਇਹੋ) ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ ਜਨਮ-ਮਨੋਰਥ ਹੀ ਇਹੀ ਹੈ)  ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਚੁਗਲ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਵਲ ਕੰਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਧਰਦਾ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ ਕਰਨੀ ਵੱਡੀ ਕਰਣੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਕਿਸੋ ਨੂੰ ਪੁੱਛ ਕੇ ਦਾਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਉੱਤਮ ਕੰਮ ਹੈ ।੬।\\""},{"question":"Zer da Sudoku jokoa?","answer":"Sudoku jokoa zenbakiak erabiliz egindako puzzle bat da, non 9x9ko taula bete behar den zenbakiak errepikatu gabe."},{"question":"Tóm tắt về nhà thơ Nguyễn Bính.","answer":"Nguyễn Bính là nhà thơ nổi tiếng của phong trào Thơ Mới với đặc trưng những bài thơ tình mang sắc thái mộc mạc, chân quê.Nhà thơ Nguyễn Bính (1918-1966) tên thật là Nguyễn Trọng Bính, quê huyện Vụ Bản, tỉnh Nam Định. Ông có người anh trai Nguyễn Mạnh Phác, nhà viết kịch với bút danh Trúc Đường, dạy học tại một trường tư thục ở Hà Đông.Thời thiếu niên, Trúc Đường đón Nguyễn Bính lên và truyền đạt cho ông về văn học Pháp. Cuộc đời Nguyễn Bính gắn bó với anh trai cả về văn chương và đời sống.Bài thơ đầu tiên được đăng báo của Nguyễn Bính là Cô hái mơ. Năm 1937, ông gửi tập thơ Tâm hồn tôi tới dự thi và được giải khuyến khích của nhóm Tự Lực Văn Đoàn."},{"question":"问：李白在中国文学史上的地位是怎样的？","answer":"答：李白在中国文学史上有着极高的地位，他的诗歌对后世影响深远，被誉为中国古代伟大的浪漫主义诗人之一。"},{"question":"ቮልታ ሐይቅ ምን ዓይነት ሐይቅ ነው?","answer":"ሠው ሰራሽ ሐይቅ"},{"question":" Sheeg Kal-Kaalisadii Ugu Horeeyey Islaamka?","answer":"Waxay Eheed Kuceybatu Al Aslaamiyah"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Akoholahy maneno an-tsena,_\\"","answer":"\\" tsy hery fa alahelo ny toerana nilaozana\\""},{"question":"«Microsoft Wordдо» иштөө ыкмаларын жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"оң тексттин арасынан бирден сөздү белгилеп көчүрүп алуу үчүн Ctrlди басып алып жылдырыңыз. "},{"question":"வினா: தமிழ்நாட்டின் முக்கடல் சங்கமிக்கும் இடம்  எது?","answer":"விடை: தமிழ்நாட்டின் முக்கடல் சங்கமிக்கும் இடம்  கன்னியாகுமாரி .விளக்கம்: கன்னியாகுமரி தமிழ்நாட்டில் உள்ள ஒரு மிக சிறிய மாவட்டமாகும். பரப்பளவில் மிகச்சிறிய (1672 சதுர கி.மீ) மாவட்டமாக இருந்தாலும் மக்கள் அடா்த்தியில் சென்னைக்கு அடுத்து இரண்டாம் இடம் வகிக்கிறது. கல்வியறிவில் தமிழ்நாட்டில் முதல் மாவட்டமாக விளங்குகிறது. இடவடிவமைப்பில், தமிழ்நாட்டில் உள்ள அனைத்து மாவட்டங்களில் இருந்து கன்னியாகுமரி வேறுபட்டு நிற்கிறது. உலகத்தில் இங்கு மட்டுமே சூரியன் உதயத்தினையும், சூரியன் மறைவினையும் ஒரே இடத்தில் பார்க்கும் வடிவமைப்பை பெற்றுள்ளது.இம்மாவட்டமானது மூன்று பக்கங்களிலும் 71.5 கி.மீ நீளம் கடல்களால் சூழ்ந்துள்ளது. இந்த சிறிய மாவட்டமானது, நீண்ட நெல் வயல்களினாலும், தென்னந்தோப்புகளாலும், ரப்பா் தோட்டங்களாலும், அரிய வகை காடுகள், அரிய வகை மணல்தாதுக்களை கொண்ட மேற்கு கடற்கரை மற்றும் எழில்மிகு மேற்குத்தொடா்ச்சி மலை பிரதேசங்களால் சூழப்பட்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"A cikin wanne nau'in ra'ayi za ku rarraba tweet mai zuwa? Mai kyau, Marar kyau, ko tsaka tsaki?@user Allah yabasu zaman lafiya, mukuma an barmu dasu Talatuwa dasu Lamunde. 💔💔 kwarya tabi kwarya.","answer":"Zan rarraba tweet ɗin da aka bayar a matsayin: Mai kyau "},{"question":"ਪੂਰਬੀ ਅਤੇ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਘਾਟਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਕੀ ਅੰਤਰ ਹਨ ?","answer":"1.ਪੱਛਮੀ ਘਾਟ ਉੱਤਰ ਤੋਂ ਦੱਖਣ ਤੱਕ ਅਰਬ ਸਾਗਰ ਦੇ ਸਮਾਨਾਂਤਰ ਫੈਲੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ ! ਇਸ ਦੇ ਉਲਟ ਪੂਰਬੀ ਘਾਟ ਦਾ ਵਿਸਤਾਰ ਖਾੜੀ ਬੰਗਾਲ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਹੈ ।2.ਪੱਛਮੀ ਘਾਟ ਦੇ ਪਰਬਤ ਇਕ ਲੰਬੀ ਲੜੀ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਪਰੰਤੂ ਪੂਰਬੀ ਘਾਟ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਕੱਟ ਜਾਣ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਅਲੱਗ-ਅਲੱਗ ਪਹਾੜੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿਚ ਦਿਖਾਈ ਦਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।3.ਪੱਛਮੀ ਘਾਟ ਦੇ ਪਰਬਤ ਪੁਰਬੀ ਘਾਟ ਦੀ ਬਜਾਏ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਉੱਚੇ ਅਤੇ ਸਪੱਸ਼ਟ ਹਨ ।4.ਪੂਰਬੀ ਘਾਟ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚੀ ਚੋਟੀ ਮਹੇਂਦਰਗਿਰੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸਦੇ ਉਲਟ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਘਾਟ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚੀ ਚੋਟੀ ਅਨਾਈਦੀ ਹੈ ।5.ਪੱਛਮੀ ਘਾਟ ਵਿਚ ਥਾਲ ਘਾਟ, ਭੋਰ ਘਾਟ, ਪਾਲ ਘਾਟ, ਸ਼ੇਨਕੋਟਾ ਆਦਿ ਦੱਰੇ ਹਨ, ਪਰੰਤੂ ਪੂਰਬੀ ਘਾਟ ਵਿਚ | ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਮਹੱਤਵਪੂਰਨ ਦੱਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"س286- من الذي قتل سيدنا عمر بن الخطاب ؟","answer":"ج286- أبو لؤلؤة المجوسي"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này:\\" 'Những cánh tay nối dài' nơi miền cực Bắc Tổ quốc\\".","answer":"Mặc dù đã \\"nhận chức\\" người có uy tín được hơn 16 năm nhưng có lẽ ông Lục Xuân Thành ở thôn Bó Lách, xã Quyết Tiến (Quản Bạ, Hà Giang) vẫn chưa có cơ hội được \\"về hưu\\" bởi dân bản vẫn tin tưởng và yêu mến ông lắm. Là người dân tộc Nùng nhưng ông Thành lại có thể nói thành thạo được nhiều thứ tiếng của các dân tộc khác như Mông, Bố Y, Dao, Tày, Hán. Cũng nhờ đó mà ông được xem như \\"trọng tài\\" hay người hoà giải của người dân trong thôn dù là chuyện lớn hay nhỏ. Đợt cao điểm phòng chống dịch bệnh COVID-19 vào cuối năm 2021, khi ấy cả xã Quyết Tiến bị phong toả, trai tráng trong thôn không đi làm được nên lại tụ tập uống rượu. Nguy cơ lây lan dịch bệnh cũng tăng lên, cán bộ đến vận động, tuyên truyền nhiều người không nghe. Lúc đó, những người có uy tín như là cánh tay phải của cán bộ y tế, chính quyền địa phương. Ông Thành nhớ lại: \\"Có những nhà trong bản cán bộ nói họ chưa nghe ngay đâu, nhưng mình nhẹ nhàng khuyên bảo để họ thấy được nguy hiểm của dịch bệnh, không tụ tập nữa. Mình sống quen với dân bản, gần gũi họ, công to việc lớn, ma chay cưới hỏi đều có mặt nên nói họ nghe ngay. Cứ thế, nhà này đến nhà kia rồi cả bản không tập trung đông người nữa\\". Rồi những xô xát trong cuộc sống của dân bản, cũng chính ông Thành là người đứng ra giải quyết thấu đáo. Ông kể: \\"Tôi nhớ có lần chỉ vì con chó của nhà này cắn con gà của nhà kia mà 2 nhà tí nữa thì động chân tay. May mình vừa đi làm về, hoà giải kịp thời chứ không chắc to chuyện\\". Giống như ông Thành, bà Lộc Thị Liên dân tộc Bố Y, thôn Nậm Lương (xã Quyết Tiến) được dân ban tin tưởng bầu làm người có uy tín đã gần 6 năm nay. Mặc dù đã hơn 60 tuổi nhưng người phụ nữ này vẫn hăng say với những công việc vốn được xem như \\"người vác tù và hàng tổng\\". Bất kể thời gian nào, khi dân bản có việc cần ý kiến tư vấn hay giúp đỡ từ những chuyện nhỏ nhặt đến công to việc lớn bà Liên đều không quản ngại. Bà Liên tâm niệm: \\"Muốn nói cho bà con nghe và tin thì trước hết mình phải làm được đã bởi dân bản mình đâu cần biết đến những điều to tát mà chỉ cần nhìn vào thực tế. Nói ngay  như việc tuyên truyền vận động người dân trong bản phát triển kinh tế bằng cách cải tạo vườn tạp, đồi hoang để trồng các loại cây ăn quả, cây rau phù hợp với khi hậu thổ nhưỡng cho kinh tế cao thì mình cũng phải làm trước đã. Có kết quả, dân thấy thì mới làm theo\\". Bằng việc đi trước, gương mẫu để thấy được đường lối, chủ trương của chính quyền là đúng bà Liên cùng gia đình cải tạo khu vườn nhà để trồng cây mận tam hoa, khồng không hạt. Cùng với đó là xen canh các loại rau ưa khí hậu lạnh, mỗi vụ ban cũng được cả chục triệu đồng. Nhìn thấy hiệu quả dân thôn Nậm Lương rủ nhau đến học hỏi làm theo, nhờ đó mà đời sống cũng cải thiện nhiều. Theo ông Nguyễn Việt Tiến - Chủ tịch UBND xã Quyết Tiến, cả xã có tất cả 13 thôn thì cũng chừng ấy thôn có người uy tín được đồng bào yêu mến. Cuộc sống nơi vùng cao biên giới vốn khó khăn nhưng đồng bào luôn tin tưởng vào chủ trương, chính sách của Đảng, Nhà nước nhờ những người có uy tín. Trong đồng bào DTTS chính là đại diện, nòng cốt tạo lên sự gắn kết giữa cấp ủy, chính quyền với nhân dân\\". Tỉnh Hà Giang là địa phương miền núi biên giới phía Bắc của Tổ quốc, có vị trí quan trọng về quốc phòng - an ninh và đối ngoại với đường biên dài trên 277km, tổng số 442 cột mốc tiếp giáp Trung Quốc. Cũng tại khu vực biên giới đang có trên 122 nghìn nhân khẩu sinh sống, chủ yếu là đồng bào dân tộc phân bố tại 34 xã, thị trấn giáp biên. Phát huy vai trò người có uy tín trong cộng đồng dân tộc thiểu số cũng chính là góp phần xây dựng thế trận an ninh nhân dân, bảo vệ vững chắc biên giới Tổ quốc. Anh Sìn Dỉ Gai, Trưởng thôn và cũng là người có uy tín tại thôn Lô Lô Chải (xã Lũng Cú, Đồng Văn), với đặc thù là thôn bản biên giới lại nằm ngay trên vị trí cực Bắc của Tổ quốc, đồng bào nơi đây luôn ý thức được trách nhiệm của mình cùng với các lực lượng biên phòng, công an giữ vững chủ quyền, an ninh biên giới. Suốt nhiều năm qua anh Gai đã thực sự trở thành những cánh tay nối dài của chính quyền trong việc tuyên truyền vận động người dân thực hiện tốt pháp luật về biên giới và xây dựng đời sống văn hoá. Anh Gai cho biết, cả thôn hiện có 96 hộ dân với với 453 nhân khẩu trong đó chủ yếu là người dân tộc Lô Lô. Đặc thù là thôn giáp biên, trước kia khi cuộc sống người dân còn nhiều khó khăn thì vẫn còn tình trạng người dân sang phía bên kia biên giới làm ăn tiềm ẩn những nguy cơ về mất an ninh trật tự. Nhưng nay khi thôn Lô Lô Chải đã phát triển du lịch cùng với cảnh sắc tự nhiên vốn có du khách đã biết đến nhiều hơn, nhờ đó cuộc sống người dân cũng dần khấm khá. Không chỉ cùng lực lượng biên phòng, chính quyền địa phương đến từng nhà tuyên truyền, phổ biến kiến thức pháp luật về biên giới, nhiều năm qua anh Gai là người tích cực vận động bà con gìn giữ và phát triển những nét văn hoá đặc sắc, riêng biệt của người Lô Lô như trang phục quần áo, hay những chiếc trống đồng cổ đến những điệu nhảy huyền bí của dân tộc mình. Chính nhờ điều này mà bản Lô Lô Chải đã trở thành một điểm đến hấp dân với du khách khi đến Hà Giang. Anh Sìn Gỉ Gai tâm sự: \\"Người Lô Lô vốn hiền hoà, yêu nước nhưng cuộc sống nơi biên giới khó khăn, mình là trưởng thôn thì phải làm sao giúp bà con xây dựng đời sống mới, phát triển kinh tế ngay trên mảnh đất quê hương. Cũng từ đó mà người dân không phải vượt biên đi làm, không vi phạm pháp luật cùng biên phòng bảo vệ đường biên cột mốc\\". Ðại tá Lưu Đức Hùng - Chính ủy Bộ đội Biên phòng tỉnh Hà Giang cho biết, người có uy tín tại các xã biên giới đã tích cực vận động nhân dân và tham gia tuần tra biên giới cùng với lực lượng biên phòng. Đội ngũ này còn cung cấp hàng trăm nguồn tin có giá trị liên quan đến an ninh trật tự ở cơ sở, đấu tranh với những việc làm sai trái, phát hiện các vụ việc mua bán phụ nữ, vận chuyển hàng hóa qua biên giới trái phép... để thông báo cho các cơ quan chức năng tổ chức ngăn chặn. Hơn 5 năm qua, tỉnh Hà Giang đã phê duyệt gần 2.000 người có uy tín thuộc 16 dân tộc trong tỉnh. Họ là những già làng, trưởng dòng họ, trưởng thôn được bầu chọn, suy tôn từ cộng đồng nên vai trò của người có uy tín rất quan trọng. Địa phương này cũng đã dành nguồn kinh phí hơn 40 tỉ đồng để thực hiện các chế độ, chính sách cho người có uy tín Qua đó tiếp tục khẳng định và phát huy vai trò của người có uy tín, là \\"cầu nối\\" giữa chính quyền với người dân, xoá đói giảm nghèo vùng DTTS và bảo vệ vững chắc an ninh biên giới."},{"question":"කුරුඳු වලට සෛන්හල කියනවද?","answer":"සෛංහල सैंहल යනු කුරුඳු සඳහා  වූ සංස්කෘත නාමයයි."},{"question":" miigan","answer":" wexey lamid tahay maqiiqan"},{"question":"'ਐਕਸ਼ਨ ਆਨ ਸਾਲਟ' ਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਸੰਗਠਨ ਨੇ 150 ਚੀਨੀ ਖਾਣਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਅਧਿਐਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਤੇ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਾ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਕੁਝ ਖਾਣਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੂਣ ਦੀ ਮਾਤਰਾ ਵੱਧ ਸੀ।ਖਾਣੇ, ਜਿਵੇਂ ਬਲੈਕ ਬੀਨਜ਼ ਸੌਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਣੇ ਬੀਫ, ਵਿੱਚ ਲੂਣ ਦੀ ਮਾਤਰਾ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਸੀ।ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਆਂਡਿਆਂ ਵਾਲੇ ਫਰਾਇਡ ਚੌਲ ਅਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਲੂਣ ਦੀ ਮਾਤਰਾ ਲੋੜ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਸੀ।ਖਾਣੇ ਦੇ ਪੈਕਟ 'ਤੇ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਪੌਸ਼ਟਿਕ ਮੁਲਾਂਕਣ (Nutritional Value) ਤੁਹਾਡੀ ਇਹ ਜਾਨਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਦਦ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਕਿੰਨਾ ਲੂਣ ਖਾ ਰਹੇ ਹੋ। 141 ਤਿਆਰ ਖਾਣਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਅਧਿਅਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ 43 ਫ਼ੀਸਦੀ ਲੂਣ ਦੀ ਮਾਤਰਾ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਸੀ। ਇਸ ਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਕਿ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਪੈਕਟ ਉੱਤੇ ਲਾਲ ਨੋਟੀਫ਼ਿਕੇਸ਼ਨ ਲੇਬਲ ਹੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਲੂਣ ਖਾਣ ਨਾਲ ਤੁਹਾਡਾ ਬਲੱਡ ਪ੍ਰੈਸ਼ਰ ਵਧ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਕਈ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਦਿਲ ਅਤੇ ਦਿਮਾਗ਼ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਲੱਗ ਸਕਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਜਿੰਨਾ ਲੂਣ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਖਾਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ, ਓਨਾ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਹੀ ਖਾਣੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਮੇਜ਼ ਉੱਤੇ ਰੱਖੇ ਲੂਣ ਨੂੰ ਖਾਣੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ। ਪੌਸ਼ਟਿਕਤਾ ਮਾਹਿਰ ਡਾ. ਐਲੀਸਨ ਟੇਡਸਟੋਨੇ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ: \\"ਬ੍ਰੈੱਡ ਦੇ ਪੈਕਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੁਣ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਨਾਲੋਂ 40 ਫ਼ੀਸਦੀ ਘੱਟ ਲੂਣ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ।\\"ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਪਰ ਕਈ ਉਤਪਾਦਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਜੇ ਵੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਲੂਣ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਘਟਾਇਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ।\\"    ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਅਸੀਂ ਫੂਡ ਇੰਡਸਟਰੀ ਦੇ 2017 ਦੇ ਲੂਣ ਵਰਤਣ ਦੇ ਟੀਚੇ ਦੀ ਮਹੱਤਤਾ ਤੋਂ ਭਲੀ-ਭਾਂਤੀ ਜਾਣੂ ਹਾਂ। ਅਸੀਂ ਇਸ ਸਾਲ ਵੀ ਇਸ 'ਤੇ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਰੱਖਾਂਗੇ।\\"(ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ।)","answer":"ਚੀਨੀ ਖਾਣਿਆਂ ’ਚ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਲੋੜ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਲੂਣ।"},{"question":"खालीलपैकी कोणत्या नदीचे उगम भारतात होत नाही?(A) चनाब नदी(B) सतलज नदी(C) रावी नदी(D) गंगा नदी=> ","answer":"(B) सतलज नदी"},{"question":"A ti ṣetán láti yan àwọn aṣòfin – Ìjọba ológun orílẹ̀-ede Gabon","answer":"Aarẹ ologun lorilẹ-ede Gabon, Ọgagun Brice Oligiu Nguema ti sọ pe oun yoo yan igbimọ alakoso ati awọn aṣofin laipẹ.O ni eyi yoo jẹ ki wọn maa jokoo papọ lati jiroro lori idagbasoke orilẹ-ede naa.Nguema lo sọrọ naa laipẹ yii loju opo ikanni X rẹ lẹyin ipade to ṣe pẹlu Aarẹ Faustin-Archange Touadéra.Nguema ati Aarẹ Touadéra pade ni Central African Republic l’Ọjọru ọsẹ yii, nibi ti ọrọ naa ti jade.Bi o tilẹ jẹ pe Ọgagun Nguema ko tii sọ patọ ọjọ ti yoo yan awọn alẹnulọrọ ati awọn aṣofin naa, ṣugbọn ikede naa lo waye latari awuyewuye to ti n lọ nipa awọn aadọrin ti yoo maa jokoo nile igbimọ aṣoju-ṣofin ati awọn aadọta mii ti yoo maa jokoo nile igbimọ aṣofin agba.Ninu oṣu Kẹsan an to kọja yii ni Ọgagun Oligui Nguema yan awọn olori l’awọn ile igbimọ aṣofin wọnyi ti wọn yoo si ṣakoso titi d’igba ti wọn yoo yan awọn ti wọn yoo jọ maa jokoo.Ipade ti Nguema ṣe pẹlu Aarẹ CAR lo waye lẹyin to ti kọkọ lọ ba awọn Aarẹ Equitorial Guinea ati Congo Brazzaville ṣe ipade, nibi to ti lọ bẹbẹ fun ifọwọsowọpọ ati atilẹyin wọn."},{"question":" waa maxay Baranbarqo ? ","answer":" Baran barqadu waa naagta qoyska. 1"},{"question":"段誉是哪个门派的人？","answer":"段誉是大理国的王子，也是大理段家的一员。"},{"question":"ඕලාරික යන පදයෙහි නිවැරදි අර්ථය පහදා දෙනු මැනවි","answer":"ඕලාරික යනු මහත් වූ, භයානක, දළ, රළු, ගොරෝසු, නීච."},{"question":"அரசூர் வம்சம்  நூலின் ஆசிரியர்  யார்?","answer":"விடை: இரா.முருகன்இரா. முருகன் (பிறப்பு: 1953) என்பவர் தமிழக எழுத்தாளர் ஒருவர் ஆவார். இவர் கணினித்துறையில் பணி புரிகின்றார்.குடும்ப பின்னணிதமிழ்நாடு, சிவகங்கையில் பிறந்த இரா. முருகனின் தந்தையார் நா.சீ.இராமசாமி, தாயார் மீனாட்சி.எழுத்துலக வாழ்வு1977-ல் கணையாழியில் முதல் படைப்பாக ஒரு புதுக் கவிதை பிரசுரமானதோடு இவருடைய எழுத்துலகப் பிரவேசம் தொடங்கியது. கவிஞராக அறியப்பட்டு பின் சிறுகதையாசிரியராக, நாவலாசிரியராக முகிழ்ந்தவர். இலக்கியப் பத்திரிகைகளிலும் வெகுஜனப் பத்திரிகைகளிலும் இவர் எழுதி வருகிறார். சென்னை அகில இந்திய வானொலியில் இவர் கதைகள் இவர் குரலிலேயே ஒலிப்பதிவாகி ஒலிபரப்பாகியுள்ளன.தமிழில் மாந்திரீக யதார்த்தக் கதையாடலாக இவர் எழுதிய அரசூர் வம்சம் புதினம் ஆங்கிலத்தில் கோஸ்ட்ஸ் ஓஃப் அரசூர் என்ற பெயரில் மொழிபெயர்க்கப்பட்டு வெளியாகி இருக்கிறது. இவர் ஆனந்தவிகடனில் எழுதிய 'உலகே உலகே உடனே வா' தமிழில் முதல் branded column ஆகும். மலையாளத்திலிருந்து குறிப்பிடத் தகுந்த மொழிபெயர்ப்புகள் செய்துள்ளார். ஆங்கிலத்தில் இருந்து அருண் கொலாட்கரின் அனைத்துக் கவிதைகளையும் மொழிபெயர்த்தார்.கமல் ஹாசனின் ‘உன்னைப் போல் ஒருவன்’ (2009) திரைப்படத்துக்கான வசனம் எழுதியுள்ளார். அஜீத் குமார் நடிக்கும் பில்லா 2 (2011) திரைப்படத்திற்கு வசனம் எழுதியுள்ளார்.இவர் எழுதிய ‘நெம்பர் 40, ரெட்டைத் தெரு’ அடிப்படையில் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட ‘ரெட்டைத் தெரு’ (2010) குறும்படத்தில் நடிகராகவும் திரையில் தோன்றியிருக்கிறார்.[1]விருதுகள்இலக்கியச் சிந்தனை ஆண்டுப் பரிசு (சிறந்த சிறுகதை), கதா விருது (சிறுகதை), பாரதியார் பல்கலைக் கழக விருது (நாவல்) போன்ற பல பரிசுகள் இவருடைய படைப்புகளுக்காகப் பெற்றிருக்கிறார் .நூல்கள்இதுவரை இரா.முருகனின் 29 நூல்கள் வெளியாகி உள்ளன.தேர் - சிறுகதைத் தொகுதி (அசோகமித்திரன் முன்னுரையோடு)ஆதம்பூர்க் காரர்கள் (சிறுகதைத் தொகுதி)சிலிக்கன் வாசல் (சிறுகதைத் தொகுதி - லில்லி தேவசிகாமணி விருது பெற்றது)கொறிக்கக் கொஞ்சம் கம்ப்யூட்டர் சிப்ஸ் (அறிவியல் கட்டுரைத் தொகுதி - இந்திய அரசின் என்.சி.ஈ.ஆர்.டி பரிசு பெற்றது)ஒரு கிராமத்துப் பெண்ணின் தலைப் பிரசவம் (கவிதைத் தொகுதி - வாசுதேவன் நினைவுப் பரிசு)கம்ப்யூட்டர் கொஞ்சம் கலகலப்பு கொஞ்சம் (அறிவியல் கட்டுரைத் தொகுதி - ராஜாராமனுடன் சேர்ந்து எழுதியது - வரதாச்சாரி விருது)தகவல்காரர் (குறுநாவல் தொகுதி)முதல் ஆட்டம் (சிறுகதைத் தொகுதி)பகல் பத்து ராப்பத்து (குறுநாவல் தொகுதி)ஐம்பது பைசா ஷேக்ஸ்பியர் (சிறுகதைத் தொகுதி)மந்திரவாதியும் தபால் அட்டைகளும் (சிறுகதைத் தொகுதி)மூன்று விரல் (நாவல் - கணினித் துறை பற்றிய முதல் தமிழ் நாவல்) இரண்டு வெளியீடுகள்சைக்கிள் முனி (சிறுகதைத் தொகுதி)ராயர் காப்பி கிளப் (கட்டுரைத் தொகுதி)அரசூர் வம்சம் (நாவல்)இரா.முருகன் சிறுகதைகள் (செம்பதிப்பு - 108 சிறுகதைகள் அடங்கியது)இரா.முருகன் சிறுகதைகள் (ஒலிப் புத்தகம் - ஆடீயோ புக்)Ghosts of Arasur (novel - translation of 'Arasur vamsam')நெம்பர் 40, ரெட்டைத் தெரு (bio-fiction)லண்டன் டயரி (பயணக் கட்டுரைகள்)ப்ராஜக்ட் எம் (பிராஜக்ட் மேனேஜ்மெண்ட் பற்றிய முதல் தமிழ் நூல்)[2]விஸ்வரூபம் (மேஜிகல் ரியலிஸம் நாவல்)அச்சுதம் கேசவம் (மேஜிக்கல் ரியலிஸம் நாவல்)வாழ்ந்து போதீரே (மேஜிக்கல் ரியலிஸம் நாவல்)தியூப்ளே வீதி (பயோஃபிக்‌ஷன் நாவல்)நண்டு மரம் (சிறுகதைத் தொகுப்பு)இரா.முருகன் குறுநாவல்கள்பீரங்கிப் பாடல்கள் (நாவல் - மலையாளத்திலிருந்து மொழிபெயர்ப்பு)1975 (நாவல்)"},{"question":"Ileya: Ijọba Kwara fagi le ipejọpọ Yidi, ṣiṣi ile itaja atawọn ibudo igbafẹ lasiko ọdun","answer":"Lati dẹkun atankalẹ arun Koronafairọọsi nipinlẹ Kwara, ijọba ti fagi le ipejọpọ ni Yidi lọdun yii. Bakan naa lawọn ile itaja nla bii Shoprite atawọn mi-in ko gbọdọ ṣilẹkun. Igbimọ to n gbogun ti arun Covid-19 ti Igbakeji Gomina, Kayọde Alabi, n dari lo kede ọrọ naa nibi ipade awọn oniroyin to waye lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ yii. Wọn ni nitori bi ero ṣe maa n pọ ni Eid nijọba fi gbe igbesẹ naa pẹlu ajọmọ igbimọ to n ṣakoso ẹsin Musulumi niluu Ilọrin.Alabi ni awọn ile itaja nla bii Shoprite ati ibudo igbafẹ bii ibudo ti wọn ko awọn ẹranko si, Unilọrin Zoological Garden, tawọn eeyan maa n rọ lọ lasiko ọdun maa wa ni titi lọjọ Ileya ati lọjọ keji.O ni eto adura Jumat ṣi wa bo ṣe wa, ṣugbọn awọn to ba lọọ jọsin gbọdọ tẹle gbogbo ilana tijọba ti la kalẹ, lara rẹ ni lilo ibomu ati titakete si ara.Bakan naa, ijọba ti tun fofin de iṣọ-oru lawọn ṣọọṣi, bẹẹ ni eto isin ọjọ isinmi ko gbọdọ ju wakati meji lọ. O tun ni gbogbo ile ọti, ile-ijo ati bẹẹ lọ gbọdọ wa ni titi. Awọn ero nibi ayẹyẹ igbeyawo tabi wẹjẹ-wẹmu kan ko gbọdọ ju aadọta lọ.O fi kun un pe awọn awakọ takiisi igboro ko gbọdọ gbe ju eeyan meji sẹyin ati ẹni kan niwaju, gbogbo wọn lo si gbọdọ lo ibomu. Ọlọkada naa ko lanfaani lati gbe ju eeyan kan ṣoṣo lọ.Ijọba ti waa ni ẹni to ba tapa sofin ti wọn ti la kalẹ yii yoo rugi oyin."},{"question":"问题：朝鲜战争是什么时候爆发的？","answer":"答案：朝鲜战争于1950年爆发。"},{"question":"ਆਰਥਿਕ ਸੰਸਥਾਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਰਣਨ ਕਰੋ ।","answer":"ਆਰਥਿਕ ਸੰਸਥਾਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਖ ਕੰਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਰਣਨ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਹੈ-(a) ਉਤਪਾਦਨ (Production) – ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦਾ ਅਰਥ ਅਜਿਹੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਆ ਤੋਂ ਹੈ ਜਿਹੜੀ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਨੂੰ ਉਪਯੋਗ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਪਰਿਭਾਸ਼ਿਤ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ । ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਵਰਣਨ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ ।(1) ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਲਈ ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਤੋਂ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਆਮ ਤੌਰ ‘ਤੇ ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਸਾਧਨ ਸੀਮਿਤ ਮਾਤਰਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਉਹ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਜੋ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਲਈ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੁੰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਸਾਧਨ ਕਹਾਉਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ । ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਭੌਤਿਕ ਵਸਤੂਆਂ ਤੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਲਈ ਪ੍ਰਯੋਗ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਤਾਕਤ ਵੀ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹਨ । ਭੌਤਿਕ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਲਈ ਵਧੀਆ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਤੇ ਜਲਵਾਯੂ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸਪਾਤ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਕੱਚਾ ਲੋਹਾ ਤੇ ਬਿਜਲੀ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਕੋਲੇ ਜਾਂ ਪਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਕਿ ਮਸ਼ੀਨਾਂ ਚੱਲ ਸਕਣ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਸਤੂ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਦਾਨ ਲਈ ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।(2) ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਾਰੀ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਤਾਕਤ ਦੀ । ਮਨੁੱਖੀ ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰੀ ਧਨ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਲਈ ਪਯੋਗ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਜਦੋਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਲਗਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਇਹੀ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੀ ਉਪਯੋਗਿਤਾ ਵਧਾ ਦਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰ ਨੂੰ ਉਸਦੀ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਦਾ ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਫਲ ਮਿਲੇ, ਉਹ ਅਰਥ-ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਿਰਭਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਿਵੇਂ ਪੁਰਾਣੇ ਸਮਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਪਿੰਡਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਵਾ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਦਾਣੇ, ਅਨਾਜ ਆਦਿ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਅੱਜ-ਕਲ੍ਹ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਤਨਖ਼ਾਹ ਜਾਂ ਦਿਹਾੜੀ ਪੈਸੇ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰੀ ਤਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਤ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਹੁਤ ਵੱਡਾ ਹੱਥ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।(3) ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੇ ਲਈ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਤੇ ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰੀ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਇੱਕ ਦੀ ਗੈਰ  ਮੌਜੂਦਰੀ ਨਾਲ ਚੀਜ਼ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣ ਸਕਦੀ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੱਦਦ ਨਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਮਸ਼ੀਨਾਂ, ਉਦਯੋਗ ਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੱਦਦ ਨਾਲ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਦਾ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਨੂੰ ਪੂੰਜੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਪੂੰਜੀ ਉਹ ਚੀਜ਼ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਕਰਕੇ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਅੱਗੇ ਹੋਰ ਪੂੰਜੀ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਯੋਗ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ |(4) ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ, ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰੀ ਤੇ ਪੂੰਜੀ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਹੋਰ ਵੀ ਕਈ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਹਨ ਜਿਹੜੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੱਦਦ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਟੈਕਨਾਲੌਜੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਟੈਕਨਾਲੌਜੀ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੇ ਪੂਰੇ ਹੁਨਰ ਤੇ ਗਿਆਨ ਦਾ ਇਕੱਠ ਹੈ । ਜਿਸ ਸਮਾਜ ਦਾ ਗਿਆਨ ਤੇ ਹੁਨਰ ਜਿੰਨਾ ਵੀ ਵਧੀਆ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ, ਉਹ ਸਮਾਜ ਉੱਨੀ ਹੀ ਵਧੀਆ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕਰੇਗਾ । ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਸਮਾਂ ਜਿਹੜਾ ਕਿ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਵਿਚ ਮਹੱਤਵਪੂਰਨ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜੇਕਰ ਅਸੀਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਕਰਨਾ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਨਿਸ਼ਚਿਤ ਸਮੇਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਹੋਣਾ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ ਨਹੀਂ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਦੀ ਲਾਗਤ ਵੱਧ ਜਾਵੇਗੀ । ਫਿਰ ਵਾਰੀ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਦੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਘੱਟ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਇਕੱਠ ਨਾਲ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਦਾ ਵੱਧ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਮਾਤਰਾ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਤਰੀਕਾ ਹੈ । ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਤਰੀਕਾ ਉਹ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਘੱਟ ਤੋਂ ਘੱਟ ਸਮੇਂ ਵਿਚ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਚੀਜ਼ ਬਣਾਈ ਜਾ ਸਕੇ ।(5) ਅੰਤ ਵਿਚ ਜਿਹੜੀ ਚੀਜ਼ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਵਿਚ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਹੈ ਉਦਯੋਗਪਤੀ । ਹਰ ਇਕ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਕਿਰਿਆ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਦਿਸ਼ਾ ਤੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਨਾ ਕਿਸੇ ਯੋਜਨਾ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਅੱਜ-ਕਲ੍ਹ ਵੱਡੇ-ਵੱਡੇ ਉਦਯੋਗਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਮੂਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਦੇਖ-ਰੇਖ ਕੁਝ ਖਾਸ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਜਾਂ ਮਾਲਕ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਕਿਰਿਆ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਆਪਣਾ ਯੋਗਦਾਨ ਪਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਕੁਝ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਕੋਲ ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਸਾਧਨ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਕਿਸੇ ਕੋਲ ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਕਿਸੇ ਕੋਲ ਪੈਸਾ ਤੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਕੋਲ ਸੰਦ । ਉੱਦਮੀ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦਾ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਮੁਨਾਫ਼ਾ ਕਮਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਕ੍ਰਿਆ ਵਿਚ ਮੁਨਾਫ਼ਾ ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਦਯੋਗਪਤੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਨੀਤੀਆਂ, ਕਾਨੂੰਨਾਂ, ਮਜ਼ਦੂਰਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਤਨਖਾਹਾਂ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਝਗੜਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਨਿਪਟਾਰਾ, ਵਪਾਰ ਤੇ ਵਣਜ ਨੂੰ ਨਿਯਮਿਤ ਕਰਨਾ, ਕੰਮ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਬੰਧਿਤ ਕਾਨੂੰਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਆਦਿ ਵੀ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹਨ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਕਾਰਨਾਂ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਸੰਸਥਾਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਕੰਮ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਕਰਨਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।(b) ਖਪਤ (Consumption) – ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ-ਨਾਲ ਖ਼ਪਤ ਦਾ ਹੋਣਾ ਵੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਬਗੈਰ ਖਪਤ ਦੇ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ । ਖਪਤ ਦਾ ਅਰਥ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦਾ ਉਪਭੋਗ ਕਰਨਾ ਅਤੇ ਉਪਭੋਗ ਦਾ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਗੁਣ ਜੋ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਨੂੰ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤ ਪੂਰਾ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਯੋਗ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਆਮ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਤਾਂ ਖਪਤ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਿਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਜਿਹੜੀ ਵੀ ਚੀਜ਼ ਉਤਪਾਦਿਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਵੰਡ ਤੇ ਖਪਤ ਅਰਾਮ ਨਾਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਆਦਿਮ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਸੀ । ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਭੋਜਨ ਦਾ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਉਪਭੋਗ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਸਨ । ਪਰੰਤੁ ਮੁਸ਼ਕਿਲ ਤਾਂ ਜਟਿਲ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਜਿੱਥੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਮੁੱਢਲੀਆਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਹੋਰ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਤੇ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤਾਂ ਵਿਕਸਿਤ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਹੜੀਆਂ ਕਿ ਜੀਵਨ ਜੀਉਣ ਲਈ ਕੋਈ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਨ ; ਜਿਵੇਂ-ਟੀ.ਵੀ., ਵਧੀਆ ਮਕਾਨ, ਕਾਰਾਂ, ਐਸ਼ ਦੇ ਸਮਾਨ ! ਜਟਿਲ ਸਮਾਜਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਚੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੀ ਖਪਤ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਅਰਥ-ਵਿਵਸਥਾ ਵੱਧਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਹਰੇਕ ਸਮਾਜ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਖ ਕੰਮ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਖਪਤ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਜ ਲਈ ਨਿਯਮਿਤ ਕਰੇ । ਖਪਤ ਨੂੰ ਨਿਯਮਿਤ ਕਈ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਿਵੇਂ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਿਯੰਤਰਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਤਪਦਨ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਿਯੰਤਰਣ ਕਈ ਤਰੀਕਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਭੰਡਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਬਚਾ ਕੇ ਰੱਖਣ ਤੇ ਤੇਜ਼ ਉਤਪਾਦਨ ਵਿਚ ਵੀ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਘੱਟ ਪ੍ਰਯੋਗ ਕਰਨਾ । ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ Export ਜਾਂ ਨਿਰਯਾਤ ਵੀ ਇਸਨੂੰ ਕੰਟਰੋਲ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ । ਖ਼ਪਤ ਨੂੰ ਅਸੀਂ advertise ਕਰਕੇ ਵੀ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵਿਤ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਜੇਕਰ ਕਿਸੇ ਚੀਜ਼ ਦਾ ਨਿਰਮਾਣ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਚੀਜ਼ ਬਾਰੇ ਟੀ.ਵੀ., ਅਖ਼ਬਾਰ ਆਦਿ ਵਿਚ advertise ਕਰਕੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੱਸ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਾਂ ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagaimana menanti ara hanyut\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud mengharapkan sesuatu yang belum tentu."},{"question":"Frase 1: Fue reemplazado en los golpes sucesivos por Murtala Mohammed (1975) y Olusegun Obasanjo (1976).Frase 2: Fue reemplazado por Olusegun Obasanjo (1976) y Murtala Mohammed (1975) en los golpes sucesivos.Pregunta: ¿La frase 1 y 2 expresan el mismo significado?","answer":"No, las frases 1 y 2 no expresan el mismo significado. Aunque ambas frases mencionan a Murtala Mohammed y Olusegun Obasanjo como personas que reemplazaron a alguien en los golpes sucesivos, el orden de los nombres y la estructura gramatical cambian el significado de la información.En la frase 1, se menciona que Murtala Mohammed fue el primero en reemplazar a alguien en un golpe sucesivo en 1975, y después de él, en un golpe posterior, fue reemplazado por Olusegun Obasanjo en 1976.En la frase 2, la secuencia se invierte. Se menciona primero a Olusegun Obasanjo como el que reemplazó a alguien en un golpe sucesivo en 1976, y después de él, en otro golpe posterior, fue reemplazado por Murtala Mohammed en 1975.Por lo tanto, aunque ambas frases hablan de reemplazos en golpes sucesivos por Murtala Mohammed y Olusegun Obasanjo, el orden y la secuencia temporal de los eventos son diferentes en cada frase."},{"question":"Wá ìdáhùn sí ìbéèrè tó díjú yìí: Àwòkẹ́kọ̀ọ́ oníhòòhò wo ni Roald Dahl ṣe tí Willem Defoe fi ohùn rẹ̀ ṣe lọ́dún 2009?","answer":"Ikọja Ọgbẹni Fox"},{"question":"Ẹgbẹ APC ti bẹ kọmiṣanna Ambọde to fẹgbẹ silẹ, wọn ní ko maa pada bọ","answer":"Ni nnkan bii ọjọ meloo kan sẹyin lọkunrin oloṣelu kan, Ọnarebu Abdul Lateef Abdul Hakeem, binu kuro ninu ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC, o lawọn kan ti wọn jẹ agba ninu ẹgbẹ n ṣatako oriire oun.Ẹgbẹ kan lo da silẹ, Iyẹpẹ 2023 lo pe e, ohun to si sọ pe o duro fun ni lilo ẹgbẹ naa lati fi ko araalu jọ fun oṣelu ati ṣíṣe itaniji fun wọn lori ọrọ oṣelu. Yatọ si eyi, ohun tí ẹgbẹ naa tun duro fun ni lati ṣíṣẹ fun un lori boun naa ṣe fẹẹ dupo gomina lọdun 2023 l’Ekoo.Bi Abdul Hakeem ṣe da ẹgbẹ tuntun yii silẹ lawon agbaagba kan ti tako o ninu APC, ìyẹn naa lo sì mu un fi ẹgbẹ silẹ.Ni bayii, awọn agbaagba kan ti pe e, wọn ti ni ko pada sinu ẹgbẹ. Ohun tí wọn sọ ni pe oloṣelu kan to ni ero rẹpẹtẹ lẹyin ni, bẹẹ lo maa jẹ adanu nla fun APC tiru Ọnarebu Yẹpẹ gẹgẹ bi awọn eeyan ẹ ṣe maa n pe e ba fi awọn silẹ.Lara awọn to pe e sipade alaafia ni alaga ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC, Alhaji Tunde Balogun, Ọmọọba Tajudeen Olusi, Abiodun Ogunlẹyẹ Rabiu Oluwa, Alhaji Bushira Alebioṣu ati Omooba Murphy Adetoro. Ohun tí wọn sọ fun un ní pe ko jọwọ, pada sinu ẹgbẹ, nítorí ipa nla lo n ko, ohun tó si gbe lọwọ, nnkan to tun le mu ẹgbẹ ni ero rẹpẹtẹ si i ni. Fun idi eyi, awọn ko ba a ja, ọrọ ẹgbẹ naa lo n ṣe.Bakan naa ni wọn ti ṣeleri lati kun un lọwọ lori Iyẹpẹ 2023 to ṣagbekalẹ ẹ yii.Bẹẹ gẹgẹ ni wọn ti parí wahala to wa laarin oun atawọn agba ẹgbẹ ti ko fara mọ akojọpọ to da silẹ naa.AbdulLateef naa ti sọrọ, o ni loootọ loun tí pada sinu ẹgbẹ.Kọmiṣanna fun ọrọ abẹle ni ọkunrin oloṣelu yii laye ijọba Ambọde, bakan naa lo tun jẹ oludamọran fun abẹnugan ile-igbimọ aṣofin, Mudashiru Ọbasa, ko too kuro ninu ẹgbẹ. Oun paapaa ti jẹ aṣofin nipinlẹ Eko ri, agbẹjọro ni, to si tun jẹ Alfaa to nimọ kuraani daadaa pẹlu."},{"question":"வினா: சில விலங்குகள் மழை வருவதை, இயற்கை அனர்த்தங்களை முன்கூட்டியே உணர்ந்து கொள்வது எப்படி?","answer":"விடை: அவை இயற்கையோடு ஒன்றி இருப்பதால்..அவற்றின் நுண்ணறிவிற்கு இயற்கையின் மாறுதல்கள் நன்றாகவே புலப்படுகின்றன.மனிதன் இயற்கைக்கு எதிராக இருப்பதால் இயற்கை மாற்றங்களை கண்டறிய நமக்கு பல கோடி மதிப்புள்ள அறிவியல் சாதனங்கள் தேவைப்படுகிறது.அவற்றைக்கொண்டும் நம்மால் பல நேரங்களில் துல்லியமாக கணிக்க முடியாதது தான் வேடிக்கை.மூன்றறிவு,நான்கறிவு,ஐந்தறிவு ஜீவராசிகள் உணர்வதை கூட மனிதனால் உணர முடியாமல் போயிற்று."},{"question":"Ijọba ipinle Ọyọ ti fẹẹ san owo ajẹmọnu awọn oṣiṣẹ to feyinti lọdun yii","answer":"Lati dena ki owo-oṣu awọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti maa pọ lọrun ijọba, ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ ti pinnu lati bẹrẹ si i san owo ajẹmọnu awọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti ipinlẹ naa lati ọdun 2019 di asiko yii.Ki eyi le baa ṣee ṣe lo mu ki ijọba fi kun owo ti wọn maa n ya sọtọ fun eleyii loṣooṣu. Ni bayii, miliọnu lọna igba o le lọgbọn (230m) si igba ati marundinlogoji (235) ni wọn ya sọtọ bayii.Lẹyin ipade awọn alaṣẹ ipinlẹ naa to waye ni ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, ni Kọmiṣanna fun eto iroyin, Dokita Wasiu Ọlatubọsun, ṣalaye ọrọ yii fawọn oniroyin.Kọmiṣanna ni lọjọ kọkandinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun yii, ni igbimọ naa gbe aba kan dide lori bi ijọba yoo ṣe tete maa san owo-oṣu awọn oṣiṣẹ-fẹyinti ati ajẹmọnu wọn ni kete ti wọn ba ti kuro lẹnu iṣẹ.Eyi lo mu ki wọn gbe igbimọ kan dide ti yoo ri si bi eyi yoo ṣe di siṣe. Lara awọn ọmọ igbimọ naa gẹge bi Ọlatubọsun ṣe sọ ni akọwe ijọba, olori awọn oṣiṣẹ, kọmiṣanna fun eto idajọ, kọmiṣanna fun eto isuna ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ.Ọlatubọsun ni lẹyin ti awọn igbimọ yii jabọ iṣẹ wọn ni awọn ya miliọnu lọna aadọta naira sọtọ lati mojuto awọn oṣiṣẹ ọba to ba fẹyinti laarin oṣu karun-un, ọdun 2019, si oṣu karun-un, ọdun 2023. O fi kun un pe sisan owo-oṣu awọn oṣiṣẹ ati ajẹmọnu awọn to ti fẹyinti jẹ ijọba Gomina Ṣeyi Makinde logun."},{"question":"खालीलपैकी कोणता असंसर्गजन्य रोग आहे?अ. क्षयरोगब. मधुमेह क. घटसर्पड. गोवर","answer":"ब. मधुमेह "},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Aleo manenina tsy nahazo ...................................... \\"","answer":"\\"  Aleo manenina tsy nahazo toy izay manenina nahazo. \\" "},{"question":"Mi o le lọ si ṣọọṣi tabi mọṣalaaṣi, Ogun lo n ṣe ohun ti mo fẹ fun mi—Agbẹdẹ Afuyẹ","answer":"Agbẹdẹ Ogunṣina Afuyẹ ko pe meji n’Itoko, l’Abẹokuta, ṣugbọn ki i ṣe n’Itoko nikan lọkunrin naa ti gbajumọ, kaakiri Abẹokuta ni.Yatọ si pe ọkunrin ti wọn n pe ni Afuyẹ yii n rọ ọkọ ati ada pẹlu awọn nnkan mi-in ti wọn n fi irin ṣẹ, o tun maa n ba awọn eeyan bọ Ogun (Ogun Federal ni wọn pe e, wọn ni gbogbo ibi ni wọn ti n waa bọ ọ lawọn ṣe n pe e bẹẹ)Eeyan le ro pe bibọ Ogun ti kasẹ nilẹ lasiko yii, ṣugbọn ti tọhun ba de Agbẹdẹ Afuyẹ, to ri i bawọn eeyan ṣe n mu oriṣiiriṣii ẹranko waa bọ Ogun, yoo mọ pe iṣeṣe ko rebi kan. ALAROYE de Agbẹdẹ Afuyẹ n’Itoko, eyi lohun t’ọkunrin naa ba wa sọ.‘‘Ọrukọ mi ni Ogunṣina ọmọ Afuyẹ. Ọwọ baba mi ni mo ti jogun iṣẹ yii, ti mo ba ti de lati ileewe nigba ti mo wa ni kekere ni mo maa n jokoo ti wọn ti mo fi kọ ọ.O ti pe ọgbọn ọdun ti mo ti n ba iṣẹ yii bọ. Ọjọ iwaju iṣẹ yii dẹ daa pupọ, nitori nigba tawọn baba temi n ṣe e, ko daa to bayii, o ṣi maa daa ju bayii lọ lẹyin tiwa naa.Mo n ba awọn eeyan bọ Ogun, ki i ṣe pe irin nikan ni mo n rọ. Mo maa n lọ s’Ekoo lọọ ba wọn b’Ogun, owo nla ni mo dẹ maa n gba bọ.‘’Ti aje ba wa daadaa, mo maa n pa to ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọrun-un kan naira (100,000) lojumọ. Owo ipabi Eṣu la maa n kọkọ gba, ẹgbẹrun marun-un niyẹn. Awọn to wa n bọ Ogun maa n mu aja wa, wọn n mu adiẹ wa, wọn n mu ẹlẹdẹ naa wa, koda, wọn maa n mu ijapa wa. A dẹ maa gbowo iṣẹ pe a ba wọn bẹ ẹ s’Ogun.‘‘Bi mo ṣe wa yii, Ogun n ṣe ohun ti mo fẹ fun mi, beeyan ba niṣoro, wọn aa ni ko lọọ bọ Ogun lọdọ Afuyẹ. To ba dẹ ti ṣe e, ọna aa la, Ogun n ṣe e.‘‘Mi o le lọ si ṣọọṣi tabi mọṣalaaaṣi, bii pe mo yọjuran lọ ni, nigba to jẹ gbogbo ohun ti mo fẹ l’Ogun n ṣe fun mi nibi, ti mo ba dẹ ba awọn eeyan bọ Ogun, ohun ti wọn ba fẹ maa n bọ si i, kin ni mo waa fẹẹ maa lọ si ṣọọṣi tabi mọṣalaaṣi fun.Looootọ, baba mi kirun ku ni tiwọn ni, ṣugbọn emi o kirun ri, ohun ti mo maa ṣe ku ni mo gbe dani yii, ti mo dẹ maa fi le ọmọ lọwọ.Awọn pasitọ kan gan-an maa n waa bọ Ogun lọdọ wa laaarọ ki wọn too lọ si ṣọọṣi, ti wọn ba ti sọ fun un pe ko lọọ bọ ọ lati dena Eṣu, ki wahala ma baa ṣẹlẹ. Ko kuku ni i de ṣọọṣi ko lọọ sọ fun wọn pe oun ti bọ Ogun, aarọ kutu lo ti maa wa sibi ta a ti maa ba a bọ ọ.Ṣe ẹ tiẹ ri Ogun tiwa yii, Ogun Fẹdira ni (Federal) iyẹn ni pe gbogbogboo ni. Ko sibi ti wọn ko ti n waa bọ ọ. Wọn n bọ ọ lati ilu oyinbo bo ṣe wa yii, lati Amẹrika ati London. Wọn maa fowo ranṣẹ, a maa ba wọn bọ ọ nibi, a dẹ maa fi fọto ẹ ranṣẹ si wọn.Mo ṣi ba ẹnikan bọ ọ laipẹ yii lẹyin to fowo ranṣẹ, mo dẹ fi fọto ẹ ranṣẹ si i.Ohun ti mo fẹẹ sọ fawọn eeyan wa ni pe ki wọn ma gbagbe iṣẹṣe, Ọlọrun wa loootọ ṣugbọn a ko gbọdọ fi awọn ohun ta a ba laye silẹ, o yẹ ka maa ṣe wọn lọ ni.ALAROYE ba obinrin alakọwe kan to gbe mọto waa bọ Ogun yii lọdọ Agbẹdẹ Afuyẹ, Abimbọla Yusuf lorukọ ẹ. Obinrin giga rọgbọdọ naa sọ pe wọn ni koun waa bọ Ogun loun ṣe wa, oun ko le ma bọ ọ lẹẹẹmeji loṣu, oun si n ri iṣẹ rẹ lara oun.Abimbọla to mu akukọ adiẹ waa bọ Ogun naa sọ pe bi ṣọọṣi tabi mọṣalaaṣi ba ya, oun n lọ, ṣugbọn Ogun yii naa ko ṣee ma bọ nitori iyẹn ni tiwa nilẹ Yoruba, atọhunrinwa lẹsin Kristẹni ati ti Musulumi."},{"question":"What is the national sport of Japan?","answer":"Sumo wrestling"},{"question":"س264- في أي عام تم تتويج الملكة إليزابيت ملكة على المملكة المتحدة ؟","answer":"ج264- عام 1953"},{"question":"කෝපි නිෂ්පාදනය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කෝපි නිෂ්පාදනය (Coffee production) යනු කෝපි ශාකයේ ඵල, කොපි නම් වන පානය බවට හැරවීමේ කාර්මික ක්‍රියාවලිය වේ. සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටවල් බොහොමයක වන කුටුම්භ මිලියන 12.5 පමණ ප්‍රධාන ආදායම් මාර්ගය වන්නේ කෝපි නිෂ්පාදනය යි."},{"question":"句子1: 系统理论的基础可以在朱利安·斯图尔德的\\"季节变化在爱斯基摩人\\"中看到, 后来在马塞尔·莫斯的作品中重现. 第二句:系统理论的基础可以在朱利安·斯图尔德的\\"爱斯基摩人的季节变化\\"中看到,后来在马塞尔·莫斯的作品中得到回应. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"السؤال: للمستقيمين المتعامدين زاوية الميل نفسها. هل العبارة صحيحة. إن كانت خاظدطئة صححها؟","answer":"الإجابة: للمستقيمين المتوازيين زاوية الميل نفسها."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 法務省によると、今年、出入国在留管理庁など入管の職員からだと言う、うその電話が増えています。電話では「パスポートに問題が見つかったため、あなたをつかまえることが決まった」などとうそを言って、お金を払うように言います。レストランなどには、うその書類が来ました。日本に住むための資格のルールが厳しくなったため、働いている外国人の銀行の口座などを教えるように書いてあります。法務省の齋藤大臣は「出入国在留管理庁が、このような電話をかけたり、書類を送ったりすることはないので、気をつけてください。日本に住む外国人に被害がないようにしていきます」と話しました。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。- 法務省: 1）裁判や法律に関した仕事をする、国の役所。- 職員: 1）役所・学校・団体などに勤めている人。- パスポート: 1）国が発行する、外国旅行に必要な身分証明書。旅券。- 書類: 1）書き物。必要なことを書き記した書きつけ。文書。- 資格: 1）何かをするときの、その人の身分や立場。2）ある職業などにつくための必要な条件。- ルール: 1）規則。決まり。- 口座: 1）銀行などでお金の出し入れのために設けられた、元になる帳簿。- 大臣: 1）内閣を構成し、国の政治で、もっとも責任のある役。また、その役の人。総理大臣と国務大臣とがある。2）昔、天皇のもとで政治を行った、いちばん上の役。また、その人。- 被害: 1）損害を受けること。また、受けた害。"},{"question":"മഞ്ഞുണ്ടാക്കുന്ന യന്ത്രങ്ങളെ കുറിച്ച് ആളുകൾക്ക് എന്തിന് ആശങ്കയുണ്ടാകണം? മുകളിലുള്ള ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഒരു ഖണ്ഡിക എഴുതുക. അത് 1 - 20 വാക്യങ്ങളാകാം. പശ്ചാത്തലം:","answer":"ഒന്നാം ലോകമഹായുദ്ധത്തിനു ശേഷമുള്ള കാലഘട്ടത്തിൽ സ്വിസ്, ഓസ്ട്രിയൻ നഗരങ്ങളിൽ സ്കീ ലിഫ്റ്റുകൾ നിർമ്മിച്ചു, ശൈത്യകാല സന്ദർശകരെ ഉൾക്കൊള്ളാൻ, എന്നാൽ വേനൽക്കാല ടൂറിസം തുടർന്നും പ്രധാനമായിരുന്നു; ഇരുപതാം നൂറ്റാണ്ടിന്റെ മധ്യത്തോടെ ഡൺഹിൽ സ്കീയിംഗിന്റെ ജനപ്രീതി വളരെയധികം വർദ്ധിച്ചു, കാരണം ഇത് കൂടുതൽ ആക്സസ് ചെയ്യാവുന്നതാക്കി. 1970 കളിൽ ഫ്രാൻസിൽ നിരവധി പുതിയ ഗ്രാമങ്ങൾ നിർമ്മിച്ചു. ലെസ് മെനുയേഴ്സ് പോലുള്ള സ്കീയിംഗിന് മാത്രമായി സമർപ്പിച്ചിരിക്കുന്നു. ഈ ഘട്ടം വരെ ഓസ്ട്രിയയും സ്വിറ്റ്സർലൻഡും ശൈത്യകാല കായിക വിനോദത്തിനുള്ള പരമ്പരാഗതവും ജനപ്രിയവുമായ ലക്ഷ്യസ്ഥാനങ്ങളായിരുന്നു, എന്നാൽ ഇരുപതാം നൂറ്റാണ്ടിന്റെ അവസാനത്തിലും ഇരുപത്തിയൊന്നാം നൂറ്റാണ്ടിന്റെ തുടക്കത്തിലും ഫ്രാൻസ്, ഇറ്റലി, ടൈറോൾ എന്നിവിടങ്ങളിൽ ശൈത്യകാല സന്ദർശകരുടെ എണ്ണം വർദ്ധിക്കാൻ തുടങ്ങി. 1980 മുതൽ ഇന്നുവരെ, സ്കീ ലിഫ്റ്റുകൾ ആധുനികവൽക്കരിക്കുകയും പല റിസോർട്ടുകളിലും മഞ്ഞ് ഉണ്ടാക്കുന്ന യന്ത്രങ്ങൾ സ്ഥാപിക്കുകയും ചെയ്തു, ഇത് പരമ്പരാഗത ആൽപിൻ സംസ്കാരത്തിന്റെ നഷ്ടത്തെക്കുറിച്ചും ശൈത്യകാല സ്കീ വ്യവസായം അതിവേഗം വികസിച്ചുകൊണ്ടിരിക്കുകയും വേനൽക്കാല ടൂറിസ്റ്റുകളുടെ എണ്ണം കുറയുകയും ചെയ്യുന്നതിനാൽ സുസ്ഥിര വികസനത്തെക്കുറിച്ചുള്ള ചോദ്യങ്ങൾക്ക് കാരണമാകുന്നു."},{"question":"O que significa o movimento 'Remetidos os Autos para Distribuição'?","answer":"O movimento 'Remetidos os Autos para Distribuição' indica que os autos do processo foram remetidos para distribuição a uma vara ou órgão judiciário específico. É uma etapa inicial do trâmite processual."},{"question":"චන්ද්‍රයාන් 3 මෙහෙයුම දියත් කරන දිනය කුමක්ද?","answer":"2023 ජූලි 14 දින චන්ද්‍රයාන් 3 මෙහෙයුම දියත් කරනු ලැබුවේය."},{"question":"පොත් හැදුවේ ඇයි?","answer":"ඒවා කතන්දර කීමට, ඉතිහාසය ලේඛනගත කිරීමට සහ අපේ ලෝකය පිළිබඳ තොරතුරු බෙදා ගැනීමට භාවිතා කර ඇත. පොත් සාදන ආකාරය කාලයාගේ ඇවෑමෙන් පරිණාමය වී ඇතත්, අතින් ලියන ලද, පිටු මත මුද්‍රණය කළ හෝ අන්තර්ජාලය හරහා ඩිජිටල්කරණය කළද, ඒවායේ අවශ්‍යතාවය සදාකාලිකව පවතී."},{"question":" \\"天下兴亡,匹夫有责\\"是哪位思想家的名言?A黄宗羲 B顾炎武 C王夫之 D王充","answer":"B顾炎武"},{"question":"காட்சி: வேகமான மென்பொருள் மேம்பாட்டு நிறுவனத்தில் நீங்கள் குழுத் தலைவராக உள்ளீர்கள். உங்கள் குழு உறுப்பினர்களில் ஒருவரான தயாளன், பணிகளை முடிக்க எடுக்கும் நேரத்தை தொடர்ந்து அதிகமாக  செலவிடுகிறார்  மற்றும் திட்ட காலக்கெடுவை அடிக்கடி தவறவிடுகிறார். குழு வெற்றி விகிதத்தை மேம்படுத்தவும், திட்ட இலக்குகளை அடையவும் இந்தச் சிக்கலை எவ்வாறு கையாள்வது?","answer":"பதில்:      இந்த சிக்கலைத் தீர்க்க, அவரது நேர மதிப்பீடு மற்றும் காலக்கெடு செயல்திறன் பற்றி விவாதிக்க ஒரு உரையாடலைத் தொடங்குவேன். உரையாடலின் போது, தவறவிட்ட காலக்கெடு மற்றும் குழு  திட்டங்களில் அவற்றின் தாக்கம் பற்றிய குறிப்பிட்ட உதாரணங்களை வழங்குவேன். பணி காலங்களை துல்லியமாக மதிப்பிடுவதில் அவர் எதிர்கொள்ளும் சவால்கள் குறித்து நான் தயாளனிடம் கேட்பேன்.    அனுபவமின்மை அல்லது தெளிவற்ற தேவைகள் போன்ற சாத்தியமான மூல காரணங்களையும் நான் ஆராய்வேன். ஒன்றாக, அவரது நேர மேலாண்மை மற்றும் மதிப்பீட்டுத் திறன்களை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கான உத்திகளில் நாங்கள் பணியாற்றுவோம், இதில் வழிகாட்டுதல், பயிற்சி அல்லது பணிகளை சிறிய பகுதிகளாகப் பிரிப்பது ஆகியவை அடங்கும். பணி மதிப்பீட்டிற்கு தயாளன் மிகவும் யதார்த்தமான அணுகுமுறையை உருவாக்க உதவுவதும், ஆதரவான மற்றும் ஆக்கபூர்வமான சூழ்நிலையை பராமரிக்கும் போதும்  ஒட்டுமொத்த குழு உற்பத்தித்திறனை மேம்படுத்துவது  இலக்காகும்."},{"question":"काकडी किव्हा टरबूज यांसारख्या फळभाज्यांमध्ये पाण्याचे प्रमाण किती असते?A. 90 टक्केB. 50 टक्केC. 92 टक्के D. 80 टक्के","answer":"C. 92 टक्के "},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Manaova Zavatra Mba .................................. \\"","answer":"\\"  Manaova Zavatra Mba Hitiavan'olona Anao \\""},{"question":"Kí ni ìjì ní ède Gẹ̀ẹ́sì?","answer":"Storm."},{"question":"请问“不可同日而语”这句谚语是什么意思？","answer":"这句话直译为不能在同一时间谈论，也形容不能相提并论,不能相比。"},{"question":"Soalan: Siapakah penyanyai wanita yang menyanyikan All of the Lights. Jawapan:","answer":"Rihanna"},{"question":"வினா: வானவில்லில் 7 வண்ணங்கள் உள்ளன என்று கண்டுபிடித்தவர்?","answer":"விடை: ஐசக் நியூட்டன்"},{"question":"பின்வரும் சொற்றொடரை முடிக்கவும்:சுபேதார் மேஜர் யோகேந்திர சிங் யாதவ்(பரம வீர் சக்கர விருதாளர்) 1999-இல் நடைபெற்ற:","answer":"கார்கில் போரின் போது, புலி மலையை (டைகர் ஹில்) கைப்பற்றுவதற்கு, பாகிஸ்தான் படைகளுக்கு எதிரான இவரது வீர தீரச் செயல்களை பாரட்டும் விதமாக இந்திய இராணுவத்தின் மிக உயரிய பரம வீர் சக்கர விருது இவருக்கு 1999-இல் வழங்கப்பட்டது."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--हातचे सोडून पळत्याच्या मागे लागणे","answer":"जे आपल्या हातात आहे ते सोडून दुसरे मिळेल या आशेने हातातली संधी सोडणे."},{"question":"வினா : திணை வழுவமைதி சான்று தந்து விளக்குக. ","answer":"திணை திணை உயர்திணை, அஃறிணை என இருவகைப்படும். மக்கள், தேவர், நரகர் முதலியோர் ஆறறிவு படைத்தவர் ஆதலின் அவர் உயர்திணை ஆவர். இவர்களைத் தவிர்த்த உயிர் உள்ளவையும் இல்லாதவையும் அஃறிணையாகும்.மக்கள் தேவர் நரகர் உயர்திணைமற்றுயிர் உள்ளவும் இல்லவும் அஃறிணை                                 (நன்னூல் :261)6.1.1 திணை வழுநிலை சொற்றொடர்களில் ஒரு திணைக்கு உரிய பெயரைப் பயன்படுத்துகிற போது அத்திணைக்கு உரிய வினையைக் கொண்டுதான் முடிக்க வேண்டும். அவ்வாறு முடிக்காவிட்டால் அது திணை வழுவாகும்.(எ.டு.)   அப்பா வந்தது.இச்சொற்றொடரில் ‘அப்பா' என்னும் பெயர் உயர்திணைக்கு உரியது. இச்சொல் எழுவாயாக வந்துள்ளது. ‘வந்தது' என்பது வினைப் பயனிலை. இஃது அஃறிணைச் சொல், அப்பா என்னும் உயர்திணை எழுவாய்க்கு, முடிக்கும் சொல்லாக ‘வந்தது' இடம்பெற்றுள்ளது. இவ்வாறு உயர்திணை எழுவாய்க்கு அஃறிணையும், அஃறிணை எழுவாய்க்கு உயர்திணையும் பயனிலையாக வருவது வழுவாகும்."},{"question":"ما هي الزكاة؟\\t","answer":"\\tالزكاة هي إخراج جزء من المال للفقراء والمساكين، وهي ركن من أركان الإسلا"},{"question":"Кто стал первым царём России?","answer":"Иван IV Грозный стал первым русским царём."},{"question":"Vraag: In welk jaar werd de slavernij afgeschaft in Nederland? A. 1789 B. 1806 C. 1848 D. 1863","answer":"Antwoord: D. 1863"},{"question":"ਕੀ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਸੋਨਮ ਕਪੂਰ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹੋ?","answer":"ਸੋਨਮ ਕਪੂਰ (ਜਨਮ ੯ ਜੂਨ ੧੯੮੫) ਇੱਕ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਬਾਲੀਵੂਡ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਅਨਿਲ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੀ ਪੁੱਤਰੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਲੀਵੂਡ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਫੈਸ਼ਨੇਬਲ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਹਸਤੀ ਮੰਨੀ ਗਈ ਹੈ।ਕਪੂਰ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਫਿਲਮੀ ਪੇਸ਼ਾ ੨੦੦੫ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੰਜੇ ਲੀਲਾ ਭੰਸਾਲੀ ਦੀ ਫਿਲਮ ਸਾਂਵਰਿਆ ਨਾਲ ਕੀਤਾ। ਇਸ ਫਿਲਮ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਸੋਨਮ ਕਪੂਰ ਨੂੰ ਉੱਤਮ ਨਵੀਂ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀ ਫਿਲਮਫੇਅਰ ਅਵਾਰਡ ਨਾਲ ਵੀ ਸਨਮਾਨਿਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ।== ਮੁੱਢਲਾ ਜੀਵਨ ==ਸੋਨਮ ਕਪੂਰ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਚੇਮਬੁਰ, ਮੁੰਬਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਇਆ। ਸੋਨਮ ਕਪੂਰ ਅਨਿਲ ਕਪੂਰ ਤੇ ਸੁਨੀਤਾ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੀ ਪੁਤਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਸੁਰਿੰਦਰ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੀ ਪੋਤੀ ਹੈ। ਸੋਨਮ ਕਪੂਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਤਿੰਨ ਭਰਾ ਤੇ ਭੈਣਾ ਵਿੱਚੋ ਵੱਡੀ ਹੈ। ਸੋਨਮ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੀ ਭੈਣ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਰੀਆ ਕਪੂਰ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਭਰਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹਰਸ਼ਵਰਧਨ ਕਪੂਰ ਹੈ।ਸੋਨਮ ਕਪੂਰ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਮੁੱਢਲੀ ਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਆਰੀਆ ਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਮੰਦਿਰ ਜੁਹੂ ਤੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਫੇਰ ਸਿੰਘਾਪੁਰ ਚਲੀ ਗਈ। ਸੋਨਮ ਕਪੂਰ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ, ਹਿੰਦੀ, ਪੰਜਾਬੀ, ਉਰਦੂ ਤੇ ਮਰਾਠੀ ਬੋਲ ਲੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਸੋਨਮ ਕਪੂਰ ਇੱਕ ਨਿਪੰਨ ਨ੍ਰਿਤ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਵੀ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਬੋਨੀ ਕਪੂਰ ਅਤੇ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਸੰਜੇ ਕਪੂਰ ਦੀ ਭਤੀਜੀ ਹੈ; ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਸ਼੍ਰੀਦੇਵੀ ਅਤੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਮੋਨਾ ਸ਼ੌਰੀ (ਬੋਨੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਪਤਨੀਆਂ) ਉਸ ਦੀ ਮਾਸੀ ਹਨ। ਕਪੂਰ ਦੇ ਚਚੇਰੇ ਭਰਾ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਅਰਜੁਨ ਕਪੂਰ, ਜਾਨਵੀ ਕਪੂਰ ਅਤੇ ਮੋਹਿਤ ਮਾਰਵਾਹ ਹਨ, ਅਤੇ ਮਾਮੇ ਦੇ ਦੂਜੇ ਚਚੇਰੇ ਭਰਾ ਰਣਵੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਹਨ।ਇਹ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਜੁਹੂ ਦੇ ਉਪਨਗਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਆ ਗਿਆ ਜਦੋਂ ਕਪੂਰ ਇੱਕ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਦਾ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਜੁਹੂ ਦੇ ਆਰਿਆ ਵਿਦਿਆ ਮੰਦਰ ਸਕੂਲ, ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਇੱਕ \\"ਸ਼ਰਾਰਤੀ\\" ਅਤੇ \\"ਲਾਪਰਵਾਹ\\" ਬੱਚਾ ਹੋਣ ਦਾ ਇਕਰਾਰ ਕੀਤਾ ਜੋ ਲੜਕਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਧੱਕੇਸ਼ਾਹੀ ਕਰੇਗੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਰਗਬੀ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਸਕਟਬਾਲ ਵਰਗੀਆਂ ਖੇਡਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਨਦਾਰ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕੀਤਾ, ਅਤੇ ਕਥਕ, ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰੀ ਸੰਗੀਤ ਅਤੇ ਲਾਤੀਨੀ ਨਾਚ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿਖਲਾਈ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤੀ। ਕਪੂਰ, ਜੋ ਹਿੰਦੂ ਧਰਮ ਦਾ ਅਭਿਆਸ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਕਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ \\"ਬਹੁਤ ਹੀ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ\\" ਹੈ, ਅਤੇ ਇਹ \\"ਆਪਣੇ-ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਯਾਦ ਦਿਵਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਤਰੀਕਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਧੰਨਵਾਦ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਹੈ।\\"ਕਪੂਰ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਨੌਕਰੀ 15 ਸਾਲ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਵੇਟਰੈਸ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੀ, ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਇਹ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਇੱਕ ਹਫ਼ਤਾ ਚੱਲੀ ਸੀ। ਇੱਕ ਅੱਲ੍ਹੜ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਭਾਰ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਕੀਤਾ: \\"ਮੇਰੇ ਕੋਲ ਭਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੀ ਹਰ ਸਮੱਸਿਆ ਸੀ ਜੋ ਮੈਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੀ ਸੀ। ਮੈਂ ਤੰਦਰੁਸਤ ਸੀ, ਮੇਰੀ ਚਮੜੀ ਖਰਾਬ ਸੀ, ਅਤੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਚਿਹਰੇ 'ਤੇ ਵਾਲ ਉੱਗ ਰਹੇ ਸਨ!\\" ਕਪੂਰ ਸੀ ਇਨਸੁਲਿਨ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਰੋਧ ਅਤੇ ਪੋਲੀਸਿਸਟਿਕ ਅੰਡਾਸ਼ਯ ਰੋਗ, ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਨਿਦਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਸ਼ੂਗਰ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਜਾਗਰੂਕਤਾ ਵਧਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਪਹਿਲ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਹੈ। ਕਪੂਰ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਪ੍ਰੀ-ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਲਈ ਸਿੰਗਾਪੁਰ ਦੇ ਯੂਨਾਈਟਿਡ ਵਰਲਡ ਕਾਲਜ ਆਫ਼ ਸਾਊਥ ਈਸਟ ਏਸ਼ੀਆ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲਾ ਲਿਆ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਥੀਏਟਰ ਅਤੇ ਕਲਾਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੁੰਬਈ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਦੇ ਪੱਤਰ ਵਿਹਾਰ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਅਰਥ ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰ ਅਤੇ ਰਾਜਨੀਤੀ ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰ ਦੇ ਕੋਰਸ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤੇ, ਈਸਟ ਲੰਡਨ ਯੂਨੀਵਰਸਿਟੀ ਤੋਂ ਵਾਪਸ ਆਉਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਉਹੀ ਵਿਸ਼ਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਬੈਚਲਰ ਡਿਗਰੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤੀ ਪਰ ਉਹ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋਣ ਦੇ ਤੁਰੰਤ ਬਾਅਦ ਮੁੰਬਈ ਵਾਪਸ ਆ ਗਈ। ਅਦਾਕਾਰਾ ਰਾਣੀ ਮੁਖਰਜੀ, ਇੱਕ ਪਰਿਵਾਰਕ ਮਿੱਤਰ, ਬਲੈਕ (2005) 'ਤੇ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਛੁੱਟੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿੰਗਾਪੁਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਣ ਗਈ ਸੀ। ਕਪੂਰ, ਜੋ ਅਸਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਅਤੇ ਲੇਖਕ ਬਣਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਸੀ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਚਾਲਕ ਦਲ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਇੱਛਾ ਜ਼ਾਹਰ ਕੀਤੀ। ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਸੰਜੇ ਲੀਲਾ ਭੰਸਾਲੀ ਨੂੰ ਉਸਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫਾਰਸ਼ 'ਤੇ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਹਾਇਕ ਨਿਯੁਕਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ।ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਿਰੀਖਣਾਂ ਦੇ ਬਾਅਦ== ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੂਚੀ ==== ਹਵਾਲੇ =="},{"question":"*ما هي الصلاة التي قتل في أثناءها عمر بن الخطاب ؟","answer":"صلاة الفجر"},{"question":"फोटोमिटर","answer":"फोटोमिटर विद्युत चुम्बकीय विकिरणको शक्ति नाप्ने यन्त्र हो। "},{"question":"Trong một hộp có 1 quả bóng xanh và 9 bóng vàng có kích thước giống nhau. An lấy ra đồng thời 2 bóng từ hộp, hỏi có tất cả bao nhiêu kết quả có thể xảy ra?A.1B.2C.3D.4","answer":"Trả lời:Các kết quả có thể xảy ra là: (1 xanh + 1 vàng) ; (2 vàng).Vậy có 2 kết quả có thể xảy ra.Đáp án cần chọn là: B"},{"question":"第一句: 约翰尼·<unk>罗斯, 一个富有的和<unk>的医生的富有的儿子, 加入了一个汽车盗<unk>团伙在法国被他的父亲拒绝买车后. 第二句话: 一个富有的和<unk>坏的医生的富有的儿子, 约翰尼<unk>罗斯加入了一个汽车盗<unk>团伙在法国被他的父亲拒绝了车. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"相同"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Apple, Samsung và Honor thống trị thị trường smartphone","answer":"Theo nghiên cứu từ Omdia, thị trường điện thoại thông minh toàn cầu trong quý 2/2022 có phần kém hơn cùng kỳ năm trước. Từ tháng 4 đến tháng 6 năm nay, có tổng cộng 293,7 triệu điện thoại thông minh được xuất xưởng. Con số này thấp hơn đáng kể so với quý 1/2022 (307,7 triệu máy) và quý 2/2022 (303,3 triệu máy). Trong đó, Apple, Samsung và Honor chiếm số lượng smartphone được bán ra lớn nhất. Theo nghiên cứu, Samsung dẫn đầu thị trường trong quý 2/2022 với tổng số 62,2 triệu điện thoại được xuất xưởng, vượt qua Apple đạt 48,9 triệu máy. Theo Omdia, doanh số ổn định từ Samsung Galaxy A13 và dòng Galaxy S22 đã đóng góp vào kết quả tích cực của công ty. Các ông lớn Trung Quốc như Xiaomi, Oppo và Vivo lần lượt đứng thứ ba, thứ tư và thứ năm. Tuy nhiên, ba công ty này lại ghi nhận kết quả kém hơn so với cùng kỳ năm 2021. Điều này cho thấy thị trường điện thoại thông minh rõ ràng đang chịu những hạn chế của lạm phát toàn cầu. Trong khi đó, các thương hiệu như Motorola và Tecno lại có kết quả tốt hơn năm ngoái. Motorola đã cải thiện danh mục điện thoại thông minh của mình với những sản phẩm thực sự thú vị hơn như Moto Edge 30 Pro. Về phần Tecno, hãng liên tục đẩy mạnh các sản phẩm smartphone mới song song với việc phát triển công nghệ để đối đầu với những ông lớn. Honor, tiền thân là thương hiệu con của Huawei đã có thể đứng cùng hàng ngũ với Apple và Samsung với một kết quả ấn tượng. Cho đến nay, Honor vẫn tập trung vào thị trường Trung Quốc với mục tiêu trở thành Huawei mới. Honor đạt doanh số bán hàng tăng 125,4% so với cùng kỳ năm ngoái. Công ty đứng thứ sáu với hơn 15,1 triệu thiết bị được xuất xưởng. Sắp tới, Honor cũng tham gia IFA 2022 (triển lãm thương mại điện tử tiêu dùng và thiết bị gia dụng) tại Đức. Điều này cho thấy Honor đang có những bước đi táo bạo để trở thành hãng sản xuất điện thoại hàng đầu thế giới. Thái Hoàng (Theo Gizchina)"},{"question":"ભરૂચ સિંગ ઘરે બનવાની રીત .","answer":"ભરૂચ સિંગસામગ્રી:ઘઉંનો લોટ - ૧ કપચણાનો લોટ - ૧/૨ કપમીઠું - ૧ ચમચીહળદર - ૧/૨ ચમચીગરમ પાણી - જરૂર મુજબતેલ - શેકવા માટેભરણ માટે:ડુંગળી - ૧ટામેટાં - ૨મરચું - ૨-૩હળદર - ૧/૨ ચમચીલાલ મરચું પાવડર - ૧/૨ ચમચીજીરું - ૧ ચમચીધાણાજીરું - ૧/૨ ચમચીમીઠું - ૧ ચમચીરીત:૧. ઘઉંના લોટ, ચણાના લોટ, મીઠું અને હળદરને મિક્સ કરીને થોડું ગરમ પાણી ઉમેરીને નરમ લોટ બાંધી લો.૨. ડુંગળી, ટામેટાં અને મરચાંને છીણી લો.૩. એક કડાઈમાં તેલ ગરમ કરો અને તેમાં જીરું અને ધાણાજીરું નાખીને તતડાવો.૪. ત્યારબાદ તેમાં ડુંગળી, ટામેટાં અને મરચાં નાખીને સાંતળી લો.૫. તેમાં હળદર, લાલ મરચું પાવડર અને મીઠું નાખીને થોડીવાર સાંતળી લો.૬. ભરણ તૈયાર થઈ જાય પછી તેને ઠંડુ થવા દો.૭. લોટને થોડો પાતળો લપેટી લો.૮. લપેટી પર ભરણ નાખો અને તેને ઢાંકીને બંને છેડાઓને મળાવી દો.૯. ભરૂચ સિંગને તેલમાં શેકીને બંને બાજુથી સોનેરી બ્રાઉન થાય ત્યાં સુધી તળી લો.૧૦. ભરૂચ સિંગ તૈયાર છે. ગરમ-ગરમ પીરસો."},{"question":"フランス語で「稲妻」という意味を持つお菓子で、細長いシュークリームの上にチョコレートをかけたものといえば何でしょう？","answer":"エクレアです。"},{"question":"ਇਸ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਸ਼ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਸਾਨ ਜਥੇਬੰਦੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਵੀਰਵਾਰ ਦੀ ਬੈਠਕ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੱਦ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ। ਅੱਜ ਕਿਸਾਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਕੇਂਦਰ ਨਾਲ ਮੁੜ ਤੋਂ ਮੀਟਿੰਗ ਹੈ।ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਨੇ ਡੇਢ ਸਾਲ ਬਾਅਦ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਾਨੂੰਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਭਵਿੱਖ ਬਾਰੇ ਸਮਝਣ ਲਈ ਖੇਤੀ-ਆਰਥਿਕਤਾ ਦੇ ਮਾਹਰ ਡਾ. ਸਰਦਾਰਾ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੌਹਲ, ਆਰਥਸ਼ਾਸਤਰੀ ਪ੍ਰੋ. ਰਣਜੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ, ਸੀਨੀਅਰ ਪੱਤਰਕਾਰ  ਜਗਤਾਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਅਤੇ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਤੇ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਮਾਮਲਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਜਾਣਕਾਰ ਡਾ. ਪ੍ਰਮੋਦ ਕਮੁਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕੀਤੀ।ਮਾਹਰਾਂ ਨੇ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਇਸ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਸ਼ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਜਿੱਤ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਇਹ ਸਵਾਲ ਵੀ ਚੁੱਕਿਆ ਕਿ ਮੁਅਤਲੀ ਦੀ ਮਿਆਦ ਪੁੱਗਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਾਨੂੰਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਬਣੇਗਾ।ਇਹ ਵੀ ਸਪਸ਼ਟ ਹੋਇਆ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਸ਼ ਤੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਤ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਜਿਸ ਐਮਰਜੈਂਸੀ ਨਾਲ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਪਾਸੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਸਨ, ਸਸਪੈਂਡ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਤੋਂ ਲਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਹੁਣ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਕੋਲ ਉਹ ਐਮਰਜੈਂਸੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।ਕਿਸਾਨਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਮੁਅਤਲੀ ਦੀ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਸ਼ ਰੱਦ।ਕਿਸਾਨ ਜਥੇਬੰਦੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਸਤਾਵ ਰੱਦ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਫ਼ੈਸਲੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਕਿਸਾਨ ਆਗੂ ਬਲਬੀਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਰਾਜੇਵਾਲ ਨੇ ਮੀਡੀਆ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕੀਤੀ ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਅਸੀਂ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਤਾਵ ਨੂੰ ਰੱਦ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਅੱਜ ਆਪਣੀ ਰਣਨੀਤੀ ਤਿਆਰ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਅੱਜ ਸਵੇਰੇ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਬੈਠਕ ਹੋਈ। ਅਸੀਂ ਸਾਫ਼ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਕਿ ਟਰੈਕਟਰ ਪਰੇਡ ਰਿੰਗ ਰੋਡ 'ਤੇ ਕਰਾਂਗੇ। ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਾਸਨ ਤੇ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਸਾਡਾ ਸਾਥ ਦੇਵੇ।\\"ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਲੋਕਤੰਤਰ 'ਚ ਕਿਸਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਖਰੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਦਾ ਗਣਤੰਤਰ ਦਿਵਸ ਮਨਾਉਣ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾਵੇ। ਅਸੀਂ ਬਿਲਕੁਲ ਵੀ ਹਿੰਸਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਵਾਂਗੇ। ਜੇ ਹਿੰਸਾ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ ਤਾਂ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਵਲੋਂ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ।\\"","answer":"ਕਿਸਾਨ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ: ਕੀ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਖੇਤੀ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਲਾਗੂ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਵਾਲੀ ਐਮਰਜੈਂਸੀ ਹੁਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਰਹੀ?"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు భావం రాయండి:చ. అటసని యశ్రమంబున హిమాచలమున్ సమతిక్రమించి వారవులు భూములున్ నదులు నద్రులునుం గడుఁ బెక్కు లంచితోత్కట ధృఢయోగసేవననితాంత నిరాకుల వర్తనంబు నొందుట గతభేదులై కడచి తూలక మేరుసమీప భూమికిన్.","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :అటసని = అలా వెళ్ళుతూహిమాచలమున్ = హిమాలయ పర్వతాన్నిసమతిక్రమించి = దాటివారు = ఆ ఏడుగురు (పాండవులు, ద్రౌపది, కుక్క)అటవులు = అడవులనుభూములున్ = భూములునదులున్ = నదులనుఅద్రులునుం = పర్వతాలనుకడున్ = పెక్కింటినిఅంచిత = ఒప్పుచున్నట్టుఉత్కట = అధికమైనదృఢయోగ సేవనన్ = దృఢమైన యోగంతోనిరాకుల వర్తనంబును = నిరాకులమైన మనస్సుతోఒందుట = పొందిగతఖేదురై = శోకాన్ని విడచినవారైకడచి = దాటుకునితూలక = చలించకఅశ్రమంబున = ఆయాసమన్నది లేకమేరుసమీప = మేరు పర్వతానికి దగ్గరగాభూమికిన్ = ప్రాంతానికి చేరుకున్నారు.భావము :పిదప వారు హిమాలయాన్ని దాటి అడవులు భూములు, నదులు, కొండలు పెక్కింటిని దృఢమైన యోగంతో, నిరాకుల మనస్సులతో, శోకాన్ని విడిచిన ఆయాస మన్నది లేక, మేరు పర్వత ప్రాంతానికి చేరుకున్నారు."},{"question":"கேள்வி : அம்பிகாபதியின் தந்தை பெயர் என்ன ? ","answer":"பதில் : கம்பர்"},{"question":" CGST/SGST दंड लागू करताना कोणत्या सर्वसाधारण शिस्तींचे पालन केले पाहिजे?","answer":"दंड लादणे/वसूल करणे हे काही विशिष्ट शिस्तविषयक व्यवस्थेच्या अधीन आहे, जे न्‍यायशास्त्र, नैसर्गिक न्‍यायतत्त्वे अणि आंतरराष्ट्रीय व्यापार आणि करार व्यवस्था नियंत्रित करणाऱ्या तत्त्वांवर आधारित आहे. सदर सर्वसाधारण शिस्तीबाबतची तत्त्वे अधिनियमाचा कलम 126 मध्ये जतन केलेली आहेत. त्याप्रमाणे :कारणे दाखवा नोटिस निर्गमित  केल्याशिवाय आणि प्रकरणाची योग्य सुनावणी झाल्याशिवाय शिक्षा/दंड लादता येणार नाही, ज्या व्यक्‍ती विरुध्द कार्यवाही चालू असेल त्याला त्याच्याविरुध्द लावण्यात आलेल्या आरोपांचे खंडन करण्याची संधी दिली पाहिजे;प्रकरणाची संपूर्ण वस्तुस्थिती आणि परिस्थितीवर शिक्षा/दंड अवलंबून असले पाहिजेत;लादलेली शिक्षा/दंड याचे प्रमाण आणि तीव्रता, कायद्यातील तरतूदी किंवा आरोपित नियम यांचा भंग केल्याच्या प्रमाणात असली पाहिजे;दंड लादण्याबाबतच्या आदेशात कायदाभंगाचे स्वरूप स्पष्टपणे नमूद केले पाहिजे;कायद्याच्या ज्या तरतूदी अंतर्गत दंड लादला गेला आहे त्या स्पष्टपणे नमूद केल्या पाहिजेत;तसेच कलम 126 मध्ये स्पष्टपणे/तपशीलवार नमूद केले आहे की विशेषत: निम्ननिर्देशित बाबींसाठी मोठ्या प्रमाणात शिक्षा/दंड लादण्यात येऊ नये :-कोणत्याही लहान कायदेभंगासाठी (लहान कायदेभंग याची अशी व्याख्या करण्यात आली आहे की जेथे तरतुदीचे उल्लंघन केलेल्या प्रकरणात कराची रक्‍कम  रु.5000/- पेक्षा कमी आहे), किंवाकायद्याच्या कार्यपध्दतीची आवश्यकता, किंवादस्तऐवजातील सहजपणे सुधारता येण्याजोगी चूक/वगळलेली गोष्ट (कायद्यात सांगितल्याप्रमाणे नोंदीतील स्पष्टपणे दिसणारी चूक) जी चूक कोणत्याही लबाडीच्या उद्देशाने किंवा संपूर्ण दुर्लक्षतेमूळे झालेली नाही.तसेच CGST/SGST अधिनियमात जेथे निश्चित रक्‍कमेचा दंड किंवा निश्चित टक्‍केवारी यांची तरतूद केलेली आहे, तीच तरतूद लागू होईल."},{"question":"¿Dónde se encuentra la basílica de la Sagrada Familia?","answer":"Esta basílica católica se encuentra en la ciudad de Barcelona."},{"question":"Amelia Earhart ගුවන් නියමුවරියක් සහ උපදේශකවරියක් ලෙස ගුවන් සේවයේ කාන්තාවන්ගේ ප්‍රගමනයට දායක වූයේ කෙසේද?","answer":"Amelia Earhart ගුවන් සේවයේ කාන්තාවන් ඉදිරියට ගෙන යාම සඳහා ප්‍රධාන කාර්යභාරයක් ඉටු කළාය. ඇය කාන්තාවන් සඳහා පළමු මහාද්වීපික ගුවන් ධාවන තරඟය සංවිධානය කළ අතර කාන්තා ගුවන් නියමුවන්ට සහාය වීම සඳහා පිහිටුවන ලද සංවිධානයක් වන අනූනවයේ පළමු සභාපතිනිය ලෙස සේවය කළාය. අර්හාර්ට් වෙනම කාන්තා ගුවන් සේවා වාර්තා සඳහා බලපෑම් කළ අතර කාන්තාවන්ගේ ආර්ථික ස්වාධීනත්වය සහ ගුවන් සේවා ආරක්ෂාව ප්‍රවර්ධනය කළාය."},{"question":"¿Qué es y para que sirve Tensorflow extended?","answer":"Tensorflow extended (TFX) es un framework creado por Google, en el que se simplifica la implementación de la secuencia de componentes del aprendizaje de automático, que va desde la ingesta de los datos, el entrenamiento y validación del modelo, hasta la puesta en producción. Se puede usar cada componente individual, pero su principal función es ayudar a los desarrolladores a desplegar modelos de forma ágil."},{"question":"Ukungcweka ngumdlalo omnandi kakhulu lapho izinsizwa zizwana khona amandla.Zisuke zingenanxa nalowo ezingcwekisana naye kodwa ziqinisana ukhakhayi ukuzezizohloniphana, kwaziwe ukuthi ubani ingqwele. Insizwa kumele iqinelwe ukhakhayiukuze ingabi lula uma ihlangene nezinye izinsizwa. Ingazitholaphi izibongo insizwauma ingumnqolo ogumbetsheni umachoba izintwala zikanina? Izibongo akuyona intoolala ungenayo uvuke ekuseni usunayo kodwa zingamagalelo akho obuqhawe.Izibongo zensizwa zisuke zichaza imivimbo enayo emzimbeni eyithole kade ilwa, ivika,ithubeleza kunzima.Ukuba nezibongo eziningi ukuthola ekungcwekeni ngoba usuke usufana nenkunziemidwayidwa. Noma bengakubhaxabula kanjani ezimbanjeni kodwa ikhanda ngekebalinuke uma uyiqhawe ngoba uzobe ulivikela ngazo zonke izindlela. Uma sekuphelileukungcweka akukho muntu obambela omunye igqubu. Phela izinsizwa amabhubesi,ziyaphelezelana zifike zigezane igazi emfuleni. Hhiya Zulu, kusuke kungempi phelakodwa kusuke kungcwekwa nje.1. Bhala imisho EMIBILI eqondile eyakhe umusho ombaxa osemgqeni","answer":"Ukuba nezibongo eziningi ukuthola ekungcwekeni.√ Usuke usufana nenkunzi emidwayidwa.√"},{"question":" Sheeg, Wax Marka Ay Siyaadaan Sii Naaqusa?","answer":" Jawaabtu waa Dayaxa."},{"question":"No contexto da biologia, explique o significado de RNA.","answer":"O RNA, ou ácido ribonucleico, é uma molécula crucial para a expressão genética. Ele atua na transferência das informações do DNA para a síntese de proteínas, desempenhando um papel fundamental no processo de tradução."},{"question":"Gbólóhùn tó fi àsìkò afànámónìí hàn ni","answer":"ó lo sí Èkó"},{"question":"Fungsi dari Bendungan adalah sebagai berikut, kecuali?A. Penyediaan air baku. B. Penanggulangan banjirC. Observasi benda-benda langitD. Obyek wisataJawaban:","answer":"Observasi benda-benda langit bukanlah termasuk fungsi Bendungan. Jadi jawaban dari pertanyaan di atas adalah C."},{"question":"Baskı Balata uğultu yapar mı?","answer":"Uğultu olsa debriyaja basınca uğultunun kesilmesi lazım arkadaşın ki sürtme gibi oluyormuş ve sürekli oluyormuş. baskı balata yenilenince ses yapmaz rodajda sadece kalkış esnasına biraz ses yapar ya takılışında yanlışlık var yada teker bilyalarından veya şanzumandan geliyordur kullanmayın sorun büyüyebilir."},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?Wallaahi xam ngeen ña jalgati woon ci yéen ca Gaawu ba. Tax ñoom ñooñu Nu ne leen: \\"Nekkleen di ay golo yu ñu beddi! \\"","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:Wallaahi xàm ngéen ña jàlgatiwoon ci yéen ca Gaawu ba. Tàx ñoom ñooñu Nu ne léen: \\"Nekkleen di ay golo yu ñu beddi!\\""},{"question":"Waa immisa qaybood tawxiidkumaxayse kala yihiin?","answer":"Tawxiidka waxaa loo qaybiyaa saddex qaybood oo kala ah (qeexidda magacyada tawxiidka ee kala duwan waxaad ka fahmi suáalaha ku xiga)."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Trưa 31/7, Công an tỉnh Thừa Thiên - Huế đã bắt giữ nghi phạm cướp tiệm vàng gần chợ Đông Ba, TP Huế. Theo nhân chứng, nghi phạm đã xả khoảng 5 phát súng vào tiệm vàng Hoàng Đức. Người đàn ông này lấy vàng trong tủ rồi tung ra giữa đường. Sau đó, nghi phạm chạy đến tiệm vàng Thái Lợi, cách tiệm vàng Hoàng Đức khoảng 20 m, rồi để cướp vàng rồi tiếp tục vứt ra ngoài đường. Sau đó, người đàn ông này chạy về hướng cầu Gia Hội và cố thủ ở nhà Lục Giác. Đại tá Đặng Ngọc Sơn, Phó giám đốc","answer":"Công an tỉnh Thừa Thiên - Huế, cho biết sau khi thực hiện vụ cướp tiệm vàng, nghi phạm cầm súng chạy về phía sông Hương. \\"Nghi phạm đòi tự sát nhưng sau đó muốn gặp đích thân tôi. Một lúc sau, tôi đã gặp nghi phạm, giải thích sự việc và nghi phạm đã hạ vũ khí, được công an dẫn giải về trụ sở làm việc\\", ông Sơn cho hay. "},{"question":" د نوي اداري ریفورم پیغامونه ؟","answer":"ځواب – – د پخواني او غير مؤثر تشکيلتو لغوه کول ۲ - د مخفي بیکاریو له منځه وړل ۳ – د معصري عامه ادارې د سیستم پراختیا ۴ – د کار موندني د ډولونو پراخوالی – د بشري منابعو د کاري وړتیاوو درلودل ۶ – د ظرفیتونو د پراختیا په موخه دآازادي سیالۍ له الري استخدام ترسره کول ۷ – د اداري فساد له منځه وړل ۸ – له تبعیض پرته ادارې رامنځته کول ۹ – د ټولني وګړو ته د ټوليزي اسوده ګي رامنځته کول "},{"question":"కొత్తగా కనుగొన్న జీవికి శాస్త్రీయ నామాన్ని ఇవ్వడానికి పాటించే సూత్రాలను పేర్కొనండి.","answer":"జీవశాస్త్ర నామాలు లాటిన్ భాషలో ఉండి, ఇటాలిక్ వ్రాయబడతాయి.జీవశాస్త్ర నామంలోని మొదటి పదం ప్రజాతిని, రెండోది జాతి నామమును తెలియజేస్తుంది.జీవశాస్త్ర నామంలోని రెండు పదాలను చేతితో వ్రాసినప్పుడు వేరువేరుగా పేరుకింద గీతగీయాలి. లేదా ముద్రణలో అయితే ఇటాలిక్లలలో సూచించాలి.ప్రజాతిని సూచించే మొదటి పదం పెద్ద అక్షరంతోను, జాతి నామాన్ని సూచించే రెండోపదం చిన్న అక్షరంతోను ప్రారంభమవుతాయి.శాస్త్రీయ నామం చివర ఆ జీవిని వర్ణించిన కర్త పేరు క్లుప్తంగా ఉంటుంది."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Drakou tävlade i två grenar för Grekland vid olympiska sommarspelen 2012 i London. Hon blev utslagen i semifinalen på","answer":"50 meter frisim och i försöksheatet på 4 x 100 meter frisim. Vid olympiska sommarspelen 2016 i Rio de Janeiro blev Drakou utslagen i försöksheatet på 50 meter frisim."},{"question":"Como você criaria um jogo divertido usando apenas papel e caneta?","answer":"Uma possível solução é criar um jogo de adivinhação, onde um jogador desenha algo em um pedaço de papel, e o outro jogador tenta adivinhar o que é. O jogador que desenha pode escolher entre diferentes categorias, como animais, objetos, lugares, pessoas famosas, etc. O jogador que adivinha tem um tempo limite para fazer perguntas de sim ou não, e pode dar um palpite a qualquer momento. O jogo termina quando o jogador que adivinha acerta o desenho, ou quando o tempo acaba. O jogador que acertar mais desenhos ganha o jogo."},{"question":"\\"ඔබ රූ සිරියෙන්\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න ","answer":"ඔබ රූ සිරියෙන් මන්මත් වී මමනොකෙලෙමි අනුවණ කම්මුලා වුණේ ඔබ මුලා නොවිමි මමමනමේ කුමාරියේඔබ රූ සිරියෙන් ඔහු නැණ ගුණයෙන්මාගේ විජිතය කෙලෙසී යනු දැකසටන් වැදිමි මම සටන් වැදිමි මමමනමේ කුමාරියේහැඩි දැඩි අප හට හුරු වූ වන ගැබඅපගේ උරුමය රකිනා රිසියෙන්සටන් වැදිමි මම සටන් වැදිමි මමමනමේ කුමාරියේඑඩ්වඩ් ජයකොඩිස්වර්ණ ශ්‍රී බණ්ඩාරඅමරදේව"},{"question":" गायत्री मंत्र कोणत्या पुस्तकामध्ये लिहिलेला आहे?उत्तर : ","answer":"ऋग्वेद"},{"question":"ጥያቄ፡ የትንሿ ፓንዳቫስ እናት ናት? መልስ፡ ","answer":"ማድሪ"},{"question":"Complete o seguinte trecho: É uma igreja de nave octogonal e de lados desiguais, barroca, de tipologia pouco vista no Algarve. Foi bastante afectada pelo","answer":"sismo de 1755, e a sua reconstrução prolongou-se até 1768. Do seu interior resta uma capela com uma abóbada tardo-medieval com as armas de famílias nobres (Melo, Costa). O retábulo principal apresenta uma pintura em \\"trompe l'oeil\\"; possui quatro retábulos, sendo dois do período rococó e os restantes do neo-clássico. Nos retábulos laterais, podem ser vistas as imagens de Nossa Senhora do Carmo e de Santa Teresa, ambas do extinto Convento do Carmo de Tavira."},{"question":"Tôi là người trẻ tuổi, đi làm tích lũy được 1,3 tỷ đồng. Thu nhập hàng tháng sau khi trừ chi phí tầm 20-30 triệu đồng. Tôi chưa có gia đình và ở cùng bố mẹ tại TP HCM.Với điều kiện tài chính trên, tôi nên mua đất ở hay đầu tư mua nhà chung cư hình thành trong tương lai?","answer":"Bạn đang phân vân giữa việc mua đất ở (đất thổ cư) hay mua nhà chung cư hình thành trong tương lai. Tôi xin nêu những ưu và nhược điểm của hai lựa chọn này xét trên các phương diện sau.Trước hết là về hiệu suất sinh lợi kỳ vọng. Thông thường, khi thị trường bất động sản không bị thanh khoản kém hoặc đóng băng, giai đoạn trước khi nhận bàn giao căn hộ là lúc mang lại nhiều lợi nhuận cho người mua nhất. Ở những thời điểm sau khi dự án cất nóc hoặc ngay khi nhận bàn giao, người mua có thể chuyển nhượng và có lợi nhuận từ 25-50% giá trị khoản tiền đã thanh toán cho chủ đầu tư.Trường hợp người mua nắm giữ căn hộ lâu dài, thống kê của các công ty bất động sản cho thấy mức tăng giá bình quân hàng năm của căn hộ như sau. Nếu khách nắm giữ căn hộ dưới 3 năm (tính từ khi nhận bàn giao đến lúc bán) có thể đạt mức tăng giá 10% một năm; nắm giữ dưới 6 năm, mức tăng giá khoảng 8% một năm. Ngoài ra, căn hộ chung cư sau khi nhận bàn giao còn tạo ra dòng tiền với hiệu suất cho thuê khoảng 4-6% một năm (hiệu suất tính trên tỷ lệ giữa thu nhập cho thuê chia cho giá trị căn hộ).Tuy nhiên, có một đặc điểm cần lưu ý là sau 6 năm kể từ khi nhận bàn giao, tốc độ tăng giá của căn hộ sẽ bão hòa và gần như chỉ tăng rất ít qua các năm. Những số liệu trên thống kê dựa trên những căn hộ có giá 4-5 tỷ đồng trở xuống. Với những căn hộ giá trị cao hơn, các con số kể trên sẽ thấp hơn.Còn đối với đất ở, hiệu suất tăng trưởng về giá thông thường sẽ tăng đều giữa các năm. Tuy nhiên, hiệu suất tăng giá chỉ đạt mức bình quân 8-9% một năm với đất ở trung tâm TP HCM và có thể đạt mức 10-12% đối với đất ở vùng ven hoặc lên đến 15% một năm với đất ở tại các tỉnh xa TP HCM."},{"question":"مجھے ایک مذاق سنائیں","answer":"ایک امیر آدمی نے شاپنگ سینٹر کے سامنے گاڑی کھڑی کی اور بے پرواہی کے ساتھ گاڑی کی چابی گاڑی میں چھوڑ کر شاپنگ سینٹر کے اندر جانے لگا۔ شاپنگ سینٹر کے گارڈ نے ان کے قریب آ کر کہا۔”جناب! آپ کو ملک کے حالات تو معلوم ہوں گے‘ آئے دن گاڑی چوری کی وار داتیں ہوتی رہتی ہیں اور آپ نے گاڑی کی چابی گاڑی میں چھوڑ دی ہے؟“ ان صاحب نے بے نیازی سے کہا۔ ”کوئی بات نہیں گاڑی انشورڈ ہے؟“ گارڈ نے گاڑی کی طرف اشارہ کرتے ہوئے کہا ”اور وہ محترمہ گاڑی میں بیٹھی ہوئی ہیں ان کی بھی انشورنس کروائی ہوئی ہے۔“"},{"question":"කල්පිත සිංහල හොල්මන් කතාවක් ලියන්න ","answer":"මම ඇත්තටම හොල්මන් අවතාර විශ්වාසය කරපු කෙනෙක් නෙවෙයි . මගේ නැන්දා  පිලිකාවක් හැදිලා හොදටම අමරු වෙලා හිටියේ . එයාට ලමයි හිටියෙත් නැහැ . එයා ටිකක් විතර නපුරුයි . එයාට පිලිකාවක් හැදිලා තියෙනවා කියලා අපි දැනගත්තෙ එයාගෙ ජිවිතෙ විශ්වාස කරන්න අමාරුයි කිය්ලා දොස්තරලා කිව්වට පස්සෙ අපේ අම්මගෙ මල්ලි ගෙ නොනා තමා නැන්දා එයා ව cancer hospital එකෙන් ගෙදරට එවලා තිබුනා ඉතින් මෙ ගැන අපිට අපෙ මාමාත් හැණ්ගුවා එදා හරියටම වෙලාව 5.15 විතර ඇති ඉරිදා උදෙ පල්ලි යන්න ඔනා නිසා අපි නැගිටිනිවා .උදෙන්ම එ දවස් වල cartoon යනවා මම බල බල හිටියෙ. අම්මා කුස්සියේ තේ හදලා මගෙ අතට ගෙනල්ලා දුන්නා එතකොටම මමයි අම්මයි දෙන්නාම දැක්කා අපෙ නැන්දා දොර ලග හිටගෙන ඉන්නවා නයිටියකුත් ඇදගෙන අම්මා කතා කළා නංගි එන්න ඇතුලට කා එක්කද අවෙ ඇයි මේ වෙලාවෙ අවේ කියලා ඇහුවා එයා අපි දිහා බලාගෙන ඉදලා අපෙ පිටිපස්සෙ පැත්තට යන්න ගියා ඉස්සර අපේ toilet එක තිබුනේ පිටිපස්සෙ ඉතින් අම්මා කිව්වා එයා toilet එකට යන්න ඇති කියලා එතකොටම විනාඩ් 2ක් වත් ගියෙ නැ මාමා කොල් කලා අම්මගෙ phone එකට නැන්දා නැතිඋනා කියලා අඩ අඩ කිව්වා. මට හින් දාඩියත් දැම්මා .එතකොට කවුද හිටගෙන හිටියෙ ?එ නැන්දා කියලා අම්මායි මමයි දෙන්නාම දැක්කා සමහර විට එයා මැරිලා අපිව බලලා යන්න ආවද ? එක නම් තාම අපිට හිතා ගන්න බැ"},{"question":"*ما القارة الوحيدة التي لا توجد بها طائر النحام؟","answer":"أستراليا"},{"question":"Beqil ma mbind mii:Wote bi nu dëgmal, ñépp xam na ñu ko, wote bu jeggi dayoo la: ndax ci la ëllëgu réew mi aaju! Wote tànn la wan yoon la Senegaal war a teggu jëm ca kanam mbaa mu teggi ko, dellu gannaaw: lawla cat! Wante li ñu soxal ci jukki bii, lu lëkkëloog loolu gaa, wante leneen la. Loo xam ne soo ko seetloo, dafa mel ni dafa am jàllarbi ci ni “politiciens” di jëfandikoo làkki réew mi! Li ñu leen doon faral di wax mooy: demokaraasi ci làkki-jambuur ay kácci neen la, mënu la nekk! Ndax demokaraasi mooy nguuru askan wi ngir askan wi!","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Wote bi nu dëgmal, ñépp xàm na ñu ko, wote bu jéggi dayo la: ndàx ci la ëllag u réew mi aju! Wote tànn la, wàn yoon la Senegaal wàr a tegu jëm ca kanam mbaa mu teggi ko, dellu gannaaw: lawla càt!Waante li ñu soxal ci jukki bii, lu lëkkaloo'g loolu gaa, waante leneen la. Loo xàm ne soo ko seetloo, da fa mel ni da fa àm jàllarbi ci ni \\"politiciens\\" di jëfandikoo làkk i réew mi! Li ñu léen doon faral di wàx moo'y: demokaraasi ci làkk i jaambur ay kàcc i neen la, manul a nekk! Ndàx demokaraasi moo'y ngùur u àskan wi ngìr askan wi!"},{"question":"Damaa réer.","answer":"I’m lost."},{"question":"ආසියාව ගැන කෙටි විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"ආසියාව යනු ලොව විශාලතම සහ ජනාකීර්ණම මහාද්වීපය යි. එය පිහිටා  ඇත්තේ පෘථිවියේ නැගෙනහිර සහ උතුරු අර්ධගෝලවලය. පෘථිවියේ මුළු මතුපිට වර්ගඵලයෙන් 8.6%ක් හෙවත් මුළු භූමි ප්‍රමාණයෙන් 29.9%ක් එයට අයත් වෙයි. එහි බිලියන 4ක ජන ප්‍රමාණයක් ජීවත් වෙන අතර මෙය වත්මන් ලෝක ජනගහණයෙන් 60%කි. 20 වැනි සියවස තුළ ආසියාවේ ජනගහණය සිව් ගුණයකින් වැඩි විය.ආසියාව අර්ථ දක්වා ඇත්තේ සූවස් ඇළෙන්, යූරල් කඳුවලින්, කොකේසස් කඳුවලින්, කැස්පියන් මුහුදෙන් සහ කළු මුහුදෙන් නැගෙනහිරින් පිහිටි යුරේසියාවේ නැගෙනහිර භූමි කොටස ලෙසයි. යුරේසියාවේ බටහිර භූමි කොටස යුරෝපය යි. ආසියාව නැගෙනහිරින් පැසිපික් සාගරයෙන් ද, දකුණින් ඉන්දියන් සාගරයෙන් ද, උතුරින් ආක්ටික් සාගරයෙන් ද මායිම් වී ඇත."},{"question":"የዚህን አንቀጽ ቀጣይነት ይጻፉ - ኤልሳ ኤልሳቤጥ ሞንቴሮሶ (የተወለደው ታህሳስ 13 ቀን 1971) ከ 1500 ሜትር እስከ ግማሽ ማራቶን ርቀት ላይ የተወዳደሩ የጓቲማላ የቀድሞ የረጅም ርቀት ሯጭ ናቸው ። በ 1990 ዎቹ እና በ 2000 ዎቹ ውስጥ ንቁ ነበር ። በ 2003 በፓን አሜሪካን ጨዋታዎች አገሯን ወክላ ሁለት ጊዜ የመጨረሻ ተወዳዳሪ ሆናለች ። በ 2000 IAAF የዓለም ግማሽ ማራቶን ሻምፒዮና ላይ በዓለም አቀፍ ደረጃ ሁለት ጊዜ ተወዳድራለች።","answer":"እና የ2004 አይኤኤኤፍ የዓለም አገር አቋራጭ ሻምፒዮናዎችም ተወዳድራለች።"},{"question":"Ayat 1: Dittionario giorgiano e italiano adalah kamus dalam bahasa Georgia dan bahasa Itali. Ayat 2: Dittionario giorgiano e italiano adalah kamus dalam bahasa Itali dan bahasa Georgia. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama?","answer":"Ya."},{"question":"volana inona no manaraka ny volana jolay?","answer":"volana septambra no volana manaraka ny jolay"},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: \\"CĐ Hà Nội vận động tham gia phòng chống sốt xuất huyết và các bệnh dịch\\".","answer":"Theo đó, Liên đoàn Lao động Thành phố yêu cầu Liên đoàn Lao động quận, huyện, thị xã; Công đoàn ngành; Công đoàn cấp trên trực tiếp cơ sở, Công đoàn cơ sở và các đơn vị trực thuộc Liên đoàn Lao động Thành phố đẩy mạnh công tác tuyên truyền, vận động cán bộ, đoàn viên, công nhân viên chức lao động thực hiện nghiêm các biện pháp phòng, chống dịch COVID-19 và các bệnh dịch mùa hè khác tại địa phương, đơn vị. Trong đó tập trung thực hiện nghiêm, linh hoạt, hiệu quả 3 trụ cột phòng, chống dịch COVID-19 (xét nghiệm, cách ly, điều trị); Công thức 2K (Khẩu trang, Khử khuẩn) + vaccine + thuốc + điều trị + công nghệ + ý thức người dân và các biện pháp khác, gắn với thực hiện tốt việc khối phục và phát triển kinh tế - xã hội. Yêu cầu các Liên đoàn Lao động quận, huyện, thị xã; Công đoàn ngành; Công đoàn cấp trên trực tiếp cơ sở, Công đoàn cơ sở, đặc biệt là Công đoàn các Khu công nghiệp và chế xuất Hà Nội cần chủ động tham mưu cấp ủy, đồng thời tích cực tham gia, phối hợp với chính quyền, chuyên môn đồng cấp và người sử dụng lao động để triển khai quyết liệt các giải pháp đẩy mạnh công tác tiêm chủng, không để tình trạng vaccine không được sử dụng kịp thời, gây lãng phí. Chủ động phối hợp với ngành Y tế địa phương trong việc triển khai chiến dịch tiêm vaccine  phòng COVID-19 mũi 3, mũi 4 trên địa bàn Thành phố; đẩy mạnh công tác tuyên truyền sâu rộng trong đoàn viên, công nhân viên chức lao động về đối tượng tiêm chủng, lợi ích, ý nghĩa của việc tiêm vaccine phòng COVID-19; tích cực tham gia kiểm tra, giám sát việc triển khai công tác tiêm chủng tại địa phương, đơn vị. Đối với dịch sốt xuất huyết và các bệnh dịch khác, tập trung tuyên truyền, vận động, hướng dẫn để đoàn viên, công nhân viên chức lao động chủ động tham gia phòng, chống dịch bệnh; chú trọng triển khai công tác phòng, chống dịch bệnh tại các khu vực di biến động về dân cư, khu vực có ổ dịch cũ, đặc biệt là tại các khu vực tập trung đông công nhân lao động đang sinh hoạt, làm việc trong các khu công nghiệp, khu chế xuất, cụm công nghiệp trên địa bàn Thành phố. Liên đoàn Lao động Thành phố Hà Nội yêu cầu thủ trưởng các cơ quan, đơn vị trực thuộc Liên đoàn Lao động Thành phố chịu trách nhiệm trong lãnh đạo, chỉ đạo triển khai thông tin, tuyên truyền, vận động cán bộ, đoàn viên và công nhân viên chức lao động thực hiện hiệu quả công tác phòng, chống dịch COVID-19, đề cao kỷ luật, kỷ cương, trách nhiệm của người đứng đầu, tuyệt đối không được chủ quan, lơ là, mất cảnh giác trước dịch bệnh; tiếp tục tham gia thực hiện mục tiêu kiểm soát dịch bệnh, không để dịch bùng phát trở lại."},{"question":"Gịnị bụ azịza gwam gwam gwam(riddle) aGwa m ihe nọ n'azụ ụlọ nne gị na-agbọ gị taa","answer":"Ọ bụ Ụkpaka/Ugba"},{"question":"බහුජාතික සමාගමක් (MNC) යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"බහුජාතික ව්‍යවසාය (MNE) හෝ transnational Corporation (TNC) ලෙසද හඳුන්වන බහුජාතික සමාගමක් (MNC) යනු අවම වශයෙන් එක් රටක භාණ්ඩ හෝ සේවා නිෂ්පාදනයේ හිමිකාරීත්වය සහ පාලනය කරන ආයතනික සංවිධානයකි."},{"question":"I was looking","answer":"I was looking towards a research for a passage in the scripture and while at it, I received this revelation about the handiwork of God towards the world by announcing who He is throughout all generations. It is an interesting strategy that is worth taking cognizance of. The scripture in Exodus, specifically mentioned the frustration seen in the eyes and felt in the heart of the children of Israel as they journey out from the land of their slavery to where they are led to worship the Most High God.They were overwhelmed by the situation and couldn’t believe the report of Moses from the Lord regarding their present circumstances. How many have been told about what the Lord is set to do regarding their predicament and what has been their response or attitude towards the report. It is so saddening that many are conversant and have adopted been perplexed by receiving and accepting report of men rather than that of God.When we look vividly at their situation, it didn’t bother God because He has promised Abraham that He will bring them out of the land of servitude.Therefore, I put this before us, who’s report do you believe? Your circumstances or of God whom circumstances bow. It is time to gain more understanding about the God of all flesh. He said in His word, “I am the God of all flesh, is there anything too hard for me?”"},{"question":"Bu yazı hangi olayla ilgilidir?: Aralık ayında Ambrose, Owens'ı 'de yenerek ilk kez Kıtalararası Şampiyonluğu kemerini kazandı. Aralık ayında Owens'a karşı ve Ocak 2016'da Ziggler'a karşı kemerini başarıyla savundu. Ambrose, daha sonra WWE Dünya AĞırsiklet Şampiyonluğu için yapılan 2016 Royal Rumble maçında finale kaldı ve maçı kazanan Triple H'e elendi. Ertesi gece \\"Raw\\" programında Ambrose'un Fastlane'de Reigns ve Brock Lesnar'la üçlü tehdit maçında karşılaşacağını, kazananın WrestleMania 32 ana etkinliğinde Triple H ile WWE Dünya Ağırsiklet Şampiyonluğu maçına çıkacağını açıkladı. 15 Şubat \\"Raw\\" programında Ambrose, Kıtalararası Şampiyonluğu kemerini beş yönlü maçta savunmaya zorlandı. Owens'ın Tyler Breeze'i tuşlamasıyla kemeri kaybetti.","answer":"Bu yazı, Aralık ayında Dean Ambrose'un Kevin Owens'ı yenerek Kıtalararası Şampiyonluğu kemerini kazanması ve sonrasında yaşanan gelişmelerle ilgilidir."},{"question":"Дүйнөдө төрт нерсе жок. - бул эмне?","answer":"Дүйнөдө төрт нерсе жок.Тооктун киндиги жок, Деңиздин капкагы жок, Көрпөнүн жеңи жок, Асмандын тирөөчү жок."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta ɗari ɗaya da talatin da huɗu a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 134"},{"question":"إقرأ المراجعة التالية: لابأس. ثم حلل مشاعرها.","answer":"المشاعر في المراجعة السابقة جيدة."},{"question":"Tôi năm nay 30 tuổi, đang là nhân viên văn phòng, lương khoảng 25 triệu đồng mỗi tháng. Tôi đã mua bảo hiểm nhân thọ, đóng 24 triệu đồng mỗi năm.Gần đây, bạn môi giới có giới thiệu tôi về bảo hiểm sức khỏe với quyền lợi chi trả phí khám chữa bệnh, nằm viện hoặc có tai nạn nghiêm trọng. Mức phí dao động 3,5-5 triệu đồng mỗi năm.Tôi vẫn phân vân có nên mua không, trong khi bản thân còn trẻ, sức khỏe vẫn tốt. Hãy cho tôi lời khuyên.","answer":"Thắc mắc của bạn cũng là thắc mắc chung của nhiều người về việc một người tạo ra thu nhập nên sở hữu những loại bảo hiểm nào. Tôi sẽ giải đáp thắc mắc trên như sau.Đầu tiên, nhất thiết phải sở hữu bảo hiểm y tế. Nếu chưa có, bạn nên mua trong thời gian sớm nhất. Nếu có rồi, đây là bảo hiểm bạn nhất thiết phải giữ, mặc dù chi phí bảo hiểm y tế sẽ tăng lên 972.000 đồng mỗi năm từ ngày 1/7 tới đây cho người thứ nhất trong gia đình mua bảo hiểm. Người thứ hai, thứ ba và thứ tư lần lượt đóng bằng 70%, 60% và 50% mức phí của người thứ nhất. Lý do tăng phí là mức đóng bảo hiểm y tế được quy định bằng 4,5% mức lương cơ sở. Từ ngày 1/7, Việt Nam sẽ tăng cơ sở từ mức 1,49 triệu đồng lên mức 1,8 triệu đồng mỗi tháng. Do đó, mức đóng phí bảo hiểm y tế cũng tăng theo.Chúng ta đang có hệ thống bảo hiểm toàn dân rất tốt so với thu nhập và chi phí sinh hoạt. Điều kiện duy nhất là thời gian chờ 30 ngày (thời gian chưa được bảo hiểm kể từ ngày mua), không phân biệt tình trạng sức khỏe, bệnh tồn tại trước đây hay tuổi tác quá cao. Nếu so sánh với các nước, để được hưởng bảo hiểm y tế tương tự, người dân sẽ phải đóng phí với tỷ lệ khá cao so với thu nhập. Nếu so với mức thu nhập 25 triệu đồng mỗi tháng của bạn, bảo hiểm y tế chỉ chiếm 0,32% thu nhập, trong khi ở các nước có thể mất 10 lần con số trên hoặc hơn.Tiếp theo, hiểu về rủi ro và cách đối phó với các loại rủi ro. Các loại rủi ro về tài sản và con người có thể phân chia theo hai tiêu chí: tần suất xuất hiện và mức độ ảnh hưởng. Từ đó, chúng ta có thể phân loại thành bốn nhóm rủi ro.Nhóm thứ nhất, rủi ro có tần suất thấp, ảnh hưởng ít. Đây là những rủi ro ít khi xảy ra và nếu có cũng không có hậu quả lớn, nên có thể chấp nhận được. Ví dụ, bạn bị bỏ quên hay đánh rơi đồ với giá trị vài chục nghìn cho đến vài trăm nghìn đồng.Nhóm thứ hai, rủi ro có tần suất cao, ảnh hưởng ít. Ví dụ, trong năm có đôi lần chúng ta lại bị bệnh vặt, nhẹ thì nghỉ ngơi sẽ khỏi, nặng thì nằm viện vài ngày. Với loại rủi ro này, chúng ta nên tìm cách giảm thiểu.Nhóm thứ ba, những sự kiện có thể gọi là \\"thiên nga đen\\" đối với mỗi cá nhân hoặc gia đình, tuy khả năng xảy ra rất thấp, nhưng mức độ ảnh hưởng lớn, hậu quả vô cùng nghiêm trọng. Đây là những rủi ro tử vong, tai nạn, bệnh hiểm nghèo với thiệt hại tài chính tính bằng thu nhập của nhiều năm, hoặc bằng phần lớn cho đến toàn bộ tài sản. Cách đối phó với nhóm rủi ro này là chuyển giao rủi ro cho bên thứ ba, tức mua bảo hiểm.Ngoài ra nhóm thứ tư là rủi ro có tần suất cao, ảnh hưởng lớn. Ví dụ, chúng ta đầu tư toàn bộ tài sản vào một thương vụ kinh doanh nào đó hay khi thực hiện các công việc nguy hiểm như nhảy dù, leo núi... Cách quản trị chỉ có thể là tránh né các rủi ro này.Như vậy, sau khi đã có bảo hiểm y tế, bạn nên quản trị rủi ro bằng cách mua bảo hiểm cho các sự kiện tử vong, tai nạn, bệnh hiểm nghèo. Theo thông tin được chia sẻ, bạn đã có bảo hiểm nhân thọ và đang đóng phí ở mức 24 triệu đồng, tương đương với 8% thu nhập năm. Mặc dù không được biết cụ thể hơn về quyền lợi bảo hiểm, nhưng xét về tỷ lệ thu nhập dành để mua bảo hiểm, đây là mức rất hợp lý.Vậy có bảo hiểm nhân thọ rồi có nên mua thêm bảo hiểm sức khỏe? Với thu nhập 25 triệu đồng một tháng, nếu không có người phụ thuộc hoặc chỉ có một người, bạn có thể tiết kiệm được 20% thu nhập, khoảng 5 triệu đồng. Hiện bạn đã dùng 2 triệu để mua bảo hiểm nhân thọ, bảo hiểm y tế và còn khoảng 3 triệu đồng. Nếu mua thêm bảo hiểm sức khỏe bạn có thể phải chi thêm 300.000-400.000 đồng mỗi tháng cho khoản này. Đổi lại, nếu phải nằm viện bạn có thể chọn điều trị tại các bệnh viện có điều kiện giường, phòng tốt hơn và chi phí cũng cao hơn.Thay vì nghĩ có nên thêm mua bảo hiểm sức khỏe hay không, bạn có thể tự hỏi bản thân: Nếu không chi cho bảo hiểm sức khỏe, bạn sẽ dùng số tiền này vào việc gì và việc đó có ý nghĩa với bạn ở mức độ nào? Chúng ta gọi điều này là chi phí cơ hội.Nếu chi phí cơ hội lớn, nghĩa là số tiền này được dùng vào những việc quan trọng và có ý nghĩa, bạn có thể cân nhắc tạm hoãn mua bảo hiểm sức khỏe. Bạn đang 30 tuổi, chưa phải là tuổi đạt độ chín muồi trong nghề nghiệp (thường ở tuổi 35) và vẫn có khả năng tăng thu nhập trong những năm sắp tới, khoản này có thể hoãn mua 2-3 năm đến khi có mức thu nhập cao hơn.Nhưng nếu chi phí cơ hội thấp, nghĩa là bạn sẽ tiêu số tiền này để đầu tư những tài sản mà bản thân chưa thật sự hiểu rõ hoặc là sẽ chi tiêu mua sắm trên mức cơ bản để đáp ứng những nhu cầu ngắn hạn trước mắt. Vậy nên chăng dùng số tiền này ưu tiên sở hữu thêm bảo hiểm sức khỏe ngay tại thời gian này?"},{"question":"Trizomi sebebi nedir?","answer":"Bir veya birkaç kromozomun bölünme sırasında kayıp olması veya fazla olması sonucu oluşur. Eğer eksik ise 'Monozomi', fazla ise 'Trizomi' olarak adlandırılır. · Her ikisi de mayoz bölünme sırasında ayrılamama (nondisjunction) sonucu oluşur. · Ayrılmama sıklığı büyük çoğunlukla anne yaşı ile ilgilidir."},{"question":"Historia garaikidean, nola eragiten du teknologia berriak XXI. mendeko gizartearen aldaketa, komunikazioa eta informazioaren sarrera?","answer":"Teknologia berriak komunikazioa, informazioa eta interakzioa azkartzeko gaitasuna dute. Honek gizartearen egitura, kultura eta ohiturak eraldatzen ditu, informazioa eta komunikazioa demokratizatuz."},{"question":"\\"একুশে বইমেলা\\" শিরোনামে একটি অনুচ্ছেদ রচনা করো।","answer":"আমাদের জীবনে একুশে ফেব্রুয়ারি তাৎপর্যপূর্ণ একটি দিন। এ দিনের ইতিহাস আমাদের সংগ্রামী চেতনার ইতিহাস। এ সংগ্রামী চেতনাকে স্মরণীয় করে রাখার জন্য ফেব্রুয়ারি মাসজুড়ে বিভিন্ন ধরনের আয়োজন করা হয়। এর মধ্যে অন্যতম আয়োজন হলো অমর একুশে গ্রন্থমেলা। একুশে ফেব্রুয়ারিকে স্মরণীয় করে রাখার জন্য বাংলা একাডেমি প্রতি বছর ফেব্রুয়ারি মাসে একুশে বইমেলার আয়োজন করে থাকে। বাংলা একাডেমি প্রাঙ্গণে ফেব্রুয়ারি মাসজুড়ে এই বইমেলা চলে। বইমেলা উপলক্ষ্যে বই বিক্রেতা ও প্রকাশকরা নানা সাজে বইয়ের স্টল বা দোকান সাজিয়ে বসেন। এখানে বিভিন্ন ধরনের বইয়ের সমাহার ঘটে। বইমেলা উপলক্ষ্যে প্রচুর নতুন বইমেলায় আসে। পুরোনো লেখকদের পাশাপাশি নতুন লেখকদের বইও পাওয়া যায় এই মেলায়। প্রতিদিন বইয়ের আকর্ষণে বইপ্রেমিক মানুষেরা মেলা প্রাঙ্গণে ছুটে আসেন। সাধারণ মানুষের পাশাপাশি লেখক, ভাষাবিদ ও বরেণ্য সব ব্যক্তিত্ব বইমেলায় আসেন। লেখক ও পাঠকদের আনন্দঘন এক মিলনমেলা তৈরি হয় এ মেলায়। এটি বাংলা একাডেমির একটি মহৎ উদ্যোগ ও আয়োজন। বইমেলার ফলে পাঠকেরা এক জায়গা থেকেই তাদের পছন্দের বইগুলো কিনতে পারেন। এছাড়া বই কেনার প্রতি সাধারণ মানুষের আগ্রহও তৈরি হয়। এ কারণে এই ধরনের বইমেলার প্রয়োজনীয়তা রয়েছে। একুশে বইমেলা আমাদের মধ্যে সাহিত্য-সংস্কৃতিবোধ জাগ্রত করে। এ বইমেলা এখন আমাদের জাতীয় চেতনার সাথে সম্পৃক্ত। ঢাকার বাইরে প্রতিবছর বইমেলার আয়োজন করে বইমেলা ও বইয়ের প্রতি সাধারণ মানুষের আগ্রহ বৃদ্ধি করা যেতে পারে।"},{"question":"Ya sunan \\"cat\\" da hausa(a)mage(B)kare(c)biri","answer":"(a)mage"},{"question":"Чилбарча фразеологизмдин мааниси эмне?","answer":"1. Майда-майда бөлүнүп, чачырап кетүү.2. Таш талканы чыгуу, талкалануу, кыйроо"},{"question":"පහත ඉඟි වැකියේ තේරුම කුමක්ද?\\"ඉබි ගමන\\"","answer":"\\"ඉබි ගමන\\" ඉඟි වැකියේ තේරුම යනු ඉතා සෙමින් යන්නය."},{"question":"Bana bir soğuk sandviç tarifi önerir misin? ","answer":"İşte sana harika ve bol proteinli bir soğuk sandviç tarifi: Malzemeler:- 4 adet sandviç ekmeği- 1 adet domates- 4 dilim kaşar peyniri- 4 dilim hellim peyniri- 4 yaprak marul- 8 adet salam- 4 adet hindi füme- 1 adet kırmızı soğanYapımı:  - İlk olarak tüm sebzeleri yıkayıp kurutun.- Ardından domates ve soğanları yuvarlak şekilde doğrayın.- Hellim peynirini 10 dakika suda bekletin. Ardından dilimleyerek kurumasını bekleyin.- Yağsız tavada hellim peynirini önlü arkalı olacak şekilde kızartın.- Hindi fümeleri de aynı şekilde kızartabilirsiniz.- Sandviç ekmeğini enlemesine kesin ve ilk olarak kaşar peynirini yerleştirin.- Üzerine marulu koyun. Ardından hindi jambon ve salamları yerleştirin.- Salamın üzerine hellim peyniri, soğan ve domatesleri dizin.- Sonra tekrar marul yerleştirerek ekmeğinizi kapatın.- Dilerseniz, tost makinesine bastırabilirsiniz. Afiyet olsun."},{"question":"Snippet: బొన్నువాడ శ్రీకాకుళం జిల్లా, టెక్కలి మండలంలోని గ్రామం. ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన టెక్కలి నుండి 3 కి. మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన పలాస-కాశీబుగ్గ నుండి 33 కి. మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 217 ఇళ్లతో, 851 జనాభాతో 155 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 435, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 416. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 64 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 0. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 581002[1].పిన్ కోడ్: 532201.I \\"బొన్నువాడ గ్రామ విస్తీర్ణత ఎంత?\\" ","answer":"155 హెక్టార్ల"},{"question":"கேள்வி: உற்பத்தி காரணிகள் அனைத்தும் எங்கே வாங்கப்பட்டு விற்கப்படுகின்றன? ","answer":"சந்தை"},{"question":"Inona ary izany: hohano aho hihinanako anao","answer":"sakay"},{"question":"２０１２年の流行語大賞を受賞した、ワイルドな芸風が人気をよんだお笑いタレントは誰？","answer":"スギちゃんです。"},{"question":"புதிதாக வருவோர் இரவில் தங்குவதற்கு வீட்டின் முன்புறம் திண்ணையும் அதில் தலை வைக்கத் திண்டும் அமைத்தனர்.திருவிழாக் காலங்களில் ஊருக்கு வரும் புதியவர்களையும் அழைத்து அன்போடு விருந்தளிப்பதைச் சில இடங்களில் காண முடிகிறது.இப்படியாகக் காலமாற்றம், தமிழர் விருந்தோம்பலில் ஏற்படுத்திய மாற்றங்கள் குறித்த கருத்துகளை எழுதுக.","answer":"*) அன்றைய காலத்தில் வழிப்போக்கர்களே விருந்தினராகப் போற்றப்பட்டனர்.*) காலமாற்றத்தால் நாகரிகம் என்னும் பெயரால், வழிப்போக்கர்களுக்கு விருந்தளிப்பது மறைந்து, நண்பர்களுக்கும் உறவினர்களுக்கும் மட்டுமே விருந்தளிக்கும் நிலையைத்தான் இன்று காணமுடிகின்றது.*) வழிப்போக்கர்களுக்கும், ஏழைகளுக்கும் கோவில் மற்றும் அன்னசத்திரங்கள் விருந்திட்டு வருகின்றன.*) விருந்தினர் என்று சொல்லி கயவர்கள் இன்று மக்களை ஏமாற்றுவதால் புதியவர்களை விருந்தினர்களாகப் போற்றப்படுவது 0 இல்லை.*) இன்றைய சமுதாயத்தில் தன்னலம் மேலோங்கியதால் விருந்தென்னும் பொதுநலம் குறைந்து வருகின்றது."},{"question":"ಒಗಟನ್ನು ಬಿಡಿಸಿ : ನೋಡಿದರೆ ನೋಟಗಳು ,ನಕ್ಕರೆ ನಗುಗಳು ,ಒಡೆದರೆ ತುಂಡುಗಳು.ಏನಿದು ?","answer":"ಕನ್ನಡಿ"},{"question":"女性歌手やアイドルの名前で、島津、高島、杉本、上戸（うえと）、松浦といえば、共通するファーストネームは何でしょう？","answer":"あやです。"},{"question":"භෞතික විද්‍යාවේ දී මාන ලෙස හඳුන්වන්නේ මොනවා ද?","answer":"මානයක් යනු භෞතික විචල්‍යයක සංඛ්‍යාත්මක අගයක් රහිත මිනුමකි. යාන්ත්‍ර විද්‍යාවේ දී භාවිත වන මූලික භෞතික රාශි 3කි.1. ස්කන්ධය (M)2. දිග (L)3. කාලය (T)"},{"question":"'පොරොව' විස්න්ධි වන්නේ කෙසේද?සන්ධිය කුමක්දැයි පහදා දිය හැකිද?","answer":"නාම ප්‍රකෘතිය සොයා ගන්න මුලින් ම.පොරෝ තලයපොරෝ මිටපොරෝ පහරපොරෝ + අපොරෝ + ව් + අපොරො + වපොරොව"},{"question":"Inona no renivohitr'i Espaina?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Espagna dia Madrid."},{"question":"Adivina la siguiente adivinanza: ¿Qué se encuentra una vez en un minuto, dos veces en un momento, pero ni una vez en cien años?","answer":"La respuesta es la letra \\"m\\"."},{"question":"Aṣiri tu! Wọn lawọn oloṣelu lo pa Dokita Aborode, ọmọwe to n ṣiṣẹ agbẹ n’Igangan","answer":"Lẹyin nnkan bii oṣu mẹta tawọn amookunṣika pa agbẹ aladaa nla kan lagbegbe Ibarapa, Ọmọwe Fatai Aborode, aṣiri awọn afurasi apaayan to gbẹmi ẹ ti tu, wọn niku ọkunrin ọmọwe naa lọwọ kan oṣelu ninu dipo awọn Fulani ti gbogbo aye n fura si lati ọjọ yii.Agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ, Ọyọ, CSP Olugbenga Fadeyi, ti fidi ẹ mulẹ pe awọn ọlọpaa ti mu baba ẹni ọgọrin ọdun kan ti wọn n pe ni Pa Ọlawuwo atawọn ẹmẹwa rẹ ti wọn fẹswun kan pe wọn lọwọ ninu iku ọkunrin naa.O ni “Lati ijẹta la ti gbe wọn lọ si kootu, ti ile-ẹjọ si ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn fi wọn pamọ si ahamọ ọgba ẹwọn titi digba ti igbẹjọ yoo maa tẹsiwaju” Tẹ o ba gbagbe, lọjọ kọkanla, oṣu kejila, ọdun 2020, lawọn ẹruuku lọọ ka Aborode to jẹ alaṣẹ ati oludasilẹ ileeṣẹ Kunfayakun Green Treasures Limited, mọnu oko ẹ to wa lọna Apodun, niluu Igangan, ti wọn si ṣa a ladaa yannayanna titi to fi ku.Ọkunrin ti wọn pa nipakupa yii lawọn ara agbegbe Ibarapa n wo gẹgẹ bii oluranlọwọ wọn, nitori bo ṣe pese iṣẹ fun ẹgbaagbeje eeyan to gba sinu oko nla to da siluu Igangan gẹgẹ bii oṣiṣẹ.Ni nnkan bii ọsẹ mẹta sẹyin ni gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ẹnjinnia Ṣeyi Makinde, ti naka aleebu si awọn ọlọpaa, o ni iku Aborode lọwọ oṣelu ninu, ati pe awọn agbofinro ti mọ awọn to ṣiṣẹ ibi naa, wọn kan kọ lati mu wọn ni.Ṣaaju igba naa, igbagbọ ọpọ eeyan ni pe awọn Fulani ni wọn pa baba naa, afi nigba ti iroyin deede lu sita pe ọwọ awọn ọlọpaa ti tẹ awọn to huwa ika ọhun, ati pe Yoruba ni wọn, wọn ki i ṣe awọn Fulani ti gbogbo aye foju si lara.Nigba to n jabọ iwadii to ṣe nipa iku Aborode ni nnkan bii ọsẹ mẹta sẹyin, Gomina Makinde ṣalaye pe “ariwo ti gbogbo eeyan n pa ni pe awọn Fulani lo pa Dokita Aborode. Ṣugbọn nigba ti mo ṣabẹwo si Ibarapa, mo lọ sile baba ẹ, wọn si jẹ ki n mọ pe iku Dokita lọwọ oṣelu ninu.“Wọn ni aiṣiṣẹ bii iṣẹ awọn ọlọpaa naa wa lara ohun to ṣokunfa iku Dokita Aborode.“Wọn ni ẹnikan lo fi ọkada gbe e lọ soko lọjọ yẹn. Bi wọn ṣe n ti inu oko bọ lawọn eeyan yẹn da wọn duro, ti wọn si ja Dokita Abodore silẹ lẹyin ọkada to gbe e.“Ẹni to fọkada gbe e kegbajare lọ sile fun iranlọwọ awọn eeyan.“Awọn kan naa ti wọn n ti inu oko wọn bọ ba wọn nibẹ, wọn si gbọ bi Dokita ṣe n bẹ awọn to fẹẹ pa a ati itakurọsọ to waye laarin wọn.  Mo ni ede wo lawọn to pa a n sọ, wọn lawọn àgbẹ̀ to gbọ ọrọ ti wọn n sọ lọjọ yẹn sọ pe Yoruba ni wọn n sọ.”"},{"question":"Aiza no toerana tena tian'ny olona aleha rehefa fialan-tsasatra?","answer":"Matetika dia toerana misy tora-pasika  no tian'ny olona aleha rehefa fialan-tsasatra."},{"question":"Напиши продовження тексту:  В сезоні 2006-07 років Джон приєднався до складу команди Хокейної ліги Сполучених Штатів (ЮСХЛ), Індіана Айс. В наступному сезоні зігравши за «Індіану» 59 матчів,","answer":"він набрав 43 (12+31) очка (найкращий показник серед захисників команди) та допоміг «індіанцям» потрапити в плей-оф. По закінченню сезону, Карлсона в першому раунді драфта новачків НХЛ 2008-го року потрапив до команди Вашингтон Кепіталс під номером 27."},{"question":"हे काय आहे जे कोणाला नको आहे, परंतु कोणीही गमावू पण इच्छित नाही?","answer":"न्यायालयातील खटला"},{"question":"A wace shekara aka haifi Adams Oshiomhole?","answer":"1952"},{"question":"Adesua Etomi","answer":"Adesua Etomi (tí a bí ní ọjọ́ kejìlélógún oṣù kejì ọdún 1986 tàbí 1988)jẹ́ òṣèré ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà kan. Ní ọdún 2014, ó kópa nínú fíìmù àgbéléwò kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ \\"knocking on heaven's door\\" èyí sì jẹ́ àkọ́kọ́ ṣe rẹ̀. Ní ọdún 2016,ó gba àmì ẹ̀yẹ fún òṣèrébìnrin tí ó dára jù lọ ti Africa Magic viewers choice, èyí sì wáyé látipa ìkópa rẹ̀ nínú eré kan \\"falling\\"Tolúlọpé Adesua Etomi ni a bí sí ìlú Owerri, ìpínlẹ̀ Imo State, ní ọjọ́ kejìlélógún oṣù kejì. Bàbá rẹ̀ jẹ́ ọ̀kan nínú àwọn ajagun ẹ̀yà Esan, ìyá rẹ̀ sì jẹ́ ọmọ Yoruba descent. Láàárín ọmọ mẹta tí òbí rẹ̀ bí, òun ni àbígbẹ̀yìn. Ilé-ìwé Corona ní Victoria Island, Lagos,ni ó lọ. Ibẹ̀ ni ó sì ti darapọ̀ mọ́ ẹgbẹ́ dírámà. Lẹ́yìn náà, ó lọ sí Queen's College, Lagos kí ó tó wá lọ sí United Kingdom ní ọdún kẹtàlá ayé rẹ̀. Ó padà gba ìwé-ẹ̀rí diploma nínú \\"physical theatre, musical theatre and performing arts\\" ní City College Coventry ní ọdún 2004."},{"question":"‘செல்லோடையே கலக்குண்பனவருபுனலே சிறைப்படுவன’ – இம்மெய்க்கீர்த்தி வரிகள் உணர்த்தும் பொருள் யாது?","answer":"மன்னர் தம் நாட்டின் வளத்தையும் ஆட்சிச் சிறப்பையும் காலம் கடந்தும் உணர்த்த வேண்டும் என்ற நோக்கத்திற்காக புகழும் பெருமையும் அழியாதவகையில் அவை அனைத்தையும் கல்லில் செதுக்கினார்கள். இதுவே மெய்க்கீர்த்தி பாடப்படுவதன் நோக்கமாகும்.பேரரசனது மெய்ப்புகழை எடுத்துக்கூறுவது மெய்க்கீர்த்தி, பொதுவாக இது சோழ மன்னருடைய சாசனங்களின் தொடக்கத்தில் அரசனுடைய இத்தனையாவது ஆட்சியாண்டு என்று கூறுமிடத்து அமைக்கப்பெறும். சிறப்பாக அவனுடைய போர் வெற்றிகளையும் வரலாற்றையும் முறையாகக் கூறி, அவன் தன் தேவியோடு வீற்றிருந்து நீடு வாழ்க எனக்கூறி, பிறகே சாசனம் எழுந்த நிகழ்ச்சியைக் குறிப்பிடும்.சோழ மன்னர் பரம்பரையில் மெய்க்கீர்த்தியோடு சாசனங்களைப் பொறிக்கும் வழக்கம் நெடுநாள் இருந்ததில்லை. முதல் இராசராசனுடைய எட்டாம் ஆண்டில்தான் மெய்க்கீர்த்திக் காணப்படுகிறது. இதன்கண் வமிச பாரம்பரியம் விதந்து ஓதப்படவில்லை . ஏனைய பகுதிகள் உள்ளன. எனினும் இது மிகவும் சுருக்கமாகவே உள்ளது. இன்னும் பின்வந்த மெய்கீர்த்திகளின் வமிச பரம்பரையை மிகவும் விரித்துக் கூறியுள்ளன.சோழ நாட்டில் :*) ஓடைகள் மட்டுமே கலக்கமடைகின்றன. ஆனால் மக்கள் கலக்கமடைவதில்லை.*) புனல் (நீர்) மட்டுமே அடைக்கப்படுகின்றன. ஆனால் மக்கள் அடைக்கப்படுவதில்லை"},{"question":"ЕАЭБ кыскартылган сөз кандай чечмеленет?","answer":"ЕАЭБ -Евразия экономикалык биримдиги "},{"question":"inona no litera farany indrindra amin'ny alfabeta malagasy?","answer":"Z no litera farany indrindra amin'ny alfabeta malagasy."},{"question":"桜のきれいな季節ですが、明治時代に日本から贈られた桜が咲き乱れる、ワシントン市内を流れる川は何でしょう？","answer":"ポトマック川"},{"question":"Көз карандысыздык Декларациясынын мааниси эмнеде?","answer":"Жооп: 1776-жылы кабыл алынган Көз карандысыздык Декларациясы америкалык колониялардын Англиянын бийлигинен көз карандысыздыгын жарыялап, Америка Кошмо Штаттарынын негизин түптөгөн."},{"question":"مرض فقر الدم يعرف علمياً بـ…؟","answer":" مرض الأنيميا"},{"question":"A cidade de São Paulo pertence a qual estado?","answer":"São Paulo pertence ao estado de São Paulo."},{"question":"Wọn ti ri ile ounjẹ korona ni Sagamu naa  o, lawọn eeyan ba bo o bii eṣu","answer":"O jọ pe adura ti awọn ara Ṣagamu ati ipinlẹ Ogun lapapọ ti gba lati ri ibi ti wọn tọju ounjẹ korona si nipinlẹ naa ti gba bayii pẹlu bi wọn ṣe bayii, pẹlu bi wọn ṣe ti ṣawari ibi ti ijọba tọju ounjẹ iranwọ asiko Korona si nibẹ naa, ti wọn si ti n ko kinni ọhun kẹtikẹti.Koda, ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, ni awọn ti a fọrọ wa lẹnu wo ni Ṣagamu ṣi n sọ pe awọn n wa ile ounjẹ ọfẹ yii o, ti wọn ni ko sohun to ni kipinlẹ Ogun naa ma ni ipin ninu ẹ, nitori awọn ti gbọ pe gbogbo ilu pata ni wọn pin ounjẹ ọhun fun.Afi bo ṣe di aarọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọjọ kẹrindinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹwaa yii, ti wọn ṣawari ẹ ni Ṣagamu.ALAROYE gbọ pe ibudo awọn agunbanirọ to wa ni Ṣagamu gan-an ni awọn ounjẹ naa wa. Wọn ni ninu gbọngan tawọn ọmọ naa maa n lo ni wọn ko awọn ohun jijẹ onipaali atawọn tinu apo naa si.Ẹnikan to n gbe nitosi ibẹ ṣalaye pe oru oni ni wọn ti kọkọ ṣi ibudo naa, awọn eeyan ko tete mọ. Ṣugbọn nigba ti yoo fi di ọwọ aarọ mọ ọsan, gbogbo ilu ti gbọ tan, ni wọn ba n ko ounjẹ lọ ni rabajigan.Koda, awọn ṣọja to wa nibẹ ko di wọn lọwọ, wọn fi awọn eeyan naa silẹ ki wọn maa ko o ni.ALAROYE gbọ pe awọn kan lo wa nidii ṣiṣi ti wọn ṣilẹkun ile ounjẹ yii kalẹ, ki i ṣe pe wọn ja ilẹkun wọle rara.Bo si tilẹ jẹ pe wọn ti ti i pada lasiko ti a n kọ iroyin yii lọwọ, a gbọ pe wọn yoo tun ṣi i fun wọn to ba dọwọ alẹ mọ oru ọla."},{"question":"කොවිඩ් ඩෙල්ටා ප්ලස් වයිරසය මුලින්ම වාර්තාවුන රට කුමක්ද ?","answer":"කොවිඩ් ඩෙල්ටා ප්ලස් වයිරසය මුලින්ම වාර්තාවුන රට වන්නේ ඉන්දියාව යි."},{"question":"Qual a resposta correcta para esta pergunta: Quem escreveu A Campânula de Vidro?","answer":"A resposta correcta para a questão é: Sua autora é Sylvia Plath, poeta, romancista e contista estadunidense. O livro é conhecido no Brasil como A Redoma de Vidro."},{"question":"Sheeg Magacyada Afar Wadan Ee Uu Maro Wabiga Niil?","answer":"Waxay Kala Yihiin1- Masar,2- Sudan,3- Uganda,4- Ethiopia"},{"question":"ඊජිප්තුව ගැන කෙටි විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"ඊජිප්තුව ( අරාබි: مصر‎ ), නිල වශයෙන් ඊජිප්තු අරාබි ජනරජය, යනු අප්‍රිකාවේ ඊසානදිග කෙළවරේ සහ ආසියාවේ නිරිතදිග කෙළවරේ සිනායි අර්ධද්වීපයේ විහිදී ඇති මහාද්වීපික රටකි. එය උතුරින් මධ්‍යධරණී මුහුද, ඊසාන දෙසින් පලස්තීනය සහ ඊශ්‍රායලයේ ගාසා තීරය, නැගෙනහිරින් රතු මුහුද, දකුණින් සුඩානය සහ බටහිරින් ලිබියාව මායිම් වේ. ඊසාන දෙසින් පිහිටි අකාබා බොක්ක ජෝර්දානය සහ සෞදි අරාබිය ඊජිප්තුව වෙන් කරයි. කයිරෝ ඊජිප්තුවේ අගනුවර සහ විශාලතම නගරය වන අතර දෙවන විශාලතම නගරය වන ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩ්‍රියාව මධ්‍යධරණී වෙරළ තීරයේ වැදගත් කාර්මික සහ සංචාරක කේන්ද්‍රස්ථානයකි.[14] ආසන්න වශයෙන් මිලියන 100 ක ජනගහනයක් සිටින ඊජිප්තුව ලෝකයේ 14 වැනි වැඩිම ජනගහන රට වන අතර අප්‍රිකාවේ තුන්වන වැඩිම ජනගහණයෙන් යුත් රට වන්නේ නයිජීරියාවට සහ ඉතියෝපියාවට පසුවය.ඊජිප්තුවට ඕනෑම රටකට වඩා දීර්ඝතම ඉතිහාසයක් ඇති අතර, නයිල් ඩෙල්ටාව දිගේ එහි උරුමය ක්‍රි.පූ. ශිෂ්ටාචාරයේ තොටිල්ලක් ලෙස සැලකෙන පුරාණ ඊජිප්තුව ලේඛන, කෘෂිකර්මාන්තය, නාගරීකරණය, සංවිධානාත්මක ආගම සහ මධ්‍යම ආන්ඩුව යන මුල්ම වර්ධනයන් කිහිපයක් පැවතියේය.[15] ඊජිප්තුවේ දිගු හා පොහොසත් සංස්කෘතික උරුමය එහි ජාතික අනන්‍යතාවයේ අත්‍යවශ්‍ය අංගයක් වන අතර, එය මධ්‍යධරණී, මැද පෙරදිග සහ උතුරු අප්‍රිකාව යන එහි අනන්‍ය මහාද්වීපික පිහිටීම පිළිබිඹු කරයි.[16] ඊජිප්තුව ක්‍රිස්තියානි ධර්මයේ මුල් හා වැදගත් මධ්‍යස්ථානයක් වූ නමුත් හත්වන සියවසේදී බොහෝ දුරට ඉස්ලාමීයකරණය විය. නූතන ඊජිප්තුව 1922 දක්වා දිව යයි, එය රාජාණ්ඩුවක් ලෙස බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය අධිරාජ්‍යයෙන් නිදහස ලබා ගන්නා විට තිබුනි. 1952 විප්ලවයෙන් පසු ඊජිප්තුව ජනරජයක් ලෙස ප්‍රකාශයට පත් කළ අතර 1958 දී එය සිරියාව සමඟ ඒකාබද්ධ වී එක්සත් අරාබි ජනරජය පිහිටුවා ගත් අතර එය 1961 දී විසුරුවා හරින ලදී. 20 වන ශතවර්ෂයේ දෙවන භාගය පුරාම ඊජිප්තුව සමාජ හා ආගමික ආරවුල් සහ දේශපාලන අස්ථාවරත්වය විඳදරාගත් අතර, 1948, 1956, 1967 සහ 1973 දී ඊශ්‍රායලය සමඟ සන්නද්ධ ගැටුම් කිහිපයකට එරෙහිව සටන් කළ අතර 1967 දක්වා ගාසා තීරය කඩින් කඩ අල්ලා ගත්තේය. 1978 දී ඊජිප්තුව ගාසා තීරයෙන් නිල වශයෙන් ඉවත් වී ඊශ්‍රායලය පිළිගනිමින් කෑම්ප් ඩේවිඩ් ගිවිසුම් අත්සන් කළේය. 2011 ඊජිප්තු විප්ලවයට සහ හොස්නි මුබාරක් බලයෙන් පහ කිරීමට තුඩු දුන් අරාබි වසන්තයෙන් පසුව, රට දිගුකාලීන දේශපාලන නොසන්සුන්තාවයකට මුහුණ දුන්නේය.2014 සිට අබ්දෙල් ෆාටා එල්-සිසිගේ නායකත්වයෙන් යුත් අර්ධ-ජනාධිපති ජනරජයක් වන ඊජිප්තුවේ වත්මන් ආන්ඩුව, සෝදිසියෙන් සිටින්නන් ගනනාවක් විසින් විස්තර කර ඇත්තේ ඒකාධිපති සහ රටේ දුර්වල මානව හිමිකම් වාර්තාව සදාකාලික කිරීම සඳහා වගකිව යුතු බවයි. ඉස්ලාමය ඊජිප්තුවේ නිල ආගම වන අතර අරාබි එහි නිල භාෂාව වේ.[17] එහි ජනතාවගෙන් අතිමහත් බහුතරයක් ජීවත් වන්නේ වර්ග කිලෝමීටර් 40,000 (වර්ග සැතපුම් 15,000 ) ප්‍රදේශයක් වන නයිල් ගං ඉවුර ආසන්නයේ වන අතර එහිදී එකම වගා කළ හැකි ඉඩම දක්නට ලැබේ. ඊජිප්තුවේ භූමි ප්‍රදේශයෙන් වැඩි කොටසක් සමන්විත සහරා කාන්තාරයේ විශාල ප්‍රදේශ ජනාවාස විරලය. ඊජිප්තුවේ වැසියන්ගෙන් 43% ක් පමණ ජීවත් වන්නේ රටේ නාගරික ප්‍රදේශ හරහා වන අතර, බොහෝමයක් විශාල කයිරෝ, ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩ්‍රියාව සහ නයිල් ඩෙල්ටාවේ අනෙකුත් ප්‍රධාන නගරවල[18] ජනාකීර්ණ මධ්‍යස්ථාන හරහා ව්‍යාප්ත වේ.ඊජිප්තුව උතුරු අප්‍රිකාව, මැදපෙරදිග සහ මුස්ලිම් ලෝකයේ කලාපීය බලවතෙකු ලෙසත් ලොව පුරා මධ්‍යම බලවතෙකු ලෙසත් සැලකේ.[19] එය විවිධාංගීකරණය වූ ආර්ථිකයක් ඇති සංවර්ධනය වෙමින් පවතින රටකි, එය අප්‍රිකාවේ තුන්වන විශාලතම ආර්ථිකය, නාමික දළ දේශීය නිෂ්පාදිතයෙන් 41 වැනි විශාලතම ආර්ථිකය සහ PPP මගින් ගෝලීය වශයෙන් 20 වැනි විශාලතම ආර්ථිකය වේ. ඊජිප්තුව එක්සත් ජාතීන්ගේ සංවිධානය, නොබැඳි ව්‍යාපාරය, අරාබි ලීගය, අප්‍රිකානු සංගමය, ඉස්ලාමීය සහයෝගිතා සංවිධානය සහ ලෝක තරුණ සංසදයේ ආරම්භක සාමාජිකයෙකි."},{"question":"Tirela wo lu ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ l’Orimẹrunmu, lo ba tẹ dẹrẹba pa","answer":"Tirela kan ti gaasi wa ninu rẹ, padanu ijanu ẹ laaarọ ọjọ Satide, ọjọ kẹrinla, oṣu kẹjọ yii, ni marosẹ Eko s’Ibadan. Bo ṣe wo lu mọto ayọkẹlẹ meji niyẹn, to si pa ọkunrin kan sinu ọkan ninu awọn mọto meji naa.Orimẹrunmu gan-an niṣẹlẹ yii ti ṣẹlẹ, loju ọna marosẹ yii. Ohun ti Babatunde Akinbiyi, Alukoro TRACE, sọ ni pe ni nnkan bii aago mẹjẹ kọja iṣẹju mẹta aarọ ni ijamba yii waye.Akinbiyi ṣalaye pe tirela to kun fun afẹfẹ idana ọhun ko ni nọmba kankan, awọn kaa to wo lu lo ni nọmba. O ni Toyota Corolla ti nọmba ẹ jẹ EQ 165 LSR ati Sienna ti wọn kọ FKJ 341 GC si lara ni tirela yii wo lu.Alukoro TRACE tẹsiwaju pe niṣe ni awakọ to wa tirela naa padanu ijanu ẹ, ohun to jẹ ko ṣubu le awọn mọto meji naa lori niyẹn.O tẹsiwaju pe ọkan ninu awọn ọkunrin to wa ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ meji naa lo doloogbe, nibi ti tanka epo wo pa a si.Nigba tawọn ti iṣẹlẹ yii ṣoju wọn n sọrọ, wọn ni tirela to gbe gaasi yii ko deede ṣubu, wọn ni ere buruku lo n sa bọ tẹlẹ.Wọn fi kun un pe baba, iya atawọn ọmọ wọn meji ti wọn jẹ ọmọde ni wọn jọ wa ninu mọto Toyota Corolla, nigba ti dẹrẹba ati awọn obinrin meji wa ninu ọkọ Sienna. Wọn ni  nnkan kan ko ṣe awọn to wa ninu Sienna, wọn ko fara pa paapaa. Afi baba to wa Corolla nikan lo dagbere faye.Ohun to dun awọn eeyan bi wọn ṣe wi ni pe awakọ to wa tirela naa sa lọ, ko sẹni to ri i mu lẹyin tijamba ọhun waye tan.Wọn ti gbe oku baba to ku ninu Corolla lọ si mọṣuari ọsibitu Famobis, ni Lotto, loju ọna marosẹ yii kan naa."},{"question":"In een straat staan 100 huizen. De huizen zijn genummerd van 1 tot en met 100. Elk huisnummer komt 1 keer voor in de straat. Hoeveel negens staan er in totaal in al deze huisnummers?","answer":" 20 (10 bij de tientallen + 10 bij de eenheden) "},{"question":"Kush e fitoi FIFA Kupën e Botës në vitin 1930?","answer":"FIFA Kupën e Botës në vitin 1930 e fitoi Uruguai."},{"question":"Nêu ý nghĩa câu thành ngữ \\"tấc đất tấc vàng\\".","answer":"Đất đai là nguồn tài nguyên vô cùng quý giá. Bởi vậy mà ông cha ta có câu: “Tấc đất tấc vàng” như một lời nhắc nhở con cháu phải biết coi trọng và giữ gìn đất đai.Đầu tiên, “tấc” là một đơn vị dùng để đo lường, “đất” hiểu đơn giản là chất rắn làm thành lớp trên cùng của bề mặt Trái Đất, tạo thành khoảng không gian có thể dùng để con người sinh sống hoặc sản xuất. Còn “vàng” chính một kim loại quý giá, có giá trị kinh tế rất cao. Ông cha ta đã so sánh “tấc đất” với “tấc vàng” để cho thấy tầm quan trọng, cũng như sự quý giá của đất đai. Và từ đó, câu tục ngữ muốn khuyên nhủ con người cần phải quý trọng, bảo vệ đất đai.Đất đai chính là nơi để con người xây dựng nhà cửa. Không chỉ vậy, đất đai còn là nơi để trồng trọt, chăn nuôi tạo ra nguồn lương thực, thực phẩm phục vụ cuộc sống hằng ngày. Với một quốc gia, đất đai chính là một phần thuộc về chủ quyền lãnh thổ - điều bất khả xâm phạm của mỗi dân tộc. Điều đó đã được chứng minh trong lịch sử. Dân tộc Việt Nam đã trải qua những cuộc đấu tranh, từ kẻ thù phương Bắc đến thực dân Pháp và đế quốc Mĩ. Rất nhiều người đã ngã xuống để bảo vệ mảnh đất của quê hương. Con người Việt Nam đã sống đúng với lời căn dặn trong di chúc của vua Trần Nhân Tông: “Một tấc đất của tiền nhân để lại, cũng không được để lọt vào tay kẻ khác”.Hiểu được tầm quan trọng của đất đai, chúng ta cần phải chung tay bảo vệ và giữ gìn: sử dụng đất đai một cách hợp lý, tránh sử dụng các chất hóa học trong sản xuất gây ô nhiễm nguồn đất, không để đất bị cằn cỗi, bạc màu…Như vậy, câu tục ngữ “Tấc đất, tấc vàng” đã cho thấy được tầm quan trọng của đất đai. Mỗi người hãy có ý thức giữ gìn, bảo vệ tài nguyên quý giá này."},{"question":"السؤال: كم مرة أقسم الله تعالى في القرآن الكريم؟","answer":"الجواب: سبع مراتٍ فقط."},{"question":"Sebuah cafe menjual dua jenis minuman. Dalam satu jam yang pertama, 25 bungkus minuman sejuk dan 30 bungkus minuman panas telah dijual. Pada jam berikutnya, 21 bungkus minuman sejuk dan 33 bungkus minuman panas telah dijual. Jumlah jualan pada jam pertama dan jam berikutnya masing-masing ialah RM227.50 dan RM214.50.Bentukkan dua persamaan linear yang memenuhi situasi tersebut.","answer":"Jawapan:25x+ 30y= 227.50 21x+ 33y=214.50 "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai ayam disambar helang\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud  seseorang itu yang tiba-tiba hilang dan kabur dari pandangan mata orang ramai. Contoh ayat:  Sharina tiba - tiba hilang bagai ayam disambar helang. Ibu dan ayahnya telah melaporkan kehilangannya kepada polis."},{"question":"Gịnị bụ Pneumonia ","answer":"Theresa Nwachukwu, dibia bekee bụ ọkachamara n'ihe gbasara ahụike ụmụaka, kwuru na 'Pneumonia' bụ ọrịa ngụgụ.\\"Ọ bụrụ na nje 'bacteria' maọbụ 'fungi' maọbụ 'virus' baa mmadụ na ngụngụ, nke a ka a na-akpọ 'Pneumonia'\\".Nwachukwu kọwara na ọrịa ngụ dị icheiche n'ihi na nje na-akpata ha abụghị otu.N'ihi nke a, etu e si agwọ ya anaghị abụcha otu ihe.Iji maa atụ, ọ bụghị ọgwụ e ji gwọọ ọịọrịa ngụ nke nje 'bacteria' kpatara ka e ji agwọ nke 'virus'kpatara."},{"question":"Magkapareho ba ang kahulugan ng dalawang pangungusap?A: \\"Hindi na ako nakapagluto ng hapunan dahil sa sobrang pagod sa trabaho.\\"B: \\"Bumili na lang ako ng hapunan sa labas dahil gabi na nang nakauwi ako sa bahay mula sa trabaho.\\"","answer":"Hindi. Bagamat tungkol sa hindi pagluto ng hapunan dahil sa trabaho ang parehong pangungusap, magkaiba ang dahilang ibinigay ng dalawa. Pagod ang dahilan kung bakit hindi nakapagluto ng hapunan sa unang pangungusap, habang oras naman sa ikalawa."},{"question":"Dünyadaki en pahalı madde nedir?","answer":"Gerçekte herhangi bir pratik kullanım alanı olmayan kaliforniyum 252, 1950 yılında keşfedilmiş bir maddedir. Kuyrukluyıldız tozu: \\"Stardust\\" uydusunun uzayda \\"Wild II\\" adlı kuyrukluyıldızdan topladığı tozun gramı 28 milyar euro'ya gelmesiyle en pahalı madde konumundadır"},{"question":"１９９７年にイギリスから中国に返還された地域はどこ？","answer":"香港です。"},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Thương Ngày Nắng Về phần 2 là phim truyền hình được yêu thích nhất hiện nay nhờ nội dung chân thực và sự thể hiện ấn tượng của dàn diễn viên. Mới đây, Đình Tú (vai Duy) đã chia sẻ lên trang cá nhân ảnh hồi 18 tuổi của mình. Theo đó, nam diễn viên được khen hết lời vì \\"đẹp từ trong trứng\\" với nhan sắc từ nhỏ đến lớn không thay đổi. Trước đó, Hồng Đăng - một soái ca khác của Thương Ngày Nắng Về cũng chia sẻ ảnh hồi học cấp 3 nhưng nhận lại phản ứng vô cùng hài hước từ khán giả.  Cụ thể, Đình Tú vừa chia sẻ một bức ảnh thời trẻ của mình lên trang cá nhân, nam diễn viên cẩn thận chú thích: \\"Mình là Tú 18 tuổi\\" kèm theo một icon hài hước. Có thể thấy, dù mới 18 tuổi nhưng Đình Tú đã ra dáng một hotboy tương lai với gương mặt vô cùng sáng sủa, thông minh. Nam diễn viên khi đó diện áo thun đơn giản, trên bàn bày nhiều đồ chơi lạ mắt, đúng với độ tuổi.  Bên dưới bài đăng, khán giả thể hiện sự bất ngờ trước ảnh hồi thanh xuân của Đình Tú. Có người còn cho rằng thanh niên trong ảnh đáng lẽ phải 16 tuổi mới đúng. Hóa ra Đình Tú năm 18 tuổi đã bộc lộ khí chất của một soái ca vạn người mê. Điều này dường như được giữ nguyên khi anh đảm nhiệm vai công tử nhà giàu - Duy trong Thương Ngày Nắng Về hiện tại. Được biết, Đình Tú không phải soái ca đầu tiên của Thương Ngày Nắng Về khoe ảnh thời \\"trẻ trâu\\". Cách đây nhiều năm, Hồng Đăng cũng chia sẻ ảnh hồi anh học cấp 3, nhưng phản ứng khán giả lại trái ngược so với Đình Tú. Thời điểm bức ảnh trên được chia sẻ, nhiều người đã không nhận ra Hồng Đăng vì trông anh có vẻ phong trần, da ngăm đen khác xa hiện tại. Bên cạnh đó, khán giả cũng thừa nhận Hồng Đăng của hiện tại đẹp và phong độ hơn nhiều.  Dù có nhiều ý kiến xoay quanh vẻ ngoài của Đình Tú và Hồng Đăng, nhưng không thể phủ nhận hai soái ca này đều đang sở hữu sự nghiệp diễn xuất rất đáng ngưỡng mộ. Các bộ phim có sự góp mặt của họ đều nhanh chóng gây sốt ngay khi lên sóng những tập đầu tiên. Trong Thương Ngày Nắng Về, Đình Tú vào vai Duy - người thừa kế của một tập đoàn lớn. Anh đem lòng yêu Trang (Huyền Lizzie) - con gái thứ trong gia đình có 3 chị em gái. Trong khi đó, Hồng Đăng đảm nhiệm vai Đức - chồng của Khánh (Lan Phương). Vợ chồng anh đã ly hôn sau nhiều biến cố lớn xảy ra, hai người con chung hiện đang ở với mẹ. Số phận của các nhân vật do Đình Tú, Hồng Đăng đảm nhiệm trong phim vẫn đang là một ẩn số. Theo Tôn Nghệ Trân (SaoStar.vn) https://saostar.vn/dien-anh/anh-hoi-tre-trau-cua-hong-dang-va-dinh-tu-trong-thuong-ngay-nang-ve-202207311254427997.html Trang Thông tin điện tử Docbao.vn Công ty Cổ phần Quang Minh Việt Nam Giấy phép thiết lập Trang thông tin điện tử tổng hợp trên Internet số 2372/GP-STTTT cấp ngày 29/8/2014. SĐT: 024. 666.40816 Địa chỉ: P604, Tầng 6, Tòa nhà Golden Field, Khu đô thị mới Mỹ Đình 1, phường Cầu Diễn, quận Nam Từ Liêm, Hà Nội Chịu trách nhiệm nội dung: Điều Thị Bích; ĐT: 0903.263.198; Email: docbao@kib.vn Đọc báo trực tuyến hiện tại chỉ sử dụng tên miền duy nhất là docbao.vn; độc giả lưu ý tránh nhầm lẫn. Chính sách bảo mật RSS","answer":"Hồng Đăng và Đình Tú đu trend đăng ảnh hồi 'trẻ trâu', ai mới là 'nam vương' của Thương Ngày Nắng Về?"},{"question":"Ngano kinahanglan jud muinom ug daghang tubig paghuman og inom o kaon og tam-is?","answer":"Kinahanglan muinom ug daghang tubig paghuman og inom o kaon og tam-is, para malikayan ang tonsilitis. Ug malikayan ang pagdebelop sa plaque sa ngipon."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Tempat titanic bersemadi.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah Atlantik. "},{"question":"පහත ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළේ අර්ථය කුමක්ද ? ඉහේ මලක් පිපුනා වාගේ","answer":"බොහෝ සතුටට පත්වීම"},{"question":"“ఒక ఆటో మొదటి కి.మీ. ప్రయాణానికి ₹30, ఆపై ప్రతి కి.మీ. ప్రయాణానికి ₹ 10 చొప్పున చెల్లించవలసి యున్నది”. పై సమాచారం ఆధారంగా ప్రశ్నకి సమాధానం రాయండి ఏర్పడిన జాబితా ఏ శ్రేణిలో ఉంటుంది ?","answer":"అంకశ్రేణి"},{"question":"Kedu isi obodo Gombe State?","answer":"Isi obodo Gombe State bụ Gombe"},{"question":"Diniho izao hafatra manaraka izao: “Ny olona ao amin’io antoko politika io dia samy mpamadika ny firenena avokoa”. Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay lahatsoratra?","answer":"Eny, maneho fankahalana vondrona politika ny hafatra."},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து சோயா சங்க் கட்லெட் செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:100 கிராம் சோயா சங்க்4 பிரட்4 to 5 உருளைக்கிழங்கு2 பெரிய வெங்காயம்2 பச்சை மிளகாய்3 பல் பூண்டு1 துண்டு இஞ்சி3 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சோள மாவு1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி ரவை½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி மஞ்சள் தூள்½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி கரம் மசாலா1 மேஜைக்கரண்டி சாட் மசாலா½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி கருப்பு மிளகு தூள்தேவையான அளவு மிளகாய் தூள்தேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்தேவையான அளவு உப்புசிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லி","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் வெங்காயம், பச்சை மிளகாய், மற்றும் கொத்தமல்லியை நறுக்கி, இஞ்சி பூண்டை பேஸ்ட் ஆக்கி ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. அடுத்து ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் சோயா சங்குகளை ஊற வைப்பதற்கு தேவையான அளவு தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி அதில் ஒரு சிட்டிகை அளவு உப்பு போட்டு அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.3. தண்ணீர் சுட்டதும் அடுப்பை அணைத்து விட்டு அதில் சோயா சங்குகளை போட்டு அதை சுமார் 25 நிமிடத்தில் இருந்து 30 நிமிடம் வரை ஊற வைக்கவும்.4. பின்னர் பிரட்களை எடுத்து மைக்ரோவேவ் அவனில் சுமார் 2 லிருந்து 3 நிமிடம் வரை வைத்து எடுத்து அதை சிறு சிறு துண்டுகளாக்கி ஒரு மிக்ஸி ஜாரில் போட்டு அதை நன்கு நற நறப்பான பதத்திற்கு அரைத்து கொள்ளவும்.5. மைக்ரோவேவ் அவன் இல்லையென்றால் பிரட்டை pan னின் மூலமாகவோ அல்லது toaster யின் மூலமாகவோ toast செய்து அரைத்து கொள்ளலாம்.6. பின்பு ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் உருளைக்கிழங்கை வேக வைப்பதற்கு தேவையான அளவு தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி அதில் உருளைக்கிழங்கை போட்டு அதை சுமார் 20 லிருந்து 25 நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும்.7. 25 நிமிடத்துக்கு பிறகு அடுப்பை அணைத்து விட்டு அதை எடுத்து சிறிது நேரம் ஒரு பாத்திரத்தில் வைத்து ஆற விட்டு பின்பு அதை எடுத்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில்போட்டு அதை நன்கு மசித்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.8. பிறகு நாம் ஊற வைத்திருக்கும் சோயா சங்குகளை எடுத்து அதை நன்றாக பிழிந்து அதில் இருக்கும் தண்ணியை முற்றிலுமாக எடுத்த பின் அதை ஒரு மிக்ஸி ஜாரில் போட்டு அதை நன்கு நற நறப்பான பதத்திற்கு அரைத்து எடுத்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.9. இப்பொழுது ஒரு கடாயை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் சுமார் 2 மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு எண்ணெய் சேர்த்து அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.10. எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் வெங்காயம் மற்றும் பச்சை மிளகாயை போட்டு வெங்காயம் கண்ணாடி பதம் வரும் வரை அதை வதக்கவும்.11. வெங்காயம் கண்ணாடி பதம் வந்ததும் அதில் நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட்டை போட்டு இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட்டின் பச்சை வாசம் போகும் வரை அதை வதக்கவும்.12. இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட்டின் பச்சை வாசம் போனதும் அதில் மஞ்சள் தூள், கருப்பு மிளகு தூள், அவரவர் விருப்பத்திற்கேற்ப மிளகாய் தூள், மற்றும் தேவையான அளவு உப்பு போட்டு அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.13. அடுத்து அதில் நாம் வேக வைத்து மசித்து வைத்திருக்கும் உருளைக்கிழங்கு மற்றும் அரைத்து வைத்திருக்கும் சோயா சங்க்குகளை போட்டு அதை நன்கு கலந்து விட்டு அதை சுமார் ஒரு நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும்.14. ஒரு நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அதில் சாட் மசாலா மற்றும் கரம் மசாலாவை தூவி அதை நன்கு கிளறி விட்டு சுமார் ஒரு நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும்.15. ஒரு நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் கொத்தமல்லியை தூவி அதை ஒரு கிளறு கிளறி அடுப்பை அணைத்து விட்டு மசாலாவை கீழே இறக்கி வைத்து சிறிது நேரம் ஆற விடவும்.16. இப்பொழுது ஒரு கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் சோள மாவை போட்டு அதனுடன் தேவையான அளவு தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி அதை நன்கு கரைத்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.17. பிறகு நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் bread crumbs ஐ எடுத்து அதில் ரவையை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து கொள்ளவும். (ரவை பிடிக்காதவர்கள் அதை தவிர்த்து விடலாம்.)18. பின்பு நாம் வதக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் சோயா சங்க் கலவை ஆறியதும் அதை அவரவருக்கு விருப்பமான வடிவில் பிடித்து அதை நாம் கரைத்து வைத்திருக்கும் சோள மாவில் நன்கு முக்கி பின்பு அதை bread crumbs ல் போட்டு நன்கு உருட்டி எடுத்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.19. இவ்வாறு மீதமுள்ள சோயா சங்க் கலவையையும் செய்து தட்டில் வைத்து பின்பு அதை சுமார் 15 லிருந்து 20 நிமிடம் வரை ஃப்ரிட்ஜில் வைக்கவும்.20. அடுத்து ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் கட்லெட்டை போட்டு பொரித்து எடுப்பதற்கு தேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.21. எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் கடாயின் அளவிற்கேற்ப அதில் நாம் ஃப்ரிட்ஜில் வைத்திருக்கும் கட்லெட்டை எடுத்து பக்குவமாக போட்டு அதை பொரிக்கவும்.22. பின்பு அது ஒரு புறம் பொன்னிறமானதும் அதை மறு புறம் திருப்பி விட்டு இரு புறமும் அது பொன்னிறமானதும் அதை ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் எடுத்து எண்ணெய்யை நன்கு வடித்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து அதை கெட்சப்புடன் சுட சுட பரிமாறவும்.23. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் மிகவும் சுவையான சோயா சங்க் கட்லெட் தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து சுவைத்து மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"In een put van 20 meter diep zit een slak op de bodem. De slak begint te klimmen naar boven. Overdag stijgt de slak 5 meter, maar 's nachts daalt de slak 4 meter. Dat gaat zo elke dag door. Na hoeveel dagen heeft de slak de rand van de put bereikt?","answer":"16 dagenNa 15 dagen heeft de slak 15 meter geklommen. Op de 16 de dag is de slak dus boven en hoeft ze 's nachts niet meer te dalen."},{"question":"Segun Agbaje","answer":"Segun Agbaje (ti a bi ni ọdun 1964) ni Oludari Alakoso ti Guaranty Trust Bank (GTBank), ile-iṣẹ iṣowo ti orilẹ-ede Naijiria kan. O tun jẹ Oludari ti PepsiCo ati ọmọ ẹgbẹ ti Mastercard Advisory Board, Aaarin-Ila oorun ati Afrika.Segun Agbaje lọ si awon ile iwe St Gregory's College, Obalende, Ipinle Eko, Nigeria, ati St Augustine Academy, Kent, England, fun eto-ẹkọ giga rẹ. Lẹhinna o tẹsiwaju si University of San Francisco California, nibi ti o ti gba Aakẹkọ ti Iṣiro ati Titunto si ti Awọn oye Isakoso Iṣowo.Segun Agbaje bẹerẹ iṣẹ ni Ernst & Young ni San Francisco o si fe bee le 1991 lati darapọ mọ ibẹrẹ GTBank. O dide nipasẹ awọn ipo lati di Alakoso ni Oṣu Kini Oṣu Kini ọdun 2000, ati Igbakeji Alakoso ni Oṣu Kẹjọ ọdun 2002.A yan Agbaje ni Oludari Alakoso Iṣakoso ti GTBank ni Oṣu Kẹrin ọdun 2011 nigbati Tayo Aderinokun, lẹhinna ni awọn ipo ipari ti akàn ẹdọfóró, gba isinmi iṣoogun. Ni iku Aderinokun ni Oṣu Karun ọdun 2011, Agbaje ni a darukọ MD / Alakoso pataki ti banki naa.A yan Agbaje si igbimọ oludari ati igbimọ ayewo ti PepsiCo ni Oṣu Keje 15 Keje 2020.Awọn ami-ẹri ti o gba nipasẹ GTBank labẹ itọsọna Agbaje pẹlu Bank ti o dara julọ ni Nigeria nipasẹ Euromoney; Bank of Africa ti Odun nipasẹ Eye African Banker; Bank ti o dara julọ ni Nigeria nipasẹ World Finance UK; Ile-ifowopamọ Innovative pupọ julọ nipasẹ EMEA Finance; Ẹgbẹ Iṣowo ti o dara julọ nipasẹ Iwe irohin Alakoso Iṣowo Agbaye ati Bank ti o dara julọ ni Nigeria ẹbun nipasẹ Awọn aami ifowopamọ.Oloye Julius Kosebinu Agbaje, oṣiṣẹ banki kan, ati Mrs. Margaret Olabisi Agbaje, olukọ kan ni Obi Segun.Egbon ree agbalagba arakunrin People ká Democratic Party Lagos oloselu, Jimi Agbaje"},{"question":"I wonder ఇండిగో సంస్థ తన మొదటి ఇంటర్నేషనల్ ఫ్లైట్ ను ఎంత దూరం నడిపింది?Can you get me some context to answer this (in the same language as my question)?","answer":"ఎయిర్ ఇండియా (Air India) (హిందీ: एअर इंिडया), భారతీయ విమానయాన సర్వీసు. ఇది భారత పతాక వాహనం. ప్రపంచమంతటా దీని నెట్ వర్క్ ప్రయాణీకులనూ, సరకులనూ చేరవేస్తూవుంది. భారత ప్రభుత్వరంగ సంస్థ.2007 ఫిబ్రవరీ 22న దీనిని ఇండియన్ ఎయిర్‌లైన్స్తో మిళితం చేశారు.[1] దీని ప్రధాన బేసులు, ఛత్రపతి శివాజీ అంతర్జాతీయ విమానాశ్రయం, ముంబై మరియు ఇందిరాగాంధీ అంతర్జాతీయ విమానాశ్రయం, ఢిల్లీ.ఈ ఎయిర్‌లైన్స్, ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తంగా 146 అంతర్జాతీయ, జాతీయ నౌకాశ్రయ గమ్యాలు కలిగివున్నది. భారతదేశంలో దీనికి 12 గేట్ వేలు గలవు. ఈ ఎయిర్ లైన్స్ స్టార్ అలియన్స్లో సభ్యత్వం పొందబోతోంది, 27 బోయింగ్ 787 కోనుగోలుకు ఆర్డర్లిచ్చింది. ఇవి 2009 లో సర్వీసులోకి వస్తాయి.చరిత్రఎయిర్ ఇండియా ఆరంభంలో టాటా ఎయిర్‌లైన్స్‌ పేరుతో 1932 అక్టోబర్ 15న జె.ఆర్.డి.టాటాచే టాటాసన్స్ లిమిటెడ్ (ప్రస్తుత టాటా గ్రూప్) సంస్థలో ఒక భాగంగా ప్రారంభం అయింది. ఎయిర్ ఇండియా సంస్థాపకుడు జె.ఆర్.డి టాటా స్వయంగా మొదటి సారిగా వి.టి.గా నమోదుచేయబడిన సింగిల్ ఇంజన్ విమానం 'డి హావ్‌లాండ్'లో ప్రయాణం చేయడం ఎయిర్ ఇండియా తొలి ప్రయాణానికి నాంది. ఈ ప్రయాణం కరాచీలోని డ్రిగ్‌రోడ్ ఏరోడ్రోమ్ నుండి అలహాబాదు మీదుగా బాంబే జుహూ ఎయిర్‌ స్ట్రిప్ వరకు సాగింది. రాయల్ ఎయిర్ ఫోర్స్‌కు చెందిన పైలెట్ నెవిల్ విన్సెంట్ సారథ్యంలో ఈ ప్రయాణం సాగింది. తరువాత ఈ ప్రయాణం బళ్ళారి మార్గంలో మద్రాసు వరకు సాగింది. ఈ ప్రయాణంలో ఇంపీరియల్ సంస్థ వారి ఎయిర్ మెయిల్ కూడా మొదటిసారిగా పంప బడింది.రెండవ ప్రపంచ యుద్ధం తరువాత భారతదేశంలో క్రమంగా వ్యాపార సర్వీసులు పునరుద్ధరింప బడ్డాయి. 1946 జూలై 26 నుండి టాటా ఎయిర్ లైన్స్, ఇండియన్ ఎయిర్ లైన్స్ పేరుతో ప్రభుత్వ సంస్థగా మారింది. భారత దేశానికి స్వాతంత్ర్యం వచ్చిన తరువాత 1948లో భారత ప్రభుత్వం కోరిన కాణంగా ఎయిర్ లైన్స్‌ లోని 49% వాటా ప్రభుత్వం స్వాధీనపరచుకుంది. ఎయిర్ లైన్స్ అంతర్జాతీయ సర్వీసులకు నిర్వహించే స్థాయికి చేరింది. భారత జాతీయపతాకం చిత్రించిన ఎయిర్ ఇండియా అంతర్జాతీయ విమానాలు 148 జూన్ మాసం నుండి తమ సర్వీసులను ప్రారంభించాయి. 1948 జూన్ మాసంలో మలబార్ రాజకుమారి పేరుతో లోక్‌హీడ్ కాంస్టలేషన్ ఎల్-749ఎ (L-749A) ని విటి-సిక్యుపి (VT-CQP) నమోదు చేసి మొదటి భారత విమాన అంతర్జాతీయ సర్వీసు బాంబే నుండి జెనీవా మార్గంలో లండన్ వరకు తొలి ప్రయాణం సాగించింది. తరువాత 1950 నుండి కైరో, నైరోబీ మరియు ఆడెన్ లకు అంతర్జాతీయ0గా నడిపి0ది. "},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegta Labada Degmo Uu Ka Bilowdo Xarafka (J) Uu Maro Wabiga Juba ?","answer":"Waa Degmooyinka Jilib Iyo Jamaame, Labadaba Waa Uu Maraa Wabiga Juba."},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து பொரி உருண்டை செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:2 கப் அவல் பொரி½ கப் வெல்லம்¼ கப் வறுத்த வேர்க்கடலை1 ½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி பொட்டுக்கடலை¼ மேஜைக்கரண்டி சுக்கு தூள்¼ மேஜைக்கரண்டி ஏலக்காய் தூள்8 அல்லது 10 முந்திரி பருப்புகள்தேவையான அளவு நெய்","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் அவல் பொரியை ஒரு துணியில் கொட்டி அதை நன்கு சுத்தம் செய்து எடுத்து ஒரு பாத்திரத்தில் வைத்து, பின்பு முந்திரி பருப்புகளை சிறு சிறு துண்டுகளாக நறுக்கி கொள்ளவும்.2. இப்பொழுது ஒரு பாத்திரத்தை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் முந்திரி பருப்புகளை போட்டு அதை சுமார் ஒரு நிமிடம் வரை வறுத்து எடுத்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.3. பின்னர் ஒரு கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் அவல் பொரி, வறுத்த வேர்கடலை, பொட்டுக்கடலை, மற்றும் நாம் வறுத்து எடுத்து வைத்திருக்கும் முந்திரியை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விட்டு ஒரு ஏர் டைட் கண்டைனரில் போட்டு வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.4. அடுத்து ஒரு கடாயை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் வெல்லத்தை தூள் செய்து போட்டு 2 கிளறு கிளறி பின்பு அதில் கொஞ்சம் கொஞ்சமாக தண்ணீர் சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கரைத்து விடவும்.5. தண்ணீர் சேர்க்கும் போது கவனமாக சேர்க்க வேண்டும் அதிகமாக தண்ணீர் சேர்த்து விடக்கூடாது.6. பின்பு வெல்லம் நன்கு கரைந்ததும் அதை ஒரு வடிகட்டியின் மூலம் வேறொரு பாத்திரத்தில் ஊற்றி அதை நன்கு வடிகட்டி கொள்ளவும்.7. பிறகு வேறொரு கடாயை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் நாம் வடிகட்டிய வெல்லத்தை ஊற்றி அதை மீண்டும் சுட வைக்கவும்.(அவ்வப்போது அதை ஒரு கரண்டியை கொண்டு கிண்டி விடவும்.)8. வெல்லம் சிறிது சூடானதும் அதில் சுக்குத் தூள் மற்றும் ஏலக்காய் தூளை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.9. பின்னர் அதை ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் எடுத்து கவனமாக ஒரு கம்பி பதத்தை பாகு எட்டி விட்டதா என்பதை பார்க்கவும்.10. வெல்லப்பாகு 2 கம்பி பதத்தை தாண்டியவுடன் ஒரு சிறிய கிண்ணத்தில் சிறிதளவு தண்ணீரை எடுத்து அதில் கொதித்து கொண்டிருக்கும் வெல்ல பாகிலிருந்து ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் 2 துளிகளை எடுத்து விடவும்.11. பின்பு அதை நம் கைகளின் மூலம் உருட்டும் போது அது நன்கு உருட்ட வரவேண்டும். (இது தான் பாகின் சரியான பதம், இந்த பதத்தை பாகு தாண்டிவிட்டால் நம் பொரி உருண்டைகள் நன்கு இறுக்கமாக ஆகிவிடும்.)12. அப்படி உருட்ட வந்தவுடன் அடுப்பை முற்றிலுமாக குறைத்து விட்டு அதில் நாம் கலந்து வைத்திருக்கும் அவல் பொரி கலவையை கொட்டி அதை பக்குவமாக ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் நன்கு கிளறி விடவும்.13. பிறகு அதில் அரை மேஜைக்கரண்டி அளவு நெய் ஊற்றி அதை நன்கு கலந்து விட்டு அடுப்பை அணைத்து விடவும்.14. இந்த பொரி கலவையை சூடாக இருக்கும் போதே நாம் உருண்டைகளாக பிடித்தால் தான் உண்டு அப்படி இல்லை என்றால் அவை ஆறியவுடன் நம்மால் பிடிக்க முடியாது.15. அதனால் நம் கைகளில் நன்கு நெய்யை தடவி கொண்டு அது சூடாக இருக்கும் போதே அதை பக்குவமாக உருண்டைகளாக பிடித்து அதை சிறிது நேரம் ஆற விட்டு பின்பு பரிமாறவும்.16. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சுவையான மற்றும் மொறு மொறுப்பாக இறுக்கும் பொரி உருண்டை தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து உண்டு மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":" Maxay ka koobanyihiin tilmaamahaiimaanku","answer":" Arkaanul-iimaan waa tiirarka uuiimaanku ku taagan yahay. Sida aydhismayaashu u leeyihiin tiirar haya oo haddiimid laga saaro uu dhismuhu dumayo, ayuuiimaankuna u leeyahay tiirar lix ah oo haddiimid ka mid ah qofku si dhab ah u rumaynwaayo uu iimaankiisu burayo (burid, buris,burin, buritaan= waa in wax jiray ay baabaáan.Waxaa loo adeegsadaa waxyaalaha aan lataaban karin, sida ballanka, caqiidada,weysada iwm.\\f"},{"question":" බුදුන්ට මල් පිදීමේ ආනිසංස මොනවද?","answer":" 1. මහත් බෝග සම්පත් ඇත්තෙකු වීම 2. පහත් කුල වල නොඉපදි උසස් කුල වලම ඉපදීම 3. කැමති කැමති යාන වාහන ලැබිම 4. බෝහෝ අගනා වස්ත්රවභරණයන්ට ලාභි වීම 5. සෑම කල්හිම අන් අයගේ ගෞරවයට පාත්ර වීම 6. උසස් කීර්තියක් ඇත්තෙකු වීම 7. සෑම කල්හිම බෝහෝ පිරිවර ජනයා ඇත්තෙකු වීම 8. තම පිරිස කිසිවෙකුට භේද කර විය නොහැකි වීම 9. ඥාතීන් අතර උසස් ශ්රේ්ෂ්ඨ අයෙකු වීම 10. ශීත උෂ්ණ දේශගුණ වලින් පීඩාවට පත් නොවීම"},{"question":"એસ્ટ્રોવર્લ્ડ\\" ગીત નો સારાંશ .","answer":"એસ્ટ્રોવર્લ્ડ\\" સારાંશ:\\"એસ્ટ્રોવર્લ્ડ\\" એ એમેરિકન રેપર અને સોન્ગરાઇટર ટ્રાવિસ સ્કોટ નું એલ્બમ છે, જે 2021 માં રિલીઝ થયું હતું. આ એલ્બમ એ મ્યુઝિક ફેસ્ટિવલ \\"એસ્ટ્રોવર્લ્ડ\\" પર આધારિત છે, જે ટ્રાવિસ સ્કોટની નામક એક સફળ સરનામું પર આધાર રાખે છે.આ એલ્બમમાં ટ્રાવિસ સ્કોટના ચિહ્નસ્થાને બનાવવામાં વ્યક્તિગત અને સાંગીતિક સફળતાઓ છે. એ એલ્બમમાં તેમના મ્યુઝિકના વિશેષ અભિનંદનાત્મક અને સ્થાયી સાંગો સાથે જોડાયા છે.\\"એસ્ટ્રોવર્લ્ડ\\" એ મ્યુઝિકના પર આધારિત એક નવું અને સફળ પ્રયાસ છે, જે ટ્રાવિસ સ્કોટને એક અગાઉથી વધુ તમામ સાંગો, સંગીત, અને શૈલીમાં કાઢીના અસર છે. આ એલ્બમ ટ્રાવિસ સ્કોટની કરિયરમાં એક નવી અને રમતમાં ભરપૂર પરિણામો લાવવાનો એવો એક પ્રયાસ છે જે તેમના પક્ષેથી અવશ્યમ હોવાથી પાસે થયો છે."},{"question":"atsodzi amabiri pogwira nsomba amagwirisira ntchito chani?","answer":"atsodzi ambiri amagwirisira ntchito mbedza kapena ukonde pogwira nsomba mu nyanja kapena mu misinje"},{"question":"வினா:அணுக்கரு இயற்பியலின் தந்தை யார் ?1.எர்னஸ்ட் ரூதர்போர்ட்2.லாவாயசியர்3.மார்டின் கூப்பர்4.கிரகாம்ப்பெல்","answer":"விடை: 1.எர்னஸ்ட் ரூதர்போர்ட்"},{"question":"(0, 5), (0, 0) (7, 0) బిందువులు శీర్షాలుగా గల త్రిభుజం(A) లంబకోణ త్రిభుజం(B) సమద్విబాహు త్రిభుజం(C) లంబకోణ సమద్విబాహు త్రిభుజం(D) సమబాహు త్రిభుజం","answer":"(A) లంబకోణ త్రిభుజం"},{"question":"Ibalwa kanjani ileta yobuhlobo ngesiXhosa ndicela umzekelo.","answer":"Nanku umzeko we-Leta ngesiXhosa.Igama lam,(igama lakho)Indawo yokuhlala:(idilesi ohlala kuyo)Usuku:(umhla nosuku)Molo Mtasekhaya,Unjani? Mna ndiyakukhumbula kakhulu, ndiyacela ukuba uyamkele imbalelwano yam.Ndifunde kwiindawo ezininzi, ndisenza izinto ezohlukeneyo. Iilali zinamhla ndenyuka zawo kodwa ndiyazi ukkuba kusekuhle ekhaya.Ndifuna ukwazisa ukuba ndiyabuya kwinyanga ezayo  kodwa andizuhlala xesoha lide.Ozithobileyo,igama lakho"},{"question":"এই বাক্যাংশের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :একই বৎসর ১৫ আগস্ট একটি ব্যর্থ","answer":"সামরিক অভ্যূত্থানে শেখ মুজিবের মৃত্যু হলে বাংলাদেশ কৃষক শ্রমিক আওয়ামী লীগ-এর সকল কার্যক্রম বন্ধ হয়ে যায়। পরবর্তীেতে,১৯৭৮ সালে জিয়াউর রহমান বহুদলীয় রাজনৈতিক ব্যবস্থা পুন:প্রবর্তনের উদ্যোগ নিলে বাকশালের কুশীলবরা পূর্বতন বাংলাদেশ আওয়ামী লীগ প্রতিষ্ঠা তথা পুনরুজ্জীবিত করে। ফলে বাংলাদেশের রাজনীতিতে বাকশাল নামক রাজনৈতিক দলের পুনারাবির্ভাব হয় নি।"},{"question":"Кванттык эсептөө деген эмне?","answer":"Кванттык эсептөөлөр кванттык механиканын принциптерин колдонуп, маалыматты классикалык компьютерлерден ашып түшө турган ыкмалар менен иштетет, өзгөчө татаал маселелерди чечүүдө."},{"question":"ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨ: ਘਰ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਕਿਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਰੱਖੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰ: ਘਰ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਫ਼-ਸੁਥਰਾ ਰੱਖਣ ਲਈ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਵੱਲ ਧਿਆਨ ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਹੈ:-੧. ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਿੰਲ੍ਹ, ਉੱਲੀ ਆਦਿ ਲੱਗਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਾਅ ਲਈ ਪਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਨਿਕਾਸ ਦਾ ਯੋਗ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਹੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਘਰ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਹਿੱਸਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਧੁੱਪ ਅਤੇ ਹਵਾ ਦਾ ਆਉਣਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ। ਘਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਾਲੀ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਬਾਰੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਦਰਵਾਜ਼ੇ ਹੋਣੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਬੰਦ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਜਾਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।੨. ਰਸੋਈ, ਘਰ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਅਤੇ ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਰਤੇ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਭਾਂਡੇ, ਚੁੱਲ੍ਹੇ ਆਦਿ ਦੀ ਰੋਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਕਰਨੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ।ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਖਾਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਭੋਜਨ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਢੱਕ ਕੇ ਰੱਖਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹੇ ਪਏ ਭੋਜਨ ਉੱਤੇ ਮੱਖੀਆਂ, ਕੀੜੇ-ਮਕੌੜੇ ਅਤੇ ਕਾਕਰੋਚ ਆਦਿ ਆ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜੋ ਸਾਡੇ ਭੋਜਨ ਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਹਿਰੀਲਾ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ। ਬੇਹੀਆਂ (ਬਾਸੀਆਂ)ਸਬਜ਼ੀਆਂ, ਬੇਹਾ ਭੋਜਨ, ਗਲੇ-ਸੜੇ ਫਲ ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੱਖਣ ਨਾਲ ਕਈ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਫੈਲਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਇਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਘਰ ਦੇ ਬਾਹਰ ਢੱਕਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਕੂੜਾਦਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੁੱਟ ਦੇਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਕੂੜੇ ਨੂੰ ਘਰ ਦੇ ਬਾਹਰ ਵੀ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਦੇਰ ਤੱਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਰੱਖਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ । ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਧੂੰਏ ਆਦਿ ਦੀ ਨਿਕਾਸੀ ਲਈ ਚਿਮਨੀ ਆਦਿ ਦਾ ਸਹੀ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਹੋਣਾ ਵੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ।੩. ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਬਜ਼ੀਆਂ, ਫ਼ਲ ਆਦਿ ਖਾਣ ਸਮੇਂ ਛਿਲਕੇ ਥਾਂ-ਥਾਂ ਤੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਖਿਲਾਰਨੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੂੜੇਦਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾ ਦੇਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।੪. ਕਈ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਥਾਂ-ਥਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਥੁੱਕਣਾ ਜਾਂ ਕੁਰਲੀ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਮਾੜੀ ਆਦਤ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਰਨ ਨਾਲ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਗੰਦਗੀ ਫੈਲਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉੱਥੇ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਜਨਮ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਕੀਟਾਣੂ ਵੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ। ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਆਦਤ ਤੋਂ' ਛੁਟਕਾਰਾ ਪਾ ਲੈਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।੫. ਸਾਰੇ ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਗਟਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਮੇਂ-ਸਮੇਂ ਕੀਟ-ਨਾਸ਼ਕ ਦਵਾਈਆਂ ਦਾ ਛਿੜਕਾਅ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਨਾਲੁ ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੱਖੀ, ਮੱਛਰ,ਕਾਕਰੋਚ ਆਦਿ ਨਹੀਂ' ਰਹਿੰਦੇ । ਯਾਦ ਰਹੇ ਕਿ ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਛਿੜਕਾਅ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਦਵਾਈ ਸਿਹਤ ਵਿਭਾਗ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਵਾਨਿਤ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ। ੬. ਘਰ ਦੇ ਗ਼ੁਸਲਖ਼ਾਨਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਵੱਲ ਵੀ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਧਿਆਨ ਦੇਣ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਹੈ। ਗ਼ੁਸਲਖ਼ਾਨੇ ਦਾ ਫ਼ਰਸ਼ ਗਿੱਲਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਰਹਿਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ । ਸਾਬਣ, ਸ਼ੈਂਪੂ,ਤੇਲ ਆਦਿ ਫ਼ਰਸ਼ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਡਿਗਣੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ । ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਤਿਲਕ ਕੇ ਡਿੱਗਣ ਦਾ ਖ਼ਤਰਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਘਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਨਾਲੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਮਲ-ਮੂਤਰ ਦੇ ਨਿਕਾਸ ਦਾ ਸਹੀ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਹੋਣਾ ਲਾਜ਼ਮੀ ਹੈ।੭. ਸੌਣ ਲੱਗਿਆਂ ਆਪਣਾ ਬਿਸਤਰਾ ਝਾੜ ਲੈਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।੮. ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਲਈ ਪੜ੍ਹਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਜਗ੍ਹਾ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾਂ ਸਾਫ਼-ਸੁਥਰੀ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ।ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਪੜ੍ਹਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਮੇਜ਼, ਕੁਰਸੀ, ਕਿਤਾਬਾਂ, ਬਸਤੇ ਆਦਿ ਦੀ ਵੀ ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਚੰਗੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਰਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ।੯. ਘਰ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਪਾਲਤੂ ਜਾਨਵਰ ਰੱਖਣ ਲਈ ਅਲੱਗ ਥਾਂ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ।ਇਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਲ-ਮੂਤਰ ਦੇ ਨਿਕਾਸ ਦਾ ਵੀ ਯੋਗ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਹੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।੧੦. ਘਰ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੋਣ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਪਹਿਨੀ ਹੋਈ ਜੁਂਤੀਚੰਗੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਝਾੜ ਲੈਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ।੧੧. ਘਰ ਦਾ ਫ਼ਰਸ਼ ਰੁਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਸਾਫ਼ ਪਾਣੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਫ਼ਿਨਾਇਲ ਪਾ ਕੇ ਧੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ।੧੨. ਘਰ ਦੀਆਂ ਦਹਿਲੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਪਾਏਦਾਨ ਰੱਖਣੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ ਹਨ। ਇਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਮੇਂ-ਸਮੇਂ \`ਤੇ ਸਾਫ਼ ਵੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਰਹਿਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਛੇ ਹੋਏ ਗ਼ਲੀਚੇ ਜਾਂ ਦਰੀ ਆਦਿ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਰੱਖਣੀ ਵੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"났다, 낳다, 낫다, 낮다 의 차이를 알려줘","answer":"\\"났다, 낳다, 낫다, 낮다\\", 글을 적을 때 많이 혼동되어 간략한 예를 중심으로 정리하여 봅니다.났다: '나다', '자라다'. '돋아나다', '발생하다' 등의 의미새삭이 났다. 여드름이 났다. 큰일 났다. 안달이 났다. 상처에서 피가 났다. 아침에 굴뚝에서 연기가 났다. 그는 화가 났다. 중동에서 전쟁이 났다. 화가 났다.낳다: 출산, 새끼, 알,  결과, 상황 등에 사용아이를 낳다. 알을 낳다. 연어는 알을 낳기 위해 강을 거슬러 헤엄쳐 올라간다. 소가 마구간에서 새끼를 낳다. 제 아내가 지금 아이를 낳고 있어요. 그녀는 그와의 사이에서 자식 넷을 낳았다. 우리 집 개가 새끼를 여섯 마리 낳았다. 논란을 낳다. 그 투자로부터 최대의 이익을 낳다. 좋은 결과를 낳다. 폭력은 폭력을 낳는다. 그는 한국이 낳은 최고의 과학자다.낫다: 질, 정도, 수준 등이 '뛰어나다'와 상처 등이 '회복하다'의 의미네가 나보다 낫다. 이 제품이 질적인 면에서 훨씬 낫다. 네 컴퓨터가 내 것보다 훨씬 낫다. 그런 일에 돈을 쓰느니 차라리 버리는 편이 낫다. 배반하느니 가난한 것이 더 낫다. 병이 낫다. 환자의 병이 오늘 휠씬 낫다. 상처가 아직 낫지 않았다. 감기가 낫는 데 한 달 이상 걸렸다. 이 약을 먹고 병이 나았다.낮다: 지위, 위치, 계급, 지위, 수준, 수치, 소리 등이 '아래라'는 의미온도가 낮다. 코가 낮다. 이 구두는 굽이 낮다.  지위가 낮다. 소령은 대령보다 계급이 낮다. 비중이 낮다. 거래량이 낮다. 우리 학급의 평균이 다른 학급의 평균보다 많이 낮다. 그 노래의 음은 내게 너무 낮다. 그들의 생활수준은 매우 낮다. 요즘 은행 이자가 너무 낮다."},{"question":"Tìm ý và lập dàn ý đơn giản để kể lại một chuyến đi đáng nhớ của em.","answer":"+ Mở bài: Chuyến đi thăm di tích lịch sử thành Cổ Loa – chuyến đi đáng nhớ.+ Thân bài: - Lí do có chuyến đi đáng nhớ: Kết thúc học kì I, nhà trường và ban phụ huynh thống nhất tổ chức tham quan cho cả trường.- Hành trình: Tập trung từ sớm → Khởi hành (2 tiếng) → Đến nơi → Tham quan đền thờ chính – An Dương Vương → Am thờ của Mị Châu →  Ra về.- Kể lại sự việc đáng nhớ: Câu chuyện về nàng Mị Châu – bức tượng của nàng công chúa.+ Kết bài: - Bài học về dựng nước và giữ nước.- Chuyến đi thăm quan bổ ích, lí thú."},{"question":"ਪਲਾਸਟਿਕ ਦਾ ਕੰਟੇਨਰ ਪਿਘਲ ਗਿਆ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੈਂ ਕੰਟੇਨਰ ਨੂੰ ਗਰਮ ਪਾਣੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਡੁਬੋ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਂ ਕੰਟੇਨਰ ਨੂੰ ਗਰਮ ਚੁੱਲ੍ਹੇ 'ਤੇ ਰੱਖਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਂ ਕੰਟੇਨਰ ਨੂੰ ਗਰਮ ਚੁੱਲ੍ਹੇ 'ਤੇ ਰੱਖਿਆ।"},{"question":"எங்கள் தோட்டத்தில் பாம்பு வந்தால், அதை எப்படி பாதுகாப்பாக அகற்றுவது? நீங்கள் தீர்வை விரிவாக விவரிக்க முடியுமா?","answer":"உங்கள் தோட்டத்தில் ஒரு பாம்பை சந்திப்பது கவலைக்குரியதாக இருக்கலாம், ஆனால் உங்கள் மற்றும் பாம்பு இருவரின் பாதுகாப்பிற்கும் முன்னுரிமை அளித்து, நிலைமையை கவனமாக கையாள்வது முக்கியம். முதலாவதாக, பாம்பிலிருந்து பாதுகாப்பான தூரத்தை பராமரிக்கவும், இது தற்காப்பு நடத்தையைத் தூண்டும் அபாயத்தைக் குறைக்கிறது. நீங்கள் ஒரு பயிற்சி பெற்ற நிபுணராக இல்லாவிட்டால், பாம்பைக் கையாள முயற்சிக்காதீர்கள், ஏனெனில் பல பாம்புகள், விஷமற்றவை கூட, அச்சுறுத்தலை உணரும்போது கடிக்கலாம்.பாதுகாப்பான தூரத்தில் இருந்து பாம்பை அடையாளம் காண்பது முக்கியம். சில பாம்பு இனங்கள் பாதிப்பில்லாதவை மற்றும் பூச்சிகளைக் கட்டுப்படுத்துவதில் மதிப்புமிக்க பங்கு வகிக்கின்றன, மற்றவை விஷம் மற்றும் சாத்தியமான ஆபத்தை ஏற்படுத்தலாம். பாம்பின் இனம் பற்றி உங்களுக்குத் தெரியாவிட்டால் அல்லது அது விஷமாகத் தோன்றினால், உதவிக்கு உள்ளூர் விலங்கு கட்டுப்பாட்டு அல்லது தொழில்முறை பாம்பு அகற்றும் சேவையைத் தொடர்புகொள்வது நல்லது. இந்த நிபுணர்கள் பாம்புகளைப் பாதுகாப்பாகக் கையாளும் அறிவு மற்றும் உபகரணங்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளனர் மற்றும் தீங்கு விளைவிக்காமல் அவற்றை இடமாற்ற முடியும்.பாம்பு விஷமற்றது என்று நீங்கள் உறுதியாக நம்பினால், அதை வெளியேற ஊக்குவிக்க விரும்பினால், உங்களை நேரடியாக தொடர்பு கொள்ளாமல் செய்யலாம். ஆபத்தை அடையாளம் காட்ட அதிர்வுகளை உருவாக்குவதும் பாம்பை பின்வாங்க ஊக்குவிப்பதும் ஒரு முறை. நீண்ட குச்சி அல்லது துடைப்பம் மூலம் பாம்பின் அருகில் தரையில் மெதுவாகத் தட்டினால், பாம்பு தரையில் உணரக்கூடிய அதிர்வுகளை உருவாக்கும். இது பாம்பு உணரப்பட்ட அச்சுறுத்தலில் இருந்து விலகிச் செல்ல தூண்டும்.அதிர்வுகளை உருவாக்குவதுடன், சுற்றுச்சூழலை பாம்புக்கு குறைவாக ஈர்க்கலாம். பாம்புகள் பெரும்பாலும் உயரமான புல், குப்பைகளின் குவியல் அல்லது பிற மறைந்திருக்கும் இடங்கள் உள்ள பகுதிகளில் தங்குமிடம் தேடும். உங்கள் தோட்டத்தில் உள்ள இந்த மறைவிடங்களை அகற்றுவது அல்லது குறைப்பது சுற்றுச்சூழலை பாம்புகளின் ஈர்ப்பைக் குறைக்கும்.எப்பொழுதும் பாதுகாப்பிற்கு முன்னுரிமை கொடுங்கள், எந்த சூழ்நிலையிலும் நீங்கள் பாம்பை கையாளவோ அல்லது தீங்கு செய்யவோ முயற்சிக்கக்கூடாது, குறிப்பாக அதன் இனங்கள் குறித்து உங்களுக்கு நிச்சயமற்றதாக இருந்தால். கொறித்துண்ணிகளின் எண்ணிக்கையைக் கட்டுப்படுத்துவதன் மூலம் சுற்றுச்சூழல் சமநிலையை பராமரிப்பதில் பாம்புகள் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கின்றன, எனவே அவற்றின் இருப்பை மரியாதையுடனும் எச்சரிக்கையுடனும் அணுகுவது முக்கியம். சந்தேகம் இருந்தால், தொழில்முறை உதவியை நாடுவது சூழ்நிலைக்கு பாதுகாப்பான மற்றும் மனிதாபிமான தீர்வை உறுதி செய்கிறது, சாத்தியமான அபாயங்களைக் குறைக்கும் அதே வேளையில் பாம்பை பாதுகாப்பாக இடமாற்றம் செய்ய அனுமதிக்கிறது."},{"question":"\\"Ny tsindry hihaona amin'ny fenitry ny fiaraha-monina tsy misy fotony dia mitaky ny fahatokisan-tena sy ny sarin'ny vatako isan'andro.\\" inona ny fihetseham-po tamin'ny fanambarana teo aloha?","answer":"Ity andian-teny ity dia miteraka fihetseham-po ratsy, miresaka momba ny fiantraikany ratsy amin'ny fanerena ara-tsosialy amin'ny fahatokisan-tena sy ny sarin'ny vatana."},{"question":"'Mhlengi, hawu Mhlengi, yini lena ongenza yona?' kuhayiza uNontobeko.'Wo, ithemba kalibulali, bengithi …' Wo, ahluleke ukuqhubeka bandla uNgidi,zigobhoze izinyembezi. Adideke manje uNomalanga ukuthi uzoduduza bani ayekebani.'Ngiyaxolisa kakhulu kinina nonke. Yiyona mpilo esengiyiphila lena.' esho esulaizinyembezi ebabuka endlini.Wayesababuka kanjalo ngenkathi kungqongqozwa kanye emnyango, kuvulekaisicabha, kungena uXolani ehefuzela, amehlo egcwele izinyembezi. Wangenaesalokhu ehayizile uNontobeko, ebalisa, ebalisa.1. Chaza umoya otholakala esingenisweni salesi siqeshana.","answer":"Umoya wokudabuka/wosizi njengoba uNontobeko ejabhile ngokubonauMhlengi esaba ngumuntu wesifazane kanjalo noNgidi uyadumala umaebona ukuthi uMhlengi waqhubeka nesinqumo sakhe."},{"question":"Wildhorse Creek nke dị n'ugwu Wildhorse bụ otu n'ime iyi ndị si n'osimiri Morgan Creek asọpụta. Nkebi ahịrịokwu nke abụọ: Osimiri Wildhorse dị na Howard Country, Texas bụ otu n'ime iyi ndị si n'osimiri Morgan. Ọ na- asọpụta n'ebe dị nso n'ugwu Wildhorse. Ajụjụ: Ọ bụ otu ihe ka ahịrịokwu nke mbụ na nke abụọ pụtara? Ee ma ọ bụ mba?","answer":"Ee, ahịrịokwu nke mbụ na nke abụọ pụtara otu ihe"},{"question":"Inona ny mahatonga ny volavo mora maty noho ny pozina ? ","answer":"Ny volavo dia tsy mahavita mandoa ka noho izany dia mora maty noho ny fihinana pozina izy ireo. "},{"question":"Complete a seguinte frase: Em 15 de setembro de 1939, Stalin concluiu um duradouro cessar-fogo com o Japão, para entrar em vigor no dia seguinte (seria promovido a um pacto de não-agressão em abril de 1941). No dia seguinte, 17 de setembro, as forças soviéticas invadiram a Polônia pelo leste. Embora alguns combates continuaram até 5 de outubro, os dois exércitos invasores realizaram pelo menos uma","answer":"parada militar conjunta em 25 de setembro, e reforçaram sua parceria não militar com o Tratado de Amizade, Cooperação e Demarcação entre a Alemanha e a União Soviética em 28 de setembro."},{"question":"Oviana ary tamin'ny fomba ahoana no nahatonga ny olombelona ho maoderina ara-anatomika ?","answer":"Ny olombelona dia nanjary maoderina ara-anatomika manodidina ny 200.000 taona lasa izay, miaraka amin'ny endri-javatra toy ny saoka voatonona sy ny atidoha lehibe kokoa."},{"question":"Euskal Herrian, hainbat festa ospatzen dira urtean zehar. Zein da urteko festa ospetsu bat?A) Tomatina, tomateak jaurtitzen diren festa.B) Tamborrada, Donostian ospatzen den festa.C) Fallas, paperzulo handiak erre diren festa.","answer":"B) Tamborrada, Donostian ospatzen den festa."},{"question":"முதன்முதலாகத் தமிழில் பாரதம் பாடியவர் யார்?","answer":"பாரதம் பாடிய பெருந்தேவனார்."},{"question":"熱帯地方に多い伝染病で、「ハマダラカ」が媒介することで知られる病気といえば何でしょう？","answer":"マラリア"},{"question":"在加拿大，駕駛置身交通事故，如需報警，多久應報警？","answer":"立刻"},{"question":"Các ngôi sao nóng nhất có màu gì?","answer":"Theo sách Thiên văn học của tác giả Rachel Firth, các ngôi sao được phân loại dựa trên sức nóng của bề mặt. Cách này được gọi là phân loại theo quang phổ.Những sao nóng nhất thường có màu xanh lam, nhiệt độ bề mặt của chúng trên 25.000 độ C. Dưới xanh lam là trắng, nhiệt độ của các ngôi sao có màu này khoảng 10.000-25.000 độ C. Kế đó là các màu vàng, cam, cam đỏ, đỏ. Những ngôi sao nguội nhất thường có màu đỏ, nhiệt độ 2.600-3.600."},{"question":"இ.சி.ஜி. எடுக்கப் பயன்படும் கருவியைக் கண்டுபிடித்தவர்?","answer":"லண்டனின் கேம்பிரிட்ஜ் சயின்டிஃபிக் இன்ஸ்ட்ரூமென்ட் நிறுவனம் - 1881 இல் சார்லஸ் டார்வினின் இளைய மகன் ஹோரேஸால் இணைந்து நிறுவப்பட்டது - 1911 இல்  ஐந்தோவனின் எலக்ட்ரோ கார்டியோகிராமின் முதல் அட்டவணை மாதிரியை உருவாக்கியது. இது 600 பவுண்டுகள் எடையுள்ளதாக இருந்தது மற்றும் அறுவை சிகிச்சைக்கு ஐந்து பேர் எடுத்தனர்."},{"question":" Você pode citar a obra de arte óptica que Bridget Riley criou em 1961 - 'Shadow Play', 'Cataract 3' ou 'Movement in Squares'?","answer":"Movimento em praças"},{"question":"Wat is de mediterrane? Schrijf, gezien de vorige vraag, een context waarin het antwoord voorkomt. Het kan 1 tot 20 zinnen zijn. Context:","answer":"De Mediterrane wordt vaak gerefereerd naar het Middellandse Zeegebied. Het Middellandse Zeegebied is het gebied rondom de Middellandse Zee, omvattende Spanje, Gibraltar, Andorra, het zuiden van Frankrijk, Monaco, Italië, Malta, San Marino, het Vaticaan, Slovenië, Kroatië, Montenegro, Albanië, Bosnië en Herzegovina, Griekenland, Turkije, Cyprus, Syrië, Libanon, Israël, Palestina, Egypte, Libië, Tunesië, Algerije en Marokko. "},{"question":"Awọn mọlẹbi Olufalayi tawọn kan lu pa l’Ado-Ekiti n beere fun idajọ ododo","answer":"Inu ọfọ nla lawọn mọlẹbi ọkunrin ẹni ọdun marundinlaaadọta kan, Olufalayi Ọbadare, wa di asiko yii, ti wọn si n beere fun idajọ ododo lori bi awọn kan ṣe lu oloogbe naa pa lẹyin ti wọn ro pe ole ni.Nibẹrẹ ọsẹ to kọja niṣẹlẹ naa waye lagbegbe Olujọda, niluu Ado-Ekiti.Gẹgẹ bi a ṣe gbọ, ni nnkan bii aago marun-un irọlẹ lawọn ọdọ adugbo kan to wa lagbegbe naa ni wọn ri ọkunrin kapẹnta ọhun to n rin lọ rin bọ bii ẹni to n wa nnkan, eyi lo si jẹ ki wọn fẹsun kan an pe o fẹẹ jale ni, ṣugbọn o sọ fun wọn pe oun gba iṣẹ kan si agbegbe tawọn eeyan ṣẹṣẹ n kọle si ọhun, oun ko si mọ ile naa gangan.Nitori ero tawọn eeyan ọhun ni lọkan latari bi wọn ṣe ni awọn adigunjale kan ti n da agbegbe naa laamu tẹlẹ, wọn ko feti si nnkan ti ọkunrin naa n sọ ti wọn fi bẹrẹ si i na an, lẹyin ti wọn si la nnkan mọ ọn lori atawọn ẹya ara mi-in lo daku, ko too pada jẹ Ọlọrun nipe.Nigba tiyawo oloogbe naa, Yẹmi, n sọrọ pẹlu ẹdun ọkan, o ni ọkọ oun kuro ni opopona Ado-Ekiti si Ilawẹ tawọn n gbe lọjọ naa pẹlu alaye pe oun ri iṣẹ kan, o si ya oun lẹnu pe awọn kan fẹsun ole kan an, ti wọn si pa a danu.Bakan naa ni Abilekọ Ọmọwumi Idowu to jẹ mọlẹbi Olufalayi sọ pe nigba toun gbọ nipa iku oloogbe naa, oun ro pe o ṣaisan ni, nitori o ni iba diẹ lọjọ meloo kan si asiko naa, bẹẹ loun ba a sọrọ ṣaaju iṣẹlẹ ọhun, to si sọ foun nipa iṣẹ to fẹẹ lọọ ṣe.Mọlẹbi oloogbe naa ti waa bẹ awọn agbofinro lati ṣiṣẹ takuntakun, ki wọn le mu awọn to ṣiṣẹ naa, ki wọn si fa wọn le ijọba lọwọ lati le jiya ẹṣẹ wọn.Lasiko ta a pari akojọpọ iroyin yii, a gbọ pe eeyan bii meje lọwọ ti tẹ lori iṣẹlẹ naa, wọn si ti n sọ tẹnu wọn lọdọ awọn ọlọpaa.Alukoro ọlọpaa Ekiti, ASP Sunday Abutu, fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, bẹẹ lo ni loootọ lọwọ ti ba awọn kan, oku oloogbe si ti wa ni mọṣuari."},{"question":"قم بتلخيص المقال التالي: استخدم فرشاة الطلاء لوضع بطانة الدهان المُخصص لدهان الميلامين. استهدف دهان كل المناطق التي يصعب الوصول إليها ببكرة الدهان. من الخيارات البديلة في بطان الدهان استخدام البطانة المخصصة لألواح الخشب. ادهن بطانة الدهان في اتجاه واحد على كل السطح. تأكد دائمًا من سلاسة حركة البكرة وتوفر الطلاء عليها، إذا لاحظت اختفاء أيًا من هاتين الخاصيتين فضع مزيدًا من بطانة الدهان عليها. في حالة استخدام غلاف بكرة جديد يحتوي على الألياف، لف البكرة بشريط لاصق قبل استخدامها. أزل الشريط اللاصق بعد الانتهاء للتخلص من الألياف المتناثرة التي كانت ستعلق في السطح الذي تقوم بطلائه. استخدم ورق صنفرة نعومة 220 لتنعيم أي سائل متكتل أو أي علامات أخرى نتج عنها بطانة الدهان. امسح السطح الذي قمت بصنفرته بقطعة شاش مرة أخرى.  تُشير التعليمات المرفقة ببطانة الدهان على المدة التي سيستغرقها ليجف. في المجمل، يستغرق بطانة الدهان حوالي 4 ساعات ليجف تمامًا. غطِ السطح سطح خزانة المطبخ بالكامل أو سطح الأثاث بالطلاء مرة أخرى. انتظر حتى تجف بطانة الدهان. لن تحتاج إلى صنفرة السطح مرة أخرى بعد وضع الطبقة الثانية من بطانة الدهان إلا إذا لاحظت وجود مزيدًا من النتوءات أو العيوب في السطح. استخدم بكرة الدهان الاسفنجية لتغطية كل أجزاء السطح تمامًا بالطلاء بشكل متساوٍ. اترك الطبقة الأولى تجف لمدة 6-8 ساعات.   إذا كنت تفضل استخدام فرشاة الطلاء، استخدم الفرشاة على السطح المحبب أولًا ثم ضع طلاء الميلامين بها.    يستغرق الطلاء المطلي على الميلامين وقتًا أطول ليجف من الطلاء المطلي على الخشب، لأن الميلامين ليس من المواد الماصة.  يمكنك شراء طلاء مخصص لأسطح الميلامين من متجر بيع الأدوات المنزلية. استخدم إما البكرة الاسفنجية أو فرشاة الطلاء لطلاء كل الأسطح. اترك الطبقة الأخيرة لمدة 24 ساعة لتجف جيدًا. ابدأ بالجزء الخلفي أو الداخلي لأي باب أو خزانة، حتى تتعود على رش الطلاء أولًا. رش بخاخ الطلاء على السطح بأكمله واتركه ليجف طوال الليل.   ارتدِ قناع التنفس عند العمل ببخاخ الطلاء. افحص بخاخ الطلاء قبل شرائه وتأكد من أنه يمكن استخدامه على أسطح الميلامين وذلك من خلال قراءة الملصق المرفق به. ضع الطبقة الثانية من بخاخ الطلاء إذا أردت ذلك، ولكن انتظر حتى تجف الطبقة الأولى أولًا..","answer":"هذا تلخيص للمقال: ضع بطانة الدهان باستخدام فرشاة الطلاء على كل الحواف والزوايا. استخدم بكرة الدهان لوضع بطانة الدهان على السطح بأكمله. صنفر بطانة الدهان بمجرد أن تجف للتخلص من أي عيوب. ضع الطبقة الثانية من بطانة الدهان. ضع الطبقة الأولى من طلاء الميلامين على الأسطح المطلية ببطانة الدهان مُسبقًا. ضع الطبقة الثانية من طلاء الميلامين بمجرد أن تجف الطبقة الأولى. استخدم بخاخ الطلاء إذا كنت تفضل سطحًا أملسًا في النهاية."},{"question":"夏季オリンピックで、「聖火リレー」が初めて採用されたのは、1936年にどこで開催された大会の時でしょう？","answer":"ベルリンです。"},{"question":"Wat is een Lelkraanvogel?","answer":"De lelkraanvogel (Grus carunculata synoniem: Bugeranus carunculata) is een grote vogelsoort uit de familie van de kraanvogels. Het is een door habitatverlies kwetsbaar geworden kraanvogelsoort die leeft in Afrika ten zuiden van de Sahara. De vogel is gemiddeld 172 cm lang en weegt 7,8 kg. De soort is de grootste kraanvogelsoort uit Afrika en de een na grootste van alle kraanvogels, op de saruskraanvogel na. De rug en de vleugels zijn asgrijs. Boven de ogen en op de kop zijn de veren donkergrijs. De twee lellen zijn wit en hangen vlak onder de keel. De staartveren zijn erg lang en hangen bijna op de grond. De borst en de nek zijn wit. De naakte huid vlak voor de ogen tot aan de snavel is rood en daar zitten verder een soort van wrat-achtige bobbels. De lelkraanvogel heeft lange zwarte poten. Het verschil tussen mannetjes en vrouwtjes is haast niet te zien; de mannetjes zijn gemiddeld iets groter. De jongen hebben minder bobbels dan de volwassen vogels."},{"question":"شنو هو اسرع طائر فالعالم؟","answer":"الجواب: النعامه."},{"question":"የኦክስፎርድ ዩኒቨርሲቲ በአስትራዜኔካ የኮቪድ-19 ክትባት ዙሪያ ጥናት ያደረገው በየትኛው እድሜ ክልል በሚገኙ ሰዎች ላይ ነው?","answer":"በሁሉም"},{"question":"Bana Meis Adası hakkında bilgi verir misin?","answer":"Yunanistan'ın en küçük ve en uzaktaki adası Meis Adası'dır. Yunanistan'ın ona en yakın adasından (Rodos) 125 km uzaklıkta iken Kaş'tan sadece 6 km uzaklıkta bulunuyor. 11 km2 yüzölçümü ile etrafındaki irili ufaklı adaların en büyüğüdür. Resmi ismi Megisti (büyük) bu özelliğinden geliyor. Ada halkı daha çok Kastelorizo ismini kullanıyor. İki dünya savaşı arasında adaya hakim olan İtalyanların etkisi ile, İtalyanca Castello Rosso(kırmızı kale)'dan gelmekte bu isim. Kırmızı Kale isminin, kalenin üzerine kurulu olduğu kayaların kırmızı renginden esinlenilmiş olduğu düşünülüyor. Meis ise Ada için sadece Türklerin kullandığı bir isim."},{"question":"కింది కర్మణి వాక్యాలను కర్తరి వాక్యాలుగా రాయండి.నాచే రచింపబడిన గ్రంథం, నేతాజీ చరిత్ర.","answer":"నేను రచించిన గ్రంథం, నేతాజీ చరిత్ర."},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Thu phí tự động không dừng ETC và những điều cần lưu ýHãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Tiếp nối thành công của Cuộc thi Hoa khôi Nam Bộ đầu tiên được tổ chức vào năm 2017, chiều 31/7, tại Cần Thơ đã diễn ra ngày sơ tuyển đầu tiên cuộc thi Hoa khôi Nam Bộ lần thứ 2. Cuộc thi Hoa khôi Nam bộ 2022 dự kiến tổ chức tuyển chọn tại ba địa điểm: TP Cần Thơ, TP HCM và Tây Ninh, ngoài tiêu chí \\"Tìm kiếm những viên ngọc thô vùng đất Nam Bộ\\" còn mang thêm ý nghĩa \\"Hành trình Đất Phương Nam\\" trong công tác tổ chức. Nhằm tạo thêm sự tự tin, sự trải nghiệm cho các thí sinh, ban tổ chức tạo điều kiện cho mỗi thí sinh có thể đăng ký tham gia tuyển chọn tại một hoặc trong cả ba địa điểm. Ban tổ chức đã nhận khoảng 200 hồ sơ đăng ký dự thi và sẽ tiếp tục nhận hồ sơ trong thời gian tới. Điều kiện thí sinh đăng ký tham","answer":"gia dự thi là các thiếu nữ có quốc tịch Việt Nam, chiều cao từ 160cm trở lên, tuổi từ 18 đến 28. Thí sinh đang sinh sống, làm việc, học tập tại các tỉnh thành Đông Nam Bộ (Hồ Chí Minh, Bà Rịa - Vũng Tàu, Bình Thuận, Đồng Nai, Bình Dương, Bình Phước, Tây Ninh); và Tây Nam Bộ (Cần Thơ, Long An, Tiền Giang, Bến Tre, Trà Vinh, Vĩnh Long, Đồng Tháp, An Giang, Kiên Giang, Cà Mau, Bạc Liêu, Sóc Trăng, Hậu Giang). Thí sinh phải chưa từng kết hôn, sinh con. Ông Võ An Nguyên, nhà sáng lập cuộc thi Hoa khôi Nam bộ chia sẻ: \\"Chúng tôi muốn thông qua cuộc thi, các thí sinh có thể trải nghiệm và tìm hiểu văn hóa, du lịch của Việt Nam nói chung, vùng đất Tây Nam Bộ và Đông Nam bộ nói riêng. Đây cũng là sự khác biệt so với năm thứ nhất, ngoài mục tiêu là tìm được những \\"viên ngọc thô\\" vùng đất Nam bộ, chúng tôi còn một trách nhiệm là quảng bá, giới thiệu được văn hóa và du lịch của vùng đất Nam bộ\\". "},{"question":"ජාත්‍යන්තර පොලිසියේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ කොහේද? ","answer":"ප්‍රංශයේ"},{"question":"Atsakykite į šį klausimą. Kada ponas Schuesteris ir Emma susitinka?","answer":"Ketvirtame sezone"},{"question":"(ephakamisa ikhanda) Sekunguwe njalo baba?(sakuncokola) Ubuza ibhasi libhaliwe?(naye athi ukumamatheka) Hawu! Kanti wena sewaba yibhasi? (bahlekebobabili)(ahlale kwesinye isihlalo) Uboshiwe ngempela uDlamini. Kusasa uzoyakobingelela imantshi.Ashile! Kuhle-ke uma eboshiwe. (athule kancane)Nginovadlwana kodwa mina baba.Kodwa! Kodwa! Uvadlwana! Yini manje?(ngokuzithoba) Baba! Igazi likaMbandlwa lichithekile, induna yaboshwa.Konke lokhu akusho lutho kuwe?(ngolaka) Uthini manje? Mina ngibona kuzobathambisa ukuboshwakwenduna.(aphakamise izwi nomoya wakhe wenyuke) Hhayi bo! Ubathathakancane wena abantu bakule ndawo. Uyakhumbula ngesikhathi sodlame?Iningi labantu balapha bayayithanda inkosi futhi bayayihlonipha. (ehliseumoya) Baba, ngicela ukubone lokhu engikushoyo. Mina bengingacabangiukuthi lesi simo sizoze sifike kuleli banga esesikulo. Uyabona, nenja umaikhonkotha uke unganaki. Wethuke uphele uma isizifikela ngamazinyokuwe. Baba, izwe lizobheduka. Mina ngibona kungcono wena uzehliseenkosini noma uyeke kwabona ubukhansela lobu.(ethukuthela) Hheyi! Hheyi! Kanti usudleni wena? Lezi zinto ozishoyozombili angizamukeli! Lungamane luchitheke uphoko! Lutho mfazi! Ngeke!(enyuke ngolaka naye) Ubani umfazi weBafana? Ubiza mina ngomfazi?Wena awufuni ukuboniswa! Ngiyakutshela, uyongikhumbula seluchithekilelolu phoko lwakho.(abhoke kakhulu) Uzwa kanjani wena! Angisilo ivaka mina! Futhi, vala lomlonyana wakho singaze sethusane1. Wayezobe enzani uDlamini uma ebingelela imantshi? ","answer":"Wayezobe eseyovela enkantolo ngecala ayelenzile."},{"question":"Bis ñaata waxtu la ?","answer":"24i waxtu"},{"question":"O jakim wydarzeniu wspomina ten tekst: Cerkiew św. Mikołaja została wzniesiona w 1870 ze składek wiernych z całej Rosji. Znajduje się na cmentarzu poległych w obronie Sewastopola w czasie wojny krymskiej. Budynek został zaprojektowany przez A. Awdiejewa, który za tę pracę otrzymał honorowy tytuł akademika w dziedzinie architektury.","answer":"O wojnie krymskiej"},{"question":"කුඹුරුවලට කියනා මේ  නම් දැනගෙන හිටියද?","answer":"කුඹුරු යන ශබ්දය ඇති වූ අයුරු ගැන මෙහිදී යමක් කීමට අදහස් නොකරන අතර, පැරණි ගම්වල තිබූ කුඹුරු සඳහා භාවිත කල නම් කීපයක් හා ඒවායේ අරුත් දැක්වීමට පමණක් මේ ලියවිල්ල සීමා කෙරේ. තවත් නම් ගණනාවක් ඇති  අතර, මෙය පළකළ හොත් ලැබෙන ප්‍රතිචාර මත ඒවා ඊළඟ කොටසින් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට බලාපොරොත්තුවෙමි. 1 අකරහ කුඹුරු-:වගා කළ නොහැකි අසාර මුඩුබිම් . මේ වචනය විශේෂයෙන් උතුරුමැද පළාතේ භාවිත වේ.(අකෘෂ්‍ය- අකරහ).2 අගාර කුඹුරු-:එරෙන කුඹුරුවලට දකුණේ භාවිත වන්නකි.ඇතැම් පැතිවල දෙණිකඩත් මෙනමින් හැඳින්වේ.අගාර යනු කඳු දෙකක් මැද පිහිටි තැනිතලා බිමයි.3 අගම්පඩි කුඹුරු-:යුදසේවය වෙනුවෙන් සෙබලුන්ට වැටුප් ගෙවීම වෙනුවට දුන් කුඹුරු.(අගම්පඩි/ අගම්පොඩි සේනාව- වැටුප් ලබමින් යුදසේවාව කළ අය.)4 අග්‍රහාර කුඹුරු-: කෝවිල්වල සේවය කළ බමුණන්ට දුන් කුඹුරු. ඉන්දියාවේද මේ නමින් හැඳින්වෙන කුඹුරු හා ගොඩ ඉඩම් ඇත.5 අටවරල කුඹුරු-: ඉටි මෙන් ඇලෙනා තද මැට්ට සහිත කුඹුරු අටවරල කුඹුරු ලෙස හැඳින්වේ.6 අඳ කුඹුරු-:අයිතිකරු විසින් වගාකිරීම සඳහා අඳයට දුන් කුඹුරු.මෙහි අඳ යන්න අඩ යන්නෙන් ආ බවට කියවුණද ඉඩම් හිමියාට දෙන අස්වැන්න ප්‍රමාණය සෑමවිටම අඩක් වූයේ නැත. 7 අනුබූ කුඹුරු -: ජලය හෝ ගස්ගල් බහුල කුඹුරු. අනුබූ යනු දිය සහිත බිමයි. ( අනුප- අනුපු - අනුබූ). \\" ශෂ්‍ය ඵල කැමැත්තාහු දෙණද් ගොඩද් අනුබුයෙහිද් බිජු වපුරෙති\\" - අමාවතුර.8 අස්වැද්දුම් කුඹුරු-:කුඹුරක් ළඟ ඇති ගොඩ ඉඩමක් කපා කුඹුරක් සාදාගත්විට එය අස්වැද්දුම් කුඹුරකි.9 ඉරවලු කුඹුරු-:පළලින් අඩු දිගෙන් වැඩි කුඹුරු. ඉරි මෙන් ඇති  කුඹුරු. ශ්‍රීපාද විහාරස්ථානයට අයත් කුඹුරු ගැන කියවෙන ලේකම් මිටියේ කීප තැනකම මේ කුඹුරු ගැන කියවේ. ඇතැම් ප්‍රදේශවල ඉරිකොඳු යනුවෙන්ද මේවා හැඳින්වේ.10 උතු කුඹුරු-:වැවකින් වගාකරනා කුඹුරුවලින් සාරවත්ම කුඹුරු( උත්තේ කුඹුරු යයිද කියවේ.). උතු යනු උතුම් හෙවත් උසස් යන අරුත් දේ. 11 ඕවිලාන් කුඹුරු-:කැරැන් ආදී පැලෑටි බහුල ජලාශ්‍රිත කුඹුරු. ගං හෝ අවට ඇති,  කුඩා පැළෑටි බහුල වගුරුබිම් ඕවිලාන් වේ.12 ඕතෙර කුඹුරු-:ගංගා , ඔයවල් අද්දර තිබෙන කුඹුරු.13 කට්ටකඩුව කුඹුරු-: කුඹුරු යායක සරු බවින් අඩුම කුඹුරු. ( පැහි කුඹුරු යයිද කියවේ).14 කන්දැති කුඹුරු-: කඳු බෑවුම්වල ඇති  කුඩා ලියදි සහිත කුඹුරු.( හෙල්මළු ක්‍රමයට වගාකෙරෙනා කුඹුරු ) කන්දැත්ත= කඳු ගැට්ට.15 කරමාරු කුඹුරු-:මාරුවෙන් මාරුවට වගාකරනා කුඹුරු( තට්ටුමාරු කුඹුරු යයිද කියත්.).කරමාරු යනු අතමාරු යන අරුත් දෙයි. කිරිමා කුඹුරු, පෙරමාස් කුඹුරු ඇතුලු තවත් නම් ඊලඟ කොටසින්! 16 කැලෑළි කුඹුරු-:පැරණි රජදවස (4 වන මිහිඳු) සෙල්ලිපියකද මෙවැනි කුඹුරක් ගැන සඳහන් වේ. කැලෑ එළිකර තැනූ කුඹුරු . ( කැලෑ ලියූ යන්නෙන් ආ බවක්ද  ඇතැම් විට කියවේ. ලියූ >ලිය් >ලී >ලි.)17 කිරිමා කුඹුරු-: කිරි යනු අමුණු සතරෙකි*. කිරිමා කළ යනු, අමුණු හතරේ කොටස් ලෙස මායිම්කළ යනුයි. එසේ කොටස්වලට කැඩීමට කිරිතනවා* යන්නද යෙදිණි. \\" තුමූ මාගම හිඳ කුඹුරු කිරිතනවා බොහෝ ගොයම් තැනවූහ.\\"- සද්ධර්මාලංකාරය.18 කුසලාන්( කොහොලාන්) කුඹුරු-:කුසල් හෙවත් පින් පිණිස දුන් කුඹුරු. පිං කුඹුරු ලෙසද දැක්වෙන්නේ මේවායි. දේවාලවලට දුන් කුඹුරු මේ අනුසාරයෙන්ම දෙහෙලාන් කුඹුරු ලෙස හැඳින්වේ.19 කොන්තවැරවැගිය කුඹුරු-:මුලදී තමා සතුව තිබී පසුව අන්සතුවූ හෝ වල් බිහිවූ හෝ කුඹුරු.( කොන්තවැර- පාලු, පුරන්, වල් බිහිවූ*.) 20  ගණේකුඹුරු-: ගණින්නාන්සේලා වාසය කළ  පන්සල්වලට අයත්ව තිබූ හෝ ඒවාට පූජාකළ හෝ කුඹුරු. 21 තරවී කුඹුරු-: හොඳ වර්ගයේ වී , මා වී වැනි වී වපුරන කුඹුරු?. \\" තරවියෙහි බොල්ලා.\\" -දශ ජාතකය.22  දරාඬ කුඹුරු-:කුඹුරු යායට ඇතුලුවෙන තැන ඇති කුඹුරු .\\"ශාලි ක්ෂේත්‍රයේ දරහඬ බඳනාසේය.\\"- පූජාවලිය.(දරාහඬ, දරාඬ- කුඹුරේ ඉහත්තාව.)23 දිවෙල් කුඹුරු-:රජයේ හෝ විහාර දේවාලවල හෝ  වැඩකළ අයට දුන් කුඹුරු. (දිවෙල්- ජීවනෝපාය.) 24 දුක්ගන්නා කුඹුරු-:දුක්ගන්නා රාජකාරිය කළ අයට දුන් කුඹුරු.දුක්ගන්නා යනු රජු වෙනුවෙන් කෙරෙනා රාජකාරියකි. 25 පිසඹුරු කුඹුරු-:කුඩමැට්ට වැනි ශාකවලින් පිරුණු අසාර කුඹුරු . \\" දියෙහි හිඳුනා සෙවෙල් සේ වෙරලොමුදු හටගනී. පිසඹුරු සේ හිසකෙහෙදු හටගනී.\\" යනුවෙන් කර්ම විභාගය නම් පැරැණි කෘතියක දැක්වේ.ඒ අනුව පිසඹුරු යනු යම් කුඩා ශාක විශේෂයක් බව පෙනෙයි. 26 පුරඳ කුඹුරු-: වතුර නැතිවීම් ආදිය නිසා පුරන් වූ කුඹුරු.පුරඳ යනු පුරන් යන්නේ ආදි ස්වරූපය බව කියවේ. \\"කෙතෙක් කලක් අස්නොවත් පුරඳව තිබෙන දෙණිකඩක් කියන්නවුන් මෙන්.\\" - සද්ධර්මරත්නාවලිය. 27 පෙරමාස් කුඹුරු-: මාස් මෝසම කොටස් තුනකි. මහමාහ, පෙරමාහ හා මාස්පස්ස යනුවෙනි. පෙරමාහට වපුරන කුඹුරු පෙරමාස් කුඹුරු වේ. 28  බදු කුඹුරු-: අයිතිකරුට බදුගෙවා ලබාගත් කුඹුරු .29 මැද්දේ කුඹුරු-:වැවකින් වගාකරනා කුඹුරු සරුබව අනුව කොටස් තුනකට බෙදූ අතර, ඒ සාරබව අතින් මැද්දේ පිහිටි කුඹුරු. ( 1 උත්තේ ,2 මැද්දේ ,3 පැසියේ.) 30 මුත්තැස් කුඹුරු-:ගොයම් කපා පාගා ගත් කුඹුරු( මුත්සස්).මෙය විශේෂ කුඹුරු වර්ගයකට භාවිත කෙරුණක් නොව, ඕනෑම කුඹුරකට අස්වැන්න කපාගත් පසුව යෙදුණකි. 31 මුල්බිජු කුඹුරු.-:විටින්විට අවටින් ඈඳාගත් කොටස් හැර මුලින් තිබූ කුඹුරු ඉඩම. මුලින්ම කුඹුර ආරම්භ කරනා විට ගොඩ ඉඩම් ලෙස අවට පැවති කොටස්ද පසුව කුඹුරට එක්කරගත් විට, ආරම්භක කුඹුරු කොටස මුල්බිජු කුඹුරයි. 32 රත්මාසර කුඹුරු-: ගංගා හොයවල් දෙපැත්තේ පාලුවට හැරි කුඹුරු.( රත්නැහැර / රත්මැහැර/ රද්මහැර කුඹුරු.) පෙරකල රජුන් සතුව තිබී පසුව වල්බිහිවූ කුඹුරු . 33 වරුපෙත් කුඹුරු-:වී හැර අනිකුත් ධාන්‍යද වගාකරණා කුඹුරු. ( වරු= ධාන්‍ය , පෙත = ඉඩම.) . වරුපෙත යනුත් කුඹුරු යාය බවද ඇතැම් අයගේ මතයයි. දන්වරුපෙත් කුඹුරු යනු භික්ෂූන්ගේ දානය සඳහා පූජාකළ කුඹුරුයි.34 වැව්ගම් කුඹුරු-:වැවක් ආශ්‍රයෙන් වගාකරණා කුඹුරු .35 මුම්මාරිය/ මානාවාරිය/ පිංමාරිය කුඹුරු-:මුම්මාරිය/ බුම්මාරිය යනුවෙන් යල කන්නය හැඳින්වේ. අහස්දියෙන් වගාකරණා කුඹුරුද, එනමින් හා  මානාවාරිය/ මලන් කුඹුරු( දිගාමඩුල්ල)යනුවෙන්ද හැඳින්වෙන අතර, පිංමාරිය කුඹුරු යනු මහ කන්නයේ වගාකරනා කුඹුරුයි. ඇතැම් කුඹුරක් ලියද්ද ලෙස හැඳින්වූවද, ලියද්ද යනුවෙන් බොහෝවිටම අදහස් කළේ කුඹුරක කොටසකි. කුඹුරක  කොටස් හැඳින්වෙන, අද වනවිට භාවිතයෙන් ඉවත්වී ගොස් ඇති හා භාවිතය ඉතාම අඩු, නම් පිළිබඳවත් ඉදිරියේදී ලිවීමට අදහස් කරමි. "},{"question":"ما فئة هذا السؤال : مَن فاز بأكثر الجوائز من مجموعة جوائز هوغو لأفضل رواية؟.","answer":"الفئة التي يأتي منها السؤال هي الكتب"},{"question":"Inona avy no teny natambatra nahazoana ny teny hoe lohataona?","answer":"Inona avy no teny natambatra nahazoana ny teny hoe lohataona dia loha sy taona"},{"question":"世界上最大的宮殿是？","answer":"故宮"},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"மாணவர்கள் அறிவியலில் நம்பிக்கை வைத்து, எந்த காரியத்தையும் துருவித் துருவிப் பார்க்க வேண்டும். முன்னோர்கள் பக்கம் திரும்பிப் பார்க்கவே கூடாது."},{"question":"E usab ang sentensya na mahimong emoji lang siya: \\"Na adto siya sa hospital para magpa-checkup.\\"","answer":"👨🏥🔍"},{"question":"Em có suy nghĩ gì về những dòng chữ in đậm: “khi một dân tộc rơi vào vòng nô lệ, chừng nào họ vẫn giữ vững được tiếng nói của mình thì chẳng khác gì nắm được chìa khóa chốn lao tù” trong bài Buổi học cuối cùng Ngữ văn lớp 7?","answer":"- Câu nói của thầy Ha-men \\"... khi một dân tộc rơi vào vòng nô lệ chừng nào họ vẫn giữ vững tiếng nói của mình thì chẳng khác gì nắm được chìa khóa của chốn lao tù...\\". Câu nói này chính là chân lí của cả câu chuyện. Nó khẳng định và làm nổi bật giá trị thiêng liêng, sức mạnh to lớn của tiếng nói dân tộc trong cuộc đấu tranh giành độc lập, tự do, thoát khỏi vòng nô lệ. Tiếng nói của dân tộc được hình thành và vun đắp bằng sự sáng tạo của bao thế hệ qua hàng ngàn năm, là thứ tài sản vô cùng quý báucủa mỗi dân tộc. Vì vậy phải biết yêu quý, giữ gìn và học tập để nắm vững tiếng nói cùa dân tộc mình, nhất là khi đất nước rơi vào vòng nô lệ.…"},{"question":"નીચેના પ્રશ્નનો જવાબ:બિલ ઑફ એક્સચેન્જ અને પ્રોમિસરી નોટ્સ વચ્ચેનો તફાવત જણાવો.","answer":"બિલ ઑફ એક્સચેન્જ અને પ્રોમિસરી નોટ વચ્ચેનો તફાવત નીચે મુજબ છે.બિલ ઑફ એક્સચેન્જ:1. બિલ લેણદાર દ્વારા તૈયાર કરવામાં આવે છે.2. બિલમાં બિનશરતી ઓર્ડર છે.3. બિલમાં ત્રણ પક્ષો છે જેમ કે ડ્રોઅર, ડ્રો કરનાર અને ચૂકવનાર.4. બિલ માટે ડ્રો કરનારની સ્વીકૃતિ જરૂરી છે.5. બિલ ડ્રોઅર અને બિલ મેળવનાર સમાન હોઈ શકે છે.6. બિલના અપમાનના કિસ્સામાં, વાંધાઓની પુષ્ટિ અને સંકેત ફરજિયાત છે.પ્રોમિસરી નોટ:1. દેવાદાર દ્વારા પ્રોમિસરી નોટ બનાવવામાં આવે છે.2. નોંધમાં બિનશરતી વચન હોય છે.3. નોંધમાં બે પક્ષોનો સમાવેશ થાય છે એટલે કે નોટ ધારક (દેવાદાર) અને ચૂકવનાર (ધીરદાર).4. નોંધને સ્વીકારની જરૂર નથી.5. જે વ્યક્તિએ નોંધ લખી છે તે ચૂકવણી કરનાર બની શકતો નથી.6. જો નોંધનું અપમાન કરવામાં આવ્યું હોય, તો કોઈ પુષ્ટિ અથવા વાંધાના સંકેતની જરૂર નથી."},{"question":"கேள்வி: இந்தியா என்ற பெயரில் இதழை நடத்தியவர் யார் ?","answer":"பதில்: இந்தியா என்ற பெயரில் இதழை நடத்தியவர் சி.சுப்பிரமணிய பாரதி  என்கிற மகாகவி பாரதியார்."},{"question":"Ислам динин кабыл алган атактууларды жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Майк ТайсонЭкс-чемпион Майк Тайсон темир тордун артында отуруп ислам динин кабыл алган. Ислам дининде алган аты Малик Абдул Азиз 2010-жылы Меккеге барып намаз окугандыгын өзүнүн интернет баракчасына жазып чыккан жана өз сөзүндө мындай деп айткан: \\"Мен ишенем Жаратуучу бар экендигине жана мени туура жолго салат\\" деп өз оюн билдирген."},{"question":"Hãy viết đoạt văn ngắn về lợi ích của việc học ngoại ngữ,","answer":"Học ngoại ngữ không chỉ giúp mở rộng tầm nhìn và cơ hội việc làm, mà còn giúp tăng cường kỹ năng giao tiếp và hiểu biết văn hóa đa dạng. Bằng cách học ngoại ngữ, chúng ta có thể truy cập được vào nhiều nguồn tài liệu giáo dục và giải trí trên toàn thế giới, mở rộng kiến thức và sự hiểu biết của mình. Hơn nữa, học ngoại ngữ cũng giúp mở ra những cánh cửa mới cho sự nghiệp và giúp tăng cường sự tự tin trong giao tiếp với người nước ngoài. Hãy dành thời gian để học ngoại ngữ mỗi ngày và bạn sẽ nhận thấy sự khác biệt trong cuộc sống của mình."},{"question":"Kelechi Iheanacho","answer":"Kelechi Promise Iheanacho ( speli Ịhean Find in Igbo ) (ti a bi ni 3 Oṣu Kẹwa Ọdun 1996) jẹ agbabọọlu ọmọ orilẹede Naijiria ti o je agbawaju fun ẹgbẹ agbabọọluLeicester City ti orilẹ-ede geesi ati ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu orilẹede Naijiria .Iheanacho bẹrẹ iṣẹ agba rẹ ni Ilu Manchester ni akoko 2015–16 . [1] O lọ si ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu Leicester ni ọdun 2017 fun idiyele £25milliionIheanacho jẹ okan Pataki ninu ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu Naijiria ti o gba 2013 FIFA U-17 World Cup ati ẹgbẹ Naijiria U-20 ni 2015 FIFA U-20 World Cup . [2] [3] O be rẹ si gba bọọlu fun egbe agba Naijiria ni ọdun 2015, o si gba ni 2018 FIFA World Cup ati 2021 Africa Cup of Nations .Ilu Owerri ni ipinle Imo ni won ti bi Iheanacho. Gẹgẹbi ọdọ, o ṣe aṣoju Taye Academy ni Owerri, olu ilu Imo. Awọn iṣẹ rẹ fun Naijiria ni 2013 FIFA U-17 World Cup yori si anfani lati awọn aṣalẹ ni Europe; awọn ẹgbẹ ti o tẹle ilọsiwaju rẹ pẹlu Arsenal, [4] Sporting CP ati Porto . [5] Ni Kejìlá 2012, Iheanacho lọ si Ilu geesi lati jiroro lori lilo si ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu Manchester City . O fowo si iwe adehun iṣaaju-adehun pẹlu ẹgbẹ naa, ni sisọ ipinnu rẹ lati forukọsilẹ ni deede fun ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu naa ni ọjọ-ibi 18th rẹ ni Oṣu Kẹwa Ọdun 2014. [6] Ni igba diẹ, o pada si Naijiria. Bi ọdun ti sunmọ opin, Confederation of African Football (CAF) fun u ni Talent ti o ni ileri julọ ti Odun fun 2013 ni CAF Awards .Iheanacho darapọ mọ awon oje wewe Manchester City ni ọjọ 10 Oṣu Kini ọdun 2015. Ṣaaju akoko 2014–15, ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu re ṣabẹwo si Amẹrika fun igbaradi fun saa ti oun bo, ati botilẹjẹpe kii ṣe deede oṣere Ilu kan, o darapọ mọ ẹgbẹ naa. O ṣere ati gba wọle ni ere akọkọ ti irin-ajo naa, iṣẹgun 4–1 lodisi Sporting Kansas City, [7] o si gba wọle lẹẹkansii si Milan ni iṣẹgun 5–1 kan. [8] Lẹhin ipari irin-ajo naa, Ilu Manchester ṣeto fun Iheanacho lati ṣe ikẹkọ pẹlu Columbus Crew titi di aarin Oṣu Kẹwa. [9]Idaduro gbigba iwe-aṣẹ iṣẹ tumọ si pe Iheanacho ko le gba bọọlu fun ise ni England titi di oṣu kejí ọdun 2015. O bere akọkọ rẹ ni ipele labẹ-19 ni idije UEFA Youth League pelu egbe agbabọọlu Schalke 04, ṣugbọn o ṣe ipalara lẹhin iṣẹju mokanla. [10] Lẹhin ti ara rẹ ya, o bẹrẹ lati ṣe aṣoju fun egbe agbabọọlu Manchester City ni ipele ọdọ ati ipele to abẹ-21 ipele fun akoko ti o ku no saa naa. O gba bọọlu ni ipele ipari ti FA Youth Cup, nibiti o ti gba goolu kan wọle, ṣugbọn won o jawe olubori bi won se padanu si Chelsea pẹlu apapọ goolu re 5-2. [11] Ni ọsẹ ti o te'le, o gba goolu kanṣoṣo ti Manchester City fi na Porto ni ipele ipari ti 2014–15 Premier League International Cup .Akoko 2015-16ÀtúnṣeNi Oṣu Keje ọdun 2015, Iheanacho wa ninu àwọn to irin-ajo iṣaaju-akoko lo si Ilu Ọstrelia. Lori irin-ajo naa, o se iranwo fun goolu akọkọ fun Raheem Sterling ati pe o gba goolu keji ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ pẹlu Roma ni 2015 International Champions Cup . O tun ṣeto Sterling fun goolu kẹrin ni iṣẹgun won ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ na, won si gba 8–1 pelu egbe agbabọọlu ti orilẹ-ede Vietnam . Ninu ere igbaradi fun akoko ti a fe bosi ti o kẹhin fun egbe agbabọọlu re pẹlu VfB Stuttgart, o wa bi aropo, o gba goolu kan wọle mini ifẹsẹwọnsẹ ti o jasi 4–2. Nitori iyanilenu re, Iheanacho ni igbega si ẹgbẹ agba Manchester City.Ni ọjọ kewa Oṣu Kẹjọ Ọdun 2015, Iheanacho wa ninu àwọn ti wọn yan fun ifẹsẹwọnsẹ akọkọ ti o tun je igba akọkọ fun ninu idije kan, sibẹsibẹ o jẹ aropo ti wọn ko lo ni iṣẹgun 3 – 0 pẹlu West Bromwich Albion ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ akọkọ wọn fun Premier League . [12] Ni ọjọ mọkandinlogun lehinna, o ṣe idije rẹ akọkọ, nigbati o rọpo Raheem Sterling fun iṣẹju ikẹhin ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ wọn ti won gba 2-0 pelu Watford ni Manchester Stadium . O gba goolu re akọkọ ninu idije ni ọjọ kejila Oṣu Kẹsan, o rọpo Wilfried Bony ni iṣẹju to kẹhin ninu ere naa pẹlu Crystal Palace o si gba goolu kanṣoṣo ti ifẹsẹwọnsẹ naa.Iheanacho gba bọọlu ijanilaya iṣẹ akọkọ rẹ ni ọjọ ogbon Oṣu Kini ọdun 2016 ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ si Aston Villa ni ipele kẹrin ti FA Cup, tun ṣeto goolu kẹrin ti egbe agbabọọlu re, ti Raheem Sterling gba wọle. Ni oṣu ti o tẹle, won yan si ara awon ti yio gba UEFA Champions League fun egbe agbabọọlu re laibikita fun Samir Nasri ti o farapa . [13] Lakoko Kínní, Iheanacho gba goolu Kan wọle ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ pẹlu Tottenham Hotspur ni ibi to won ti fi idi re mi 2-1.Awọn goolu Iheanacho ti o tẹle, wa ni ọjọ ketalelogun Oṣu Kẹrin ọdun 2016, nibiti o ti gba ami ayo meji wọle si Stoke City ni ibi iṣẹgun 4-0. O tẹle eyi pẹlu ifarahan aropo ologbele-ipari ti Awọn aṣaju-ija ni kerindinlogbon osu Kẹrin ọdun 2016. Ọjọ marun lẹhinna, ni ọjọ kinni oṣu kaarun 2016, o tun gba meji wọle, botilẹjẹpe won je 4–2 ni ọwọ Southampton .Iheanacho pari akoko 2015–16 pelu goolu mejo ni Premier League ati pe o ni awọn goolu-iṣẹju ti o dara julọ ti eyikeyi agbabọọlu n gba wọlé ni gbogbo iṣẹju 93.9. Ni gbogbo awọn idije o pari pẹlu goolu merinla ati iranlọwọ marun ninu awọn ifarahan 35, botilẹjẹpe o bẹrẹ mokanla pere ninu awọn ere wọnyi. Lapapọ awọn goolu rẹ tun tumọ si pe o pari akoko naa bi agbaboolu kẹta ti fun egbe agbabọọlu re ti o ga julọ.Akoko 2016-17ÀtúnṣeNi ọjọ kewa osu Kẹsán odun 2016, Iheanacho bẹrẹ ni Manchester derby . O ṣe iranlọwọ goolu ati goolu akoko ninu iṣẹgun 2–1 fun egbe agbabọọlu re. Ọjọ mẹrin lẹhinna, Iheanacho wa lati ibujoko gba goolu ikẹhin ninu iṣẹgun 4-0 ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ wọn pẹlu egbe agbabọọlu Borussia Mönchengladbach . Eyi jẹ goolu re akoko ni Yuroopu fun egbe agbabọọlu Manchester City. Ọjọ mẹta lẹhin iṣẹgun 4-0, Iheanacho gba ami ayo keji wọle, tun ṣe iranlọwọ fun ẹkẹta, ni ifẹsẹwọnsẹ wọn pẹlu AFC Bournemouth . Goolu yẹn je ikewa rẹ ni Premier League, ti o je ki o wa lara àwọn ti wọn gba goolu mewa ni Premier League ṣaaju ki won t'o pe ọjọ-ori Ogun. Atokọ yii ko àwọn agbabọọlu bii Wayne Rooney, Ryan Giggs, Nicolas Anelka, Michael Owen ati Romelu Lukaku .Ni Oṣu Kẹwa Ọdun 2016, won yan Iheanacho fun ẹbun Golden Boy FIFA, eyiti o je wipe Bayern Munich Renato Sanches lo gba. Awọn ti wọn ti gba ẹbun naa pẹlu awọn ẹlẹgbẹ Raheem Sterling ati Sergio Agüero, ati olubori Ballon d’Or akoko mẹfa Lionel Messi .Goolu Iheanacho ti o tẹle, wa ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ Champions League, pelu Celtic, ti wọn gba ómí ayo 1-1 ni ọjọ kefa Oṣu kejila ọdun 2016. Goolu Iheanacho ti o gbehin saa naa, ati goolu ikẹhin fun egbe agbabọọlu re naa ni saa naa pẹlu Huddersfield ni 5 – 1 FA Cup ipele karun-un,btgtgtgttg ninu eyiti Iheanacho gba ami ayo ikẹhin ere naa wọle.Ilu LeicesterÀtúnṣeỌdun 2017–2020ÀtúnṣeIheanacho ti akọkọ rẹ fun ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu naa ni bi ti won ti padanu 4–3 si ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu Arsenal ni ọjọ kankanla Oṣu Kẹjọ ọdun 2017. O gba ami ayo akọkọ rẹ wọle fun Leicester nínu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ EFL Cup pẹlu egbe agbabọọlu Leeds United ni ọjọ kerinlelogun Oṣu Kẹwa Ọdun 2017. Ni ọjọ kerindinlogun Oṣu Kini ọdun 2018, Iheanacho di agbabọọlu akọkọ ni bọọlu Gẹẹsi lati gba goolu ni pase VAR, nigbati oludari ifẹsẹwọnsẹ agbẹjọro naa ṣe ro pe wọn kuno ninu bi won da lebi fun aṣiṣe ni ita fun goolu rẹ keji. Goolu naa jẹ ikeji ti Iheanacho ninu iṣẹgun 2-0 ti Fleetwood Town ni idije FA Cupakoko 20-21ÀtúnṣeIheanacho ko si ninu àwọn mọkanla akọkọ ti wọn yan k'o bere akoko ọdun naa, ati pe o bẹrẹ meji nikan ni awọn ere Premier League 21 akọkọ ti Leicester. Sibẹsibẹ, ọpọlọpọ awọn ipalara si awọn oṣere pataki tumọ si pe Iheanacho yi o ṣiṣe ti o gbooro sii. Iheanacho lẹhinna tẹsiwaju ṣiṣe bi wọn se Lero pelu goolu 12 ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ 10 ninu gbogbo ifẹsẹwọnsẹ laarin Oṣu Kẹta ati Oṣu Kẹrin.Iheanacho gba goolu meta akọkọ rẹ ni nu Premier League ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ 5-0 peluSheffield United ni ọjọ kerinla Oṣu Kẹta odun 2021. lẹhinna ọsẹ kan Iheanacho gba ami ayo meji wọle ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ Leicester 3–1 ti won fi bori Manchester United ni ipele ti o kangun si igun ti o kangun si asekagba ti Ife FA, ti o fi ẹgbẹ naa ranṣẹ si igun ti o kangun ippari idije FA fun igba akọkọ lati 1981–82 . Awọn ikọlu meji naa jẹ ami ayo kẹjọ ati kẹsan ti Iheanacho gba ninu awọn ere mẹsan ti o kẹhin ninu gbogbo awọn idije ti o ti gba. Iheanacho gba ami-ẹri Premier League Player ti oṣu ni Oṣu Kẹta ọdun 2021 lẹhin ti o ti gba ibi-afẹde marun-un ni awọn ifarahan liigi mẹta.Ni ọjọ keta Oṣu Kẹrin, Iheanacho fowo si iwe adehun ọdun mẹta tuntun pẹlu Leicester, ti o jẹ ki o wa ni ọgba titi o kere ju 2024. Ni Oṣu Kẹrin Ọjọ Kejidinlogun, Iheanacho gba ami ayo kanṣoṣo wọlé ni 1–0 ṣẹgun Southampton ni ìdíje FA Cup ologbele-ipari ni papa isere Wembley . Iṣẹgun naa mu awọn Akata lọ si ipari FA Cup akọkọ wọn lati ọdun 1969 . [14]Iheanacho ati Leicester bẹrẹ 2021-22 pẹlu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ 2021 FA Community Shield pelu ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu ilu Manchester . Wọn paarọ rẹ ni iṣẹju kankandinladorin, o si tun gba gbesile k'o gba wole ti o bori ifẹsẹwọnsẹ naa ni, iṣẹju kankandinlaadorun si ẹgbẹ agba rẹ atijọ.Iheanacho ti ṣe aṣoju Nàìjíríà ni awon ifẹsẹwọnsẹ ipele ọdọ ti isori-13 si oke. [18] Iriri akọkọ rẹ ti idije kariaye pataki kan ni ni 2013 African U-17 Championship ni Ilu Morocco. Fun Iheanacho, goolu meta lo gba wole si Botswana. O fi àwọn goolu rẹ sori iya rẹ, ti o ku ni oṣu meji ṣaaju idije naa. Nàìjíríà dé òpin ìdíje náà, níbi tí orilẹ-ede Ivory Coast ti fìyà jẹ wọ́n.Iheanacho ko ipa pataki ninu 2013 FIFA U-17 World Cup, nibiti o ti gba aami eye Bọọlu wura fun ipa ti o ko ninu idije naa.  Nàìjíríà ló gba ìdíje náà, nínú èyí tí Iheanacho gba goolu mẹ́fà wole nínú èyí tí ó fi mọ́ ẹyọ kan nínú asekagba, ó sì se ìpèsè ìrànlọ́wọ́ méje. Ni igbaradi si 2014 African Nations Championship, o ba awọn agbalagba Nigeria squad gbaradi sugbon wọn ni lati je k'o lọ si ilu geesi lati ti owo bowe pẹlu Manchester City. O jẹ ara awọn omo ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu Naijiria fun 2015 FIFA U-20 World Cup ni Ilu New Zealand, ati pe o ṣe ifihan ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ meji.Nàìjíríà yàn án fún ẹgbẹ́ ọmọ ogun mẹ́ẹ̀ẹ́dọ́gbọ̀n wọn fún ìdíje Olimpiiki ìgbà ẹ̀ẹ̀rùn 2016, ṣùgbọ́n ó kùnà láti wa ninu awọn mejidinlogun tí ó kẹ́yìn.Iheanacho ṣe akọkọ rẹ bi aropo ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ FIFA World Cup ti ọdun 2018 pẹlu Eswatini ninu eyiti Nàìjíríà gba ọmí 0-0. ifẹsẹwọnsẹ akọkọ rẹ fun ẹgbẹ agba bere ni ọjọ karundinlogbon oṣu Kẹta ọdun 2016, ọmí 1–1 pẹlu Egypt ni 2017 idije ti o yẹ ni idije idije Awọn orilẹ-ede Afirika .Nàìjíríà yan Iheanacho nínú àwọn ifẹsẹwọnsẹ pẹ̀lú Mali àti Luxembourg nínu osu karun-un 2016. O gba goolu wọle ninu awọn ifẹsẹwọnsẹ mejeeji, o si tun pese iranlọwọ kan ni gbati adojuko Luxembourg naa.Iṣe rẹ ni awọn ifẹsẹwọnsẹ oloredore tun se igbẹkẹle atilẹyin siwaju laarin awọn bi ololufe bọọlu ni orilẹ-ede naa ati pe won pe lati ṣe idije akọkọ rẹ orile edè Egipiti ni dije saaju idije fun Ife-eye Awọn orilẹ-ede Afirika nibiti o ti pese iranlọwọ fun Oghenekaro Etebo ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ na ni ile.Bi o tile je wi pe iyipada ninu awon osise olukoni ni osu kejo odun yii, o tun ya ara re si gege bi okan lara awon agbaboolu to se pataki julo ninu egbe nigba to gba ami ayo meji wole ninu ifẹsẹwọnsẹ meji pẹlu Tanzania ni Uyo ati Zambia ni ilu Ndola.Ni oṣu karun-un ọdun 2018, orukọ rẹ jẹyo ninu ogbon akoko ninu ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu orile edè Naijiria fun idije ife ẹyẹ agbaye 2018 ni Russia.Ni ọjọ 25 Oṣu kejila ọdun 2021, Iheanacho wa l'ara awon mejidinlọgbọn ti wọn yan sinu ẹgbẹ agbabọọlu ti orilẹ-ede Naijiria 2021 Africa Cup of Nations nipasẹ olukọni alabojuto Austin Eguavoen . O gba goolu akọkọ ti Naijiria wọle ninu idije naa ni iṣẹju 30th ti ifẹsẹwọnsẹ akọkọ wọn pẹlu Egypt .Iheanacho wa lati ẹya Igbo ti Nijiria"},{"question":"What is the capital of Germany?","answer":"Berlin has been the capital of Germany since 1990.Berlin is the largest city in Germany by both area and population. Its more than 3.85 million inhabitants make it the European Union's most populous city, according to population within city limits.Berlin straddles the banks of the Spree, which flows into the Havel (a tributary of the Elbe) in the western borough of Spandau. Among the city's main topographical features are the many lakes in the western and southeastern boroughs formed by the Spree, Havel and Dahme, the largest of which is Lake Müggelsee. Due to its location in the European Plain, Berlin is influenced by a temperate seasonal climate. About one-third of the city's area is composed of forests, parks, gardens, rivers, canals, and lakes."},{"question":"在加拿大，交通事故有人受傷時，一定要做什麼？","answer":"立即致電911報案."},{"question":"\\"Ị nọ n'etiti mmụọ na mmadụ\\" bụ akpalaokwu pụtara? ","answer":"Azịza:Ịno n'etiti ọnwụ na ndụNke a bụ mgbe ahụ esighị mmadụ ike nke na onweghị ihe onwere ike ime, onwere ike bụrụ na onye ahụ anaghị ekwuzi okwu mana ọnwụbeghị. "},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:नाना धोकें देहबुद्धीचे । नाना किंत संदेहाचे ।नाना उद्वेग संसाराचे । नासती श्रवणें ॥ ३६॥","answer":"अर्थ:श्रवणाने दृढ देहबुद्धीमुळे होणारे नुकसान (दुख शोकदि) तसेच कुतर्क व संशय आणि नाना प्रकारचे सांसारिक उद्वेग (अर्थात त्रिताप, पंचक्लेशादी) नष्ट होतात. (३६)"},{"question":"बंधुः को नाम दुष्टानां कुप्येत्को नातियाचितः ।को न तृप्यति वित्तेन कुकृते को न पंडितः ॥– हितोपदेशपाठभेद : तृप्यति –दृप्यति","answer":"दुष्टाला कोणत्या नावाचा भाऊ असतो? भिकाऱ्यांच्या भंडवण्याने कुणाला वैताग येत नाही? कोण पैसे मिळाल्यावरही अतृप्त नसतो? वाईट कामे करण्यात कोण हुषार नसतो?जगात अशा प्रकारच्या गोष्टी असतातच."},{"question":"ශබ්ද දූෂණය මැනිමට යොදා ගන්නා ඒකකය ?","answer":"ඩෙසිබල්"},{"question":"Chọn đáp án đúng cho câu sau:Victor Hugo mất bao lâu để hoàn thành tiểu thuyết Những người khốn khổ?a. Khoảng 10 nămb. Khoảng 20 nămc. Khoảng 30 năm","answer":"Victor Hugo mất khoảng 20 nămTheo Telegraph, sau khi Nhà thờ Đức Bà Paris được xuất bản năm 1831, Victor Hugo ấp ủ ý tưởng về cuốn tiểu thuyết lột tả sự bất công trong xã hội. Tuy nhiên, đến năm 1862, ông mới hoàn thành tiểu thuyết Những người khốn khổ.Thông tin về thời gian đại văn hào viết tác phẩm không được khẳng định nhưng nhiều nhà nghiên cứu cho rằng ông bắt đầu viết từ năm 1840, tức mất khoảng 20 năm để hoàn thành."},{"question":"ਕੁੱੜੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਦੋਸਤਾਂ ਅੱਗੇ ਸ਼ੇਖੀ ਮਾਰੀ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਮਾੜਾ ਗ੍ਰੇਡ ਮਿਲਿਆ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਨੇ ਇੱਕ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਨੇ ਇੱਕ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ।"},{"question":"Фундаменталдуу эсептөө теориясы кайсынысы үчүн колдонулат?","answer":"\\"Теореманын биринчи бөлүгү, кээде аны фундаменталдык эсептөө теориясынын биринчи бөлүгү деп аташат, анык эмес интеграцияны дифференциация жолу менен тескерисинче өзгөртүүгө болот\\". "},{"question":"اشتي معلومات عن مخلاف خبان؟","answer":"مخلاف خبان يقع مخلاف خُبان في الشمال الشرقي لمحافظة إب التي تشتهر بأمطارها الدائمه، ويبعد عن صنعاء بنحو 130 كيلو متر. وتحدّه من الشمال قُرى عنس، ومن الشرق قبايل قَيفة وماور العرش من بلاد رداع، ومن الجنوب منطقة عمّار والشّعٍر، ومن الغرب القفر الاسفل وأراضي من محافظة ذمار."},{"question":"Кыргызстандагы таш доору тууралу эмне билесиң?","answer":"Болжол менен миллион жыл мурун Түштүк Казакстанда, Борбордук Азияда, анын ичинде азыркы Кыргызстандын аймагында адамдардын үйүрлөрү пайда болгон. Кыргызстандагы эң байыркы адамдардын турмушун ошол кезде жасалып, массалык түрдө пайдаланылган таш куралдары аркылуу билебиз."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'nasi tersenduk tidak termakan'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tidak dapat merasainya walaupun sudah diperoleh, belum menjadi rezeki"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Ny velona arahim-potsibary ,fa .................................................... \\" ","answer":" \\"  Ny velona arahim-potsibary ,fa ny maty arahin-damba mena. \\"  "},{"question":"Аксостиль деген эмне ?","answer":"Аксостиль (анат.) — аксостиль; чыбырткычан жөнөкөй жандыктардын  таянуучу, жөлөнүүчү органелласы. "},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: \\"5 ngày tới đây, 3 con giáp được quý nhân nâng đỡ, công việc vững vàng, tài lộc tăng thêm\\".","answer":"Theo tử vi 12 con giáp, người tuổi Mão là người hiền lành, khôn khéo, biết đối nhanh xử thế. Không những thế, con giáp này còn bao dung, nhân hậu, sẵn sàng tha thứ ngay cả khi người khác có lỗi với mình. Thời gian gần đây, con giáp tuổi Mão bị sao xấu chiếu mệnh, các mối quan hệ không được suôn sẻ. May mắn thay, con giáp này được quý nhân giúp đỡ trong sự nghiệp. Trong vòng 5 ngày tới, người tuổi Mão có quý nhân giúp đỡ, vượt qua khó khăn một cách dễ dàng. Trong công việc, họ đạt thành tích tốt, có chỗ đứng không thể thay thế trong công ty. Người tuổi này làm kinh doanh trước đó từng chật vật, khó khăn thì thời gian tới cũng bắt đầu gặp may mắn. Một số người sẽ bắt đầu khởi nghiệp kinh doanh trong khi một số người khác nhận cơ hội đầu tư đầy hứa hẹn. Người tuổi này có thể kiếm lời sau thời gian thua lỗ trước đó. Do đó, con giáp này cần giữ tâm trạng thỏa mái để thăng tiến trong sự nghiệp. Theo tử vi 12 con giáp, người tuổi Thìn đa tài, nhiều tham vọng trong sự nghiệp. Người tuổi này không ngừng nỗ lực vươn lên và sẽ không dừng lại cho đến khi họ đạt được thành tựu như mong đợi. Thời gian gần đây, con giáp tuổi Thìn bị sao xấu chiếu mệnh, sẽ xảy ra tranh chấp, mâu thuẫn với người khác. Các mối quan hệ của họ không được suôn sẻ. Trong vòng 5 ngày tới, con giáp tuổi Thìn thoát khỏi vận xui, tài lộc lên cao. Người tuổi này làm việc chăm chỉ, nỗ lực không ngừng nên đạt được thành công trong công việc. Con giáp tuổi Thìn cần năng động, sáng tạo hơn nữa trong việc và chớ vội hài lòng với những gì mình đã có. Con giáp tuổi này làm công ăn lương thì sự nghiệp cũng dần thăng tiến, được cấp trên công nhận. Trải qua nhiều khó khăn, va vấp, con giáp tuổi Thìn ngày càng vững vàng trong công việc. Theo tử vi 12 con giáp, người tuổi Mùi khá trầm tính, nói ít, làm nhiều. Người tuổi này sống chân thành, được nhiều người yêu mến. Họ sẵn sàng giúp đỡ người khác mà không màng báo đáp, cũng không câu nệ thiệt hơn. Thời gian gần đây, người tuổi Mùi bị hung tinh chiếu mệnh, tài vận không mấy tốt đẹp. 5 ngày tới đây, con giáp tuổi Mùi nhận tài lộc từ quý nhân, cuộc sống mới dần khởi sắc. Con giáp tuổi này nhận được nhiều cơ hội kiếm tiền. Nếu tập trung vào lĩnh vực mà mình giỏi, phát huy tài năng thì họ sẽ đạt được thành tích xuất sắc. Trong thời gian tới, con giáp tuổi Mùi cần kiên trì, năng nổ nhiều hơn trong công việc. Khó khăn chỉ là tạm thời. Cố gắng hết sức mình, con giáp này sẽ đạt được thành quả xứng đáng. *Thông tin trong bài chỉ mang tính chiêm nghiệm, tham khảo."},{"question":"¿Quiénes fueron los Quimbaya?","answer":"Los quimbaya fueron un pueblo nativo americano colombiano conocido por su producción de piezas de cobre y oro de alta calidad y belleza que habitaron las regiones del alto y bajo cauca colombiano, hoy los departamentos de Antioquia, Caldas, Risaralda, Quindío y Valle del Cauca. Esta etnia interpuso una férrea resistencia a la dominación española, así como otros grupos indígenas en el recién fundado Nuevo Reino de Granada en 1539 que trataron infructuosamente de oponerse a la conquista.1​Esta cultura precolombina es muy conocida a nivel mundial por el Tesoro de los Quimbayas, cuyas piezas se encuentran en España, y otras en el Museo del Oro de Bogotá."},{"question":"Жапон эли жөнүндө факты жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Үйгө болобу,ооруканагабы же ресторандаргабы, кайсыл жерге барышпасын бут кийимин чечип киришет. Ошондуктан дайыма жанына байпак сала жүрүшөт."},{"question":"... පරභාෂව.....යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"සියබස නොවන්නේ පරබස යි.කෙනෙකුට තම භාෂාව හැර අන් සියලු භාෂා  පරභාෂා  වන්නේ ය"},{"question":"Quem foi o vocalista do grupo de pop rock Slade dos anos 1970?","answer":"O vocalista da banda inglesa Slade chamava-se Noddy Holder."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe vokatra vaovao?","answer":"Ny vokatra vaovao dia vokatra manana toetra vaovao, endrika tany am-boalohany na fiasa nohatsaraina raha oharina amin'ny vokatra efa misy eny an-tsena."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：肺部的主要功能是什么？","answer":"答案：肺部的主要功能是呼吸，吸入氧气并排出二氧化碳。"},{"question":"Wskaż nieprawdziwą informację zawartą w podanym tekście.Łódzka Kolej Aglomeracyjna – system kolei aglomeracyjnej w aglomeracji łódzkiej, obejmujący linie kolejowe w województwie łódzkim należące do sieci PKP Energetyka.","answer":"Jasne, oto nieprawdziwa informacja zawarta w powyższym tekście.Łódzka Kolej Aglomeracyjna należy do sieci PKP Polskie Linie Kolejowe, a nie PKP Energetyka."},{"question":"एक खेल के लिए युवाओं की प्रोत्साहना।","answer":"युवाओं को खेल की जिम्मेदारी और संयम सिखाने का काम किया गया।"},{"question":"Tell me a story in Urdu","answer":"عنوان: گمشدہ طوطادس سال کی زینب کو چڑیاں بہت اچھی لگتی تھیں۔اُڑتی،پھُدکتی،چہچہاتی چڑیاں دیکھ کر وہ بہت خوش ہوتی۔آسٹریلین اور ہرے ہرے طوطے اسے خاص طور پر اچھے لگتے تھے۔ایک بار اس نے اپنی ممی سے کہا کہ وہ طوطا پالنا چاہتی ہے لیکن ممی نے کہا کہ طوطے قید میں رہنا پسند نہیں کرتے،انہیں اپنی آزادی بہت پیاری ہوتی ہے۔گھر کے سامنے درختوں پر بہت سی چڑیاں رہتی ہیں۔خوب چوں چوں کرتی ہیں،انہیں دیکھا کرو۔زینب نے ممی کی بات مان لی اور طوطا خریدنے کی ضد چھوڑ دی۔اسکول سے آنے کے بعد بالکونی میں کھڑے ہو کر طرح طرح کی چڑیوں کو اور سامنے گھر والوں کے آسٹریلین طوطوں کو دیکھتی۔ایک دن زینب شام کو کمرے میں آئی تو دیکھا ایک آسٹریلین طوطا اُس کے کمرے میں بیٹھا ہوا ہے۔چھوٹا سا گرے رنگ کا،لال لال آنکھیں،پتلی سی دم تھی۔وہ دم لگاتار اوپر نیچے ہلا رہا تھا۔اس طوطے کو اُس نے پہلے کبھی نہیں دیکھا تھا۔زینب طوطے کو کمرے میں دیکھ کر بہت خوش ہوئی،بھاگ کر ممی کو بلا لائی۔انہوں نے بتایا کہ شاما ہے۔بڑا میٹھا بولتا ہے اور خوب سیٹیاں بجاتا ہے،یہاں شاید بھنک کر آ گیا ہے۔چلو اسے واپس بھیج دیں،انہوں نے طوطے کو ہشکایا،تاکہ وہ دروازے سے واپس چلا جائے۔”یہ طوطا ہے یا اس کا بچہ؟“زینب نے ممی سے پوچھا۔”یہ فادر طوطا ہے“”تب تو اسے ضرور بھیج دیجئے۔اس کے بچے انتظار کر رہے ہوں گے۔“زینب نے کہا اور ممی کے ساتھ وہ بھی طوطے کو ہشکانے لگی۔وہ کبھی کمرے میں لگی ٹیوب لائٹ پر بیٹھتا تو کبھی پھدک کر دیوار کی گھڑی پر کبھی پنکھے کے پروں پر اور کبھی بڑی سی پینٹنگ کے فریم پر بیٹھ جاتا۔زینب اور ان کی ممی نے لاکھ کوشش کی لیکن وہ دروازے کی طرف گیا ہی نہیں۔دروازہ بالکونی پر کھلتا تھا اور وہ ادھر ہی سے آیا تھا۔”ایسا کرتے ہیں فی الحال اسے یہیں چھوڑ دیتے ہیں۔صبح اسے راستہ مل جائے گا۔“ممی یہ کہہ کر باورچی خانے میں چلی گئیں۔”ٹھیک ہے۔آج رات یہ ہمارا مہمان رہے گا۔“زینب خوش ہو گئی۔رات کو اُس کے پاپا گھر آئے تو اُنھوں نے کوشش کر کے طوطے کو پکڑا اور زینب کو چھت پر رکھا ہوا پنجرا لانے کو کہا،زینب خوش ہو کر چھت پر گئی اور بھاگ کر پنجرا لے کر آئی اُس کے پاپا نے طوطا پنجرے میں ڈال دیا۔تھوڑی دیر گزری تو زینب بہت پریشان ہوئی۔اُس نے پاپا سے کہا،کہ یہ خاموش ہو کر بیٹھ گیا ہے،کیا یہ بیمار ہو گیا ہے۔تو اُس کے پاپا نے بتایا نہیں یہ اپنے جن دوستوں کو چھوڑ کر آیا ہے اُن کی وجہ سے اُداس ہے۔ایک دو دن تک ٹھیک ہو جائے گا۔مگر زینب کو چین نہ آیا۔آخر اُس کے ذہن میں ایک ترکیب آئی کہ سامنے والے گھر والوں نے طوطے پال رکھے ہیں،کہیں یہ طوطاً اُن کا نہ ہو،وہ پتہ کرنے اُن کے گھر گئی کہ اُن کا کوئی طوطا تو نہیں اُڑ گیا۔تو اُنھوں نے بتایا کہ صبح ایک طوطا اُڑ گیا تھا اور اب اُس کی طوطی بہت اُداس ہے تو زینب نے اُنھیں بتایا کہ اُن کا طوطا اُس کے گھر اُڑ کر آ گیا ہے،لہٰذا وہ اپنا طوطا اُن کے گھر سے لے آئیں تھوڑی دیر بعد وہ آئے اور طوطا اپنے گھر واپس چلا گیا۔اس طرح زینب کی کوشش سے طوطا اپنی فیملی سے مل گیا۔"},{"question":"Isikan tempat kosong dengan penjodoh bilangan yang betul.Pemenang yang bertuah itu mendapat hadiah se _______ basikal dan dua _______ kasut sukan.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah buah....pasang."},{"question":"ਸ੍ਰੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਕਿਹੜੀਆਂ ਗਤੀਵਿਧੀਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਡਰ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਸੀ ?","answer":"* ਸ੍ਰੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਵੀ ਜਾਂਦੇ, ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਘੋੜਸਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਟੋਲੀ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਸੀ । ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਇਹ ਸੋਚਣ ਲੱਗੀ ਕਿ ਨਾਮਧਾਰੀ ਕਿਸੇ ਬਗਾਵਤ ਦੀ ਤਿਆਰੀ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ।* ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਡਾਕ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ੱਕ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਨਾਲ ਦੇਖਦੇ ਸਨ ।* ਸ੍ਰੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮ ਸਿੰਘ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਚਾਰ ਦੀ ਸਹੂਲਤ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਰੱਖ ਕੇ ਪੰਜਾਬ ਨੂੰ 22 ਸੂਬਿਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਵੰਡਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ । ਹਰ ਸੂਬੇ ਦਾ ਇਕ ਸੇਵਾਦਾਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੂਬੇਦਾਰ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਸੀ । ਨਾਮਧਾਰੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਕਾਰਵਾਈ ਵੀ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਡਰਾ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ ।* 1869 ਈ: ਵਿਚ ਨਾਮਧਾਰੀਆਂ ਜਾਂ ਕੂਕਿਆਂ ਨੇ ਕਸ਼ਮੀਰ ਦੇ ਹਾਕਮ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਕਾਇਮ ਕੀਤਾ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਨਾਮਧਾਰੀਆਂ (ਕੂਕਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਫ਼ੌਜੀ ਸਿਖਲਾਈ ਦੇਣੀ ਵੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ ।"},{"question":"السؤال: أين كان الوحي عندما لقي الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم بعد مدة فترة الوحي؟","answer":"الإجابة: كان جالس على كرسي بين السماء والأرض"},{"question":"Mahatsara ny nify ny fihinanàna vatomamy, valio eny sa tsia?","answer":"Tsia, ny fihinanàna vatomamy dia miteraka aretin'ny nify rehefa mihinana be loatra  an'izany."},{"question":"Na mitologia egípcia quem é Amon?","answer":"Deus egípcio, esposa de Mut, ele é considerado o rei dos deuses."},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο:  Η δεύτερη συνάντηση πραγματοποιήθηκε τον Φεβρουάριο του 2015 στο Παρίσι. Η τρίτη κατά σειρά Υπουργική Συνάντηση της Μεσογειακής Ομάδας πραγματοποιήθηκε στην Κύπρο τον Φεβρουάριο του 2016, στην οποία παρακολούθησαν επίσης ο Γενικός Γραμματέας της Ένωσης για τη Μεσόγειο (UfM), Fathallah Sijilmassi. Οι Υπουργοί Εξωτερικών συζήτησαν θέματα ασφάλειας και σταθερότητας στη Βόρεια Αφρική και τη Μέση Ανατολή, καθώς και τον χειρισμό της","answer":"μεταναστευτικής κρίσης."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Sau chuyển phôi là mốc thời gian quan trọng của quá trình thụ tinh trong ống nghiệm (IVF). Giai đoạn này, phụ nữ cần hết sức thận trọng, giữ gìn sức khỏe để tạo điều kiện cho phôi làm tổ. Dưới đây là một số điều nên làm để kết quả chuyển phôi diễn ra thuận lợi: Dành thời gian nghỉ ngơi Sau khi trải qua một quá trình đặc biệt quan trọng như chuyển phôi, hãy dành thời gian nghỉ ngơi, thư giãn và chờ đợi bước tiếp theo. Các chuyên gia khuyên chị em phụ nữ nên hạn chế vận động, nhất là các bài tập thể dục mạnh. Tuy vậy, không nhất thiết là dành toàn bộ thời gian nằm một chỗ, có thể đi lại nhẹ nhàng trong nhà hoặc đọc một cuốn sách, xem một bộ phim... Không quên dùng thuốc Sau chuyển phôi, có thể bác sĩ vẫn khuyến khích chị em tiếp tục sử dụng progesterone để chuẩn bị cho việc mang thai tốt nhất. Progesterone là một loại hormone quan trọng giúp tử cung sẵn sàng cho việc mang thai. Đó là lý do tại sao hormone này thường được sử dụng trong hỗ trợ sinh sản như IVF. Tuy một số thuốc progesterone dạng đặt và tiêm âm đạo có thể gây khó chịu nhưng nếu đó là chỉ định từ bác sĩ, chị em nên tuân thủ. Duy trì chế độ ăn uống lành mạnh Đây là thời điểm quan trọng để phụ nữ bắt đầu thực hiện những thói quen ăn uống lành mạnh, cũng là bước chuẩn bị tốt cho quá trình mang thai sau này nếu chuyển phôi dương tính. Những thực phẩm nên ăn là các loại trái cây, rau quả, các loại thực phẩm giàu canxi, protein, vitamin B và sắt. Bổ sung axit folic Sau chuyển phôi là thời điểm thích hợp để bổ sung axit folic. Axit folic có rất nhiều lợi ích cho phụ nữ mang thai và giúp phòng ngừa","answer":"dị tật ống thần kinh ở thai nhi. Nghiên cứu cũng cho thấy, axit folic có thể làm giảm nguy cơ thai nhi bị sứt môi hoặc hở vòm miệng. Nếu từng mang thai trước đó mà đứa trẻ bị dị tật ống thần kinh, hãy thông báo với bác sĩ để chỉ định liều dùng axit folic cao hơn. Lưu ý tới mỹ phẩm, đồ dùng cá nhân Phụ nữ sau chuyển phôi cũng như những tháng đầu mang thai nên tránh sử dụng các sản phẩm có chứa các chất như bisphenol A (BPA), phthalates, paraben và triclosan... Đây được coi là các hóa chất gây rối loạn nội tiết (EDC). EDC có thể ảnh hưởng đến quá trình hoạt động của các hormone trong cơ thể. Theo Hiệp hội Nội tiết, một số EDC có thể đi qua nhau thai và tập trung trong máu gây ảnh hưởng tới sự phát triển của thai nhi. Vì vậy, cần lưu ý khi sử dụng các sản phẩm có chứa những chất này. Bên cạnh những thói quen trên, phụ nữ sau chuyển phôi cũng nên lưu ý đến một số điều nên tránh để nhận kết quả chuyển phôi dương tính như: kiêng quan hệ tình dục vì có thể gây ra các cơn co thắt, phá vỡ cấu trúc phôi vừa chuyển vào hoặc trường hợp xấu nhất là gây sẩy thai. Chị em cũng không nên quá lo lắng đi thử thai ngay sẽ gây nên tâm lý bồn chồn, căng thẳng, không tốt cho thai nhi. Hãy quan sát những dấu hiệu từ cơ thể để và báo ngay với bác sĩ trong trường hợp cảm thấy đau dữ dội ở bụng hay có những dấu hiệu nguy hiểm khác. Bảo Bảo (Theo Healthline)"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bahasa menunjukkan bangsa\\"? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud bahasa ialah ciri pengenalan atau identiti bangsa. Orang Jepun sentiasa menggunakan bahasa ibunda mereka walaupun di peringkat antarabangsa kerana bagi mereka bahasa menunjukkan bangsa."},{"question":"ਵਿਸ਼ਾਃ ਸੋਮਨਾਥ ਚੈਟਰਜੀ ਦਾ 89 ਸਾਲ ਦਾ ਉਮਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਲਕਾਤਾ 'ਚ ਦੇਹਾਂਤ।","answer":"ਪੱਛਮੀ ਬੰਗਾਲ ਦੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਅਬਦੁਸ ਸੱਤਾਰ ਨੇ ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਸੋਮਨਾਥ ਚੈਟਰਜੀ ਨੂੰ ਦਿਲ ਦਾ ਦੌਰਾ ਪੈਣ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਇੱਕ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਹਸਪਤਾਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਗਈ।ਉਹ ਗੁਰਦੇ ਦੀ ਬਿਮਾਰੀ ਨਾਲ ਵੀ ਲੜ ਰਹੇ ਸਨ। ਦਿਲ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਦੌਰਾ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜੂਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਪਿਆ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਉਹ ਕਈ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਹਸਪਤਾਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਭਰਤੀ ਰਹੇ ਸਨ।ਚੈਟਰਜੀ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ 25 ਜੁਲਾਈ, 1929 ਨੂੰ ਹਿੰਦੂ ਮਹਾਂ ਸਭਾ ਆਗੂ ਐਨ ਸੀ ਚੈਟਰਜੀ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਹੋਇਆ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਯੂਕੇ ਦੇ ਮਿਡਲ ਟੈਂਪਲ ਤੋਂ ਬੈਰਿਸਟਰ ਦੀ ਪੜ੍ਹਾਈ ਕੀਤੀ। ਉਹ ਸਾਲ 1968 ਵਿੱਚ ਸੀਪੀਆਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੋਏ ਅਤੇ 1971 ਵਿੱਚ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਚੋਣ ਲੜੀ।ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਦਾ ਦਿਲਚਸਪ ਮੌਕਾ ਉਹ ਸੀ ਜਦੋਂ ਸਾਲ 2008 ਵਿੱਚ ਯੂਪੀਏ ਦੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਕਾਰਜ ਕਾਲ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨੇ ਡਾ਼ ਮਨਮੋਹਨ ਸਿੰਘ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਨਾਲ ਕੀਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਮਾਣੂ ਸਮਝੌਤੇ ਕਰਕੇ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਦੇ ਸਪੀਕਰ ਦੇ ਅਹੁਦੇ ਤੋਂ ਅਸਤੀਫ਼ਾ ਦੇਣ ਲਈ ਕਿਹਾ।ਪਰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਕਹਿ ਕੇ ਅਸਤੀਫ਼ਾ ਦੇਣ ਤੋਂ ਇਨਕਾਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਕਿ ਸਪੀਕਰ ਇੱਕ ਸੰਵਿਧਾਨਕ ਅਹੁਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਪਾਰਟੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਸਿਆਸਤ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚਾ ਹੈ।ਸਾਲ 1971 ਤੋਂ 2009 ਤੱਕ 10 ਵਾਰ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਰਹੇ ਸੋਮਨਾਥ ਚੈਟਰਜੀ ਨੂੰ 1996 ਵਿੱਚ ਬੇਹਤਰੀਨ ਸੰਸਦ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਦਾ ਪੁਰਸਕਾਰ ਮਿਲਿਆ। ਚੈਟਰਜੀ ਸੀਪੀਐਮ ਦੇ ਕੱਦਾਵਰ ਆਗੂਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਗਿਣੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਸਨ ਪਰ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਕੱਢ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਉੱਘੇ ਕਾਨੂੰਨਦਾਨ ਵੀ ਸਨ। ਉਹ ਦੇਸ ਦੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਲੰਬੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਤੱਕ ਸੰਸਦ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਰਹੇ ਅਤੇ ਕਈ ਸੰਸਦੀ ਕਮੇਟੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਰਹੇ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਵਰਧਮਾਨ, ਬੋਲਪੁਰ ਅਤੇ ਜਾਘਵਪੁਰ ਸਮੇਤ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਬੰਗਾਲ ਦੀਆਂ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਸੀਟਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਚੋਣਾਂ ਲੜੀਆਂ।ਆਪਣੇ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਉਹ ਸਾਲ 1984 ਵਿੱਚ ਜਾਘਵਪੁਰ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਸੀਟ ਤੋਂ ਮਮਤਾ ਬੈਨਰਜੀ ਤੋਂ ਹਾਰੇ ਸਨ। ਉਸ ਸਮੇਂ ਮਮਤਾ ਬੈਨਰਜੀ ਨੇ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੀ ਟਿਕਟ ਉੱਪਰ ਚੋਣ ਲੜੇ ਸਨ।ਸੋਮਨਾਥ ਚੈਟਰਜੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਪਾਰਟੀ ਨੂੰ ਮਮਤਾ ਬੈਨਰਜੀ ਦੀ ਵਧ ਰਹੀ ਹਰਮਨਪਿਆਰਤਾ ਬਾਰੇ ਸੁਚੇਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਆਖ਼ਰ 2011 ਵਿੱਚ ਮਮਤਾ ਨੇ ਸੀਪੀਆਈ ਨੂੰ ਬੰਗਾਲ ਦੀ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਚੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਦੇ ਸਪੀਕਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਵੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਤਾਰੀਫ਼ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਸੀ। ਸਿਆਸੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਖ ਹੋਣ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਵੀ ਉਹ ਦੇਸ ਦੇ ਸਿਆਸੀ ਮਾਹੌਲ ਬਾਰੇ ਬੇਬਾਕ ਟਿੱਪਣੀਆਂ ਕਰਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਸਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਕਰਾਤ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਵਾਲੀ ਸੀਪੀਆਈ ਦੀ ਵੀ ਆਲੋਚਨਾ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ।ਇਹ ਵੀ ਪੜ੍ਹੋ꞉(ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਨਾਲ FACEBOOK, INSTAGRAM, TWITTER ਅਤੇ YouTube 'ਤੇ ਜੁੜੋ।)"},{"question":"EFCC ya wọ ile igbafẹ kan n’Ibadan, ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ mẹwaa ni wọn ri mu","answer":"Nnkan ko ṣẹnuure fawọn afurasi onijibiti kan ti wọn n pe lọmọ ‘Yahoo’ nigboro Ibadan lafẹmọju aarọ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọsẹ kọja pẹlu bi awọn oṣiṣẹ EFCC, iyẹn ajọ to n gbogun ti jibiti ati iwa magomago, ẹka tilu Ibadan ya lu wọn lojiji nibi ti wọn ti n ṣe faaji lọwọ.O jọ pe iṣẹ ọwọ awọn paapaa ko fi wọn lọkan balẹ. Bi wọn ṣe ri awọn agbofinro ni wọn fọn danu, ti kaluku si wa’bi sa gba lọ. Ṣugbọn mẹwaa ninu wọn lọwọ awọn EFCC papa tẹ, ti wọn si fi ṣẹkẹṣẹkẹ ko wọn lọ sinu atimọle.Orukọ wọn ni Isaac Ogundayọ; David Ayọdele; Etiowe Kelvin; Ṣeun Afọlabi; Saheed Ọlalekan; Oluwatobi Damilọla; Sukanmi Ọdọfin; Ademọla Okunọla; Joseph Damilare ati Abass Sodiq.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ fawọn oniroyin n’Ibaban, Agbenusọ fun ajọ EFCC, Ọgbẹni Wilson Uwujaren sọ pe awọn to ri ọna ti awọn ọmọdekunrin wọnyi n gba nawo ninaakunaa ni wọn ta ajọ EFCC lolobo ti awọn fi lọọ ka wọn mọ ode faaji ti wọn ti n ba owo ninu jẹ lọwọ laduugbo Ajinde, nigboro Ibadan, nibi ti wọn ti ṣe ariya lati alẹ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, mọju Furaidee.ALAROYE gbọ pe oriṣiiriṣii ayederu iwe, eyi to jọ pe wọn fi lu awọn eeyan ni jibiti lawọn agbofinro ka mọ awọn afurasi ọmọ ‘Yahoo’ wọnyi lọwọ.Ni kete ti iwadii ba pari lori iṣẹlẹ yii lajọ EFCC yoo gbe awọn mẹwẹẹwa lọ sile-ẹjọ gẹgẹ bi agbẹnusọ ajọ naa ṣe fidi ẹ mulẹ."},{"question":"مواد اصلی لازم برای پختن کلم پلوی شیرازی چه هستند؟","answer":"برنج، گوشت چرخ کرده، سبزی کلم پلو، کلم برگ سفید، پیاز، ادویه و روغن مواد اصلی در تهیه کلم پلو هستند."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 78年前の3月10日、アメリカ軍の飛行機が東京にたくさんの爆弾を落としました。この東京大空襲で、約10万人が亡くなりました。「東京大空襲・戦災資料センター」は5日、空襲を経験した人から話を聞く会を開きました。100人ぐらいが集まりました。小学校6年生だった女性は、両親より先に小さいきょうだいと一緒に逃げました。女性は「火事が広がって、亡くなった人をたくさん見ました。両親も亡くなったと思いました。次の日に会うことができたときは、大きな声を出して泣きました」と話しました。そして「日本は平和ですが、世界では恐ろしいことが起こっています。戦争ではなくて、話し合ってほしいです」と言いました。センターの人は「自分で経験していなくても想像することができるので、話を聞くことは大切です」と話しています。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"Жандооч деген эмне ? ","answer":"Жандоочтор – өз алдынча лексикалык мааниге ээ болбогон, сүйлөмдө атоочсөздөрдү жандап, аларды байланыштырып, ага кошумча маани киргизет.Жандоочтор жандаган сөзү менен бирге сүйлөмдүн бир мүчөлүк милдетинаткарып, бирге суроого жооп берет."},{"question":"அயர்ன்சைட் நடவடிக்கை  என்பது இரண்டாம் உலகப் போரின் மேற்குப் போர்முனையில் நிகழ்ந்த ஒரு ஏமாற்று நடவடிக்கை . இது, நாசி ஜெர்மனியின் ஆக்கிரமிப்பிலிருந்த மேற்கு ஐரோப்பா மீதான படையெடுப்பு ஆகும்.","answer":"நிகழும் இடத்தை ஜெர்மானிய போர் உத்தியாளர்கள் கணிக்காது இருக்கவும், அவர்களது கவனத்தை வேறு இடங்களின் மீது திசை திருப்பவும் தேச  நாடுகளால் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட பாடிகார்ட் நடவடிக்கையின் ஒரு பகுதியாகும். இந்த நடவடிக்கையில் தேச  நாட்டு கடல்வழிப் படையெடுப்பு பிரான்சின் பிஸ்கே குடா பகுதியில் போர்டோ நகர் அருகே நிகழ்ப்போவதாக ஜெர்மானியர்களை நம்ப வைக்க முயற்சிகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டன."},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Ururka Midowka Afrika Magaaladii Lagu Soo Dhisay?","answer":"Jawaab: Ururka Midowga Afrika Waxa Lagu Soo Dhisay Magaalada Addis Ababa Ee Dalka Itoobiya (Ethiopia)."},{"question":"ਰਿਤਿਕ ਰੌਸ਼ਨ  ‘ਡਾਨ-2’ ‘ਚ ਮਹਿਮਾਨ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਅ ਕੇ ਆਲੋਚਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਰਿਤਿਕ ਰੌਸ਼ਨ  ‘ਅਗਨੀਪੱਥ’ ਨਾਲ ਵੀ ਕੁਝ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਹੀ ਕਰ ਦਿਖਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਹੈ। ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ‘ਕਾਈਟ’ ਨਹੀਂ  ਸੀ ਚੱਲੀ ਪਰ ‘ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼-2’ ਲਈ ਰਿਤਿਕ ਰੌਸ਼ਨ ਤਕ ਤਿੰਨ ਚੋਟੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਅਭਿਨੇਤਰੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਪਹੁੰਚ  ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਰਿਤਿਕ ਰੌਸ਼ਨ ਦੀ ਖ਼ੂਬੀ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਹਰ ਕੰਮ ਜਨੂੰਨ ਨਾਲ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਹਰ  ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਲਈ ਦਿਨ-ਰਾਤ ਇੱਕ ਕਰ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ।‘ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਨਾ ਮਿਲੇਗੀ ਦੁਬਾਰਾ’ ਚਾਹੇ ਬਹੁਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਚੱਲੀ ਪਰ ਅੱਜ ਵੀ ‘ਕੋਈ ਮਿਲ ਗਿਆ’,  ‘ਕਹੋ ਨਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੈ’ ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਲੋਕ ਚੇਤੇ ‘ਚ ਹਨ। ‘ਅਗਨੀਪੱਥ’ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਸ ਦਾ  ਸਾਰਾ ਧਿਆਨ ‘ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼-2’ ਵੱਲ ਹੈ। ਹੁਣ ਰਿਤਿਕ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਜਿਸਮ ਦੀ ਬਣਤਰ ‘ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼-2’ ਲਈ  ਬਦਲਣੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਚਾਰ ਵਰ੍ਹਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਦਿਮਾਗ ‘ਚ ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ ਹੀ ਹੈ ਰਿਤਿਕ  ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਦਾ ਪੂਰਾ ਸਾਥ ਮਿਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਰਿਤਿਕ ‘ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼’ ਲਈ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਪਤਲਾ ਹੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ। ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਸਹੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਕਦੇ-ਕਦੇ ਪਿੱਠ  ਦੀ ਦਰਦ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਸਤਾਉਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਰਿਤਿਕ ਐਨਾ ਕੁ ਤੰਦਰੁਸਤ ਹੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ  ਮਾੜੀ-ਮੋਟੀ ਦਰਦ ਦਾ ਪਤਾ ਹੀ ਨਾ ਚੱਲੇ। ਅੱਜ-ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਰਿਤਿਕ ਦੀ ਚਹੇਤੀ ਮਾਡਲ ਸੌਰਯ  ਚੌਹਾਨ ਹੈ ਜੋ ‘ਕਿੰਗ ਫਿਸ਼ਰ’ ਦੀ ਮਾਡਲ ਬਣ ਕੇ ਬਾਲੀਵੁੱਡ ਲਈ ਆਕਰਸ਼ਣ ਬਣੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ।  ‘ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼-2’ ‘ਚ ਰਿਤਿਕ ਹੁਣ ਸੌਰਯ ਚੌਹਾਨ ਨਾਲ ਵਧੀਆ ਤਾਲਮੇਲ ਬਿਠਾ ਕੇ ਇੱਕ ਹੋਰ ਨਵੀਂ  ਹਿੱਟ ਜੋੜੀ ਦੇਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਰਿਤਿਕ ਰੌਸ਼ਨ ਦੀਆਂ ਕੁਝ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਸੋ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ‘ਕੋਈ ਮਿਲ ਗਿਆ’, ‘ਕਹੋ ਨਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਹੈ’ ,‘ਕਾਈਟ’ ‘ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼-2’,‘ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਨਾ ਮਿਲੇਗੀ ਦੁਬਾਰਾ’ ।"},{"question":"Daqiiqad yar oo aad la qaadato naftaada maxaad ka faaideysa .","answer":"Daqiiqado yar oo aad la qaadato naftaada ayaa dhisa deegaanka gudahaaga. Aminta aynnu nafteenna la qaadaneynno, waxa aynnu dhiddibada u taageynaa, xiidhiidhka awooddeenna gudeed. Si aanu xidhiidhkan u wanaajino, waxa aanu u baahanahay in aanu ka qayb qaadano waxyaabaha maskaxdeenna ku abuura, hormooyin farxad ah.  Is-ogaalka gudeed aynnu baahanahay waxa ka soo muuqdaa aqoonta aynnu u leenahay nafteenna. Si aan uga baxnno oomanaanta nafteenna, waa in aan aqoon u yeelanaa waxa haraadkeenna bi'in kara.  Haddii aynnu ogaal gudeed isku yeelan waynno, ma aqoonsaneyno waxa hareerteenna, ka dhacaya.  Si aan nolosha kaga jawaabno waajibaadkeeda guud iyo midkeeda gaarka ah waa in aan leenahay aqoonta nafteenna.  Naf-garadnimada waxay suuragalisaa in qofka nolosha xalkeeda in uu ku ogaado si fudud.Dadku waxay inta badan ka cawdaan inay aad ugu mashquulsan yihiin innay waqti u helaan naftooda. Waxay helaan wakhti ay ku sameeyaan wax kasta oo kale, laakiin marka ay timaado caafimaadkooda iyo fayoobaantooda, waxay ku eedeeyaan mudnaanta kale. In kasta oo aan dhammaanteen mudnaanta nolosha ku leenahay, haddaynaan fududayn maskaxdeenna oo aan keenin raaxada gudaha, noloshu waxay ahaan doontaa mid adag. Naftaada waqtiga ugu tayada badan la qaado.  Maskaxdaada ka fogey adduunka macna beelka ah si aysan nolosha kaaga macno beelin.Daqiiqado yar oo aad la qaadato naftaada waxay keenayaan isbedello wanaagsan oo nolosha ah."},{"question":"Manana an'ity teny nakorontana ity ianao :\\" ariom\\"Vinavinao ilay teny rehefa alamina.","answer":"Toy izao ilay teny rehefa alamina : \\"miora\\"."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa Muhaajiriintii u hijrootay magaalada Madiina qofkii ugu horeeyay oo galay kee buu ahaa?","answer":"Abuu Salama oo looyiqiinay Ibnu Cabdi Asad."},{"question":"azavao ny hoe milondolondo","answer":"ny hoe milondolondo dia midika hoe sorisorena, tsy falifaly, mavesabesatra ihany toy te hatory"},{"question":"Como é a lenda pessoal central na narrativa de \\"O Alquimista\\"?","answer":"A lenda pessoal é central na narrativa de \\"O Alquimista\\". através da representação do propósito individual único que cada pessoa possui na vida. Santiago, o protagonista, descobre que seguindo os sinais do universo e ouvindo o seu coração, pode cumprir a sua lenda pessoal. A busca pela realização não se limita apenas a um tesouro material, mas envolve a busca interna pela própria identidade e destino. A lenda pessoal simboliza a jornada de autodescoberta, transformação e conexão com um propósito maior."},{"question":"Inona ary izany, sola be minaonaona?","answer":"Aponga no valin'izany, lazaina fa sola ny aponga satria malama be ny tapony ary minaonaona izy satria rehefa velesina dia maneno."},{"question":"What is the purpose of the inla.read.graph() function in R-INLA?","answer":"To read the adjacency file representing the neighborhood structure into R-INLA."},{"question":"《清明上河图》是一幅","answer":"社会风俗画"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'pandai mengambil otak di dalam kepala, tiada diketahui tuan tubuh'? Berikan satu contoh ayat.","answer":"Ia bermaksud bijak berkata-kata.Contoh ayat: Pak cik Mat dipilih mewakili pihak keluarga lelaki untuk berunding tentang perkahwinan Zakaria dengan Azlina kerana dia pandai mengambil otak di dalam kepala, tiada diketahui tuan tubuh."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：美國的「德國移民」主要集中在哪些州？","answer":"答案：美國的德國移民主要集中在俄亥俄州、賓夕法尼亞州、密蘇里州和威斯康辛州等地。許多德國移民在19世紀和20世紀初期來到美國，並在這些州份建立了繁榮的德國社區。"},{"question":"Сабак-бул:а)Жаңы билимдерди берүүгө багытталган процессб)Чындыкты издөөгө багытталган процессв)Билген билимдерин бекемдөөгө багытталган процесс","answer":" Тураа жообу:б)Чындыкты издөөгө багытталган процесс"},{"question":"Nitori ọrọ aabo, Sheikh Gumi ṣabẹwo s’Ọbasanjọ l’Abẹokuta","answer":"Gbajugbaja Aafaa ilu Kaduna nni, Sheikh Ahmad Gumi, ti ṣabẹwo si aarẹ Naijiria tẹlẹ, Oloye Oluṣẹgun Ọbasanjọ, niluu Abẹokuta, nitori ọrọ aabo orilẹ-ede yii to mẹhẹ.Ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, ọjọ kẹrin, oṣu kẹrin, ọdun 2021, ni Gumi ko ikọ lẹyin, ti wọn ba Ọbasanjọ ṣepade atilẹkun mọri ṣe nile baba naa to wa ni OOPL, l’Abẹokuta.Koko abẹwo naa bo ṣe lu sawọn akọroyin lọwọ ni pe Sheikh Gumi ṣalaye fun Ọbasanjọ nipa irinajo to rin lọ sọdọ awọn Fulani agbebọn ti wọn n jiiyan gbe lapa Ariwa Naijiria.O ni igbagbọ oun ni pe ijọba apapọ yoo ri aba toun gbe kalẹ lati fa awọn eeyan naa mọra bii imọran to daa, ati ọna kan ti wọn le fi ṣẹgun iṣoro ijinigbe ati jagidijagan, ti yoo si seso rere gan-an ti wọn ba le gba a wọle.Ọbasanjọ ati Gumi tilẹ jọ kọwọ bọwe kan ti wọn lawọn fi gba pe iṣoro ijinigbe, idigunjale atawọn iwa ọdaran mi-in ti kari Naijiria. Wọn lawọn gba pe awọn eeyan lati orilẹ-ede yii, ati lawọn ilẹ ibomi-in ni wọn n lọwọ si awọn iṣoro yii, bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn ẹya kan pọ ninu ẹ ju awọn mi-in lọ.Wọn tun lawọn gba pe ibi ti eto aabo mẹhẹ de ni Naijiria bayii ti kọja afarada, eyi lo si fa a ti Gumi fi ti Kaduna waa ba Ọbasanjọ l’Abẹokuta lati jiroro lori ẹ.Aikawe to awọn kan, ọrọ-aje to rugọgọ jura wọn lọ lawọn ibomi-in, iyapa ẹsin ati ẹya, wa ninu awọn ohun to n fa iṣoro aabo nilẹ yii bi wọn ṣe wi, bẹẹ lawọn oloṣelu onijibiti naa n da kun un pẹlu.Lati ṣẹgun iṣoro gbogbo to n koju Naijiria yii, Gumi ati Ọbasanjọ sọ pe ọna meji ni. Wọn ni awọn ajinigbe atawọn agbebọn ti wọn gba lati ṣiwọ iwakiwa yii, kijọba fa wọn mọra. Ki wọn ko wọn kuro ninu igbo, ki wọn wa ile ti wọn yoo maa gbe fun wọn pẹlu iṣẹ ti wọn yoo maa ṣe.Awọn to ya pooki ti wọn ko fẹẹ yipada ninu iwa ọdaran, wọn ni kijọba da sẹria to yẹ fun wọn bọwọ ba tẹ wọn, ki wọn fimu wọn danrin.Bẹẹ ni wọn ni ijọba apapọ gbọdọ ji giri si ojuṣẹ ẹ nipa aabo, nitori bi nnkan ṣe wa yii ko ṣẹ rara ni.Ko gbọdọ si ninaka aleebu sẹnikẹni bi a ba fẹẹ tete ri ere igbesẹ ti wọn ni kijọba gbe yii, kaka bẹẹ, wọn ni ki gbogbo ọmọ Naijiria ri aabo bii ohun ti gbogbo wa yoo jọ jija ẹ, titi ti yoo fi ri bo ṣe yẹ ko ri ni.Bakan naa ni wọn sọ pe iṣoro yii ko le dopin, nigba ti awọn ipinlẹ kan ba n ba awọn ajinigbe dunaa-dura nipa iye owo ti wọn yoo fi gba eeyan wọn ti wọn ji gbe silẹ, to si jẹ pe awọn kan n ba wọn ja, wọn n yinbọn fun wọn ni.Wọn ni gbogbo agbegbe ni wọn gbọdọ ro lagbara lati koju awọn to n kọ lu wọn lojiji, bẹẹ si ni ẹbun to jọju gbọdọ maa wa fawọn to ba ta ijọba lolobo nipa awọn agbebọn wọnyi, ko le maa jẹ koriya fun wọn lati ṣe ju bẹẹ lọ.Fawọn tọwọ ba tẹ pe wọn n lọwọ si ijinigbe atawọn wahala yooku, wọn ni kijọba da ile-ẹjọ pataki kan silẹ ti ko ni i gbọ ẹjọ mi-in ju tiwọn lọ, ti wọn yoo si ti maa da sẹria to ba yẹ fun wọn labẹ ofin. Ẹnikẹni ti wọn ba si ri to n gbe nnkan ija kiri lai gbaṣẹ ijọba, wọn ni kijọba da sẹria gidi fun un.Lakootan, Sheikh Gumi sọ fun Oloye Ọbasanjọ pe koun naa wa si Kaduna, kawọn tun jọ wo ọrọ aabo yii wo, kawọn si le fori awọn ọna abayọ yii ti sibi kan.Ọbasanjọ naa loun gba lati lọ si Kaduna, ṣebi ki nnkan le daa naa ni.Ọba Agura, Babajide Bakre, wa nibi ipade naa. Biṣọọbu Tunde Akinsanya, alaga CAN nipinlẹ Ogun naa wa nibẹ pẹlu Sheikh Sa’addallah Alade Bamigbola, Imaamu agba ilẹ Ẹgba, Oloye Kenny Martins, Oloye Babajide Jaiyeọba ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ."},{"question":"Inona no renivohitr'i Slovakia?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Slovakia dia Bratislava."},{"question":"na nga def?","answer":"Maa ngi fi"},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en esta categoría: Política. ","answer":"¿Cuántas veces ha declarado Joe Biden su candidatura a la presidencia de Estados Unidos? Él ha declarado su candidatura 3 veces."},{"question":"Vraag: Wat was het enige Nederlandstalige nummer in de top 10 van de Top 2000 van 2022?","answer":"Antwoord: Avond van Boudewijn de Groot"},{"question":"ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமியின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"எந்த மனிதனும் எனக்கு கிழானவன் அல்ல.அதுபோல எவனும் எவனுக்கும் மேலானவனும் அல்ல."},{"question":"Bagaimanakah proses penyaduran elektrik dapat mencegah pengaratan pada permukaan objek besi?A. Melindungi daripada air dan oksigenB. Menyingkirkan agen pengaratanC. Menghasilkan lapisan elektrostatikD. Bertindak balas dan menghasilkan bahan baharu yang tahan kakisan","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah A. Melindungi daripada air dan oksigen"},{"question":"Karbon ayak izini azaltmanın en etkili yolları nelerdir?","answer":"Karbon ayak izini azaltmak için bir dizi etkili yol bulunmaktadır. İşte bu amaçla uygulanabilecek bazı ana stratejiler:-Yenilenebilir Enerji Kullanımı: Fosil yakıtların yerine güneş enerjisi, rüzgar enerjisi ve hidroelektrik enerji gibi yenilenebilir enerji kaynaklarına geçmek, enerji tüketiminin daha temiz ve daha az karbon emisyonlu olmasını sağlar.-Enerji Verimliliği İyileştirmesi: Evlerde, işyerlerinde ve endüstriyel tesislerde enerji verimliliğini artırmak, daha az enerji tüketilmesini ve dolayısıyla daha az karbon emisyonu oluşmasını sağlar. LED aydınlatma, yalıtım, enerji verimli cihazlar gibi önlemler alınabilir.-Sürdürülebilir Ulaşım: Toplu taşıma kullanımını artırmak, bisiklet veya yürüyüş gibi çevre dostu ulaşım seçeneklerine yönelmek ve daha az yakıt tüketen araçları tercih etmek, kişisel ulaşımın karbon ayak izini azaltabilir.-Daha Az Atık Üretimi: Geri dönüşüm ve atık azaltımı yapmak, atık yönetimi sırasında oluşan metan gazı emisyonlarını azaltabilir.-Sürdürülebilir Tarım: Tarımın karbon ayak izini azaltmak için sürdürülebilir tarım uygulamalarına yönelmek önemlidir. Bu, daha verimli üretim yöntemleri ve ormanların korunması gibi faktörleri içerebilir."},{"question":"قم بتشكيل النص التالي: عبارة المغني في جميع ما مر من الشروط والأحكام لأن الإشراك تولية في بعض المبيع ا هـ قوله وإدخال أل إلخ عبارة المغني واعترض المصنف في إدخاله الألف واللام على بعض وحكي منعه عن الجمهور ا هـ فلو أطلق الإشراك كأشركتك فيه صح العقد وكان المبيع مناصفة بينهما لأن ذلك هو المتبادر من لفظ.","answer":"حسناً. هذا تشكيل النص السابق: عِبَارَةُ الْمُغْنِي فِي جَمِيعِ مَا مَرَ مِنْ الشُرُوطِ وَالْأَحْكَامِ لِأَنَ الْإِشْرَاكَ تَوْلِيَةٌ فِي بَعْضِ الْمَبِيعِ ا هـ قَوْلُهُ وَإِدْخَالُ أَلْ إلَخْ عِبَارَةُ الْمُغْنِي وَاعْتَرَضَ الْمُصَنِفُ فِي إدْخَالِهِ الْأَلِفَ وَاللَامَ عَلَى بَعْضٍ وَحُكِيَ مَنْعُهُ عَنْ الْجُمْهُورِ ا هـ فَلَوْ أَطْلَقَ الْإِشْرَاكَ كَأَشْرَكْتُك فِيهِ صَحَ الْعَقْدُ وَكَانَ الْمَبِيعُ مُنَاصَفَةً بَيْنَهُمَا لِأَنَ ذَلِكَ هُوَ الْمُتَبَادَرُ مِنْ لَفْظِ."},{"question":"Vilket är det enda fotbollslaget i Värmland som spelat i Allsvenskan?","answer":"Degerfors grundades redan 1907 och är en av Sveriges mest anrika fotbollsklubbar. Laget är också det enda i Värmland som spelat i herrarnas högsta division, Allsvenskan. "},{"question":"A = {2, 4, 6, 8, 10} అయిన క్రింది ఎంపిక జాబితాలో ఏది Aని సూచించదు ?A) {x ; x = 2n, n ∈ N మరియు n<5}B) {x: x అనేది 11 కన్నా తక్కువైన సరి సహజసంఖ్య }C) {x : x = 2n, n ∈ N మరియు n < 5}D) {x : x = 2n, n ∈ W మరియు 1 ≤ n ≤ 5}","answer":"C) {x : x = 2n, n ∈ N మరియు n < 5}"},{"question":"மிதிபட்டு இச்சொல்லை பிரித்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது ____________மிதி + பட்டுமிதிப் + பட்டுமீதி + பட்டுமீதிப் + பட்டு","answer":"விடை : மிதி + பட்டு"},{"question":"සිංහල දිග මනින මිණුම් ඒකක දෙන්න.","answer":"සිංහල දිග මනින මිණුම් ඒකක පහත දැක්වේ.පරමාණු 36 = අණු 1අණු 36 = තජ්ජාරි 1තජ්ජාරි 36 = රථරේණු 1රථරේණු 36 = ලික්ඛ 1ලික්ඛ 7 = උක්ඛ 1උක්ඛ 7 = ධණ්ණමාස 1උක්ඛ 7 = ධණ්ණමාස 1ධණ්ණමාස 7 = ආංගුල 1ආංගුල 12 = වියත් 1වියත් 2 = රියන් 1රියන් 4 = බඹ 1රියන් 7 = යෂ්ට් 1යෂ්ටි 20 = ඉසුබු (උසබ) 1ඉසුබු (උසබ) 20 = සැතපුම් 1සැතපුම් 4 = ගව් 1ගව් 4 = යොදුන් 1"},{"question":"Sheeg magaca gabyaaga tiriyey tuducyada soo socdo:Dhalashada afkaygiyoDhigashada fartaydaanKaga baxay dhibaatoonHawlihii ku dhaafeeIyadaa dhaqaalahaDhidibbada u aastooDheelliga u diidaye","answer":"Waxaa tiriyey Max’ed Ibraahin Hadraawi."},{"question":" காகிதப் பணத்தைப் பயன்படுத்திய முதல் நாடு எது?","answer":"விடை: சீனா"},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Trao đổi với VietNamNet trưa nay, một lãnh đạo Công an TP Huế cho biết, đơn vị đang phối hợp với các Phòng nghiệp vụ Công an tỉnh TT-Huế bảo vệ hiện trường, truy bắt đối tượng cướp tiệm vàng. Một số người dân chứng kiến vụ việc cho biết, khoảng 12h45 ngày 31/7, họ hốt hoảng khi nghe những tiếng súng nổ phát ra từ tiệm vàng H.Đ. ở trước cửa chợ Đông Ba. Sau tiếng súng nổ, một người đàn ông mang theo súng AK, chạy từ tiệm vàng ra đường cầm theo nhiều túi nghi đựng vàng. Nghi phạm  sau đó vứt các túi nghi đựng vàng này ra giữa đường rồi chạy trốn tuyến đường Trần Hưng Đạo (trước cổng chợ Đông Ba), rồi bỏ chạy tiếp theo hướng cầu Đông Ba – đường Trịnh Công Sơn. ","answer":"Nổ súng AK cướp tiệm vàng, công an vây đường ở Huế để truy bắt hung thủ"},{"question":"الجملة الأولى: بعضها موضح أدناه وبعضها مرتبط بـ \\" الروابط الخارجية \\" . الجملة الثانية: تم وصف بعضها أدناه ، وبعضها مرتبط تحت \\" الروابط الخارجية \\". السؤال: هل تعبر الجملة الأولى والجملة الثانية عن نفس المعنى؟ نعم أم لا؟","answer":"نعم تتحدث الجملتان عن نفس المعنى."},{"question":"Kirjoita tämä sama asia toisin: Mulla on viime päivinä ollu runsaampi valkovuoto kuin yleensä ja se saa myös alapääni kutiamaan.","answer":"Viime aikoina olen huomannut lisääntynyttä valkovuotoa, mikä aiheuttaa kutinaa alapäässäni."},{"question":"Qual foi o IDH do Suriname, em 2021?","answer":"O IDH do Suriname, em 2021, foi 0.730."},{"question":"கேள்வி : மிக வெட்பமுள்ள நட்சத்திர நிறம் என்ன ?","answer":"பதில் : நீலம்."},{"question":"Waaan rabaa inaan guursado, maxaad igula talin lahayd?","answer":"Marka aad rabto inaad guursato waxaa jiraan meelo badan oo lagaa rabo inaad iska fiiriso.1: iska hubi inaad dhaqaale ahaan isku filan tahay, mar haddii aad guursato waxaa lagaa rabaa inaad dahqaale ahaan qof isku filan.2: guurso qof aad is fahmeesaan, si fiican isaga hubi  qofka aad guursaneesid inaad isku dabeecad tihiin.3: iska hubi qofka aad guursaneesid qaraabadiisa, tusaale haddii ay qaraabadu fiicantahay qofkaasi waxay ubadantahay inuu asna wanaagsanaan doono.waxaa kaloo jiri karaan meelo badan ay tahay inaad iska hubisid."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الذي تزوّج اثنتين من بنات رسول الله؟","answer":"\\tالجواب: عثمان بن عفان رضي الله عنه."},{"question":"Tambaya: Mi ake nufi da \\"living room\\" da Hausa? \\t\\t\\t","answer":"Amsa: tana nufin \\"dakin zama\\"\\t\\t"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਸਚਾ ਸੇਵੀ ਸਚੁ ਸਾਲਾਹੀ ॥ਸਚੈ ਨਾਇ ਦੁਖੁ ਕਬ ਹੀ ਨਾਹੀ ॥ਸੁਖਦਾਤਾ ਸੇਵਨਿ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਇਨਿ ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਮੰਨਿ ਵਸਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ਹਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਜੀਉ ਵਾਰੀ ਸੁਖ ਸਹਜਿ ਸਮਾਧਿ ਲਗਾਵਣਿਆ ॥ਜੋ ਹਰਿ ਸੇਵਹਿ ਸੇ ਸਦਾ ਸੋਹਹਿ ਸੋਭਾ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਸੁਹਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸਭੁ ਕੋ ਤੇਰਾ ਭਗਤੁ ਕਹਾਏ ॥ਸੇਈ ਭਗਤ ਤੇਰੈ ਮਨਿ ਭਾਏ ॥ਸਚੁ ਬਾਣੀ ਤੁਧੈ ਸਾਲਾਹਨਿ ਰੰਗਿ ਰਾਤੇ ਭਗਤਿ ਕਰਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੨॥ਸਭੁ ਕੋ ਸਚੇ ਹਰਿ ਜੀਉ ਤੇਰਾ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਮਿਲੈ ਤਾ ਚੂਕੈ ਫੇਰਾ ॥ਜਾ ਤੁਧੁ ਭਾਵੈ ਤਾ ਨਾਇ ਰਚਾਵਹਿ ਤੂੰ ਆਪੇ ਨਾਉ ਜਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੩॥ਗੁਰਮਤੀ ਹਰਿ ਮੰਨਿ ਵਸਾਇਆ ॥ਹਰਖੁ ਸੋਗੁ ਸਭੁ ਮੋਹੁ ਗਵਾਇਆ ॥ਇਕਸੁ ਸਿਉ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਗੀ ਸਦ ਹੀ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਮੰਨਿ ਵਸਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੪॥ਭਗਤ ਰੰਗਿ ਰਾਤੇ ਸਦਾ ਤੇਰੈ ਚਾਏ ॥ਨਉ ਨਿਧਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਸਿਆ ਮਨਿ ਆਏ ॥ਪੂਰੈ ਭਾਗਿ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਸਬਦੇ ਮੇਲਿ ਮਿਲਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੫॥ਤੂੰ ਦਇਆਲੁ ਸਦਾ ਸੁਖਦਾਤਾ ॥ਤੂੰ ਆਪੇ ਮੇਲਿਹਿ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਜਾਤਾ ॥ਤੂੰ ਆਪੇ ਦੇਵਹਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਡਾਈ ਨਾਮਿ ਰਤੇ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੬॥ਸਦਾ ਸਦਾ ਸਾਚੇ ਤੁਧੁ ਸਾਲਾਹੀ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਜਾਤਾ ਦੂਜਾ ਕੋ ਨਾਹੀ ॥ਏਕਸੁ ਸਿਉ ਮਨੁ ਰਹਿਆ ਸਮਾਏ ਮਨਿ ਮੰਨਿਐ ਮਨਹਿ ਮਿਲਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੭॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਹੋਵੈ ਸੋ ਸਾਲਾਹੇ ॥ਸਾਚੇ ਠਾਕੁਰ ਵੇਪਰਵਾਹੇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮੁ ਵਸੈ ਮਨ ਅੰਤਰਿ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੀ ਹਰਿ ਮੇਲਾਵਣਿਆ ॥੮॥੨੧॥੨੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 122 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਮੈਂ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਮੈਂ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ‑ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ।ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਿਆਂ ਕਦੇ ਕੋਈ ਦੁੱਖ ਪੋਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ । ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਭ ਸੁਖ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਤੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾਈ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਮੈਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਸਦਾ ਸਦਕੇ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਹਾਂ, ਜੇਹੜੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਦੀ ਸਮਾਧੀ ਲਾਈ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਨ । ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬਣੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਲੋਕ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ) ਸੋਭਾ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੁਰਤਿ ਸਦਾ ਸੁਹਾਵਣੀ ਟਿਕੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। (ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਉਂਞ ਤਾਂ) ਹਰੇਕ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਤੇਰਾ ਭਗਤ ਅਖਵਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ (ਅਸਲ) ਉਹੀ ਭਗਤ ਹਨ ਜੇਹੜੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਚੰਗੇ ਲੱਗਦੇ ਹਨ । (ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਉਹ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਲਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਤੇਰੇ ਪੇ੍ਰਮ-ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਹੋਏ ਤੇਰੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੨। ਹੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਜੀ ! ਹਰੇਕ ਜੀਵ ਤੇਰਾ (ਹੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ) ਹੈ । (ਪਰ ਜਦੋਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ (ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ) ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਦੋਂ (ਉਸ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦਾ) ਗੇੜ ਮੁੱਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਜਦੋਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਚੰਗਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜਦੋਂ ਤੇਰੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ), ਤਦੋਂ ਤੂੰ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ) ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜਦਾ ਹੈਂ । ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਆਪਣਾ) ਨਾਮ ਜਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ ।੩। ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਆਪਣੇ) ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾ ਲਿਆ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ (ਦੀ ਲਾਲਸਾ) ਗ਼ਮੀ (ਤੋਂ ਘਬਰਾਹਟ) ਮੁਕਾ ਲਈ, ਉਸ ਨੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ) ਸਾਰਾ ਮੋਹ ਦੂਰ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ । ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਲਗਨ ਸਦਾ ਹੀ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ) ਨਾਲ ਲੱਗੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਹਰੀ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾਈ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪। ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੇਰੇ ਭਗਤ (ਬੜੇ) ਚਾਉ ਨਾਲ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਮ-ਰੰਗ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜੋ, ਮਾਨੋ) ਨੌ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ (ਹੈ) । ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਪੂਰੀ ਕਿਸਮਤ ਨਾਲ ਗੁਰੂ ਲੱਭ ਲਿਆ, ਗੁਰੂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ) ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਾ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੫।ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੂੰ ਦਇਆ ਦਾ ਸੋਮਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਸਦਾ (ਸਭ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਸੁਖ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈਂ, ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਲ) ਮਿਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ ।ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਜੀਵ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਡੂੰਘੀ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੂੰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਨਾਮ ਬਖਸ਼ਦਾ ਹੈਂ (ਨਾਮ ਜਪਣ ਦੀ) ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈਂ । ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਮ (-ਰੰਗ) ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ ।੬। ਹੇ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! (ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰ) ਮੈਂ ਸਦਾ ਹੀ ਸਦਾ ਹੀ ਤੇਰੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਰਹਾਂ । ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਰਨ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ (ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਝ) ਨਹੀਂ (ਪਾ ਸਕਦਾ) । (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਸ ਦਾ) ਮਨ ਸਦਾ ਇਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜੇ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦਾ) ਮਨ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਯਾਦ ਵਿਚ) ਗਿੱਝ ਜਾਏ, ਤਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਬਾਹਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਭਟਕਦਾ) ।੭। ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ-ਪਰਨਾ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਕਾਇਮ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੇ-ਪਰਵਾਹ ਠਾਕੁਰ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ) ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੮।੨੧।੨੨।\\""},{"question":"සිංහල රාජවංශයේ අවසානය සිදුවූයේ කුමන වසරේද ?","answer":"ක්‍රි.ව. 1739 ( වීර පරාක්‍රම නරේන්ද්‍රසිංහ රජුගේ අභාවයත් සමග )"},{"question":"సార్వభౌమిక దేశపు దివాలా పై ఒక వ్యాసం వ్రాయండి.","answer":"సార్వభౌమిక దేశ ప్రభుత్వం తన రుణాన్ని తిరిగి చెల్లించాల్సిన సమయంలో పూర్తిగా తిరిగి చెల్లించడంలో వైఫల్యం చెందడం లేదా చెల్లించేందుకు నిరాకరించడాన్ని సార్వభౌమిక దేశపు దివాలా అంటారు. ఇంగ్లీషులో దీన్ని సావరిన్ డిఫాల్ట్ అంటారు. బకాయి చెల్లింపులు నిలిపివేసేటపుడు ఆ ప్రభుత్వం, రుణాలను చెల్లించలేమని గాని లేదా పాక్షికంగా మాత్రమే చెల్లిస్తామని గానీ ప్రకటన చెయ్యవచ్చు లేదా అసలు ప్రకటన చెయ్యకనే పోవచ్చు.కొన్ని సందర్భాల్లో కొన్ని దేశాలు ద్రవ్యోల్బణం ద్వారా తమ అప్పుల నిజమైన భారం నుండి తప్పించుకున్నాయి. వాస్తవంగా తక్కువ విలువ కలిగిన కరెన్సీతో రుణాన్ని తీర్చేస్తారు కాబట్టి సాధారణ అర్థంలో దీన్ని \\"దివాలా\\" అనరు. కొన్నిసార్లు ప్రభుత్వాలు తమ ద్రవ్య విలువను తగ్గించుకుంటాయి. డబ్బును ఎక్కువగా ముద్రించడం ద్వారా గానీ, లేదా తమ కరెన్సీలను విలువైన లోహాలుగా లేదా విదేశీ కరెన్సీగా స్థిర ధరలకు మార్చుకుని దాని చెలామణీని ఆపేయడం మొదలైనవి చేసి ఇలా ద్రవ్యవిలువను తగ్గించుకోవచ్చు. వడ్డీ లేదా మూలధన ఎగవేత కంటే దీన్ని లెక్కించడం కష్టమైన పని.రుణదాతలు లేదా బాండ్ కొనుగోలుదారులు, ప్రభుత్వం తమ రుణాన్ని తిరిగి చెల్లించడంలో విఫలమవుతుందని అనుమానించడం ప్రారంభిస్తే, ఎగవేత ముప్పుకు పరిహారంగా వారు అధిక వడ్డీ రేటును డిమాండ్ చేయవచ్చు. ప్రభుత్వం రుణాన్ని గౌరవించడంలో విఫలమవుతుందనే భయంతో వడ్డీ రేటు పెరగడాన్ని సార్వభౌమిక రుణ సంక్షోభం అంటారు. ప్రత్యేకించి, స్వల్పకాలిక బాండ్ల ద్వారా తెచ్చే అప్పులపై ఆధారపడినప్పుడు ప్రభుత్వాలు సార్వభౌమ రుణ సంక్షోభానికి గురవుతాయి. ఎందుకంటే ఇది వారి స్వల్పకాలిక బాండ్ ఫైనాన్సింగ్, వారి దీర్ఘకాలిక ఆస్తి విలువల మధ్య మెచ్యూరిటీ అసమతుల్యతను సృష్టిస్తుంది.కరెన్సీ అసమతుల్యత కారణంగా కూడా వారు సార్వభౌమ రుణ సంక్షోభానికి గురయ్యే అవకాశం ఉంది: వారి స్వంత కరెన్సీలో బాండ్లకు విదేశాలలో పరపతి లేనపుడు, దేశం విదేశీ కరెన్సీలో బాండ్లను జారీ చేస్తాయి. వారి స్వంత కరెన్సీ విలువ తగ్గునపుడు, ఆ బాండ్లను తిరిగి చెల్లించడం చాలా ఖరీదైన పని అవుతుంది.సార్వభౌమ ప్రభుత్వపు నిర్వచనం ప్రకారం, అది దాని స్వంత వ్యవహారాలపై నియంత్రణ దానిదే. కాబట్టి, అది తన రుణాన్ని తిరిగి చెల్లించడంలో దానిపై నిర్బంధమేమీ ఉండదు. అయినప్పటికీ, రుణాలు ఇచ్చే దేశాల నుండి ప్రభుత్వాలు తీవ్రమైన ఒత్తిడిని ఎదుర్కోవచ్చు. కొన్ని తీవ్రమైన సందర్భాల్లో, రుణదాత దేశం, ఆస్తులను స్వాధీనం చేసుకోవడానికి రుణాన్ని తిరిగి చెల్లించడంలో విఫలమైనందుకు రుణగ్రహీత దేశంపై యుద్ధ బెదిరింపులు చేసేవి లేదా యుద్ధమే చేసేవి. (UN చార్టర్ ఆర్టికల్ 2 (4) ద్వారా దేశాలు ఇతర దేశాలపై బలాన్ని ఉపయోగించడాన్ని నిషేధించక ముందు). ఉదాహరణకు, 1882లో, యునైటెడ్ కింగ్‌డమ్ ఈజిప్టుపై దాడి చేసింది. 1890ల మధ్యకాలంలో వెనిజులాలో యునైటెడ్ స్టేట్స్ చేసిన \\"గన్‌బోట్ దౌత్యం\\", 1915లో ప్రారంభమైన హైతీపై అమెరికా ఆక్రమణలు కూడా దీనికి ఉదాహరణలే.దివాలా తీసిన ప్రభుత్వం మరింత రుణం పొందలేకవచ్చు; దాని విదేశీ ఆస్తులలో కొన్నిటిని జప్తు చేయవచ్చు; అలాగే దేశీయంగా అప్పులిచ్చినవారు తమ రుణాన్ని తిరిగి చెల్లించమని రాజకీయంగా ఒత్తిడి చేయవచ్చు. అందువల్ల, ప్రభుత్వాలు చాలా అరుదుగా గానీ తమ రుణం యావత్తునూ ఎగగొట్టవు. దాని బదులు అవి, తమ రుణదాతలతో చర్చలు జరిపి రుణ పునర్వ్యవస్థీకరణ చేయమని లేదా రుణాన్ని పాక్షికంగా తగ్గించమని గానీ కోరతాయి."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"awak kecil makan hendak banyak, sayap singkat terbang hendak tinggi\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah mengangan-angankan sesuatu yang tidak sepadan dengan kemampuan diri sendiri"},{"question":"Di manakah seseorang mungkin  mempunyai kenyataan dicetak? Pilihan: - surat - akhbar - telefon pintar - siaran akhbar.  Berikan penjelasan. ","answer":"Surat khabar mengandungi kenyataan yang dicetak. Seseorang mungkin mempunyai kenyataan yang dicetak di akhbar. Jadi, jawapannya ialah akhbar."},{"question":"කුඩාම ප්‍රථමක සංඛ්‍යාව කුමක්ද?","answer":"කුඩාම ප්‍රථමක සංඛ්‍යාව 2 වේ. එය ප්‍රථමක සංඛ්‍යා  අතර විශේෂ  වන්නේ එය එකම ඉරට්ටේ ප්‍රථමක සංඛ්‍යාව වන බැවිනි. ප්‍රථමක සංඛ්‍යාවක් යනු 1 සහ එම සංඛ්‍යාව හැර වෙනත් ධන සංඛ්‍යාවකින් නොබෙදෙන 1 ට වඩා  වැඩි සංඛ්‍යාවක් ලෙස අර්ථ දැක්වේ. 2 සමානව බෙදිය හැක්කේ 1 සහ 2 න් පමණක් බැවින්, එය ප්‍රථමක සංඛ්‍යාවක් සඳහා  වන නිර්ණායක සපුරාලයි."},{"question":"ඕස්ට්‍රේලියාව මුලින්ම සොයාගනු ලැබුවේ","answer":"Willem Janszoon"},{"question":"ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ: ਯੋਗ ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦੇਵ ਵੈਦਿਕ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਬੋਰਡ ਦੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਮੁਖੀ ਬਣ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ। ਪਤੰਜਲੀ ਟਰੱਸਟ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਾਰਿਸ਼ ਉਪਰ ਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਬੁੱਕ ਟਰੱਸਟ ਦੇ ਚੇਅਰਮੈਨ ਗੋਵਿੰਦ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦ ਸ਼ਰਮਾ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਹੇਠਲੀ ਚੋਣ ਕਮੇਟੀ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਸੂਤਰਾਂ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਪਤੰਜਲੀ, ਐਮਿਟੀ ਗਰੁੱਪ ਅਤੇ ਮਹਾਰਾਸ਼ਟਰ ਇੰਸਟੀਚਿਊਟ ਆਫ਼ ਟੈਕਟਾਲੋਜੀ ਤੋਂ ਤਜਵੀਜ਼ਾਂ ਮਿਲੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਪਤੰਜਲੀ ਨੇ ਬੋਰਡ ਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਲਈ 21 ਕਰੋੜ ਰੁਪਏ ਦੇਣ ਦਾ ਵਾਅਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ।ਪਤੰਜਲੀ ਨੇ ਵੈਦਿਕ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਬੋਰਡ ਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਲਈ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਪੈਸੇ ਦਾ ਵਾਅਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਪਤੰਜਲੀ ਨੇ ਵੈਦਿਕ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਬੋਰਡ ਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਲਈ 21 ਕਰੋੜ ਰੁਪਏ ਦਾ ਵਾਅਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\" Aleo kely fanahy sitrak'olona, toy _\\"","answer":"\\" Aleo kely fanahy sitrak'olona, toy izay be fanahy maty foana\\""},{"question":"ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම ලඟින් පිහිටි පළාත් අගනගර දෙක කුමක්ද ? ","answer":"ලංකාවේ වඩාත්ම ලඟින් පිහිටි පළාත් අගනගර දෙක වන්නෙ මහනුවර -කුරුණෑගල (42KM)"},{"question":"Arı sokmalarında ilk yardım nasıl yapılır?","answer":"Arının soktuğu yer soğuk su ve sabunla yıkanmalıdır. Soğuk su rahatlatırken, sabun da kalan kiri ya da zehri bölgeden temizlemeye yardım eder. Şişlik ve kaşıntının olduğu yer kaşınmamalıdır. Şişliği indirmek amacıyla buz uygulaması yapılabilir."},{"question":"Гидрофобия деген эмне ?","answer":"Гидрофобия (гидро... жана гр. phobos — коркуу, коркунуч) — суудан коркуу, кутурма оорусунун эски аты."},{"question":"Inona avy ny vokatra tsara ateraky ny finoana ny anjara?","answer":"Ny anjara dia ahafantarana mialoha izay ho fizotry ny fiainana. Hita taratra fa mahatonga ny olona hanana fanantenana ny finoana izany. Mandrisika ny olona hiezaka, hikarakara ny fomba enti-manatsara ny fiainana. Mahatonga ny olona hanaiky ny fahefan’ Andriamanitra, mamolavola ny olona hahay manamboatra saina ka mahatonga azy ireo hanana fiononana. Anisan'ny mahatonga ny olona ho sahy handray andraikitra ihany koa ny finoana ny anjara."},{"question":"Tên gọi ban đầu của làng Mộ Trạch là gì?","answer":"Tên gọi ban đầu của làng Mộ Trạch là Khả Mộ trang, có nghĩa là ấp đáng mến. Cụ Vũ Hồn là người lập làng, đặt tên làng là Khả Mộ với hy vọng làng sẽ trở nên trù phú và được mến mộ. Tên gọi này được sử dụng cho đến khoảng thế kỷ 13, khi làng được đổi tên thành Mộ Trạch."},{"question":"ඉන්දියානු රාජ්‍ය බුද්ධි තොරතුරු ඒකකය හදුන්වන කෙට් නම ","answer":"RAW"},{"question":"أجب على السؤال الرياضي التالي: 120 في ( 1/4 ) على 60..","answer":"س = 120 * (1/4) / 60 = 30 / 60 = 0.5. "},{"question":"Jelaskan secara singkat sejarah Persatuan Sepak Bola Seluruh Indonesia (PSSI)? ","answer":"PSSI adalah organisasi yang mengurus sepak bola di Indonesia. Organisasi ini didirikan pada 19 April 1930 di kota Yogyakarta. Adapun nama awal organisasi ini adalah 'Persatuan Sepak Raga Seluruh Indonesia'. Mulanya, organisasi ini diketuai oleh Soeratin Sosrosoegondo. Pada 1952, PSSI resmi bergabung dengan FIFA, badan sepak bola dunia, dan dua tahun berselang, yaitu 1954, PSSI bergabung pada AFC, organisasi sepak bola Asia. Di usia yang ke-93 tahun ini PSSI dikomandoi oleh Erick Thohir. Erick akan memimpin PSSI hingga tahun 2027. "},{"question":"\\"বিদ্যালয়ের শেষ দিন\\" শিরোনামে একটি অনুচ্ছেদ লিখুন।","answer":"এসএসসি পরীক্ষার কিছুদিন আগে আমাদের বিদ্যালয়ে বিদায় অনুষ্ঠানের আয়োজন করা হয়। কিছুদিনের মধ্যে এসএসসি পাস করে কলেজে ভর্তি হব এ বিষয়টি ভেবে আনন্দ লাগলেও বিদায় নিতে হবে ভেবে আমি ভীষণভাবে বিষণ্ন। কারণ দীর্ঘ পাঁচ বছরের অতি পরিচিত বিদ্যালয় থেকে নতুন জীবনে পদাপর্ণের জন্য বিদায় নিতে হচ্ছে। এ দীর্ঘ সময়ে বিদ্যালয়ের সাথে ধীরে ধীরে এক নিবিড় সম্পর্ক গড়ে উঠেছিল। বিদ্যালয়ের শ্রদ্ধেয় শিক্ষকমণ্ডলী, বন্ধু-বান্ধব, অগণিত ছাত্র ও পরিবেশের সাথে এক আত্মিক সম্পর্ক রচিত হয়েছিল। পরিচিত পরিবেশ-পরিমণ্ডলসহ বিদ্যালয় ছেড়ে যাওয়ার এক অব্যক্ত ব্যথায় আমার মন ব্যথিত হয়ে উঠেছিল। সমস্ত বিদ্যালয়ে একটা ভাবগম্ভীর পরিবেশ বিরাজ করছিল। অশ্রুসজল চোখে প্রিয় শিক্ষকদের কাছ থেকে বিদায় নেওয়ার সময় তাঁরা পরমস্নেহে বিদায়ী শিক্ষার্থীদের সান্ত্বনা দিলেন। তাঁদের অমূল্য উপদেশ ও দোয়াকে জীবন চলার পাথেয় করে নিয়ে দুঃখ ভারাক্রান্ত মনে বাসায় ফিরলাম।"},{"question":"Svara på den här frågan: Damm och aska som kommer in i atmosfären till följd av vulkanutbrott kan påverka jordens Välj ditt svar från: (a) Tidvattenaktivitet. b) Orbitalform. c) väder och klimat. d) Rotation och revolution. Svar:","answer":"c) Väder och klimat."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"கற்பு என்ற சொல், பெண் ஓர் அடிமை; சீவனற்ற ஒரு பொருள் என்று காட்டவே ஆகும்."},{"question":"Gift gun Gbenga lọbẹ pa n’Ibadan, wọn ni bo se pa ọkọ ẹ naa niyẹn","answer":"Bi ọkunrin ẹni ọdun mejidinlogoji (38) kan, Babafẹmi Gbenga, ba ri wolii kan riran si i pe nipasẹ ere ṣiṣe ni yoo gba rọrun alakeji, ati pe lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, lọjọ naa yoo jẹ, ọkunrin mẹkaniiki yii iba wulẹ ma ti jade rara lọjọ Tusidee to kọja yii debi ti yoo kọju eréepá si ẹni ti yoo gbẹmi ẹ ni rèwerèwe.Gbenga ati obinrin ẹni ọdun mẹrindinlogoji, Efe Gift, ko ṣẹṣẹ maa bara wọn ṣere, ṣugbọn bi ere ti wọn ti jọ maa n ṣe tẹlẹ ti ki i dija yii ṣe di ohun ti ọmọbinrin Ibo yii n gun ọrẹ ẹ pa, lo sọ Tusidee, ọjọ karun-un, oṣu kin-in-n,i ọdun 2021 yii, di ọjọ buruku eṣu gbomi mu fun wọn.Bi ki i baa ṣe pe iṣẹlẹ yii ti wa ninu akọsilẹ Ẹlẹdaa, ṣebi aanu lọkunrin yii fẹẹ ṣe to fi lọọ pade iku ojiji, ẹnikan lo fẹẹ ran lọwọ to fi lọ sibi ti wọn ti pa a.Iwadii akọroyin wa fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ọti ẹlẹridodo lo n mu lọwọ jẹẹjẹ ni ṣọọbu ọga ẹ to n kọ ọ niṣẹ mẹkaniiki nitosi ileeṣẹ awọn aṣọbode (kọ́sítọ́ọ̀mù) laduugbo Ikọlaba, n’Ibadan, ni nnkan bii aago kan ọsan ọjọ naa. Ẹnikan to sọ pe ori n fọ oun ni Gbenga pinnu lati lọọ ba ra oogun nigba ti onitọhun ko ri ọmọde kankan to maa ran loogun yẹn nitosi.Oogun ̣ọhun lo lọọ ra nitosi ṣọọbu wọn nibẹ to fi fẹsẹ kan ya sọdọ Gift, ṣe ẹgbẹ kan ibi ti wọn ti n ta oogun lobinrin naa ti maa n hun apẹrẹ, to si maa n patẹ awọn ọja naa sẹgbẹẹ titi ládojúkọ ileeṣẹ awọn aṣọbode.Gẹgẹ bi ọkan ninu awọn tiṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣoju wọn ṣe ṣalaye fakọroyin wa, “Nibi ti obinrin alapẹrẹ yẹn ti bẹrẹ mọlẹ to n ṣiṣẹ lọwọ ni Gbenga ti fọwọ mejeeji rìn ín lẹgbẹẹ látẹ̀yìn. Bẹẹ niyẹn yán ọwọ sẹyin lojiji, ti ọbẹ to mu lọwọ si ya Gbenga lọwọ.“Ọrọ yii di ibinu Gbenga, awọn eeyan bẹrẹ si i bẹ ẹ pe ko fi obinrin yẹn silẹ, ṣugbọn o loun ko ni i gba, nitori pe o ti mu ẹjẹ lara oun. Nibi to ti fẹẹ sun mọ ọn niyẹn ti doju ọbẹ kọ ọ, to si fi gbogbo agbara gun un lọbẹ nigbaaya lẹẹmẹta.“Lẹyin eyi lo rẹ Gbenga wẹ̀sì, nitori ẹjẹ to jade loju ọgbẹ igbaaya rẹ ti pọ ju. Idi ni pe ọbẹ yẹn ti gún un lọ́kàn, gbogbo bo ṣe n mí lẹjẹ n tú kọ̀líkọ̀lí gba ibi ọkan rẹ jade. Bo ṣe ṣubu lulẹ to bẹrẹ si i japoro iku niyẹn.“Awọn eeyan ni wọn gbe e dide nibi to ṣubu si. Wọn sare gbe e lọ si UCH (ileewosan ijọba apapọ n’Ibadan). Nibẹ lawọn dokita ti fidi ẹ mulẹ pe o ti ku, wọn lo ti ku ki wọn too gbe e de.”Nṣe ni ibi ti ọkunrin mẹkaniiki yii ṣubu si ko too di pe wọn gbe e lọ sileewosan kun fun ẹjẹ, afi bii oju ibi ti wọn dunbu ẹran ọdun si. Ipasẹ ẹjẹ ọhun si han loju titi lọ titi de ibi ti wọn ti gbe e sinu mọto lọ sọsibitu.Araadugbo ọhun kan to pera ẹ ni SP ṣalaye f’ALAROYE pe “Gbenga ati obinrin alapẹrẹ yẹn ko ṣẹṣẹ jọ maa ṣere. Ara ṣọọbu awọn Gbenga kan lo n fẹ obinrin yẹn. Mo ro pe nitori ki ẹni to n fẹ yẹn ma baa ka wọn mọ ibi ti wọn ti n ṣere lo ṣe dà á si ibinu mọ Gbenga lọwọ.”Ọpọ ninu awọn to b’akọroyin wa sọrọ fidi ẹ mulẹ pe opó ni Gift, oun naa lo pa ọkọ ẹ, bo ṣe fọbẹ gun Gbenga pa naa lo gun ọkọ to bimọ fun lọbẹ pa.Iwadii ALAROYE fidi ẹ mulẹ pe Gbenga ko ti i niyawo, bẹẹ ni ko ti i niṣẹ lọwọ. Lasiko ti baba ẹ ba a riṣẹ si sẹkiteriati ijọba apapọ to wa ni Ikọlaba niṣẹlẹ to da ẹmi ẹ legbodo yii waye.Agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ, CSP Olugbenga Fadeyi, fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, o ni awọn ọlọpaa teṣan Ikọlaba ti mu Gift lọ si ẹka to n tọpinpin iṣẹlẹ ọdaran nileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ naa fun iwadii.Titi ta a fi pari akojọ iroyin yii, yara ti wọn n ṣe oku lọjọ si nileewosan UCH lòkú Gbenga wa nigba ti iwadii awọn ọlọpaa ṣi n tẹsiwaju."},{"question":"Which of the following is the most critical component of the triple constraint?a. Quality, then cost, then time.b. Time, then cost, then scope.c. They are all of equal importance unless otherwise stated.d. Scope.","answer":"c. They are all of equal importance unless otherwise stated."},{"question":"من هو الصحابي الذي قام بقتل أمية بن خلف؟\\t","answer":"\\tهو بلال بن رباح."},{"question":"Mariam fun ọmọ iyawo ẹ ni majele jẹ l’Ẹdẹ, o l’eṣu lo ti oun toun fi pa a","answer":"Iyaale ile kan, Musa Mariam, ti sọ pe eṣu lo ti oun ti oun fi pa ọmọ iyawo ti wọn fẹ le oun.Lasiko ti Mariam n ba ALAROYE sọrọ nileeṣẹ ọlọpaa niluu Oṣogbo, lọsan-an oni lo sọ pe ọdun mẹrin sẹyin loun fẹ ọkọ oun niluu Ẹdẹ, ṣugbọn nigba ti ọmọ ti oun kọkọ bi ku ni ọkọ oun fẹyawo kekere le oun.Mariam, ẹni ọdun mẹrinlelogun, ṣalaye pe latigba tiyawo yẹn ti bimọkunrin ni wahala ti de ninu ile, o ni ṣe ni ọkọ oun maa n kẹ ọmọ naa loju-nimu, ti oun ko si ri oju rẹ nilẹ mọ.O ni wahala naa pọ si i nigba ti oun bimọ obinrin, ṣe lo maa n fi ọmọ oun kẹ ọmọkunrin tiyawo bi, idi si niyẹn tẹmi eṣu fi ko si oun ninu lọsan-an ọjọ kẹrindinlọgbọn, oṣu kejila, ọdun to kọja, ti oun si fun ọmọ naa ni oogun pakopako (Rocket) mu.Mariam ṣalaye pe ṣe lọmọ naa, Rokeeb Musa, ọmọ ọdun mẹta, ro pe omi lasan loun fun un to fi mu majele naa, loju ẹsẹ lo si bẹrẹ si i bi, o ni awọn gbe e lọ sileewosan, ṣugbọn lọjọ kẹrin lo pada jade laye.O fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe funra oun loun pe ọkọ awọn lori foonu lọjọ kẹta iṣẹlẹ naa lẹyin ti oun sa kuro ninu ile nitori ẹri-ọkan, ti oun si sọ fun un pe oun loun fun ọmọ naa ni oogun pakopako mu, ṣugbọn ko dariji oun.Kọmisanna ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, Wale Ọlọkọde, sọ pe laipẹ ni Mariam yoo foju bale-ẹjọ."},{"question":"संविधान के अनुच्छेद 245 और 246 में क्या अंतर है?","answer":"अनुच्छेद 245 संसद और राज्यों के विधानमंडलों द्वारा बनाए गए कानूनों की सीमा के बारे में बात करता है। यह संसद को कानून बनाने की शक्ति देता है और विधायी निकाय को उन्हें निरस्त करने की शक्ति भी देता है । जबकि अनुच्छेद 246 संघ और राज्यों के बीच शक्ति के विभाजन से संबंधित है । यह तीन सूचियों (संघ सूची, राज्य सूची और समवर्ती सूची) में उनकी शक्तियों को वर्गीकृत करके संघ और राज्य की शक्तियों का सीमांकन करता है ।अनुच्छेद 245 : इसके अनुसार, संविधान के उपबंधों के अधीन रहते हुए, भारत की संसद देश के संपूर्ण क्षेत्र अथवा उसके किसी भाग के लिये कानून बना सकती है तथा किसी राज्य का विधानमंडल उस संपूर्ण राज्य अथवा किसी भाग के लिये कानून बना सकता है । संविधान के भाग- XI में अनुच्छेद 245 से 255 तक केन्द्र-राज्य विधायी संबंधों की चर्चा की गई है । हालाँकि इस अनुच्छेद में कुछ शर्तें भी हैं :- तीन केंद्र-शासित प्रदेशों – अंडमान -निकोबार, लक्षद्वीप और दमन-दीव एवं दादर नगर हवेली के लिए, भारत के राष्ट्रपति को भी ‘शांति, प्रगति और सुशासन’ के लिए नियम बनाने का अधिकार है । ऐसा कानून इतना शक्तिशाली होगा कि यह इन क्षेत्रों के संबंध में संसद द्वारा बनाए गए कानून को भी निरस्त या संशोधित कर सकता है ।पाँचवीं अनुसूची के अनुसूचित क्षेत्रों के मामले में, राज्यपाल यह निर्देश दे सकता है कि कोई विशेष संसदीय कानून ऐसे क्षेत्र पर लागू हो या नहीं । राज्यपाल यह भी निर्देश दे सकते हैं कि क्या ऐसा कानून उपयुक्त संशोधनों और अपवादों के साथ लागू हो सकता है ।छठी अनुसूची के राज्यों (असम, मेघालय, त्रिपुरा और मिजोरम) के मामले में राज्यपाल निर्देश दे सकते हैं कि क्या कोई संसदीय कानून संशोधन के साथ लागू हो या नहीं । इस प्रकार, भारत के पूरे क्षेत्र या किसी भी हिस्से के लिए कानून बनाने की संसद की शक्ति सर्वोपरि नहीं है और इसे संविधान के अन्य प्रावधानों के अधीन पढ़ा जाना चाहिए ।अनुच्छेद 246 : 246 (1) – खंड (2) और (3) में किसी भी प्रावधान के होने के बावजूद, संसद के पास सातवीं अनुसूची में सूची 1 में उल्लिखित किसी भी मामले के संबंध में कानून बनाने की विशेष शक्ति है ।246 (2) – खंड (3) में किसी भी प्रावधान के होने के बावजूद, संसद और, खंड (1) के अधीन, किसी भी राज्य के विधानमंडल को भी, सातवीं अनुसूची की सूची 3 में उल्लिखित किसी भी मामले के संबंध में कानून बनाने की शक्ति है ।246 (3) – खंड (1) और (2) के अधीन, किसी भी राज्य के विधानमंडल के पास ऐसे राज्य या उसके किसी भाग के लिए सातवीं अनुसूची में सूची 2 में उल्लिखित किसी भी मामले के संबंध में कानून बनाने की विशेष शक्ति है ।246 (4) – संसद को भारत के किसी भी हिस्से के लिए किसी भी मामले के संबंध में कानून बनाने की शक्ति है, जो किसी राज्य में शामिल नहीं है, भले ही ऐसा मामला राज्य सूची में शामिल हो ।"},{"question":"Калп жөнүндө макал билесиңби?","answer":"Калп айткан киши жарыбайт,Калптын казаны кайнабайт."},{"question":"من هو مؤلف كتاب تاريخ موجز للزمن؟","answer":"كتاب تاريخ موجز للزمن هو كتاب ممتع للفيزيائي الشهير ستيفن هوكنج."},{"question":"Lutax?","answer":"Why?"},{"question":"तीजको बारेमा भन न","answer":"तीज नेपाली महिलाहरुको महान पर्व हो, जुन प्राय भदौ महिनामा पर्दछ।  पुरानो जमानामा तीज नेपली महिलाहरुको दुख सुख को भारि बिसाएर रमाउने चाड थिय।  कतिले भन्छन आजभोलि तीज मनाउने क्रममा बिकृति हरु आएका छन तर कति मान्छे चाहि यसलाई समय अनुसारको परिवर्तन मान्छन।  "},{"question":"Ṣe àkópọ̀ àwọn ọ̀rọ̀ wọ̀nyí:#FIFAWWC: Amẹ́ríkà to pàṣán máa r'ágbà fín sí ìdí Thailand. Ẹrù ìyà ni Norway dì lé Super Falcons l'órí ní 2019 Women's World Cup.Orílẹ̀-èdè Amẹ́ríkà gb'ògo lọ́wọ́ ẹgbẹ́ agbábọ́ọ̀lù obìnrin Orílẹ̀-èdè Thailand pẹ̀lú àmì ayò mẹ́tàlá nínú ìfẹsẹ̀wọnsẹ̀ àkọ́kọ́ wọn ní ìdíje ife ẹ̀yẹ f'áwọn obìnrin tó ń lọ lọ́wọ́ l'órílẹ̀-èdè France.Kódà, kò sí ìdíje ife ẹ̀yẹ bọ́ọ̀lù àjọ FIFA kankan tí irúfẹ́ èyí ti ṣẹlẹ̀. Agbábọ́ọ̀lù  orílẹ-èdè Amẹ́ríkà, Alex Morgan gbá góòlù márùún wọlé nínú ìfẹsẹ̀wọnsẹ̀ náà, Lavelle (méjì), Mewis (méjì), Horan, Megan Rapinoe, Mallory Pugh àti Carli Lloyd  pẹ̀lú náà gbá góòlù kọ̀ọ̀kan wọlé nínú ìfẹsẹ̀wọnsẹ̀ náà.Ìfẹsẹ̀wọnsẹ̀ ọ̀hún ni àkọ́kọ́ fún orílẹ-èdè Thailand nínú ìdíje ife ẹ̀yẹ àgbáyé.","answer":"Fún ìgbà àkọ́kọ́ nínú ìtàn ìdíje ife ẹ̀yẹ bọ́ọ̀lù, àwọn obìnrin lágbàáyé, orílẹ-èdè kan yóò máa gbo ewúro sójú orílẹ-èdè mìíràn pẹ̀lú àmì ayò mẹ́tàlá."},{"question":"Сынган кылыч романдагы 📚 Кудаяр хан ким болгон?","answer":"Кудаяр хан — Кокондун хандыгында үч жолу такка олтурган. Атасы – Шерали, апасы – Жаркынайым. Мусулманкулдун кызын аялдыкка алып, анын кайната экенине карабай кыпчактар кыргынын уюштурган. Кыргыздардан барган кырк элчинин наркты бузуп, башын алдырган. Тарыхта эң адилетсиз, мыкаачы, каардуу хан катары ысмы калган. Саясий күрөштө бир нече жолу тактан түшүп, элдин шылдыңына кабылганына карабай, кыйын кырдаалда эл кызыкчылыгын аттап, падышачылык Россиянын колониялык саясаты менен келишип кеткен, туруксуз адам."},{"question":"ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਸੰਸ਼ਲੇਸ਼ਣ ਲਈ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਗੈਸ ਲੋੜੀਂਦੀ ਹੈ ?ਉੱਤਰ-","answer":"ਪ੍ਰਕਾਸ਼ ਸੰਸ਼ਲੇਸ਼ਣ ਲਈ ਕਾਰਬਨ-ਡਾਈਆਕਸਾਈਡ ਗੈਸ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Sri Lanka has a rich tradition of tea production. Could you elaborate on the charm of the country's tea estates, the tea culture, and how these plantations contribute to the scenic beauty of the hill country?","answer":"Sri Lanka's tea estates, particularly in regions like Nuwara Eliya and Ella, are enchanting landscapes of rolling hills covered in vibrant green tea bushes. The tea culture is deeply ingrained in the country's identity, with rituals like \\"High Tea\\" offering a serene experience amidst picturesque plantations. These tea estates not only produce world-renowned Ceylon tea but also contribute to the breathtaking beauty of Sri Lanka's hill country."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe olona mahery vintana?","answer":" Ny olona mahery vintana dia olona sarotra asian-dratsy, mandresy ny vintan’ny hafa, ilazana ny olona teraka alakaosy."},{"question":"Dapọ Abiọdun fun akẹkọọ Ogun to yege ju lọ ni LASU ni miliọnu meji naira ati ile kan","answer":"Idunnu ṣubu lu ayọ fawọn akẹkọọ meji kan, Ọladimeji Ṣotunde, ọmọ bibi ipinlẹ Ogun to pegede ju lọ ni Yunifasiti LASU, l’Ekoo, ati ọmọbinrin kan, Faith Ọdunsi, akẹkọọ ileewe Girama  Ambassadors College, Ọta, to ṣe daadaa ju lọ ninu imọ iṣiro lagbaaye,nigba ti Gomina fun Ọladimeji ni miliọnu meji ati ile kan, to si fi milliọnu marun-un naira si asunwọn iranlọwọ ti wọn ṣi fun Faith Ọdunsi.Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọjọ kejilelogun, oṣu kẹrin yii, ni eto naa waye l’Oke-Mosan, l’Abẹokuta. Bi Ọladimeji ṣe pegede ni LASU, bẹẹ ni Faith toun jẹ akẹkọọ nileewe girama naa jawe olubori ninu idije ẹkọ nipa iṣiro ti wọn pe ni ‘ Global Open Mathematics Tournament.’Nibi eto ti wọn tun fi da awọn olukọ to yẹ lọla naa ni Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun ti sọ pe awọn eeyan to gba ami-ẹyẹ yii tubọ gbe ipinlẹ Ogun sori atẹ agbaye ni, o ni wọn ti gbe ipinlẹ yii ga, idi si niyẹn tijọba fi mọ riri wọn.Abiọdun sọ pe ijọba oun yoo maa ṣe ẹtọ to yẹ bayii fawọn akẹkọọ ati olukọ nipinlẹ Ogun, lati maa jẹ koriya fun wọn, ti yoo si maa jẹ nnkan idagbasoke ati iyi nla fun ipinlẹ yii kaakiri agbaye.Awọn ọmọwe nla bii Ọjọgbọn Wọle Ṣoyinka, Ọjọgbọn Adewale Ṣolarin, Ọjọgbọn Isiaq Oloyede atawọn mi-in ni wọn ki Gomina Abiọdun fun bo ṣe mu ẹkọ ni koko, wọn ni ohun to fa aṣeyọri awọn akẹkọọ yii atawọn olukọ wọn niyẹn."},{"question":"Ang isang lawa ay may pangkat na mga lily pad. Araw-araw, dumobole ang laki ng pangkat. Kung aabutin ng 48 na araw para masakop ng pangkat ang buong lawa, gaano katagal bago masakop ng pangkat ang kalahati ng lawa?","answer":"Aabutin ng 47 araw para masakop ng pangkat ng lily pad ang kalahati ng lawa. Sinasabi sa sitwasyon na dumodoble ang laki ng pangkat kada araw. Kaya, kung nasakop ng pangkat ang buong lawa sa ika-48 na araw, nangangahulugan ito na kalahati ng lawa ang nasakop ng pangkat sa nakaraan o ika-47 na araw."},{"question":"2023 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான புக்கர் பரிசு வென்றவர் யார்1)சாரா பெர்ன்ஸ்டீன்2)பால் ஹார்டிங்3)பால் லிஞ்ச்4)பால் முர்ரே","answer":"விடை -  3)பால் லிஞ்ச்ஐரிஷ் எழுத்தாளரான பால் லிஞ்ச் தனது ‘Prophet Song’  ‘ நாவலுக்காக 2023 ஆம் ஆண்டின் புக்கர் பரிசை வென்றார், இரண்டாவது இடம் இந்திய வம்சாவளி எழுத்தாளர் சேத்னா மாரூவின் “Western Lane ” நாவலுக்கு கிடைத்தது ."},{"question":"\\"Nandeha nilalao vao maraina izy miralahy.\\"Inona no mety ho fiafaran'ity tantara ity?A. Noana sady reraka izy ireo rehefa niverina avy any.B. Ariva mody masoandro izy ireo vao niverina nody.","answer":"A. no ampoizina fa mety ho fiafaran'ity tantara ity kokoa."},{"question":"Faith Tabernacle","answer":"Igbagbọ Tabernacle jẹ ile ijọsin ihinrere nla kan ati ile-iṣẹ ti Ile-ijọsin Igbagbọ Living Ni agbaye. Ó wà ní ilẹ̀ Kénáánì, Ota, Lagos , Nàìjíríà, ní báyìí o jẹ́ ìgbìyànjú tuntun. Olori alufa ilu yii ni Dokita David Oyedepo lati igba ti o ti da silẹ ni ọdun 1983. ni 2015, awọn wiwa wà 50.000 eniyan.Ni ọdun 1981, David Oyedepo ni ẹni ọdun 26, ni iran kan fun iṣẹ-iranṣẹ rẹ. A da Ile ijọsin silẹ ni Oṣu kejila ọjọ 11, ni ọdun 1983. Ni ọdun 2014, Living Faith Church Ni agbaye wa ni orilẹ-ede 65. ni 2020, Tẹmpili Igbagbọ ni awọn olukopa 50,000.A ti ra ilẹ Kenan ni 1998 ati pe o jẹ 560 acres (.3 km2), ti o wa ni Ota, Ogun, Nigeria. Olu ile ijọsin ti kariaye, Faith Tabernacle, ni a kọ ni Cannanland laarin ọdun 1998 ati 1999, ti o gba oṣu 12 lati pari. Ipilẹ jẹ idasilẹ ni Oṣu Kẹjọ Ọjọ 29, Ọdun 1998.Ni 1999, Tẹmpili Igbagbọ ti ṣii pẹlu awọn ijoko 50,400. Agọ ni a mọ si ile ijọsin ti o tobi julọ ni agbaye ni awọn ofin ti agbara. O bo bii 70 saare ati pe a ṣe sinu ohun-ini kan ti a npè ni Kenanland, eyiti o ni diẹ sii ju saare 10,500 (42km2) ni Ota, Lagos agbegbe. A kọ ile ijọsin naa ni oṣu 12 a si fi wọn lelẹ ni Oṣu Kẹsan, ọdun 1999."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe drôna ?","answer":"Ny drôna dia fiaramanidina tsy natao hitondrana olona fa voaprograma hanao asa isan-karazany, anisan'izany ny sary an-habakabaka, ny fanaterana entana, ary ny fanaraha-maso sy amin'ny lafin-javatra maro hafa koa."},{"question":"Tsimpony ny teny misy tirin-teny sara-droa amin'ity fehezanteny ity:« Betsaka no tsy nino toa azy tamin'ireo olona nitantarany.»","answer":"\\"Nitantarany\\" no teny misy tirin-teny sara-droa amin'io fehezan-teny io."},{"question":"From Dynamite to Diplomacy: The Unexpected Origins of the Nobel Prizes","answer":"Alfred Nobel, the inventor of dynamite, may seem an unlikely figure to inspire prestigious awards for peace and progress. However, his journey from industrialist to philanthropist offers a fascinating insight into the origins of the Nobel Prizes:A Legacy of Destruction: Nobel amassed his fortune through the production of explosives, including dynamite, which was used for both construction and warfare. Witnessing the devastating consequences of these inventions, Nobel experienced a profound moral shift.From Destruction to Creation: Nobel sought to channel his wealth into endeavors that would benefit humanity. In his 1895 will, he established five awards to recognize outstanding achievements in the fields of physics, chemistry, medicine, literature, and peace.Evolution of the Prizes: Since their inception, the Nobel Prizes have undergone significant changes. The Peace Prize, initially criticized for focusing on traditional diplomacy, has broadened its scope to encompass human rights and environmental activism. The addition of the Sveriges Riksbank Prize in Economic Sciences in Memory of Alfred Nobel in 1968 further expanded the reach of the awards.The Nobel Prizes stand as a testament to Alfred Nobel's desire to promote peace and progress. While his initial motivations may seem paradoxical, his legacy serves as a reminder that even those involved in destructive industries can choose to leave a different kind of mark on the world."},{"question":"විලියම් ෂේක්ස්පියර් යනු විද්‍යාඥයෙකි.","answer":"මෙම ප්‍රකාශය වැරදිය. විලියම් ෂේක්ස්පියර් ඉංග්‍රීසි නාට්‍යකරුවෙකු, කවියෙකු සහ නළුවෙකි."},{"question":"ජාත්‍යන්තර ඔලිම්පික් දිනය කවදාද?","answer":"ජාත්‍යන්තර ඔලිම්පික් දිනය ජූනි 20 යි."},{"question":"आर्थिक योजनामा ​​परोपकार र परोपकारलाई कसरी एकीकृत गर्न सकिन्छ?","answer":"परोपकार दानको लागि आम्दानीको एक भाग विनियोजन गरेर वित्तीय योजनाको हिस्सा हुन सक्छ। परोपकार एकीकरणले वित्तीय सफलतामा उद्देश्य र पूर्ति थप्छ।"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന വാചകം പൂർത്തിയാക്കുക: സെപ്റ്റംബർ 11, 2001 ആക്രമണത്തെത്തുടർന്ന്, അമേരിക്ക അഫ്ഗാനിസ്ഥാൻ ആക്രമിക്കുകയും അഫ്ഗാൻ സേനയുടെ സഹായത്തോടെ താലിബാനെ പുറത്താക്കുകയും ചെയ്തു. യുഎസ് പിന്തുണയുള്ള വടക്കൻ സഖ്യത്തിനെതിരെ ബരാദർ യുദ്ധം ചെയ്തു, \\"ന്യൂസ് വീക്കിന്റെ അഭിപ്രായത്തിൽ\\", താലിബാൻ പ്രതിരോധം തകർന്നതിനാൽ 2001 നവംബറിൽ \\"മോട്ടോർ സൈക്കിളിൽ കയറ്റി തന്റെ പഴയ സുഹൃത്തിനെ (ഒമറിനെ) പർവതങ്ങളിൽ സുരക്ഷിതത്വത്തിലേക്ക് കൊണ്ടുപോയി\\". ഒരു മാസത്തിനുള്ളിൽ അമേരിക്കയുമായി ബന്ധമുള്ള അഫ്ഗാൻ സൈന്യം ബരാദറിനെയും മറ്റ് താലിബാൻ നേതാക്കളെയും പിടിച്ചുവെന്ന് പറയുന്നുണ്ടെങ്കിലും പാകിസ്താൻ രഹസ്യാന്വേഷണവിഭാഗം അവരെ മോചിപ്പിക്കാൻ ഇടപെട്ടു. ","answer":"ഡച്ച് ജേർണലിസ്റ്റ് ബെറ്റെ ഡാം റിപ്പോർട്ട് ചെയ്ത മറ്റൊരു വാർത്തപ്രകാരം, താലിബാൻ വിരുദ്ധ സേന കെട്ടിപ്പടുക്കാൻ അഫ്ഗാനിസ്ഥാനിൽ എത്തിയപ്പോൾ ഹമീദ് കർസായിയുടെ ജീവൻ ബരദാർ രക്ഷിച്ചു എന്നാണ്."},{"question":"Eré wo làkọ́kọ́ tí òṣèré Lilian Esoro ṣe?","answer":"Eré Extended Family ni."},{"question":"விடைக்கேற்ற வினா அமைக்க: மொழி என்ற ஒன்று பிறந்தவுடன் ‘உலகம்’ என்பதும், ‘நான்’ என்பதும் தனித்தனியாகப் பிரிந்து, தங்களைத் தனித்துவமாக நிலைநிறுத்திக் கொள்கின்றன.","answer":"வினா : ‘உலகம்’ என்பதும் ‘நான்’ என்பதும் தனித்தனியாகப் பிரிந்து, தங்களைத் தனித்துவமாக நிலைநிறுத்திக் கொள்வது எப்போது?"},{"question":"Ataköy Konakları zemini nasıl?","answer":"Ataköy konutları bile kıyı kenar çizgisi içinde kalıyor. Kıyı kenar çizgisi içinde zemin yumuşaktır. 6 şiddetinde bir depreme bile dayanamaz. Sağlam kaya 25-30 metre altta."},{"question":"சரியானதைத் தேர்க.அ) யார்? எது? – பால் வேறுபாடுஆ) ஆசிரியர் வந்தார் – பலர்பால் விகுதி உயர்வு விகுதி வரும்இ) அவர் வந்தார் – பன்மைப் பொருளை உணர்த்துகிறதுஈ) தங்கமணி பாடினான் – பெண்பால் விகுதி பெற்றுள்ளது","answer":"ஆ) ஆசிரியர் வந்தார் – பலர்பால் விகுதி உயர்வு விகுதி வரும்"},{"question":"2023 දී දැවයෙන් කරන ලද චන්ද්‍රිකාවක් ගුවන්ගත කිරීමට සූදානම් රට වන්නේ කුමක්ද?","answer":"ජපානය"},{"question":"Quelle est l’histoire du ballet de cour ?","answer":"Les danses religieuses, guerrières et théâtrales des Grecs, les jeux dansés du Moyen Âge ont abouti aux intermèdes des fêtes somptueuses de la Renaissance (surtout en Italie), dont est issu à son tour le ballet de cour, fusion de la danse, de la musique, du chant, de la peinture. Sous le règne de Louis XIV, le musicien italien Jean-Baptiste Lully joue un rôle considérable. Auteur de la musique de nombreux ballets, il collabore avec Molière pour les livrets et avec Charles Louis Beauchamp pour la danse dans les comédies-ballets (le Bourgeois gentilhomme, musique de Lully, ballet de Beauchamp, 1670). Vient ensuite la tragédie-ballet, où la danse intervient au cours de l'action (Cadmus et Hermione, musique de Lully, livret de Philippe Quinault, 1673) et à laquelle succède l'opéra-ballet, composé de plusieurs actes indépendants chantés et dansés (Europe galante, d'André Campra, 1697).Avec l'apparition des danseurs professionnels (Triomphe de l'Amour, musique de Lully, ballet de Louis Guillaume Pécour et Beauchamp, 1681), la création de l'école de danse de l'Opéra (1713), l'élaboration de règles, l'enrichissement de la technique et du vocabulaire des pas, le ballet passe à la scène. La vogue de l'opéra italien (qui avait introduit en France les « grandes machines ») s'estompe, et le ballet français fait école. De grands danseurs apparaissent : Pécour, Blondy, Jean Ballon, Louis Dupré, Louis-Antoine Duport, Jean Dauberval, les Vestris, les Gardel, Jules Jospeh Perrot. Les danseuses s'imposent à leur tour : Mlle Fontaine (ou La Fontaine), la Camargo, Marie Sallé, Mlle Prévost… Très controversé, le ballet sans action cède la place au ballet d'action (où la pantomime joue un rôle primordial), innové en France par Jean Georges Noverre (Lettres sur la danse et les ballets, 1760) qui, par ailleurs, supprime masques, robes à paniers et perruques. Le ballet d'action rayonne, s'implante en Russie grâce aux disciples de Noverre. Le drame dansé de l'Italien Salvatore Vigano ajoute un élément émotionnel au ballet."},{"question":"\\"She's Mine\\"  ગીત નો ગુજરાતીમાં સારાંશ આપો.","answer":"\\"She's Mine\\" નો ગુજરાતીમાં સારાંશ:આ ગીતમાં જેકોલેએ તેની પત્ની પ્રત્યે તેના પ્રેમ અને સમર્પણ વિશે વાત કરી છે. તે તેની સુંદરતા, તેની મનોહરતા અને તેના માટે તેનો અપાર પ્રેમ વર્ણવે છે. તે તેના પર ગર્વ કરે છે અને તેને તેના જીવનનું સૌથી મહત્વનું સંપત્તિ ગણે છે.ગીતના શબ્દોમાં, જેકોલેએ તેની પત્નીને \\"તેનું\\" કહ્યું છે, જે તેની નિઃસ્વાર્થતા અને તેના પ્રેમની ઊંડાઈ દર્શાવે છે. તે તેનો પત્રકાર, તેના રક્ષક અને તેના સ્વપ્નોનો સાથી બનવાનું વચન આપે છે.ગીતનો મહત્વનો મેસેજ એ છે કે સત્કારાવાહી અને ભક્તિપૂર્ણ પ્રેમ જીવનમાં સુખ અને સમૃદ્ધિ લાવે છે. જેકોલેના શબ્દોમાં, \\"તેનું\\" તેનો એકમાત્ર પ્રેમ છે, અને તે તેના માટે બધું જ કરવા તૈયાર છે.જો તમે પ્રેમમાં છો, તો આ ગીત તમારા માટે પ્રેરણાસ્પદ હોઈ શકે છે. તે તમને યાદ અપાવે છે કે પ્રેમ એક શક્તિશાળી અને સંતોષકારક ભાવના છે જે તમારા જીવનમાં ઘણું બધું બદલી શકે છે."},{"question":" Sheeg Asxaabtii Uu Rasuulka (NNKH) U Doortay Inay Quraanka Soo Dagaya Uruuriyaan","answer":" Wuxu U Doortay Sayid Bin Thaabid, Ubaya Bin Kacab, Mucaad Bin Jabal, MucaawiyeBin Abuu Sufyaan, Iyo Afartii Khaliif"},{"question":"Ọjọ́ pẹ́ tẹ́nu ti ń kun ọ̀pọ̀ adájọ́ Nàìjíríà l'órí ẹ̀sùn ìwà ìbàjẹ́.Àwọn adájọ́ méjèèjì ọ̀hún ni Adájọ́ Adéníyì Adémọ́lá, tílé ẹjọ́ gíga àpapọ̀ tó wà nílùú Abuja, tí wọ́n fún ní àṣẹ ìfẹ̀yìntì tipátipá pẹ̀lú Adájọ́ O.O Tokode, tílé ẹjọ́ gíga àpapọ̀ tó wà nílùú Benin, tí wọ́n yọ kúrò lẹ́nu iṣẹ́.Ààrẹ Buhari buwọ́lu àbá ìgbìmọ̀ elétò ìdájọ́ tó ga jùlọ lórílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà l'órí àwọn adájọ́ méjèèjì yìí ní ìbámu pẹ̀lú ẹsẹ àkọ́kọ́ abala òfin ọ̀ọ́dúnrún ó dín mẹ́jọ, ìwé òfin ilẹ̀ wa tọdulún 1999.Ìgbìmọ̀ onídàájọ tún dábàá pé, yàtọ̀ sí pé wọ́n yọ Adájọ́ Tokode nípò, ó tún gbọdọ̀ dá gbogbo owó oṣù àti àjẹmọ́nú gbogbo tó gbà lọ̀nà tí kò bófinmu láàrin ọjọ́ kejì oṣù kejìlá ọdún 2015 tí wọ́n búra fún-un gẹ́gẹ́bí adájọ́ ilé-ẹjọ́ gíga sí àsìkò tí wọ́n yọọ́ nípò padà fún ìjọba.Àtẹ̀jáde kan tó wà lójú òpó ìkànsíraẹni twítá tí ààrẹ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà tún kéde wípé, ààrẹ Buhari ti bẹ̀rẹ̀ ìgbésẹ̀ láti ri pé àwọn adájọ́ tó pegedé, nìkan ni ìgbìmọ̀ onídàájọ ń yàn sípò adájọ́.Ẹnú ti ń kun ọ̀pọ̀ onídàájọ lórílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà fún ìgbà díẹ̀ báyìí, pàápàá jùlọ lẹ́yìn tàwọn òṣìṣẹ́ iléeṣẹ́ ọ̀tẹlẹ̀múyẹ́ ní Nàìjíríà, DSS, kọlu ilé àwọn adájọ́ kan lóru, lọ́dún 2016 pẹ̀lú ẹ̀sùn pé ejò wọn l'ọ́wọ́ nínú l'órí àwọn ẹ̀sùn ìwà ìbàjẹ́ àti ìjẹkújẹ gbogbo. Fún mi ní àkòrí tó dára fún àpilẹ̀kọ tí ó wà lókè yìí.","answer":"Buhari fọwọ́sí àbá ìgbìmọ̀ onídàájọ láti yọ adájọ́ méjì nípò."},{"question":"Which U.S. state is the only state to grow coffee beans?","answer":"Hawaii"},{"question":")මාතලේ දිස්ත්‍රිකයත් හම්බන්තොට දිස්ත්‍රික්කයත් මායිම් ලෙස පිහිටන දිස්ත්‍රිකයක් වන්නේ ?","answer":"අම්පාර"},{"question":"Cahit Sıtkı Tarancı'nın 'Yaş 35' şiirinde geçen İtalyan şairin ismi nedir?","answer":" Dante Alighieri"},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన భావం వచ్చేలాగా ఒక పద్యాన్ని రాయండి మరియు రాసిన పద్యంలో ప్రతి పదంకి అర్ధము రాయండిశివుని ఆగ్రహం’ చూసిన పంచభూతములు, పిశాచములు సింహనాదం చేసాయి. స్తుతి చేసే వందిమాగధులు వణికిపోయారు. భయపడిన నంది రంకె వేసాడు.","answer":"భూతపిశాచాల్బొబ్బరిభినవివందిమాగధులువణికారుభయపడి బసవడురంకె వేసినాడు.ప్రతిపదార్థం :భూతములు = పంచభూతములుపిశాచములు = అధోముఖం, ఊర్ధ్వముఖం, తిర్యణ్మఖంబొబ్బరిల్లిట = సింహనాదం చేశాయివంది మాగధులు = స్తుతి చేయవారుబసవడు = నందిరంకె = అరచుట"},{"question":"අඟහරු වායුගෝලයේ ඇති ප්‍රධාන වායුව කුමක්ද ?","answer":"අඟහරු වායුගෝලයේ ඇති ප්‍රධාන වායුව කාබන්ඩයොක්සයිඩ් වේ."},{"question":"次の段落の内容を書き続けてください： 京都の鴨川では毎年5月から、川の上に作った「納涼床」で店の食事やお酒を楽しむことができます。 今年は川のそばにある87の店が席を用意しています。去年までは、新型コロナウイルスの問題で席と席の間を広くしていましたが、今年は特別なルールは作っていません。","answer":"100年ぐらい前からある日本料理の店には、予約をした家族などが来ました。埼玉県から来た人は「川の風を感じながら食事ができて、とてもおいしいです」と話しました。 店の人は「新型コロナの問題で大変でしたが、今年はたくさんの人に来てほしいです」と話しました。 鴨川の納涼床は9月30日まで続く予定です。"},{"question":"Topic: ఏలూరుArticle: ఏలూరు (Eluru, Ellore), ఆంధ్ర ప్రదేశ్ రాష్ట్రములోని పశ్చిమ గోదావరి జిల్లా యొక్క ముఖ్య పట్టణము.[1] పిన్ కోడ్ నం. 534 00*., ఎస్.టి.డి.కోడ్ = 08812.ఏలూరు (ఒకప్పుడు హేలాపురిగా వ్యవహరించబడేది) 1866 లో మునిసిపాలిటిగా ఏర్పడింది. (దేశంలో రెండవ మోడల్ మునిసిపాలిటి) 2005 లో మునిసిపల్ కార్పొరేషన్ గా గుర్తించబడింది.మద్రాసు - కలకత్తా జాతీయ రహదారి (NH5) పై ఏలూరు నగరం విజయవాడ నుండి 63 కి.మీ. రాజమండ్రి నుండి 98 కి.మీ. దూరంలో ఈ రెండు నగరాల మధ్య ఉంది. జిల్లా కేంద్రమైనందున ప్రభుత్వ కార్యాలయాల కేంద్రంగాను మరియు చుట్టు ప్రక్కల గ్రామాల ప్రజల వ్యాపార, వైద్య, విద్య, రవాణా అవసరాల కేంద్రంగా ఉంటున్నది. వరి, కూరగాయలు, పొగాకు వర్తకం, చేపల ఎగుమతి, రా పెద్ద నిమ్మకాయల సి.ఆర్.రెడ్డి కాలేజి, అంబికా దర్బార్ బత్తి, జూట్ మిల్లు, తమ్మిలేరు, కృష్ణ కాలువ, సమీపంలో కొల్లేరు సరస్సు - ఇవి ఏలూరు గురించి చెప్పేటప్పుడు ప్రధానంగా ప్రస్తావించ దగిన అంశాలు.ఏలూరు ప్రస్తుతం ఒక స్పెషల్ గ్రేడ్ మునిసిపల్ కార్పొరేషన్, మండల కేంద్రం, జిల్లా కేంద్రం, శాసనసభ నియోజక వర్గం, పార్లమెంట్ నియోజక వర్గం కూడాను.పట్టణం స్వరూపం, జనాభా2011 జనాభా ప్రకారం, ఈ నగర జనాభా 217, 876.[2]ఏలూరు నగరానికి ఒక ప్రక్క పల్లపు ప్రాంతాలు (కొల్లేరు, కైకలూరు), మరొక ప్రక్క మెరక ప్రాంతాలు (చింతలపూడి, జంగారెడ్డిగూడెం) ఉన్నందున ఇక్కడి నిత్య జీవనంలో రెండు ప్రాంతాల ప్రభావం కనిపిస్తుంది.మెరక ప్రాంతమైన చింతలపూడి వైపు నుండి వచ్చే తమ్మిలేరు వాగు ఏలూరి చివర రెండుగా చీలుతుంది (అశోక్ నగర్ వద్ద) . ఎడమవైపు చీలిన వాగు తంగెళ్లమూడి మీదుగా ప్రవహిస్తూ నగరానికి ఒక వైపు సరిహద్దుగా ఉంటుంది. రెండవ చీలిక ఆశోక్ నగర్, అమీనా పేట మీదుగా ప్రవహిస్తూ బస్‌స్టాండు, సి.ఆర్.రెడ్డి కాలేజీ పక్కగా ప్రవహిస్తూ, నగరానికి వేరే సరిహద్దుగా కనిపిస్తుంది. ఈ రెండు చీలికలమధ్య డెల్టాలా ఏలూరు ప్రధాన పట్టణం వుంటుంది. ఈ కారణం వల్లే నాగిరెడ్డి గూడెం ప్రాజెక్ట్ కట్టక మునుపు ఏలూరు ముంపుకు గురి అయ్యేది.కృష్ణానది నుండి వచ్చే ఏలూరు కాలువ పట్టణం మధ్యలో నైఋతి నుండి ఈశాన్యం దిశగా ప్రవహిస్తుంది.కలిసి కొల్ గోదావరి నుండి వచ్చే ఏలూరు కాలువ, కృష్ణ కాలువ, తమ్మిలేరు - ఇవి మూడూ పాలగూడెం (మల్కాపురం) వద్ద కోలేరులో కలవడానికి సాగుతాయి. ఈ కాలువల సంగమం గురించి వేమూరి వెంకటేశ్వరరావు \\"ఈమాట\\" అంతర్జాల పత్రికలో \\"మరపురాని స్మృతులు\\" అనే వ్యాసంలో ఇలా వ్రాశాడు - మా ఊరికి...","answer":"ఏలూరు"},{"question":"Каркыра деген эмне ?","answer":"1. Тумшугу, мойну жана буту узун келген, саздуу жерлерде жүрүүчү келгин куш. Бала кез, көктөм убак, жазгы баар, Асманда карк-карк этет каркыралар (Осмонов). Каркыра, турналар желесин тартып, ысык жакты көздөй жөнөшкөн экен (Каимов).Ушул канаттуунун кооздук үчүн сайына турган канаты. Эндик, упа, каркыра кыз балага жарашат (Токтогул). Каркырасын сайынып («Саринжи-Бөкөй»).2. Сайманын же оюунун бир түрү. Жүк үстүнө килем жайдырып, анын үстүнө каркыра сайдырган (Жантөшев)."},{"question":"Cuba jawab teka-teki berikut: Apa yang buatkan anda senyum?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah otot muka."},{"question":"سبزیوں کے باغ کی منصوبہ بندی کرتے وقت کن اہم عوامل پر غور کرنا چاہیے؟","answer":"سبزیوں کے باغ کی منصوبہ بندی میں کئی اہم عوامل شامل ہیں۔ سب سے پہلے، اپنے منتخب کردہ مقام پر سورج کی روشنی کا اندازہ لگائیں، کیونکہ زیادہ تر سبزیوں کو کم از کم 6-8 گھنٹے سورج کی روشنی درکار ہوتی ہے۔ مٹی کا معیار بہت اہم ہے، لہذا غذائیت کی سطح اور پی ایچ کا تعین کرنے کے لیے مٹی کا ٹیسٹ کروائیں۔ بہترین نشوونما کے لیے پودوں کے درمیان مناسب فاصلہ ضروری ہے۔ مٹی سے پیدا ہونے والی بیماریوں کو روکنے کے لیے فصل کی گردش پر غور کریں۔ آخر میں، اپنی آب و ہوا اور بڑھنے کے موسم کے لیے موزوں سبزیوں کا انتخاب کریں، اور پانی کی دستیابی کے لیے منصوبہ بنائیں، یا تو باقاعدہ بارش یا آبپاشی کے ذریعے۔"},{"question":"نفسیات میں فطرت کی پرورش کی بحث کیا ہے، اور یہ انسانی ترقی کو کیسے متاثر کرتی ہے؟","answer":"فطرت کی پرورش کی بحث نفسیات میں ایک مرکزی مسئلہ ہے جو انسانی نشوونما اور رویے میں جینیات (فطرت) اور ماحولیات (پرورش) کے رشتہ دار شراکت کا جائزہ لیتی ہے۔ یہ بحث اس حد تک گھومتی ہے کہ جینیاتی عوامل اور حیاتیاتی رجحانات بمقابلہ ماحولیاتی اثرات کسی فرد کی شخصیت، ذہانت اور رویے کے مختلف پہلوؤں کو تشکیل دیتے ہیں۔ اسکالرز عام طور پر اس بات پر متفق ہیں کہ فطرت اور پرورش دونوں انسانی ترقی میں اہم کردار ادا کرتے ہیں۔ جینیات افراد کو وراثت میں ملنے والی پیش گوئیوں اور صلاحیتوں میں حصہ ڈالتے ہیں، مزاج اور بعض علمی صلاحیتوں جیسے پہلوؤں کو متاثر کرتے ہیں۔ دوسری طرف، ماحولیاتی عوامل، بشمول پرورش، ثقافت، اور زندگی کے تجربات، ان موروثی خصلتوں کی شکل اور ان میں ترمیم کرتے ہیں۔فطرت کی پرورش کی بحث کا اثر نفسیاتی عوارض، تعلیمی حکمت عملیوں اور یہاں تک کہ عوامی پالیسی کے بارے میں ہماری سمجھ تک پھیلا ہوا ہے۔ جینیات اور ماحول کے درمیان تعامل کو تسلیم کرنے سے ماہرین نفسیات کو مخصوص ضروریات کے حامل افراد کے لیے مداخلتوں کو تیار کرنے میں مدد ملتی ہے، خواہ وہ ذہنی صحت، تعلیم، یا سماجی مدد کے لحاظ سے ہو۔"},{"question":"如何理解中国文化中的“和”？","answer":"“和”是中国文化中的一个重要概念，包含了和谐、合作、平衡等多重含义。在社会关系中，强调和谐共处，避免冲突；在艺术中，强调色彩、线条、音律等元素的和谐与平衡；在人与自然关系中，强调人与自然的和谐共生。"},{"question":"கரையான் நாள் ஒன்றுக்கு ................. முட்டைகளை இடுகின்றன?","answer":"ராணியைப் பற்றி பேசுகையில், ராஜாவுடன் சேர்ந்து வேலை செய்யும் கரையான்கள் அவளுக்கு உணவளிக்கும் அளவுக்கு முட்டைகளை இடுவது அவளுடைய முக்கிய வேலை. காலனியில் நிபுணத்துவத்தைக் கட்டுப்படுத்தும் பெரோமோன்களையும் அவள் சுரக்கிறாள். ஒரு ராணி ஒரு நாளைக்கு 1000 முதல் 2000 முட்டைகள் வரை உற்பத்தி செய்வதாக 25 ஆண்டுகள் அல்லது அதற்கு மேல் வாழ முடியும்."},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هي السوره اللي ما كاتقراش فيها البسمله فالاول؟","answer":"الإجابة: سورة التوبة، أو براءة"},{"question":"வினா :தமிழ்நாட்டில் பெட்ரோலியம் கண்டறியப்பட்டுள்ள இடம்A. திருநெல்வேலிB. திருச்சிC. தஞ்சாவூர்(நரிமணம்)D. மதுரை","answer":"விடை : C. தஞ்சாவூர்(நரிமணம்)"},{"question":"छत्रपती राजारामच्या मृत्यूनंतर त्यांच्या पत्नी ताराबाईने कोणाला गादीवर बसविले?","answer":"छत्रपती राजारामच्या मृत्यूनंतर त्यांच्या पत्नी ताराबाईने दुसरा शिवाजीस गादीवर बसविले."},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚14 жашында Манас айтып баштап, 25 жашында чоң манасчылардын ката-рына кошулган кайсы манасчы? а) Кенжекара Калча уулу б) Тыныбек в) Саякбай  г) Жусуп Мамай","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚в) Тыныбек "},{"question":"Nhà tôi xây 3 tầng, sắp xong phần thô, dự tính cất nóc vào đầu tháng 7 âm lịch. Mọi người đều khuyên tôi nên kiêng triển khai trong tháng ngâu. Vậy tôi nên làm như thế nào?","answer":"Với câu hỏi của bạn, có hai cách lý giải như sau:Một, theo góc nhìn tâm linh, tháng 7 âm lịch được gọi là tháng \\"cô hồn\\", mọi người ít khi thực hiện những việc quan trọng như xây sửa nhà, cất nóc, khai trương... Tùy văn hóa tín ngưỡng của từng người hay vùng miền, sẽ có nhiều quan điểm khác nhau, thậm chí trái ngược về việc này.Hai, dưới góc độ khoa học, ở nhiều địa phương, tháng 7 có tên gọi khác là tháng \\"ngâu\\", do điều kiện thời tiết đặc trưng thường mưa nhiều và dài ngày. Thời tiết này cũng không thích hợp động thổ hay đổ mái vì trong quá trình làm sẽ vất vả hơn, tốn nhiều nhân công, chưa kể ảnh hưởng đến chất lượng.Trên thực tế, không ít công trình vẫn được thực hiện triển khai xuyên suốt tháng 7 âm lịch, do đã cam kết tiến độ với chủ đầu tư, đồng thời áp dụng công nghệ, kỹ thuật hiện đại để khắc phục, hạn chế ảnh hưởng từ thời tiết, đảm bảo chất lượng xây dựng. Tuy nhiên, không thể phủ nhận rằng nếu phải thi công trong điều kiện mưa dài ngày sẽ gặp nhiều khó khăn hơn so với bình thường.Xây nhà là một việc lớn trong đời người, vì thế tùy vào quan điểm tín ngưỡng, cũng như tính chất công việc, chủ nhà có thể cân nhắc quyết định nên hay không nên cất nóc vào thời điểm này.Trong trường hợp muốn tránh triển khai trong tháng 7 âm lịch, bạn có thể bàn bạc với tư vấn giám sát hoặc đơn vị thầu bố trí hoàn thiện các hạng mục công việc khác, nhằm tránh ảnh hưởng đến tiến độ. Ví dụ, cho thợ ghép cốt pha trước cho khu vực chuẩn bị cất nóc, làm sắt, xây tường ngăn chia phòng, trát hoàn thiện mặt trong, xây bậc cầu thang. Song song tiến hành xử lý chống thấm các khu vực có nguy cơ thấm dột cao như nhà vệ sinh, ban công... Bên cạnh đó, bạn cũng có thêm thời gian tìm hiểu năng lực và lựa chọn nhà thầu ở các hạng mục như sơn bả, nội thất, cơ khí, cửa sổ, cửa ra vào..., phục vụ giai đoạn hoàn thiện sau này."},{"question":"Explain the difference between \\"farther\\" and \\"further.\\"","answer":"\\"Farther\\" refers to physical distance, while \\"further\\" is used for figurative distance or degree."},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Inde ?","answer":"New Delhi mooy gëblag réewum Inde. "},{"question":"క్రింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండి: భారతదేశంలో అతి పొడవైన జాతీయ రహదారి?","answer":"ఎన్.హెచ్. -44"},{"question":"Can athletes from unrecognized or disputed territories participate in the Olympics?","answer":"Athletes from unrecognized or disputed territories can participate in the Olympics under certain conditions. They may compete as part of a recognized National Olympic Committee or as independent athletes under the Olympic flag. This allows them to showcase their talent and participate in the spirit of the Games."},{"question":"Kaip vadinasi Lietuvos kariuomenės specialiųjų operacijų pajėgų eskadronas, ne vienerius metus veikęs Afganistane? Pavadinimas yra \\"pasiskolintas\\" iš lietuvių mitologijos.","answer":"Aitvaras. Lietuvių mitologijoje pavadinimas – pagoniškojo panteono dieviška būtybė, atmosferos, vandens, ypač debesų, saugotojas, turintis ryšį su žeme ir jos turtais. Tai materialines gėrybes nešanti būtybė."},{"question":"Cho 10 điểm phân biệt trong đó không có ba điểm nào thẳng hàng, cứ qua hai điểm ta vẽ một đoạn thẳng. Hỏi vẽ được tất cả bao nhiêu đoạn thẳng?A. 10B. 90C. 40D. 45","answer":"Trả lời:Số đoạn thẳng cần tìm là10.(10−1)/2 = 45 đoạn thẳngĐáp án cần chọn là: D"},{"question":"Qual é o esporte nacional do Canadá?","answer":"Lacrosse. O lacrosse foi declarado o esporte nacional do Canadá em 1859. No entanto, em 1994, o Parlamento canadense aprovou a Lei do Esporte Nacional do Canadá, que tornou o lacrosse o esporte nacional de verão e o hóquei o esporte nacional de inverno."},{"question":"人工智能如何应用于智能化教育？","answer":"人工智能可以应用于智能化教育中的个性化学习、智能辅导、教学评估等方面。"},{"question":"ਕੁੜੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਗਣਿਤ ਦੇ ਅਧਿਆਪਕ ਦਾ ਧੰਨਵਾਦ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਸੀ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਕੁੜੀ ਨਜ਼ਰਬੰਦੀ ਲਈ ਸਕੂਲ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਰੁਕ ਗਈ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਕੁੜੀ ਅਧਿਆਪਕ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਸੇਬ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਆਈ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਕੁੜੀ ਅਧਿਆਪਕ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ ਸੇਬ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਆਈ।"},{"question":"வினா : பளபளப்புக்கொண்ட அலோகம் ","answer":"விடை : அயோடின்"},{"question":"இந்தியாவிற்கு எந்த திசையில் வங்காள விரிகுடா அமைந்துள்ளது?","answer":"வங்காள விரிகுடா இந்தியாவின் கிழக்கே அமைந்துள்ளது, அரபிக் கடல் அதன் மேற்கில் அமைந்துள்ளது. நாடு மத்திய ஆசியாவிலிருந்து வடக்கே இமயமலையால் பிரிக்கப்பட்டு தெற்கே இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலால் சூழப்பட்டுள்ளது."},{"question":" Gartay in ay isa soo gelayaan \\"Laailaaha illa Laahu\\" iyo \\"In Ilaahay la rumeeyo\\",balse sidee ayey shanta tiir ee dambe eearkaanul-iimaanku u soo hoos gelayaanqiritaanka: \\"Muxammed waa Rasuulkii Alle\\"","answer":" Marka la qiro inuu Muxammed (scw)Rasuulkii Alle yahay, waxaa la rumeeyeyrasuullada Ilaahay, maxaa yeelay NebiMuxammed (scw) wuxuu ka mid yahayIlaahay rasuulladiisa. Haddii la qiro inuuMuxammed (scw) rasuulkii Alle yahay waxaala rumeeyey kutubtii Ilaahay, Maxaa yeelay Muxammed (scw) wuxuu Rasuul ku noqday in Kitaabka Quráanka ah loo soo dhiibay, quráankuna wuxuu ka mid yahay kutubta Alle.Rumeynta Nebi Muxammed (scw) waxaa soohoos gelaya, rumeynta wax alla wixii uu kawarramay. Sidoo kale in la rumeeyo quraanka\\f"},{"question":"Inona no renirano lava indrindra any Azia?a) Renirano \\"Yellow\\" (Huang He)b) Renirano \\"Yangtsé\\" (Chang Jiang)d) Renirano \\"Amour\\" (Amur)e) Renirano \\"Ganges\\"","answer":"Ny renirano \\"Yangtsé\\" no renirano lava indrindra any Azia."},{"question":"Inona no ranomasina lehibe indrindra eto an-tany?","answer":"Ny Ranomasimbe Pasifika no ranomasina lehibe indrindra eto an-tany."},{"question":"ما هي أكبر قارات العالم حيث المساحة؟","answer":"تعتبر آسيا أكبر قارات العالم من حيث المساحة."},{"question":"In de serie A Song of Ice and Fire, wie is de oprichter van Huis Karstark?","answer":"Het antwoord is Karlon Stark."},{"question":"Como se deram as tentativas de solução negocial do conflito civil angolano? ","answer":"As tentativas de solução negocial do conflito passaram pela assinatura de vários acordos como de Gbadolite (1989), Lusaka (1994), Bicesse (1991), e as eleições de 1992. Mas, todos esses acordos fracassaram; tendo a Guerra Civíl Angolana somente terminado em 2002."},{"question":"Xeexub Iraŋ ak Iraag kañ la tàmbali ?","answer":"Xeexub Iraŋ ak Iraag moo ngi tàmbali ci atum 1980."},{"question":"A o fẹ Wakili l’Ayetẹ mọ o, awọn alalẹ ilẹ yii o ni i jẹ ka tun riru ẹ n’Ibarapa mọ – Ọba Ayetẹ","answer":"Asawo tilu Ayetẹ, Ọba Emmanuel Okeniyi, ti sọ pe awọn o ni i gba ki afurasi ọdaran Fulani, Iskilu Wakili, ti wọn mu laipẹ yii, atawọn ẹmẹwa ẹ to ṣẹku tun pada sagbegbe naa mọ, bẹẹ lọba alaye naa ni iyalẹnu ni bi ijọba ṣe sọ awọn ọmọ OPC to mu Wakili satimọle, o ni igbesẹ naa ku diẹ kaato.Ninu ọrọ to ba ALAROYE sọ lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, lori foonu nipa awọn iṣẹlẹ to waye lagbegbe naa, ati wahala tawọn ọmọ-ẹyin Wakili n da silẹ lẹyin ti wọn ti mu ọga wọn, lo ti sọ pe akoba gidi ni igboke-gbodo awọn Fulani nilẹ Ibarapa, o ni wọn ti mu ki owo ounjẹ gbowo lori bayii.Aṣawo ni, “Ki i ṣe ọrọ ọdun marun-un ti Wakili ti n ṣẹ Yoruba, to n huwa ibi nilẹ Yoruba, pẹlu boun atawọn ẹmẹwa ẹ ṣe n fi maaluu jẹ oko awọn agbẹ, to n ba ire-oko wa jẹ. Ọmọ wa kan dako bii eeka mẹẹẹdogun lọdun mẹta sẹyin, awọn ọmọ Wakili si lọọ fi maaluu jẹ oko paki rẹ to fi jẹ pe ọmọ naa ko ri ẹyọ paki kan mu ninu oko naa. A fọlọpaa mu un, ko da awọn ọlọpaa lohun, a si sọ pe ko kuro lori ilẹ wa, niṣe lo ta ku to loun o nibi kan an lọ. A tun pe e lẹjọ, ile-ẹjọ ni ẹnikan o le le ẹnikan kuro nibi kan, ẹ o ri iya ti wọn fi n jẹ wa.“Tori ẹ lo fi jẹ pe igbesẹ tawọn OPC gbe yii, o dun mọ mi gidi, o si tẹ mi lọrun pẹlu, a ti gbiyanju titi, ta o ri Wakili mu, ti ko si lọ, a waa jaja ri ẹni ba wa ṣi i nidii, a o ni i jẹ ko tun pada sori ilẹ yii mọ, awọn alalẹ ilẹ yii o ni i jẹ ka tun ri Wakili atawọn eeyan ẹ lagbegbe Ibarapa, ki i ṣe Ayetẹ nikan, ni gbogbo agbegbe Ibarapa ati Oke-Ogun pata ni, eegun rẹ ko gbọdọ tun ṣẹ nilẹ yii mọ.“Wakili ti ko arajẹ ba wa lori ilẹ awọn baba wa. Ẹni to ba n febi paayan, tọhun fẹ keeyan ku ni, awa ta a o niṣe meji ju iṣẹ agbẹ lọ, ẹ wo iye ti wọn n ta apo paki bayii, o ti di ẹgbẹrun lọna mẹẹẹdọgbọn naira, baafu ẹ ti di ẹgbẹrun mẹwaa naira, baafu kan pere, awọn Fulani lo sọ wa dẹni ti o ri paki jẹ. O ti ju oṣu meji lọ bayii ti ọpọ agbẹ ti lọ soko gbẹyin.“Iyẹn lo fi jẹ pe o ya mi lẹnu gidi nigba tẹnikan n ba tiwa jẹ, tawọn ọmọ wa si dide, ti wọn mu onitọhun, ti wọn o lu u, wọn o pa a, wọn fa a le ijọba lọwọ ni, to si yẹ kijọba ṣe ẹtọ lori ẹ, to tun waa jẹ awọn ọmọ waa naa ni wọn ti mọle. Bi wọn ṣe ti awọn ọmọ OPC mọle yẹn ku diẹ kaato, ko tiẹ daa rara. Ọrọ ijọba nigba mi-in, nnkan ni.”Ọba Okeniyi tun sọ pe awọn lade-lade nilẹ Ibarapa lo dunnu si bi wọn ṣe mu Wakili. O lawọn ọba naa si n kọminu si bijọba to wa lode yii ṣe n dọgbọn huwa bii ẹni n ṣatilẹyin fawọn Fulani ti wọn n ṣe wa ni ṣuta."},{"question":"خرطوم کے بارے میں بتایے","answer":"خرطوم سوڈان کا دار الحکومت ہے۔ یہ عین اس مقام پر واقع ہے جہاں نیل ابیض اور نیل ازرق آپس میں ملتے ہیں۔ اول الذکر دریا یوگینڈا سے جبکہ آخر الذکر ایتھوپیا سے سفر کرتا ہوا یہاں دریائے نیل کی صورت اختیار کرتا ہے اور پھر مصر سے بہتا ہوا بحیرہ روم میں جا گرتا ہے۔ حقیقی شہر کی آبادی 10 لاکھ سے زیادہ ہے جو اسے ملک کا دوسرا سب سے بڑا شہر بناتی ہے لیکن منسلک مضافاتی علاقوں شمالی خرطوم اور ام درمان کو ملایا جائے تو اس کی آبادی 40 لاکھ سے تجاوز کر جاتی ہے۔ابتدائی تاریخوالی مصر محمد علی پاشا نے 1821ء میں مصری افواج کی ایک چوکی کے طور پر خرطوم کی بنیاد رکھی لیکن یہ تجارت کے ایک علاقائی مرکز کی حیثیت اختیار کر گیا۔ محمد علی مہدی المعروف مہدی سوڈانی کی زیر قیادت سوڈانی افواج نے 13 مارچ 1884ء کو خرطوم کا محاصرہ کیا، جس کا دفاع جنرل چارلس جارج گورڈن کی زیر قیادت انگریز فوج کر رہی تھی اور مہدی کی افواج کو کامیابی ملی اور یوں شہر انگریزوں کے ہاتھوں سے چھن گیا۔ بدلے کی آگ میں جلتے ہوئے انگریزوں نے ستمبر 1898ء میں ہوراٹیو کچنر کی قیادت میں مہدی کے مرکز ام درمان کا محاصرہ کر لیا اور خونریز لڑائی کے بعد شہر پر قبضہ کر لیا۔ انگریزوں نے مہدی سوڈانی کی لاش قبر سے نکال کر جلا دی۔ 1899ء میں خرطوم انگریز و مصر کے زیر قبضہ سوڈان اور 1956ء میں اسے آزاد سوڈان کا دار الحکومت قرار پایا۔حالیہ تاریخ1973ء میں یہ شہر اس وقت عالمی سطح پر توجہ کا مرکز بنا جب بلیک ستمبر گروپ کے اراکین نے سعودی سفارت خانے میں 10 افراد کو یرغمال بنا لیا جس میں سے 5 سفارت کار تھے۔ اس کارروائی میں امریکی سفیر، امریکی نائب سفیر اور بیلجیم کے چارج ڈی افیئرز کو قتل کر دیا گیا۔ بقیہ یرغمالی رہا کر دیے گئے۔ خرطوم اور پورٹ سوڈان کے درمیان تیل کی پہلی پائپ لائن 1977ء میں بنی۔ 1970ء اور 1980ء کی دہائی میں خرطوم چاڈ، ایریٹریا، ایتھوپیا اور یوگینڈا میں ہونے والے تنازعات کے باعث مہاجرین کا گڑھ بن گیا۔ یہ مہاجرین شہر کے نواح میں واقع بڑی کچی آبادیوں میں رہتے۔ 1980ء کی دہائی کے وسط سے یہ شہر دوسری سوڈانی خانہ جنگی اور دارفر تنازع سے متاثر ہونے والے افراد کی بڑی تعداد کا میزبان ہے۔ 1998ء میں امریکی سفارت خانے پر ہونے والے بم دھماکے کے بعد امریکا نے اسامہ بن لادن کے القاعدہ گروہ کو ذمہ دار قرار دیا اور 20 اگست کو خرطوم شہر کے دواساز کارخانے الشفاء پر کروز میزائلوں سے حملہ کر دیا۔ اس حملے سے کارخانہ مکمل طور پر تباہ ہو گيا اور سوڈانی معیشت کو زبردست دھچکہ لگا۔ تحقیقات سے ثابت ہوا کہ کارخانے کا اسامہ بن لادن یا القاعدہ سے کوئی تعلق نہ تھا۔معیشتشہر کی صنعتوں میں طباعت، شیشے کی تیاری، غذائی اور پارچہ بافی کی صنعتیں شامل ہيں۔ پٹرولیم کی مصنوعات ریاست خرطوم کے انتہائی شمالی علاقوں میں تیار ہوتی ہیں جس سے شہر سے وابستہ کئی افراد کو روزگار حاصل ہے۔ سوڈان کے بڑے تیل صاف کرنے والے کارخانوں میں سے ایک شمالی خرطوم میں واقع ہے۔تعلیمشہر خرطوم سوڈان کی کئی اعلٰی جامعات کا مرکز ہے جن میں:جامعہ خرطوم، جسے 1902ء میں گورڈن میموریل کالج کے طور پر قائم کیا گیا تھا تاہم 1930ء کی دہائی میں اسے شہر کے نام سے موسوم کر دیا گیا۔اکادمی برائے طبی علوم و ٹیکنالوجی (The Academy of Medical Sciences and Technology) المعروف AMST 1996ء میں پروفیسر مامون حمیدہ نے شہر کے قلب میں قائم کی۔ یہ ملک کے اعلٰی ترین تعلیمی اداروں میں سے ایک سمجھی جاتی ہے اور سوڈان کی بہترین نجی جامعہ قرار دی جاتی ہے۔جامعہ سوڈان برائے علوم و ٹیکنالوجی (University of Sudan for Science and Technology)کمپیوٹر کالج برائے حضراتجامعہ جوبا۔ خانہ جنگی کے ایام میں اسے جوبا سے خرطوم منتقل کر دیا گیا۔ اب حالات بہتر ہونے کے ساتھ اسے دوبارہ منتقل کرنے کا منصوبہ ہے۔بایان جامعہ برائے علوم و ٹیکنالوجی (Bayan Science and Technology University)ذرائع نقل و حملخرطوم سوڈان کے سب سے بڑے ہوائی اڈے 'خرطوم بین الاقوامی ہوائی اڈا' کا حامل ہے۔ یہ سوڈان کی اہم ایئر لائن سوڈان ایئرویز کا مرکز ہے۔ ہوائی اڈے کو شہر کے جنوبی علاقے میں قائم کیا گیا تھا لیکن تیزی سے بڑھتی ہوئی شہری آبادی کے باعث اب یہ شہر کے قلب میں آ گیا ہے۔ ایک نیا بین الاقوامی ہوائی اڈا اس وقت ام درمان میں تعمیر کیا جا رہا ہے۔ یہ خرطوم کی جگہ سوڈان کے اہم ترین ہوائی اڈے کی جگہ لے گا۔ علاوہ ازیں جوبا اور پورٹ سوڈان کے ہوائی اڈے بھی معروف ہیں۔جڑواں شہرترکیہ کا پرچم استنبول ، ترکی {{{2}}}چین کا پرچم ووہان ، چین {{{2}}}مصر کا پرچم قاہرہ ، مصر {{{2}}}اردن کا پرچم عمان ، اردن {{{2}}}ترکیہ کا پرچم انقرہ ، ترکی {{{2}}}روس کا پرچم سینٹ پیٹرز برگ ، روس {{{2}}}سانچہ:Country data ایریٹریا اسمارا ، ایریٹریا {{{2}}}\\tویکی ذخائر پر خرطوم سے متعلق سمعی و بصری مواد ملاحظہ کریں۔سانچہ:عرب ممالک کے دار الحکومت سانچہ:فہرست افریقی دار الحکومت archINFORM location ID: https://www.archinform.net/ort/1739.htm — اخذ شدہ بتاریخ: 6 اگست 2018   ویکی ڈیٹا پر (P1566) کی خاصیت میں تبدیلی کریں\\"صفحہ خرطوم في GeoNames ID\\". GeoNames ID. اخذ شدہ بتاریخ 8 اکتوبر 2023ء.   ویکی ڈیٹا پر (P982) کی خاصیت میں تبدیلی کریں \\"صفحہ خرطوم في ميوزك برينز.\\". MusicBrainz area ID. اخذ شدہ بتاریخ 8 اکتوبر 2023ء."},{"question":"Inona no toeran'ny teknolojia amin'ny fanabeazana?","answer":"Mihabetsaka ny fampiasana ny teknolojia ho hanatsarana ny fampianarana sy ny fianarana."},{"question":"Футбол боюнча, Испания чемпионаты эмне деп аталат?","answer":"Испаниянын профессионалдык футболдук клубдарынын беттеши - Ла Лина деп аталат."},{"question":"Inona no mahatonga ny jambes lourdes ?","answer":"Matetika ny jambes lourdes dia vokatry ny tsy fikorontanan’ny fikorian’ny rà ao amin’ny lalan-drà be. Izany hoe tsy mahavita mitondra ny rà avy any amin’ny ranjo mankany amin’ny fo intsony ny lalan-drà misahana izany. Maro moa ny antony mety mahatonga izany jambes lourdes izany, toy ny hafanana be loatra, ny fipetrahana na ny fitsanganana mandritra ny fotoana maharitra, akanjo tery loatra… Anisan’ny mahatonga ny jambes lourdes ny fandehanana voyage lavitra satria mipetraka mandritra ny ora maro ilay olona."},{"question":"Кандай жаңылмач билесиң ?","answer":"Мына сизге жаңылмач:Бир түп тыт, Бир түп турп, Турп тытты түртөт, Тыт турпту түртөт. "},{"question":"Кыргыз акча бирдиги канча жолу өзгөргөн?","answer":"Кыргыз валютасынын дизайны төрт жолу өзгөргөн. Кыргыз банкноттору ийкемдүү келет, аларды беш миң ирет бүктөсө болот.Эски сомдор жок кылынгандан кийин калдыктары картон жасоого жөнөтүлөт. Улуттук акчага \\"сом\\" деген аталышты алуу үчүн Кыргызстан Казакстан менен таймашкан. Натыйжада Кыргызстан биринчилерден болуп сомду киргизген. Жергиликтүү валютанын наркын сактап калуу үчүн 2015-жылы Улуттук банк болжол менен 320 миллион доллар кетирген. Эски сомдор чет жерде кымбат турат. Мисалы 1994-жылкы 100 сомдук акча 119 долларга бааланган. "},{"question":"句子1: 车站于1890年12月8日关闭,1969年11月8日开放,1971年被拆除. 第二句: 站于1890年12月8日开放,于1969年11月8日关闭,并于1971年拆除. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Corée du Nord","answer":"Péeyum réwum Corée du Nord mu ngi tudu Pyongyang"},{"question":"Quais são as universidades federais no contexto brasileiro? ","answer":"No Brasil, uma universidade federal corresponde a uma universidade pública mantida pela União que possui como objetivo ofertar ensino superior público e gratuito à população, além de realizar também pesquisas e projetos de extensão."},{"question":"සිංහල  කතන්දරයට සුදුසු මාතෘකාවක් දෙන්න. එක්තරා දක්ෂ වෙළෙන්දෙකුට භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහනය කර දීමට බූරුවෙකු සිටියා. උදෑසන සිට සවස් වන තෙක්ම මේ බූරුවා ට වෙළෙඳ භාණ්ඩ ප්‍රවාහනය කිරීමට සිදු වුණා. ඔහුට විවේකයක් ලැබුණේ රාත්‍රියට පමණයි.රාත්‍රී කාලයේ ආහාර සොයාගෙන ඈතට යාමට අකමැත්තක් දක්වූ මේ බූරුවා, ගමේ අහල පහල වතු වල මිනිසුන් වවන ලද එළවළු, පලතුරු ආදිය කෑමට පුරුදුව සිටියා. දිනක් මේ බූරුවා ට ආහාර සොයාගෙන ගමට පැමිණි හිවලෙකු මුණ ගැසුණා. මෙලෙස වතාවත් කිහිපයක්ම මුණු ගැසුණු පසු ඔවුන් දෙපළ ගජ මිතුරන් බවට පත් වුණා. දෙදෙනාම දැන් එකට එකතු වී, කෑම සොයා යාමට පුරුදු වුණා. \\"බූරු හාමි..!! මට නම් හැමදාම එකම වගේ කෑම කාළා එපා වෙලා.එහා පැත්තේ තියෙනවා වට්ටක්කා යායක්. එහෙ හොඳට ඉදුණු, පැණි බේරෙන, තැඹිලි ම තැඹිලි පාට, මෙලෙක් වට්ටක්කා තියෙනවා මන් දැක්කා. එහෙ මටත් කන්න පොඩි පොඩි සත්තු එමටයි. අපි අද කන්න එහාට යමු.\\" හිවලා සතුටින් උඩ පනිමින් පැවසුවා. බූරුවා ත් එකහෙලාම ඊට එකඟ වුණා.ඔන්න ඉතින් දෙන්නත් එක්කම ඒ ඉසව්වට ගිහින්, හොඳට බඩ කට පිරෙන්නම කෑවා. බොහොම මහන්සි වී සිටි බූරුවා ට මේ ආහාර වේල නිසා හිත සතුටින් ඔද්දල් වුණා.\\"යාළුවේ.. !! අපි අද දවස සමරන්න ඕනා. අපි හයියෙන් සින්දු කියමු ගමටම ඇහෙන්න.\\" මෝඩ බූරුවා හිවලාට යෝජනා කළා. \\"මේ සින්දු කියන්න වෙලාවක් නෙමෙයි. සද්ද කලොත් අපි දෙන්නා හොරා කන බව අහු වෙනවා.ඒ නිසා සද්ද කරන්නේ නැතුව ඉන්න.\\" හිවල් හාමි සැර කළා. නමුත් බූරුවා ට තරහා ගියා. බූරුවා ට ඕන වුණේ, කොහොමහරි ම සින්දු කියන්න. ඉතින් බූරුවා හිවලා සමඟ තර්ක කර, හිවලා ව කෙසේ හෝ සින්දු කීමට කැමති කරවා ගත්තා. නමුත් බූරු හාමිගේ මේ මෝඩ වැඩේ, දෙදෙනාටම විනාශය ගෙනෙන බවත්, කොතරම් වෙර දැරුව ද, බූරු හාමි ව කැමති කර ගත නොහැකි බවත් තේරුම් ගත් හිවලා,\\"බූරු හාමි සින්දු කියන්න. මන් වැට ලඟට ගිහින් බලන්නම් කව්රුහරි එනවා ද කියලා\\" බූරුවා ට පැවසුවා. බූරුවා ද ඊට එකඟ වුණා. ලද අවස්ථාවෙන් ප්‍රයෝජන ගත්, හිවලා වැට ලඟට ගොස්, කැලයට පැන දිව්වා. නමුත් බූරුවා ශබ්ධ නඟා සින්දු කියන්න ගත්තා. ටික වෙලාවකින්, අයිතිකරුවන් හා අසල්වාසීන් අවධි වුණා. බූරුවාට ගල් මුල් ප්‍රහාර එල්ල කර, පන්නා දැමුවා.","answer":"බූරුවාගේ මෝඩකම"},{"question":"A esquistossomose (barriga-dʼágua) caracteriza-se pela inflamação do fígado e do baço causada pelo verme Schistosoma mansoni (esquistossomo). O contágio ocorre depois que larvas do verme são liberadas na água pelo caramujo do gênero Biomphalaria, seu hospedeiro intermediário, e penetram na pele humana. Após o diagnóstico, o tratamento tradicional utiliza medicamentos por via oral para matar o parasita dentro do corpo. Uma nova estratégia terapêutica baseia-se na utilização de uma vacina, feita a partir de uma proteína extraída do verme, que induz o organismo humano a produzir anticorpos para combater e prevenir a doença.Uma vantagem da vacina em relação ao tratamento tradicional é que ela poderá:a) impedir a penetração do parasita pela pele.b) eliminar o caramujo para que não haja contágio.c) impedir o acesso do esquistossomo especificamente para o fígado.d) eliminar o esquistossomo antes que ocorra contato com o organismo.e) eliminar o esquistossomo dentro do organismo antes da manifestação de sintomas.","answer":"A resposta correcta é a alternativa: e) eliminar o esquistossomo dentro do organismo antes da manifestação de sintomas."},{"question":"Peux-tu écrire une nécrologie de Jimmy Buffet qui a mourir le 1er septembre 2023 ?","answer":"Voila un L'auteur-compositeur-interprète américain Jimmy Buffett, connu pour sa chanson « Margaritaville » et pour ses succès en affaires, est mort hier à 76 ans, selon son attaché de presse.« Jimmy s'est éteint paisiblement dans la nuit du 1er septembre, entouré de sa famille, de ses amis, de sa musique et de ses chiens » peut-on lire dans un communiqué publiés sur le site officiel du chanteur, qui ne précise pas l’endroit ni la cause de son décès.En mai dernier, Jimmy Buffett avait été contraint de reporter des concerts prévus en raison d'une maladie. À cette époque, il avait partagé sur les médias sociaux qu'il avait été hospitalisé, sans fournir de détails supplémentaires.Au cours de sa carrière, il a apporté sa contribution à la création de plus de 50 albums, généralement en collaboration avec son groupe, le Coral Reefer Band. Son talent lui a valu deux nominations aux Grammy Awards, ainsi que deux distinctions aux Academy of Country Music Awards et un prix du Country Music Association.Par la suite, Jimmy Buffett a réussi à investir efficacement les revenus issus de son travail artistique, ce qui l'avait conduit à devenir milliardaire. Il possédait notamment un restaurant et un casino à Las Vegas, un casino dans le Mississippi et un hôtel à Pensacola Beach."},{"question":"\\"Адам чакырса барбайм деген ...\\"  деген макал-лакапты улантып берчи?","answer":"Сиз суранган макал-лакап мындай болушу мүмкүн: \\"Адам чакырса барбайм деген, аш чакырса калбайм дейт.\\""},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki ini: Siapa yang berperang di udara?","answer":"Jawapannya lalah tentera udara."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe zorofirarazana?","answer":"Ny zoro eo avaratra-atsinanana eo amin' ny trano na ny tanàna, atao hoe zoron' Alahamady, no zoro atokana ho an' ny razana, atao hoe zorofirarazana na zoro firarazana. Zoro saro-pady sy masina indrindra ny Alahamady satria eo no itodihana raha mivavaka amin' Andriananahary sy ny razana ary eo no apetraka ireo zava-masina rehetra."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Kelebihan Amalan Gotong-Royong kepada Masyarakat.","answer":"Gotong-royong merupakan tradisi turun-temurun yang diamalkan oleh masyarakat terdahulu. Amalan ini lazimnya dibuat untuk menjalankan majlis seperti kenduri perkahwinan atau majlis keramaian yang melibatkan komuniti setempat. Namun, dalam meniti arus kemodenan hari ini, amalan gotong royong semakin dilupakan oleh masyarakat konvensional di mana pelbagai manfaat yang mampu diperoleh menjadi kerugian. Tidak dinafikan, perkembangan corak kehidupan masyarakat masa kini lebih ke arah menjana pendapatan tetapi ia tidak menghalang kita untuk tetap mengamalkan gotong-royong di peringkat kecil seperti di taman perumahan dan blok pangsapuri yang kita huni. Peribahasa Melayu berkata, tak basah dek hujan, tak lekang dek panas yang bermaksud warisan tradisi kita seharusnya sentiasa relevan dan diingati oleh masyarakat kita. Oleh hal yang demikian, penting untuk kita mengenali kelebihan amalan bergotong-royong dalam masyarakat.Antara manfaat prima yang akan diperoleh apabila kita bergotong-royong adalah ia dapat memupuk semangat perpaduan antara satu sama lain. Umum sedia maklum, Malaysia merupakan negara yang unik di mana pelbagai kaum, bangsa dan agama duduk di bawah satu negara sejak mencapai kemerdekaan. Kemajmukan masyarakat ini perlu diperkukuh dari semasa ke semasa kerana terdapat segelintir daripadanya yang cuba menjadikan perbezaan perkauman dan sebagainya sebagai satu isu tetapi disebaliknya hanya ingin mendapatkan kepentingan diri. Dengan melibatkan diri dalam aktiviti gotong-royong, kita dapat mengenali jiran tetangga kita dengan lebih baik. Hubungan silaturahim akan terjalin di samping bersama-sama menyiapkan tugasan yang telah diberikan. Persis lagu nukilan artis tempatan, ikan di laut, asam di darat, dalam periuk bikin muafakat. Intihannya, bergotong-royong dapat mengukuhkan nilai perpaduan antara masyarakat supaya kesejahteraan dan keamanan yang kita kecapi hari ini berkekalan sampai bila-bila.Di samping itu, amalan bergotong-royong memberikan kelebihan kepada setiap ahli masyarakat kerana ia akan memudahkan tugasan atau objektif yang ingin dicapai. Sebagai contoh, aktiviti gotong-royong dianjurkan oleh Pihak Berkuasa Tempatan untuk membersihkan kawasan persekitaran dewan serbaguna komuniti setempat. Jika setiap diantara ahli komuniti terbabit melibatkan diri bersama-sama melakukan aktiviti pembersihan seperti mengutip sampah dan menyapu dedaun kering, ia pasti dapat diselesaikan dalam masa yang singkat. Maka, secara tidak langsung kita dapat meluangkan masa yang lebih untuk melakukan aktiviti bermanfaat yang lain. Jika dipandang daripada sudut yang lain, kita juga dapat menjimatkan kos perbelanjaan yang digunakan untuk menyelenggara kebersihan kemudahan awam. Ibarat sambil menyelam minum air. Peruntukan yang dijimatkan dapat disalurkan ke arah yang lebih baik seperti pembinaan lorong berbasikal di kawasan tertentu dan juga kemudahan gimnasium di pasang di taman rekreasi untuk penggunaan awam. Kesannya, pelbagai kerja dan manfaat lain yang akan kita peroleh sekiranya sentiasa mengamalkan aktiviti bergotong-royong.Pada masa yang sama, kebersihan kawasan persekitaran dapat dijamin jika kita kerap menjalankan aktiviti gotong-royong. Endemik denggi semakin hari semakin merunsing fikiran dan ketenteraman masyarakat kita. Nyamuk aedes yang membawa penyakit denggi lazimnya membiak di kawasan takungan air yang lama dan tidak terusik. Dengan adanya aktiviti bergotong-royong, kita dapat bersama-sama pihak berkuasa dalam membanteras pembiakan nyamuk-nyamuk yang menyebabkan berlakunya penularan wabak denggi. Setiap di antara kita perlu sedar bahawa tanggungjawab menjaga kebersihan adalah tanggungjawab bersama. Janganlah kita bersikap seperti sudah terhantuk baru terngadah di mana apabila sesuatu perkara itu menimpa kita barulah timbul kesedaran untuk melakukan sesuatu tindakan. Justeru, setiap komuniti atau organisasi seperti Rukun Tetangga seharusnya menganjurkan aktiviti gotong-royong di kawasan masing-masing sebagai langkah mengawal dan membanteras segala bentuk ancaman kesihatan kepada masyarakat. Sesungguhnya, mencegah sesuatu perkara adalah lebih baik daripada merawat perkara tersebut.Melalui kegiatan yang mulia ini, kita juga dapat mewujudkan kawasan persekitaran yang indah, kemas dan teratur. Rumahku syurgaku merupakan satu perumpamaan yang menunjukkan bahawa rumah adalah tempat dimana segala perkara yang bermakna berlaku dan memberi memori yang indah buat kita yang mendiaminya. Sejajar dengan itu, kita seharusnya berusaha sebaik mungkin untuk memelihara kebersihan dan keindahan kawasan persekitarannya dengan mengajak jiran tetangga untuk bergotong-royong. Rumah merupakan keperluan asas setiap manusia dan sudah pasti bagi menjamin keindahan dalam hidup yang kita jalani setiap hari hendaklah bermula daripada rumah kita. Kaajian menyatakan bahawa kejiranan yang berada dalam keadaan bersih, kemas dan teratur melahirkan komuniti yang bahagia dan sejahtera. Tambahan pula, kita sebagai penghuni kediaman akan berasa lebih selamat untuk kekal menetap di kawasan tersebut kerana jiran tetangga kita mempunyai kesedaran atas tanggungjawab yang sama iaitu menjamin kesejahteraan semua. Natijahnya, bergotong-royong dapat memperindahkan lagi kawasan persekitaran kita kerana pemandangan yang indah melahirkan sifat bahagia dan tenteram.Secara tuntas, amalan bergotong-royong sudah semsetinya akan memberikan pelbagai kelebihan kepada masyarakat yang menyertainya dengan aktif. Amalan tradisi nenek dan moyang kita pastinya memeberi seribu satu manfaat kepada kita secara umumnya. Kalau tidak, mengapa mereka mengamalkan pada ketika dahulu. Kini ia terletak kepada kesedaran setiap individu sama ada untuk melibatkan diri dalam aktiviti komuniti atau bersikap endah tak endah. Kita telah simpulkan bahawa dengan aktiviti bergotong-royong yang melibatkan setiap ahli komuniti dapat menjadi agen penyatu antara satu sama lain di samping faedah-faedah lain. Saranan dan galakan daripada pihak seperti Kementerian Wanita, Keluarga dan Masyarakat seharusnya lebih giat dan menggunakan semua media yang menjadi sasluran informasi masyarakat masa kini. Semoga Masayarakat yang madani dan inteligensia dapat dilahirkan hasil daripada penglibatan dalam aktiviti gotong royong dalam membantu meringankan ujian atau musibah yang melanda negara kita. Bak kata pepatah ke bukit sama didaki, ke lurah sama dituruni."},{"question":"Mickey Mouse almost went by a different name. What was it?","answer":"Mortimer Mouse is the name Mickey Mouse almost went by. "},{"question":"Wacece mace ta farko da ta fara tuka mota a Najeriya?","answer":"Funmilayo Ransome-Kuti ce ta fara tuka mota a Najeriya."},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.\\"ගියොත් ආයෙත් නොයෙයි\\"","answer":"\\"ගියොත් ආයෙත් නොයෙයි\\" යන තේරවිල්ලේ විසඳුම වයස වේ."},{"question":"Araka ity lahatsoratra manaraka ity, iza no firenena mpifanolo-bodirindrina amin’i Madagasikara?Nosy mitoka-monina ara-jeografika i Madagasikara, tsy mizara sisin-tany amin'ny firenena hafa. Voahodidin'ny Ranomasimbe Indianina izy io.","answer":"Tsy manana mpifanolo-bodirindrina aminy i Madagasikara ary voahodidin’ny ranomasimbe Indianina."},{"question":" Yaya sunan yakin da musulmai suka yaki yahudawa a cikinsa?","answer":"(a) Uhud (b) Khaibar (c) Zatur Riqa'i"},{"question":"කෙළ යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කෙළ හෙවත් ඛෙටය ක්‍ෂීරපායීන්ගේ ඛේට ග්‍රන්ථි තුල නිපදවා ජලය සහ වෙනත් සංඝටක සහිත දියරයකි."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : నేడు వరిని ఏ విధంగా సేద్యం చేస్తున్నారు?","answer":"నేడు వరిని క్రింది విధంగా సేద్యం చేస్తున్నారు.మొదటగా భూమిని చదును చేసి, గట్లు కడతారు.తర్వాత నీరు పెట్టి, దమ్ము చేస్తారు. (మెత్తగా చేస్తారు)తర్వాత నాట్లు వేస్తారు (కొన్ని ప్రాంతాలలో వెద పెట్టడం జరుగుతుంది)తర్వాత కలుపు తీయటం, పంటకు అవసరమైన ఎరువులు వేయటం జరుగుతుంది.అవసరమనుకుంటే పురుగు మందులు చల్లటం జరుగుతుంది.తర్వాత వరి కంకులు రావడం జరుగుతుంది. కంకులు ముదిరిన తర్వాత పొలంలోని నీరు తీసేస్తారు.తర్వాత వరికోతలు చేపట్టి, కుప్ప పోస్తారు. తర్వాత నూర్పిడి చేస్తారు.తూర్పార బట్టి వడ్లను వేరు చేస్తారు. (కొన్ని ప్రాంతాలలో వరికోత యంత్రం ద్వారానే ఇవన్నీ చేస్తున్నారు.)"},{"question":"வினா:ரிச்சர்ட் டாக்கின்சு மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"விடை:இந்த உலகில் உண்மையான கவிதைகள் இருக்கின்றன. ஆனால் அறிவியலோ உண்மைகளின் கவிதைகள்."},{"question":"Que língua é falada no país Colômbia?","answer":"A língua oficial é o espanhol."},{"question":"సమస్యలను చూసి భయపడేవారికి ధైర్యాన్ని కలిగించే సూక్తులను రాయండి.","answer":"భయపడకు నేస్తం. ఉంటుంది ఆదుకొనే హస్తం.సమస్యల వల్ల కష్టాలు రావు.కష్టాలే ఉంటాయనుకొంటే సమస్యలు పెరుగుతాయి.ప్రతి సమస్యనూ కాలం పరిష్కరిస్తుంది.సమస్యలు ఏర్పడినపుడే బుర్ర చురుకుగా పనిచేస్తుంది.సమస్యలు లేని జీవితం పందిరి లేని పాదు వంటిది.సమస్యలు మనుషులకు కాక మానులకొస్తాయా ?సాధన చేస్తే సాధ్యం కానిది లేదు.ప్రయత్నిస్తే పరమాత్మైనా కనిపిస్తాడు.ధైర్యమే విజయం."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe rahona?","answer":"Ny rahona dia vongan-drano manana endrika rivotra, izay afaka mitete, na koa kristaly ranomandry mihantona ao amin'ny atmosfera."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Tối 31-7, một nguồn tin của Báo Người Lao Động xác nhận luật sư Trịnh Văn Hoan (SN 1981, quê Châu Thành, Tiền Giang) đang cấp cứu tại Bệnh viện Nhân dân Gia Định trong tình trạng hôn mê sâu. Luật sư Trịnh Văn Hoan thuộc Đoàn Luật sư TP HCM và có văn phòng tại xã Bình Hưng, huyện Bình Chánh, TP HCM. Chiều cùng ngày, luật sư Trịnh Văn Hoan được đưa vào Bệnh viện Quân dân y miền Đông (TP Thủ Đức, TP HCM) cấp cứu trong tình trạng bị chém trọng thương, mất nhiều máu, hôn mê sâu. Lúc này, luật sư Trịnh Văn Hoan đang trong tình trạng nguy kịch nên ê kíp bác sĩ đã đặt nội khí quản và đến gần 22 giờ khi bệnh nhân có mạch trở lại đã được chuyển đến Bệnh viện Nhân dân Gia Định tiếp tục cấp cứu, điều trị. Hiện luật sư Trịnh Văn Hoan đang được theo dõi sát sao tại Bệnh viện Nhân dân Gia Định trong tình trạng nguy kịch. Bệnh viện Nhân dân Gia Định đã bật quy trình báo động đỏ để cấp cứu bệnh nhân. Luật sư Nguyễn Văn Trung (Chủ nhiệm Đoàn Luật sư TP HCM) cho biết đã nắm thông tin luật sư Trịnh Văn Hoan đang được cấp cứu và đang phối hợp sát sao với các cơ quan chức năng làm rõ vụ việc.","answer":"Một luật sư thuộc Đoàn Luật sư TP HCM bị chém hôn mê sâu"},{"question":"Berikan maklumat tentang buku yang bertajuk Himpunan 60 Kisah Lucu.","answer":"Penulis: Abdul Wahab Paloh NyiorMuka surat: 168 ISBN: 978-983-097-456-9Kod: GB0270Harga: RM 10.00Sinopsis:Himpunan 60 Kisah Lucu ini menceritakan himpunan kisah pelik Juha. Semua kisah ini berkait rapat dengan seluruh aspek kehidupan manusia. Antaranya ialah kisah tentang orang kaya dan miskin, tentang orang pemurah dan bakhil, tentang wanita dan kanak-kanak, tentang pemuda dan orang tua, juga kisah tentang penjual dan pembeli. Semua orang yang membaca kisah-kisah Juha ini pasti akan berasa lapang dan gembira."},{"question":"Iza no heverina ho \\"King of Rock 'n' Roll\\"?","answer":"Elvis Presley dia antsoina matetika hoe \\"King of Rock 'n' Roll.\\" Manana fiantraikany lehibe amin'ny karazana mozika izy ary malaza amin'ny hira toy ny \\"Heartbreak Hotel\\" sy \\"Hound Dog.\\""},{"question":"Quem é o do signo de Leão?","answer":"Quem nasceu entre 22 de julho (22/07) e 22 de agosto (22/08)."},{"question":"ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਕਿਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਧਾਰਨਾ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਸੰਰਚਨਾ ਇੱਕ ਸਥਾਈ ਧਾਰਨਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Qual destas obras arquitetônicas brasileiras é uma das Sete Maravilhas do Mundo Moderno?a) Elevador Lacerdab) Cristo Redentorc) Estação da Luzd) One Towere) Palácio da Alvorada","answer":"Alternativa b: Cristo Redentor.Dentre 200 monumentos inscritos por vários países, o Cristo foi escolhido como uma das Sete Maravilhas do Mundo Moderno."},{"question":"Kung mayroong tatlong tasa ng asukal at kinuha ka ng isa, ilan ang mayroon ka?","answer":"Isa, yung kinuha mo."},{"question":"ኢትዮጵያ በአድዋ ጦርነት ያሸነፈችው ማንን ነበር?","answer":"መጋቢት 1 ቀን 1896 በተደረገው የአድዋ ጦርነት በአፄ ምኒልክ የሚመራው የኢትዮጵያ ጦር የኢጣሊያ ወራሪ ጦርን በትግራይ ጠቅላይ ግዛት አድዋ ከተማ አቅራቢያ ድል አድርጓል። ድሉ በቅኝ ግዛት ዘመን በአፍሪካ ሀይሎች የአውሮፓ ሃይል የመጀመርያው አስከፊ ሽንፈት በመሆኑ በኢትዮጵያ እና በአፍሪካ ታሪክ ውስጥ ጉልህ ስፍራ ያለው ክስተት ነበር።"},{"question":"این عبارت را کامل کنید: \\"جنگ مغول-کین میان سالهای ۱۲۱۱–۱۲۳۴ میلادی مابین امپراتوری مغول و مردم جورجی در شمال چین روی داد و به مدت ۲۳ سال ادامه داشت و عاقبت ...\\"","answer":" به سقوط سلسله کین به دست مغول انجامید. همچنین، با این پیروزی دامنه متصرفات مغولان تمام شمال چین را دربر گرفت."},{"question":"ඉන්දියාවේ ජාතික ගංගාව නම් කරන්න.","answer":" ගංගා නම් ගංගාව"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe motera hybrid?","answer":"Ny motera hybrid dia manambatra ny motera lasantsy na gazoala miaraka amin'ny motera elektrika mba hanatsarana ny fahombiazan'ny solika."},{"question":"nsomba ya chambo yomwe imapezeka mu nyaja ya Malawi","answer":"Chambo cha ku Malawi ndi mtundu wa nsomba zomwe zimapezeka ku Nyanja ya Malawi yomwe imadziwikanso kuti Nyanja ya Nyasa. Nsombazi zili m'banja la Tilapia."},{"question":"Na frase a seguir substitua os animais por frutas:O macaco estava andando pela selva quando encontrou com a girafa. Nesse encontro a girafa contou para o macaco que o jacaré estava precisando de uma ajuda. O macaco então foi para o rio, casa do jacaré, para ajudá-lo. Ao chegar lá o macaco perecebeu que o jacaré estava com dificuldade para retirar as folhas do rio que estavam sujando sua residência. Dessa forma, o macaco retirou algumas folhas do rio para ajudar o jacaré.","answer":"O morango estava andando pela selva quando encontrou com a banana. Nesse encontro a banana contou para o morango que o acabate estava precisando de uma ajuda. O morango então foi para o rio, casa do abacate , para ajudá-lo. Ao chegar lá o morango perecebeu que o abacate estava com dificuldade para retirar as folhas do rio que estavam sujando sua residência. Dessa forma, o morango retirou algumas folhas do rio para ajudar o abacate."},{"question":"பின்வரும் சொற்றொடரை முடிக்கவும்:  இருப்பினும்","answer":"கொரியப் போரின்போது தென் கொரியத் திரைப்படத்துறை பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. 1950 முதல் 1953 வரை 14 படங்கள் மட்டுமே தயாரிக்கப்பட்டன. 1953ல் நடந்த கொரிய ஆயுத போரை தொடர்ந்து தென் கொரிய அதிபர் சிங்மேன் ரீ என்பவர் திரைப்படத்துறையை ஊக்கிவிக்கும் நோக்கத்துடன் வரிவிதிப்பில் இருந்து விலக்கு அளித்து திரைப்படத் துறையை புத்துயிர் பெற முயற்சித்தார். மேலும் தென் கொரிய திரைப்படத் தயாரிப்பாளர்களுக்கு அதிகமான திரைப்படங்களைத் தயாரிக்கத் தேவையான உபகரணங்கள் மற்றும் தொழில்நுட்பங்களை வழங்கினார்."},{"question":"පීතෘ ඝාතක චෝදනාවෙන් පීඩාවට පත්වූ සීතාවක රාජසිංහ රජු වෙනුවෙන් , අරිට්ඨ කීවෙණ්ඩු බමුණා විසින් සිදුකරන ලද පූජාව ( යාගය ) කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ගංගා රෝහණ පූජාව .( ගඟ මැද සැදූ වේදිකාවක් මත සිට , සතුන් දහසක් මරා දෙනු ලැබූ බිලි පූජාවකි )"},{"question":"어떤 요소가 거래에서 승자 입찰자에게 약간의 정체성과 권력을 유지하도록 허용했습니까? 위 질문을 고려하여 대답을 포함한 문맥을 작성하시오. 문맥은 1~20개의 문장이 될 수 있습니다. 배경: ","answer":"UPT의 회장이었던 레너드 골든슨은 1951년 UPT가 ABC를 인수할 것을 제안하면서 노블에 접근했습니다다. 노블은 CBS의 창립자 윌리엄 S. 페일리 (William S. Paley) 의 제안을 포함하여 다른 제안을 받았지만, CBS와의 합병은 그 네트워크가 적어도 뉴욕시와 로스앤젤레스 방송국을 판매하도록 강요했을 것입니다. 골든슨과 노블은 1951년 늦은 봄에 UPT가 ABC를 인수하고 회사의 자회사로 전환하여 경영에 자율성을 유지할 것이라는 잠정적인 합의에 도달했습니다. 1951 년 6 월 6 일, 잠정 협약 은 UPT 의 이사회 에서 승인 되었습니다. 그러나 이 거래는 텔레비전 네트워크의 존재와 최근 파라마운트와 UPT의 분리 때문에 FCC의 승인을 받아야했습니다. 파라마운트 픽처스는 이미 듀몬트 텔레비전 네트워크의 주주였기 때문에, FCC는 파라마운트가 유나이티드 파라마운트 시어터스에서 정말로 분리되었는지, 그리고 그것이 반독점법을 위반했는지 확인하기 위해 일련의 청문회를 실시했습니다."},{"question":"Joxeel péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Sëriñ Maamun Buso yilimaan i jumaay Tùubaa, tay daf a waar (xutba) mbooloo mi ci araab tekki ko ci wolof, te li nu baaxoowoon gìs ci moom moo'y, araab rekk la ko daa def.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Sëriñ Maamun Buso yilimaan i jumaay Tùubaa, tay daf a waar (xutba) mbooloo mi ci araab tekki ko ci wolof, te li nu baaxoowoon gìs ci moom moo'y, araab rekk la ko daa def.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Sëriñ: PROPNMaamun: PROPNBuso: PROPNyilimaan: NOUNi: ADPjumaay: NOUNTùubaa: PROPN,: PUNCTtay: ADVdaf: AUXa: AUXwaar: VERB(: PUNCTxutba: VERB): PUNCTmbooloo: NOUNmi: DETci: ADParaab: NOUNtekki: VERBko: PRONci: ADPwolof: NOUN,: PUNCTte: CCONJli: PRONnu: PRONbaaxoowoon: VERBgìs: VERBci: ADPmoom: PRONmu: PRONa: AUX'y: AUX,: PUNCTaraab: NOUNrekk: ADVla: AUXko: PRONdaa: AUXdef: VERB.: PUNCT"},{"question":"લોથલ વિશે જણાવો","answer":"ભારત દેશના પશ્ચિમ ભાગમાં આવેલા ગુજરાત રાજ્યના જુના પાટનગર અમદાવાદથી દક્ષિણ-પશ્વિમે ૮૦ કિલોમીટર જેટલા અંતરે અમદાવાદ જિલ્લામાં આવેલા ભાલ વિસ્તારમાં આવેલા લોથલની શોધ ઇ. સ. ૧૯૫૪ ના નવેમ્બર માસમાં કરવામાં આવી હતી. લોથલ શબ્દનો અર્થ મૃત્યુ પામેલા થાય છે. લોથલ કેન્દ્ર સરકાર દ્રારા રક્ષિત અને રાષ્ટ્રીય મહત્વ ધરાવતી પ્રાચીન જગ્યા છે. લોથલ ખૂબજ જૂની સંસ્કૃતિનું સ્થળ મનાય છે. જેનો સમય ઇ.સ.પૂર્વે ૨૪૫૦થી ૧૯૦૦ સુધીનો માનવામાં આવે છે. માનવામાં આવે છે કે લોથલમાં માનવ વસ્તીનો પહેલવહેલો વસવાટ થયો હતો. તેમજ ઇ.સ. પૂર્વે ૨૩૫૦માં કુદરતી હોનારતને કારણે તમામ ઘરો આવાસો નાશ પામ્યા. બાદમાં ફરી એકવાર ઊંચા ટેકરા પર નગરનું આયોજન કરવામાં આવ્યું. લોથલમાં સુઆયોજિત નગર-વ્યવસ્થા હતી તે અહીંથી મળેલા વિવિધ અવશેષો જોઇ માલુમ પડે છે. તે સમયે મકાનો પણ વિશાળ હતા. સુવ્યવસ્થિત બજારો, રસ્તાઓ, ગટર વ્યવસ્થા, તે સમયના લોકોની સુઝબુઝનો પરિચય આપે છે. ખાસ કરીને અહીંના મકાનો ભઠ્ઠીમાં પકવેલી ઈંટોમાંથી બનાવવામાં આવ્યા હતા.લોથલનું યુનેસ્કો વર્લ્ડ હેરિટેજ યાદીમાં નામાંકન કરવામાં આવ્યું છે."},{"question":"Qual dos livros de Game of Thrones levou mais tempo para George R.R. Martin escrever?","answer":"A Dance with Dragons"},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा सोप्या शब्दात अर्थ सांगा  अर्थी दान महापुण्य","answer":"गरजू माणसाला दान दिल्यामुळे पुण्य मिळते."},{"question":"Waa maxay Kombiyuutar?","answer":"Kombiyuutarku waa aalad ku shaqeysa koronto (elektroonik) si gaar ahna u qabata xogta lagu kaydiyo, marka loo baahdana si qeexan uga jawaabta."},{"question":"ਗੁਰੂ ਹਰਿਗੋਬਿੰਦ ਜੀ ਨੂੰ “ਬੰਦੀ ਛੋੜ ਬਾਬਾ’ ਦੀ ਉਪਾਧੀ ਕਿਉਂ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋਈ ?","answer":"52 ਕੈਦ ਰਾਜਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਛੁਡਾਉਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਗੁਰੂ ਹਰਿਗੋਬਿੰਦ ਜੀ ਨੂੰ “ਬੰਦੀ ਛੋੜ ਬਾਬਾ’ ਦੀ ਉਪਾਧੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਹੋਈ ।"},{"question":"திரைப்படத்துறை என்பது ஆயிரம் பேரைக் காப்பாற்றும் தொழிலா? அல்லது கலைகளின் சங்கமமா? உங்கள் பார்வையைக் கட்டுரையாக்குக.","answer":"திரைப்படத்துறை – ஒரு கலை:புதுமை வாழ்வில் எத்தனையோ அற்புதங்களைக் கண்டு மகிழ்கிறோம். நாடகத்தின் மறுமலர்ச்சியாக, மக்களை மயக்கும் கலையாக திரைப்படத்துறை தவிர்க்கமுடியாத ஒன்றாகத் திகழ்ந்து வருகிறது. இந்தத் துறை வளர்ச்சியின் பின்னால் எத்தனைத் துறைகள் அடங்கியிருப்பது பற்றி யாரும் திரும்பிப் பார்ப்பது கிடையாது.சான்றாக, கதை, கதை-உணர்த்தும் நீதி, எண்ணத்தை ஈர்க்கும் வசனம், கதாநாயகன், நாயகிகள் தேர்வு, ஆடை அலங்காரம், இடங்கள் தேர்வு, புகைப்படக் கருவி, நடனக் குழுக்கள் என்று பட்டியல் நீண்டுகொண்டே இருக்கும். இதற்குள் எத்தனையோ நிகழ்வுகள் உள்ளன.எல்லாக் கலைஞர்களும் அருகி வரும் நிலையில் இத்துறையின் வளர்ச்சி உயர்ந்த நிலையில் உள்ளது. ஒரு திரைப்படம் எடுக்க எத்தனை கோடிகள், எவ்வளவு செலவீனங்கள் என வளர்ந்து கொண்டே போகும். இதற்கு இடையில் குடும்பப் படங்கள், அரசியல் படங்கள், பக்திப் படங்கள் என்றும் பற்பல பிரிவுகளில் எடுக்கப்படுகின்றன.இவற்றிற்கும் மேலாக ஒவ்வொரு பிரிவிலும் விற்பன்னர்கள் தேவைப்படுகிறார்கள். அதற்கென்று திரைப்படத்துறை சார்ந்த படிப்புகளும் உருவாகி உள்ளன. இத்துறையில் முழு ஈடுபாடு கொண்டால்தான் சிறக்கும்.இதைப்பலகலைகளின்சங்கமம்என்றே கூறலாம். நடிகர்களின்நடிப்புக்கலை,ஒப்பனைக்கலை, வசனம் (பேச்சுக்கலை), (கேமரா) படமெடுப்பதில் கலையம்சம், ஒலிப்பதிவுக்கலை, ஒளிப்பதிவுக் குழு நடனக் கலை என ஒட்டுமொத்த கலைஞர்களால் மட்டும்தான் இது நடந்தேறி வருகிறது.கணினி சம்பந்தப்பட்ட ஒத்துழைப்புகளாலும் உதவியாலும் இத்துறை மெருகூட்டப்படுகிறது. கண்டுபிடிப்புகள் அதிகமானாலும் கலையம்சம் நிறைந்தது திரைப்படத்துறையே. எனவே கலைகளின் சங்கமம் என்பது பொருத்தமானதே.திரைப்படத்துறை ஆயிரம் பேரையல்ல, ஆயிரம் குடும்பங்களை வாழவைக்கிறது. கேளிக்கைகள் நிறைந்த இவ்வுலகில் திரைப்படத்துறைக்கு மட்டும் கலைஞர்கள், தொழில்நுட்ப 1121 வல்லுநர்கள், ஒப்பனைக்காரர்கள், ஆடை அலங்கார வல்லுநர்கள், ஆண்-பெண் நடனக் குழுக்கள், சண்டைக் காட்சிகளில் பங்குபெற எதிர்த்தலைவன் மற்றும் துணைவர்கள், உதவியாளர்கள் என எத்தனையோ ஆட்கள் இதை நம்பி இருக்கிறார்கள்.திரைப்படத்துறையில் மட்டும் கால் வைத்து விட்டால் அவர்களுக்கு மற்ற தொழில் மறந்துவிடுகிறது. எல்லாம் இருந்தவர்கள் ஏன் இத்துறைக்கு வருகிறார்கள் என்று தெரிவதில்லை. சென்னை-கோடம்பாக்கத்தில் கலைத்துறை சார்ந்த குடும்பங்கள் ஆயிரக்கணக்கில் இதை நம்பியே வாழ்ந்து வருகின்றன.“ஆங்கோர் ஏழைக்கு எழுத்தறிவித்தல் இறைப்பணி” என்பது போல அனைத்துக் கலைஞர்களுக்கும் வாழ்க்கையும் வாய்ப்பும் கொடுக்கும் துறையாக திரைப்படத்துறை திகழ்கிறது. இந்தக் கலையைக் கற்க முடியாது. பயிற்சியால்தான் பெற முடியும். மறவோம் கலைஞர்களை! மதிப்போம் கலைஞர்களை!"},{"question":"Kirjoita seuraava lause omin sanoin: Jos tällä ampuu muukalaista takaraivoon, näkee vain vaaleanpunaista sumua.","answer":"Tällä kun ampuu muukalaista päähän, jäljelle jää vain vaaleanpunaista sumua."},{"question":"📚 Илим жөнүндө макал билесизби?","answer":"Илим башка жугат, хна ташка чыгат.Илим өнөрсүз болбойт, куш канатсыз болбойт.Илим — тозбогон кудук, билбеген киши —дудук.Илимдин падышасы — акыл, сөздүн падышасы — макал.Илимдүү баштайт, илимсиз ээрчийт.Илим—элге, суу — жерге."},{"question":"Quais as consequências para o Brasil decorrentes da crise na Venezuela?a) Sobrecarregamento no sistema público de saúde em Roraimab) Fortalecimento do Mercosulc) Aumento de mão-de-obrad) Crescimento de investimentos estrangeirose) Melhoria nos serviços sociais a fim de atender os imigrantes venezuelanos","answer":"Alternativa a: Sobrecarregamento no sistema público de saúde em Roraima.Além do Amazonas, o estado de Roraima faz fronteira com a Venezuela. É para lá que muitos venezuelanos têm se refugiado.Com isso, a rede pública de saúde fica com um sério problema de superlotação."},{"question":"Wanene gwamnan soja na farko a jihar Kano?","answer":"Sani Bello (an haife shi a ranar 27 ga Nuwamba 1942) ɗan Najeriya ne kuma soja ne wanda ya yi Gwamnan Jihar Kano daga 1975 zuwa 1978."},{"question":"*كم نجمة على علم أستراليا؟","answer":"6 نجوم"},{"question":"¿Qué es la secuencia de Fibonacci?","answer":"La secuencia de Fibonacci es una secuencia en la que se empieza por 0 y 1, y luego cada nuevo número es la suma de los dos últimos números que tenemos. Por ejemplo, los primeros 10 términos de la secuencia serían: 0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21, 34, Podemos ver que 1=0+1, 2=1+1, 3=2+1, 5=3+2, 8=5+3, 13=8+5, 21=13+8, 32=21+12. Entonces, el siguiente número sería 34+21=55.Matemáticamente, podemos decir que esta es una recurrencia lineal de segundo orden f(n), donde f(n) es el n-ésimo número en la sucesión.Obviamente, f(n) = f(n-1) + f(n-2) para cualquier n > 1, y f(0) = 0, f(1) = 1.Existe una fórmula cerrada (no recurrente) para calcular f(n). Es la siguiente:f(n) = ((1+sqrt(5))^n - (1-sqrt(5))^n)/(sqrt(5)*2^n)"},{"question":"Àwọn Àdúgbò Oyé-Èkìtì","answer":"1. Ijisẹ:- Àdúgbò ti a n pen i Ijisẹ ni o fẹ ilu Ọye do lati Ile Ifẹ wa. Wọn pa erin ibi ti ẹrin náà ku si iba ni wọn pe ni atẹba ẹni to pa erin náà ni ọlọta aburo ijise ibi ti wọn pa erin náà si ni wọn pe ni ijisẹ. Ijisẹ lo pa àwọn ara Ọyẹ wa lati ile ifẹ pe wọn ti ri ibi tí wọn magbe. Ijisẹ ni orisu ilu Ọyẹ lati ile-ifẹ wa.2. Ọgbọ mẹta :- Ọ̀nà mẹta ni àwọn ara ọgbọ mẹta ti si wa ki wọn to tẹ̀dó si ilu Ọyẹ.3. Ọmọdọwa:- Ibi jẹ agbegbe ti ọba ilu maa n gbe.4. Ire:- Aburo Oloye ni Àdúgbò to wa ni Iyeni, Ọde ni se idi ti o fi ń de ade ogun5. Ulọdo:- Ibe ni wọn ti se ọdẹ6. Ilẹsẹ:- Àdúgbò yi kọ de igọsi ko si de ilu Ọyẹ wọn wa ni arin meji.7. Ilẹdara:- Orukọ ti àdúgbò yi jẹ wa lati ile-ifẹ wa ni wọn tun jẹ ni ìgba ti wọn de ilu Ọyẹ.8. Odo:- ibi ti àdúgbò yi deto si je egbe odọ.9. Iwaro:- Oni imọlẹ kan ti wọn máa ń jo ni ibẹ ìdí ti wọn fi pe ni ìwarọ ni yẹn.10. Ijagun:- Awọn ti on jagun ni wọn gbe ni àdúgbò yìi.11. Oke-Ọfa:- Apa oke ni àdúgbo naa wa12. Ayegbaju:- Wọn tun pe àdúgbò yi ni odo-oje nitori pe ẹgbẹ odo ni ilu náà wa.13. Ẹgbẹ:- Ọ̀nà mẹta ni àwọn ara ẹgbẹ ti si wa ki wọn to wa si mọ àwọn ara ijisẹ.14. Ijagẹmọ:- Àwọn ara àdúgbò yin i a mọ si ologun tàbí onija láti ìle-ifẹ wa. Igbati wọn de ilu Ọyẹ wọn sit un pe wọn ni ijagẹmọ nitorí ija wọn.15. Ilogbo:- àdúgbo yi jẹ pàtàkì ni ìlú Ọye, Ijalọ po púpọ̀ si arin wọn itorí náà ni wọn ni ọmọ orin yọyọ ilugbo.16. Ilupeju:- Ireko ilu Ọyẹ ni, àwọn ni wọn máa ń sin ọba Ọyẹ wọn máa ń pe jọ si ilu Ọyẹ láti ba ọba ji roro, ìdí ti wọn fi pe wọn ni ilupeju.17. Orisunmíbare:- Wọn jẹ àdúgbò ti o ko owo ati oríṣìíríṣìí dukiya wa si ilu Ọyẹ, àwọn ara Ọyẹ ri pe ọlọrọ ni wọn jẹ ni wọn se pe wọn ni orísunmibare.18. Esọ sin :- àdúgbò yi ti wọn pe ni esọ sin jẹ ara àwọn ti ogun ko wa lati ile- ifẹ.19. Ile ya o :- Ogun ko wọn láti Iyao wa si ìlú Ọyẹ ti wọn wa ya ile gbe ni ilu Ọyẹ ni wọn fi ń pe ni ile-yao.20. Ileesa:- Wọn jẹ àdúgbò to ji náà si ìlú nitorí wọn ko ogùn ba ilu púpọ̀.21. Ilẹmọ:- O wa lati ile-ifẹ wa si ilu Ọyẹ wọn si kin jẹ iyọ ni àdúgbọ̀ yi.22. Ipamọ:- wọn jẹ ọmọ ìya si ilẹmọ, wọn jẹ ara ilẹmọ ìdí ti wọn fi ń pe ni ilẹmọ ni yen.23. Idọfin:- Ọ̀nà mẹrin ni àwọn ara àdúgbò yi ti si wa kì wọn to para po wa si Ijisẹ.24. Irare:- Ilare ni wọn jẹ ni ilẹ-Ifẹ wọn wa ń jẹ́ irare ni ìgbati wọn de ilu Ọyẹ.25. Oke ìyin-Araroni:- Ọ̀nà mẹta ni wọn ti si wa26. Iyeni:- jẹ àdúgbò ti wọn ti jẹ orogun ni ilu Ọyé.27. Asara:- àdúgbò yìí jẹ ibi àwọn ìransẹ ọba ń gbe.28. Oloyagba:- Iya gba ni ogun tí ki wọn wa sí ilu Ọyẹ ni wọn se ń jẹ oloyagbe. 29. Ibẹru:- Ọlota ni aburo Ijise lati ile ifẹ wa nígbati wọn de Ọyẹ iberu ati Ijisẹ wa yapa o sit un jẹ àdúgbò ti o bẹru ogun tàbí ija púpọ̀.30. Imijẹ:- Àdúgbò yii wa láti ilu Itapu iṣẹ ọdẹ ni baba ń la wa n se. Iṣẹ yii lo se wa si ilu Ọyẹ ìdí ti wọn fi tẹ̀dó si ìlú Ọyẹ ni èyí."},{"question":"ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਕਿਹੜੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਪਰੰਪਰਾਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਆਲੋਚਨਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਸੀ?","answer":"ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਵਿਅਕਤੀ ਦੀ ਅਧਿਆਤਮਿਕ ਉੱਨਤੀ ਲਈ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਰਸਮਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਮਹੱਤਵ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਇਸ ਲਈ ਗੁਰੂ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਨੇ ਤਰਕਹੀਣ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਰੀਤੀ-ਰਿਵਾਜਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਰੀਤੀ-ਰਿਵਾਜਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਆਲੋਚਨਾ ਕੀਤੀ। ਗੁਰੂ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਨੇ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਰਸਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਿਖੇਧੀ ਕੀਤੀ, ਉਹ ਸਨ ਵੈਦਿਕ ਸੰਸਕਾਰ, ਯੱਗ, ਮੂਰਤੀ ਪੂਜਾ, ਤੀਰਥ ਯਾਤਰਾਵਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਬੇਕਾਰ ਰਸਮਾਂ। ਗੁਰੂ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਨੇ ਤਪੱਸਵੀ ਯੋਗਿਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਢੰਗ ਨੂੰ ਪਛਾਣਨ ਤੋਂ ਇਨਕਾਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਗੁਰੂ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਨੇ ਸੰਨਿਆਸੀ ਜਾਂ ਯੋਗੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਦੋ ਕਾਰਨਾਂ ਕਰਕੇ ਆਲੋਚਨਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ:ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਸ਼ੁੱਧ ਸ਼ਰਧਾ ਦੀ ਘਾਟਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਜ਼ਿੰਮੇਵਾਰੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਅਣਦੇਖੀ.ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਨੇ ਭਗਤੀ ਦੇ ਵੈਸ਼ਨਵ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਾਰਸ਼ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਅਵਤਾਰਵਾਦ (ਅਵਤਾਰਵਾਦ) ਦੀ ਧਾਰਨਾ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਨਤਾ ਦੇਣ ਤੋਂ ਵੀ ਇਨਕਾਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਗੁਰੂ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਨੇ ਮੁਸਲਮਾਨ ਪਾਦਰੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਸਮਾਜ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਰੀਤਾਂ, ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸਾਂ, ਪਰੰਪਰਾਵਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਗਤੀਵਿਧੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਵੀ ਆਲੋਚਨਾ ਕੀਤੀ।"},{"question":"Şu cümleyi tamamlayın: Haziran 1948'de, Sovyetler Birliği, Müttefik Kuvvetler'i Berlin'den çıkarmak için,","answer":"Şehrin batısındaki tüm su, demiryolu ve otoyol bağlantılarını kapattı. Batı Berlin'i terk etmek ya da tüm malları hava yoluyla tedarik etmek arasında seçim yapmak zorunda kalan batı güçleri, kuşatma altındaki şehre 24 saat boyunca hava yoluyla yaşamsal malzeme taşımalarına başladı. \\"Operasyon Vittles\\" lakabı olan hava köprüsü, tüm zamanların en büyük hava kargo operasyonu oldu. Berlin Hava Köprüsü'nün başlıca iş atı C-54 Skymaster kargo uçağıydı ve Kelly, uçakta kullanılan Pratt ve Whitney R2000 motorlarının onarılması ve yenilenmesi için ülkedeki tek depoydu. 31 Aralık'a kadar, Tedarik Bölümü, hava köprüsü için 1,7 milyon dolar değerinde 1,317 R2000 motoru gönderdi."},{"question":"Wangsulana pitakonan nganggo konteks artikel ing ngisor iki.Topik: Indra penglihatan kucing.Artikel:Kucing duwe penglihatan sing apik banget nalika wengi lan bisa ndeleng ing pepetengan nganggo mung seperenam level cahya sing dibutuhake kanggo penglihatan manungsa. Iki sebagean minangka asil saka mripat kucing sing duwe tapetum lucidum, sing nggambarake cahya sing ngliwati retina bali menyang mripat, saengga nambah sensitivitas mripat kanggo cahya sing surem. Pupil sing gedhe iku adaptasi kanggo cahya sing surem. Kucing domestik duwe pupil sing dipotong, sing ngidini fokus cahya sing padhang tanpa aberasi kromatik. Ing kahanan sing kurang padhang, pupil kucing saya amba nganti nutupi mripaté. Kucing domestik duwe penglihatan warna sing kurang apik lan mung rong jinis sel kerucut, dioptimalake kanggo sensitivitas biru lan ijo kuning; kemampuane mbedakake antarane abang lan ijo diwatesi. Tanggepan kanggo dawa gelombang tengah saka sistem liyane saka sel batang bisa uga amarga jinis kerucut kaping telu. Iki katon minangka adaptasi kanggo tingkat cahya sing kurang tinimbang makili sesanti trichromatic sejati. Kucing uga duwe membran nictitating, saengga bisa kedhip tanpa ngalangi penglihatan.Pitakonan:Pira jumlah level cahaya sing dibutuhake kucing supaya bisa ndeleng ing pepetengan dibandhingake karo manungsa? Wangsulan:","answer":"Kucing bisa ndeleng ing pepetengan nganggo seperenem level cahaya sing dibutuhake kanggo penglihatan manungsa."},{"question":"Sheeg wax ay ayadka dhamantod arkaan balse alle usan arag ? ","answer":"Waaa Alxilmi ."},{"question":"மணியம்மையின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினைத்தரவும்.","answer":"வீட்டில் இருப்பவர்களை முதன் முதலில் நாம் திருத்தி விட்டால் சுலபமாக நாட்டிலும் நம் காரியத்திலும் வெற்றி பெற்றுவிட முடியும்."},{"question":"په HMS بیګل کې د ډاروین سفر څنګه د هغه د تکامل تیورۍ په پراختیا کې مرسته وکړه، او کوم مهم مشاهدې او تجربې د هغه بنسټیز نظریات اغیزمن کړل؟","answer":"په HMS بیګل کې د ډاروین سفر یو بدلون راوړونکی سفر و چې د هغه د تکامل تیورۍ په پراختیا یې خورا اغیزه وکړه. د پنځه کلن سفر په جریان کې، ډاروین په مختلفو براعظمونو کې د مختلفو ډولونو او ایکوسیستمونو پراخه ډولونه ولیدل. د ګالیپاګوس ټاپوګان، په ځانګړې توګه، د ډولونو تنوع او د فینچونو تطابق وړ وړانګو په اړه مهم لیدونه وړاندې کړل. د ډاروین دقیقې مشاهدې، په ځانګړې توګه د ژوندی موجوداتو او د هغوی د چاپیریال ترمنځ د بدلونونو په اړه، د طبیعي انتخاب او د ډولونو د تکامل په اړه د هغه د انقلابي نظریاتو بنسټ جوړ کړ."},{"question":"Se eu recebo R 25 por cada produto vendido e vendo 15 produtos, quanto dinheiro eu ganharei?","answer":"Você ganhará um total de 25 x 15 que é igual a R 375."},{"question":"Kukhona eziphatha izihlangu ezimaqandakawayiba, ezimpevu kanyenezinhlobonhlobo ngokwehlukana kwemibala yezinkomo. Zisuke zidlana imilala kulenkundla okudliselwa kuyona. Izinsizwa zishayane amakhanda bese ziyogezaemfuleni, zibuye sezincokolisana zitshelana ukuthi ngokuzayo kuyokuba omunyeoyobe ezogezwa lapha. Kwakungavamisile ukuthi izinsizwa zibambelane amagqubungemuva kokungcwekisana. Uma ungakaganwa, omama bakubuza njalo ukuthiuyoganwa nini. Naye-ke uManyoba kwakuwumbuzo ayewuphendula zonke izinsukulo. Kwase kuwuye kuphela kubafana owayengakaganwa, kodwa-ke kulokhuwabethembisa ukuthi usezothatha abammele kancane nje. Wayeyishaya induku lomuntu owayekhulumela phansi futhi ehlonipha. Nangalo Khisimuzi wayehlobileemuhle njengawo wonke umfana osekhulile.1. Ucabanga ukuthi yayiyoba njani impilo kaManyoba ukuba waqhubekanokusebenza epulazini? Sekela impendulo yakho ngamaphuzuAMATHATHU.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMATHATHU kwalandelayo:• Wayengeke abe nemali eyanele yokulobola uNtombi, eyokondla umndeniwakhe, ukufundisa izingane zakhe kanye nokuzakhela umuzi wakhe.• Wayezophila ngokuhlukumezeka epulazini kanti nezingane zakhezazingeke zibe nekusasa eliqhakazile.• Wayengeke alithole ithuba lokufunda esikoleni sasebusuku kanyenokufundela ukushayela.• Wayezoba yisehluleki impilo yakhe yonke angakwazi ukuzithuthukisa."},{"question":"What education is required to become a machine learning engineer","answer":"Most machine learning engineer positions require at least a bachelor's degree in computer science, mathematics, or a related field, though many employers prefer a master's degree or Ph.D."},{"question":"బక్సర్ తిరుగుబాటు గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"1764 అక్టోబర్ 17న మీర్ ఖాసిం, అయోధ్య నవాబు, మొగల్ చక్రవర్తి షా ఆలంల కూటమికి, ఆంగ్లేయులకు బక్సార్ వద్ద జరిగిన యుద్ధాన్ని బక్సార్ యుద్ధం అంటారు. ఈ యుద్ధంలో ముగ్గురు పాలకుల కూటమి ఓడిపోయింది. ఈ యుద్ధం భారతదేశంలో ఆంగ్ల సామ్రాజ్య విస్తరణకు తోడ్పడింది."},{"question":"Ibinzana 1: Ngowe - 2005, uKershaw 'Then And Now' wapapasha ingqokelela yezinto zakudala ezineengoma ezintsha. Isivakalisi 2: Ngowe - 2005, uKershaw wakhupha 'Then And Now ', ingqokelela yomsebenzi wakhe wangaphambili kunye neengoma ezine ezintsha. Umbuzo: Ngaba isivakalisi 1 nesivakalisi 2 zithetha into enye? Ewe okanye Hayi?","answer":"Ewe."},{"question":"Was sind die Nachbarländer von Deutschland? Gib mir lediglich die Länder, getrennt mit einem Komma. Die Antwort soll keine weiteren Wörter enthalten.","answer":"Frankreich, Belgien, Niederlande, Luxemburg, Dänemark, Polen, Tschechien, Österreich, Schweiz"},{"question":"Chọn đáp án đúng cho câu hỏi sauTổng (hiệu) nào dưới đây chia hết cho 5?A. 136 + 420B. 621 – 450C. 1 . 2 . 3 . 4 . 5 + 42D. 1 . 2 . 3 . 4 . 5 . 6 – 35 ","answer":"Lời giảiVì 5 chia hết cho 5 nên theo tính chất chia hết của một tích ta có1 . 2 . 3 . 4 . 5 . 6 chia hết cho 5Lại có 35 có chữ số tận cùng là 5 nên 35 chia hết cho 5Do đó theo tính chất chia hết của một hiệu ta có 1 . 2 . 3 . 4 . 5 . 6 – 35 chia hết cho 5. Chọn đáp án D."},{"question":" Sheeg webiga qaarada Asia ugu dheer Iyo Wadanka uu Ku Yaal?","answer":"Waa Webiga La-Yiraahdo Yangesti Wuxuuna Ku Yaalaa Wadanka Shiinaha (China)."},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--हत्तीच्या दाढे मध्ये मिऱ्याचा दाणा","answer":"मोठ्या उपायांची गरज असताना अतिशय छोटे उपाय करावे"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ॥ਬਿਖਿਆ ਬਿਆਪਿਆ ਸਗਲ ਸੰਸਾਰੁ ॥ਬਿਖਿਆ ਲੈ ਡੂਬੀ ਪਰਵਾਰੁ ॥੧॥ਰੇ ਨਰ ਨਾਵ ਚਉੜਿ ਕਤ ਬੋੜੀ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸਿਉ ਤੋੜਿ ਬਿਖਿਆ ਸੰਗਿ ਜੋੜੀ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸੁਰਿ ਨਰ ਦਾਧੇ ਲਾਗੀ ਆਗਿ ॥ਨਿਕਟਿ ਨੀਰੁ ਪਸੁ ਪੀਵਸਿ ਨ ਝਾਗਿ ॥੨॥ਚੇਤਤ ਚੇਤਤ ਨਿਕਸਿਓ ਨੀਰੁ ॥ਸੋ ਜਲੁ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਕਥਤ ਕਬੀਰੁ ॥੩॥੨੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 328 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਭਗਤ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਸਾਰਾ ਜਹਾਨ ਹੀ ਮਾਇਆ (ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ) ਨਾਲ ਨੱਪਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ; ਮਾਇਆ ਸਾਰੇ ਹੀ ਕਟੰੁਬ ਨੂੰ (ਸਾਰੇ ਹੀ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ) ਡੋਬੀ ਬੈਠੀ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ! ਤੂੰ (ਆਪਣੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀ) ਬੇੜੀ ਕਿਉਂ ਰੜੇ ਥਾਂ ਤੇ ਹੀ ਡੋਬ ਲਈ ਹੈ? ਤੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਤੋੜ ਕੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਨਾਲ ਗੰਢੀ ਬੈਠਾ ਹੈਂ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੀ) ਅੱਗ ਲੱਗੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ (ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ) ਦੇਵਤੇ ਤੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸੜ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ।(ਇਸ ਅੱਗ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਾਂਤ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਨਾਮ-ਰੂਪ) ਪਾਣੀ ਭੀ ਨੇੜੇ ਹੀ ਹੈ, ਪਰ (ਇਹ) ਪਸ਼ੂ (ਜੀਵ) ਉੱਦਮ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਪੀਂਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਉਹ ਨਾਮ-ਰੂਪ) ਪਾਣੀ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਹੀ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ) ਪਰਗਟ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ,ਕਬੀਰ ਆਖਦਾ ਹੈ— ਉਹ (ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ-) ਜਲ ਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੀ ਅੱਗ ਉਸੇ ਜਲ ਨਾਲ ਬੁਝ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ) ।੩।੨੪।\\""},{"question":"Buatlah artikel yang singkat dan informatif sebagai jawaban atas pertanyaan berikut.Apakah yang dimaksud dengan birokrasi?Jawaban:","answer":"Jadi arti harfiah birokrasi adalah orang yang bekerja di meja dengan aturan yang ketat. Pada awalnya, birokrasi merupakan lembaga yang dibentuk untuk para pejabat, yang melayani raja atau penguasa bukan untuk melayani kepentingan rakyat. Maka karakter birokrasi terkesan feodal. Istilah birokrasi kerap digunakan untuk menggambarkan organisasi yang kompleks dengan sistem atau proses yang berlapis-lapis dan bersifat hierarki.Istilah ini muncul sejak abad ke-19, seperti yang dilansir dari buku Birokrasi (Kajian Konsep, Teori Menuju Good Governance).Menurut Kamus Besar Bahasa Indonesia (KBBI), birokrasi adalah sistem pemerintahan yang dijalankan oleh pegawai pemerintah karena telah berpegang pada hierarki dan jenjang jabatan. Secara etimologi, birokrasi diambil dari kata bereau dalam bahasa Prancis dan kratos dalam bahasa Yunani. Bureau berarti meja tulis, sedangkan kratos artinya pemerintahan. Maka dapat disimpulkan birokrasi adalah sekumpulan orang yang bekerja di balik meja, baik di perkantoran atau di bidang pemerintahan. Max Weber, ahli politik dan sosiolog asal Jerman mendefinisikan birokrasi adalah suatu bentuk organisasi yang penerapannya berhubungan dengan tujuan yang hendak dicapai. Sementara menurut Fritz Morstein Marx, birokrasi adalah tipe organisasi yang biasa digunakan pemerintahan modern untuk melaksanakan tugas yang sifatnya spesialis dan dilakukan oleh aparatur pemerintah dalam suatu sistem administrasi."},{"question":"د هاضمي سیسټم څنګه د هاضمي انزایمونو خوشې کول تنظیموي، او کوم عوامل پدې پروسه اغیزه کوي؟","answer":"د هاضمي انزایمونو خوشې کول د هورمونل سیګنالونو لخوا تنظیم کیږي. ګیسټرین معده هڅوي چې د معدې جوس خوشې کړي ، پداسې حال کې چې سیکرټین او کولیسیسټوکینین (CCK) په ترتیب سره د ځیګر څخه د پانقراټيک انزایمونو او صفرا خوشې کول تنظیموي. فکتورونه لکه د خواړو ډول او د هاضمې په جریان کې د pH کچه په دې هورمونل سیګنالونو اغیزه کوي."},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: W 1924 podczas igrzysk w Chamonix zajął 18. miejsce w konkursie kombinacji norweskiej, był 20. w zawodach w biegach...","answer":"... narciarskich oraz 22. w skokach narciarskich."},{"question":"এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :১৯৮৭ সালে প্রথম সামরিক জাদুঘরটি প্রতিষ্ঠিত হয় এবং ১৯৯৯ সালে জাদুঘরটি স্থায়ীভাবে বিজয় সরণিতে স্থানান্তর করা হয়। ১৯৭১ সালে মুক্তিযুদ্ধের","answer":"সময় সেনাবাহিনীর কমান্ডারদের ব্যাজ, পোশাক, অস্ত্র, গোলাবারুদ, ক্যানন, এন্টি এয়ারক্রাফ্ট গান এবং যোগাযোগের জন্য ব্যবহৃত বিভিন্ন যানবাহন জাদুঘরটিতে রক্ষিত রয়েছে। মুক্তিযুদ্ধের পর তৎকালীন পাকিস্তান সেনাবাহিনীর কাছ থেকে উদ্ধার হওয়া বিভিন্ন যানবাহন এবং অস্ত্রও এখানে সংরক্ষিত রয়েছে।"},{"question":"Манас эпосу тууралуу кандай маалыматың бар?","answer":"Кыргыз элинин эпикалык көркөм ойлоо аң-сезимин философиялык, эстетикалык, психологиялык, филологиялык- фольклордук жагынан терең жана комплекстүү изилдөө окумуштуулардын кезектеги милдети деп түшүнөм. Анткени, оозеки чыгармачылыктагы көркөм ойлоо аң-сезиминин жалпы көркөмдүк принциптери, маселен синкретизм, индивидуалдуу автордун белгисиздиги, же жоктугу, оозеки формада өнүгүү ж. б. «Манас» эпосуна мүнөздүү болсо дагы, менин терең ишенимимде эпос катарында бул көркөм чыгарма дүйнөлүк эпикалык практикада өтө уникалдуу көрүнүштүн катарына жатат. Бул бөтөнчөлүк баарынан мурда эпостун структуралык негизинде жаткан көркөм ойлоо аң-сезимине байланыштуу. Дал ушул кылымдардан бери өнүгүп-өөрчүп келаткан көркөм ойлоо аң-сезиминин бай жана күчтүү традициясынын негизинде гана Сагымбай Орозбаков, Саякбай Каралаев сыяктуу индивидуалдуу көркөм сүрөткерлер (негизинен «Манас» эпосун кесип кылгандар) өсүп чыгышкан. Тилекке каршы ушундай улуу манасчылардын далайынын аты унутулуп, тарыхтын терең, калың катмарларында калды, айрымдар легенда түрүндө бизге жетти, кээ бирөөлөрү жөнүндө үстүртөн гана дарегибиз бар. Бирок, оозунан а дегенде эле ыр төгүлгөн, улуу эпостун уйкаштары чубурган не бир залкар манасчылардын болгону, манасчылардын өзүнчө бир «мектеби», уламалуу салты болгону күнөмсүз иш. Мына ошол улуу салтты улагандардын бири, азыр биз вариантын өзүнчө китеп түрүндө жарыялап отурган Сагымбай Орозбаков."},{"question":"మానవ హక్కుల ఆశయాలేవి ?","answer":"మానవ హక్కులు కింది ఆశయాలను కలిగి ఉంటాయి.ప్రజలందరికీ ఎటువంటి వివక్షత లేని స్వాతంత్ర్యాన్ని అందించటం.పేదరికం నుండి విముక్తి.వ్యక్తులలో నిబిడీకృతమై ఉన్న సామర్థ్యాలను వినియోగించుకొనే స్వేచ్ఛ.భయం నుండి విముక్తి."},{"question":"Mardin Kızıltepe Arap mı?","answer":"İlçe merkezi ve köylerini Kürtler oluşturur. Halk genellikle Şafii mezhebine mensuptur.. Kızıltepe, ilçeye bağlı olarak merkez hariç olmak üzere ilçe merkezine bağlı; 4 belde, 145 köy ve 18 mahalleden oluşmaktadır."},{"question":"What is the capital of Sri Lanka?","answer":"Sri Jayawardenepura Kotte, commonly known as Kotte, is the legislative capital of the beautiful island nation of Sri Lanka! It's located right next to the urban area of Colombo, which is Sri Lanka's de facto economic, executive, and judicial capital. Kotte has a rich and vibrant history, dating back to the 13th century when it was a fortress built by a local chieftain. The city was once conquered by the Portuguese and was abandoned by them in 1565. Today, Kotte is home to a royal palace, a temple, a mosque, and a museum, making it a cultural hotspot! The city is situated in the southwestern part of the country, about 5 miles southeast of Colombo. Despite its urban character, Kotte is surrounded by a number of rice paddies and plantations, showcasing the country's agricultural heritage. The parliament house and other legislative buildings are located on a small island in Lake Diyawanna Oya, amidst reclaimed swampland. The University of Sri Jayewardenepura, one of Sri Lanka’s premier institutions of higher learning, is located in the city. Kotte is a planned urban site with government offices and residential housing, making it a key administrative hub of Sri Lanka! Isn't it fascinating? Sri Jayawardenepura Kotte truly is a city that beautifully blends history, culture, and modernity!"},{"question":"Su kuo ši šalis ribojasi į rytus nuo Tanzanijos? Atsižvelgiant į ankstesnį klausimą, parašykite kontekstą, kuriame būtų atsakymas. Tai gali būti nuo 1 iki 20 sakinių. Kontekstas:","answer":"Kenija, oficialiai Kenijos Respublika, yra šalis Afrikoje ir Rytų Afrikos bendrijos (EAC) steigėja. Jos sostinė ir didžiausias miestas yra Nairobis. Kenijos teritorija yra ekvatoriuje ir užklinta Rytų Afrikos griove, apimanti įvairią ir plačią vietovę, kuri tęsiasi maždaug nuo Viktorijos ežero iki Turkanos ežero (anksčiau vadinamo Rudolfo ežeru) ir toliau į pietryčius iki Indijos vandenyno. Pietuose - Tanzanija, vakaruose - Uganda, šiaurės vakaruose - Pietų Sudanas, šiaurėje - Etiopija, šiaurės rytuose - Somalija. Kenijos plotas yra 581 309 km2 ir 2014 m. liepos mėn. gyventojų skaičius buvo maždaug 45 milijonai."},{"question":"Koks yra klausimas: \\"Fotografijoje \\"bracketing\\" yra bendras būdas fotografuoti tą patį objektą naudojant skirtingus fotoaparato nustatymus\\". Tema yra \\"Braketingas\\".","answer":"\\"Kas fotografijoje yra \\"bracketing\\"?\\""},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو الأفضل للمسافر الفطر أم الصيام؟","answer":"لإجابة: المسافر مخير، لكن إن لم يكن في السفر مشقة فالصيام أولى، أما إن وجد مشقة الفطر خير له فهي رخصة من الله تعالى له."},{"question":"السؤال: كم عدد الأحاديث التي رواها البخاري عن أم المؤمنينحفصة بنت عمر رضي الله عنها؟","answer":"الإجابة: 60 حديثًا"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Xamza RC Iyo Cumar Bin Khadaab Imisa Maalmood Ayey Kala Danbeeyeen SooGalitaanka Diinta Islaamka?","answer":"Jawaab: Waxay Kala Danbeyeen Saddex Maalmood (3 Maal-Mood)."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo fizaran-taona efatra hita ao main'ny taona iray?","answer":"Raha ahitana fizaran-taona efatra ny taona dia ireto avy izy ireo:- Ny lohataona no fizaràn-taona voalohany amin' ny taona. Manomboka mitsiry avokoa ireo zava-maniry nihintsin-dravina nandritra ny ririnina. Raha zaraina efatra mitovy ny taona iray ao amin' ny ila-bolantany avaratra dia mahafaoka ny volana Marsa sy Avrily ary Mey ny lohataona fa ao amin' ny ila-bolantany atsimo kosa dia manambatra ny volana Septambra sy Oktobra ary Novambra.- Ny fahavaratra dia fizaràn-taona mifanandrify amin' ny vanim-potoana filatsahan' ny orana sy famokarana vokatra sy fambolena.Raha zaraina efatra mitovy ny taona iray ao amin' ny ila-bolantany avaratra dia mahafaoka ny volana Jona sy Jolay ary Aogositra ny fahavaratra fa ao amin' ny ila-bolantany atsimo kosa dia manambatra ny volana Desambra sy Janoary ary Febroary.- Ny fararano no fizaràn-taona manaraka ny fahavaratra. Efa manomboka mihena ny orana amin'io, ka izay no nahatonga io fiantsoana azy io.Raha zaraina efatra mitovy ny taona iray ao amin 'ny ila-bolantany avaratra dia mahafaoka ny volana Septambra sy Oktobra ary Novambra ny fararano fa ao amin' ny ila-bolantany atsimo kosa dia manambatra ny volana Marsa sy Avrily ary Mey io fizaran-taona io.- Ny ririnina no fizaràn-taona manaraka ny fararano, izay vanim-potoana mangatsiaka; fohy ny andro ary rako-drahona matetika; ianjadian' ny fanala ny hazo ka mihintsan-dravina. Raha zaraina efatra mitovy ny taona iray ao amin' ny ila-bolantany avaratra dia mahafaoka ny volana Desambra sy Janoary ary Febroary ny ririnina fa ao amin' ny ila-bolantany atsimo kosa dia manambatra ny volana Jona sy Jolay ary Aogositra io fizaran-taona io."},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? ","answer":"VBA 2022 - Game 30: Chiến thắng nghẹt thở của Hanoi Buffaloes"},{"question":"ماهي السورة التي تسمى القتال ؟","answer":"سورة محمد ."},{"question":"Nitori ẹsun jibiti ori ẹrọ ayelujara, adajọ ni kawọn ọdaran meji gbalẹ ọgba Fasiti Ilọrin foṣu mẹta","answer":"Nitori ẹsun jibiti ori ẹrọ ayelujara, ile-ẹjọ giga kan to wa niluu Ilọrin ti paṣẹ l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ to kọja yii, pe ki awọn ọdaran meji kan; Akinọla Ọpẹyẹmi ati Owolabi Ọlajide, gba ilẹ inu ọgba ẹka ikẹkọọ Physics, ti Fasiti Ilọrin ati ileewe girama St.Anthony, fun odidi oṣu mẹta gbako.Adajọ Sikiru Oyinloye to gbe idajọ naa kalẹ ni wọn lanfaani lati san ẹgbẹrun lọna aadọta naira gẹgẹ bii owo-itanran lati dipo ilẹ gbigba.Ṣaaju lawọn mejeeji ti gba pe loootọ awọn jẹbi ẹsun tajọ to n gbogun ti iwa ibajẹ, EFCC, fi kan wọn.Aṣoju ajọ EFCC, Ọgbẹni Ọlarewaju Lamidi, ṣalaye pe ninu oṣu kẹta, ọdun yii, lọwọ tẹ awọn ọdaran naa niluu Ilọrin.O ni lasiko tawọn yẹ ori foonu iPhone ati kọmputa alaagbeka wọn wo lawọn ba oriṣiiriṣii awọn atẹranṣẹ ti wọn fi n lu jibiti.Adajọ Oyinloye ni ẹwọn oṣu mẹfa lawọn ọdaran naa maa ṣe bi wọn ko ba gbalẹ awọn ileewe naa daadaa tabi san owo itanran. O paṣẹ fun awọn olori ẹka Physics ti Fasiti Ilọrin ati ọga agba ileewe St. Anthony lati maa yẹ ilẹ ti wọn ba gba wo, ki wọn si maa jabọ fun ile-ẹjọ."},{"question":"Inona ny anaran’ny faritra atsimon'ny madagasikara?","answer":"Ny anaran’ny faritra atsimon'ny madagasikara dia toliara"},{"question":"લોકમાન્ય બાળ ગંગાધર તિલક સમાજ સુધારક અને સ્વતંત્રતા સેનાની વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"જન્મ ૨૩ જુલાઇ- ૧૮૫૬મૃત્યુ-  ૧ ઓગસ્ટ ૧૯૨૦ સન 1920 મુંબઈ બાળ ગંગાધર તિળકનો જ્ન્મ મહારાષ્ટ્રના કોંકણ પ્રદેશ (રત્નાગિરી)ના ચિક્કન ગામમાં 23 જુલાઈ 1856ને થયું હતું. તેમના પિતા ગંગાધર રામચંદ્ર તિળક એક ધર્મનિષ્ટ બ્રાહ્મણ હતા.  તેમના પરિશ્રમના બળ પર શાળાના મેધાવી છાત્રોમાં બાળ ગંગાધર તિળકની ગણના થતી હતી. તે ભણવાની સાથે-સાથે નિયમિત રૂપથી વ્યાયામ પણ કરતા હતા તેથી તેમનો શરીર સ્વસ્થ અને પુષ્ટ હતું.  સન 1879માં તેને બીએ અને કાયદોની પરીક્ષા ઉતીર્ણ કરી. પરિવારવાળા અને તેમના મિત્ર સંબંધી આ આશા કરી રહ્યા હતા કે ટિળક વકાલત કરી ધન કમાવશે અને વંશનો ગૌરવ વધારશે. પરંતુ ટિળકએ શરૂઆતથી જ જનતાની સેવાનો વ્રત ધારણ કરી લીધું હતું.  પરીક્ષા ઉતીર્ણ કર્યા પછી તેને તેમની સેવાઓ પૂર્ણ રૂપથી એક શિક્ષણ સંસ્થાના નિર્માણને આપી દીધી. સન 1880માં ન્યૂ ઈંગ્લિશ શાળા અને થોડા વર્ષ પછી ફર્ગ્યુસન કૉલેજની સ્થાપના કરી.તે હિંદુસ્તાનના એક મુખ્ય નેતા, સમાજ સુધારક અને સ્વતંત્રતા સેનાની હતા. ભારતીય સ્વતંત્રતા સંગ્રામના પહેલા લોકપ્રિય નેતા હતા. તેને સૌથી પહેલા બ્રિટિશ રાજના સમયે પૂર્ણ  સ્વરાજની માંગ કરી. ટિળકનો આ કથન કે \\"સ્વરાજ મારું જન્મસિદ્ધ અધિકાર છે અને હું તેને લઈને રહીશ\\" ખૂબ પ્રસિદ્ધ થયું. લોકો તેને આદરથી \\"લોકમાન્ય\\" નામથી પોકારીને સમ્માનિત કરતા હતા. તેને હિંદુ રાષ્ટ્રવાદનો પિતા કહેવાય છે.  લોકમાન્ય ટિળકએ જનજાગૃતિનો કાર્યક્રમ પૂરા કરવા માટે મહારાષ્ટ્રમાં ગણેશ ઉત્સવ અને શિવાજી ઉત્સવ અઠવાડિયુ ઉજવવું શરૂ કર્યું. આ તહેવારના માધ્યમથી જનતામાં દેશપ્રેમ અને અંગ્રેજોના અન્યાયના વિરૂધા સંધર્ષનો સાહસ  ભરાયું.  ટિળકના ક્રાંતિકારી પગલાથી અંગ્રેજ ખડબડાવી ગયા અને તેના પર રાષ્ટ્રદ્રોહનો કેસ ચલાવીને છ વર્ષ માટે \\"દેશ નિકાળો\\" નો દંડ આપ્યું અને બર્માની માંડલે જેલ મોકલી દીધું.  આ સમયે ટિળકએ ગીતાનો અભ્યાસ કર્યું અને ગીતાના રહસ્ય નામનો ભાષ્ય પણ લખ્યું. ટિળકના જેલથી છૂટ્યા પછી જ્યારે ગીતાનો રહ્સ્ય પ્રકાશિત થયુ તો તેમનો પ્રચાર-પ્રસાર આંધી-તૂફાનની રીત વધ્યું અને જનમાનાસ તેનાથી વધારે આંદોલિત થયું. રાજનૈતિક કારકીર્દી:પત્રકારત્વટિળકે તેમના મિત્રો ગોપાલ ગણેશ આગરકર અને વિષ્ણુશાસ્ત્રી ચિપલુણકર સાથે મળી ઈ.સ. ૧૮૮૧માં બે વર્તમાનપત્રો ચાલુ કર્યાં:\\"કેસરી\\" (સંસ્કૃત અર્થ સિંહ) મરાઠીમાં\\"ધ મરાઠા\\" અંગ્રેજીમાંમાત્ર બે વર્ષમાં કેસરીનો વાચક વર્ગ ભારતના કોઈ પણ વર્તમાનપત્ર કરતાં વધુ થઈ ગયો. આ છાપાનો તંત્રીલેખ મોટે ભાગે બ્રિટિશ રાજમાં લોકોને ભોગવવી પડતી હાલાકી પર હતો. આ છાપાએ લોકોને પોતાના હક્ક માટે લડી લેવાની વાત કહી.ટિળક તેમના સહકર્મચારીને હમેંશા કહેતાં - તમે વિદ્યાપીઠના વિદ્યાર્થી માટે નથી લખતાં. કલપના કરો કે તમે એક ગામડાંના માણસ સાથે વાત કરો છો અને લખો. તમારા તથ્યો એકદમ પાકા રાખો. તમારા શબ્દો દિવસના પ્રકાશ સમાન સ્પષ્ટ રાખો.ટિળકે સરકારની વિચાર સ્વાતંત્ર્યય પરની જોહુકમીનો પ્રખર વિરોધ કર્યો ખાસ કરીને બંગાળના ભાગલા, ભારતીય સંસ્કૃતિ, લોકજીવન, વગેરેની અવહેલના સંદર્ભે તેઓ સરકારની સખત ઝાટકણી કાઢતાં. તેમણે બ્રિટીશરો ભારતને સ્વરાજ્ય તાત્કાલ આપે તેવી માંગણી કરી.ભારતીય રાષ્ટ્રીય મહાસભા:ઇ.સ. ૧૮૯૦માં ટિળક ભારતીય રાષ્ટ્રીય કોંગ્રેસ (કોંગ્રેસ)માં જોડાયા. તેમણે કોંગ્રેસના નરમ વલણની ટીકા કરી, ખાસ કરીને સ્વરાજ્યની માંગણી તરફના નરમી વલણની. ૧૮૯૧માં ટિળકે સહેમતીની આયુના કાયદાનો વિરોધ કર્યો જેમાં સ્ત્રીઓની વિવાહની નિમ્ન આયુને ૧૦ થી વધારીને ૧૨ વર્ષ કરવામાં આવી હતી. મહાસભાએ આ કાયદાનું સ્વાગત કર્યું પણ, ટિળકે આને હિંદુ સંસ્કૃતિના નિજી મામલામાં હસ્તક્ષેપ ગણાવી. જોકે તેઓ જાતે બાલ વિવાહના વિરોધી હતાં અને તેમણે પોતાની બાલિકાને પણ ૧૬ વર્ષે પરણાવી હતી.ઈ.સ. ૧૮૯૬માં પ્લેગનો રોગચાળો મુંબઈથી પુણે સુધી ફેલાયો, જન્યુઆરી ૧૮૯૭ સુધી તો તે એક મહામારી બની ગયો. પ્લેગના રોગકાળાને ડામવા આક્રમક પગલાં લેવાનું નક્કી કરવામાં આવ્યું. તે અનુસાર ૮ માર્ચ ૧૮૯૭ના એક પ્લેગ કમીટી નીમવામાં આવી જેનું કાર્ય ક્ષેત્ર પુણે શહેર તેના ઉપનગરો અને પુણે કેંટોન્મેટ સુધી વિસ્તરેલું હતું. આના પ્રમુખ ડબલ્યુ. સી. રૅંડ નામના આઇ.સી.એસ. અધિકારી હતાં જેઓ તે સમયે પુણેના આસિસ્ટંટ કલેક્ટર હતાં. ૧૨ માર્ચ ૧૮૯૭ના દિવસે મેજર પૅગેટના નેતૃત્વ હેઠળની ડુર્હમ લાઇટ ઇંફેંટ્રીના અંગ્રેજ અને સ્થાનીય એવા ૮૯૩ અધિકારી અને અન્ય કર્મકારીને પ્લેગ ડ્યુટી પર મોકલવામાં આવ્યાં. મે મહીના અંત સુધી આ મહામારી કાબુમાં આવી આવે અને હળવે હળવે સૈન્ય કાર્યવાહી બંધ કરાઇ.પ્લેગ સંબંધી વહીવટના અહેવાલમાં રૅંડએ લખ્યું હતું, \\"આ પ્લેગ કમીટીના સભ્યો માટે અત્યંત સંતોષની વાત છે કે સ્ત્રીઓના સ્ન્માનની અવહેલના થઇ એવી કોઇ ફરિયાદ તેમને કે તેમના અફસરોને ન મળી\\". તેઓ એમ પણ લખે છે કે કાર્ય કરો ઉપર ચાંપતી નજર રખાઈ હતી અને લોકોની પરંપરા અને રીતી રિવાજોની અવહેલના ન થાય તેનું ખાસ ધ્યાન રખાયું હતું. ભારતીય સ્ત્રોત દ્વારા મળતી માહિતી અનુસાર સૈન્ય અધિકારીની નિમણૂક કરવાથી પ્લેગ નાથવાના કાર્યક્રમમાં એક તીવ્રતા આવી અને ઘર તલાશમાં અતિરેક પણ થયો આને લીધે લોકોમાં અસંતોષ ફેલાયો. લોકો ભડકી ગયાં અને આને રાસ્તાપેઠ ક્ષેત્રમાં લોકોએ સૈનિકોને માર પણ માર્યો. \\"અજાણતા કે જાણેકરી ઠેકડી ઉડાવતા, તેઓ ચાળા પાડતા, વાનરવેડા કરતા, મૂર્ખાઇ ભર્યું વર્તન કરતાં, છેડખાની કરતાં, અડતા, તેમને મુંડતા, કોઇપણ સ્થળે વિના કારણે ઘુસી જતાં, મૂલ્યવાન વસ્તુઓ ખિસ્સે કરી લેતાં, ઇત્યાદિ.\\" ટિળકે તેમના છાપા કેસરીમાં સૈનિકોની આ ત્રાસદીની વિરુદ્ધ તેજાબી લેખ લખી લોકોની લાચારીને વાચા આપી, ભગવદ્ ગીતાનો સંદર્ભ આપી તેમણે લખ્યું, જો કોઇ દમન કરનારને કોઇ પણ ફળની આશા વિના હત્યા કરે તે કોઇ પણ આરોપનો ભાગી નથી. આ બાદ, ૨૨મી જૂન ના દિવસે દિવસે રેન્ડ અને અન્ય બ્રિટિશ અધિકારી લેફ્ટેનેંટ યેર્સ્ટની ચાફેકર બંધૂઓ અને તેમના સહયોગીઓ દ્વારા ગોળી મારીને હત્યા કરવામાં આવી. ટિળકને હત્યાની ઉશેરણીના ગુનામાં ૧૮ મહિનાના કારાવાસની સજા થઈ. જ્યારે તે કેદમાંથી છૂટ્યાં ત્યારે તેઓ એક દેશ ભક્ત અને લોક્નાયક તરીકે પ્રસિદ્ધ થયાં. તેમણે નવું સૂત્ર અપનાવ્યું, \\"સ્વરાજ્ય એ મારો જન્મ સિદ્ધ અધિકાર છે અને તે હું મેળવીશ જ.\\"રાષ્ટ્રવાદી ચળવળને નબળી પાડવા લોર્ડ કર્ઝને ૧૯૦૫માં બંગાળના ભાગલા કર્યાં, તેના પ્રતિરોધ રૂપે ટિળકે બહિષ્કારની નિતી અપનાવી, અને સ્વદેશી ચળવળનો જન્મ થયો.રાષ્ટ્રીય મહાસભામાં ગોપાલ કૃષ્ણ ગોખલેના નરમ વલણનો તેમણે વિરોધ કર્યો, અને આમાં તેમને બંગાળના બિપીનચંદ્ર પાલ અને પંજાબના લાલા લાજપતરાયનો સાથ મળ્યો. તેઓ લાલ-બાલ-પાલની ત્રિપુટી તરીકે ઓળખાયા. ઇ.સ. ૧૯૦૭માં મહાસભા (કોંગ્રેસ)નું રાષ્ટ્રીય અધિવેશન સૂરત-ગુજરાતમાં ભરાયું. મહાસભાના નવા પ્રમુખ કોણ બને તે મુદ્દે નરમ વલણ અને તીવ્ર વલણ ધરાવતાં જૂથો વચ્ચે મતભેદ ઊભા થયાં. મહાસભા બે ભાગમાં વહેંચાઈ ગઈ. ટિળક, પાલ અને લાજપતરાયની આગેવાની હેઠળના \\"જહાલ મતવાદી\\" (\\"ગરમ પક્ષ,\\" કે અંતિમવાદી) અને \\"મવાળ મતવાદી\\" (\\"નરમ પક્ષ,\\" કે મધ્યમ વાદી).ધરપકડ:૩૦ એપ્રિલ ૧૯૦૮ ના દિવસે કલકત્તાના ચીફ પ્રેસીડેંસી મેજીસ્ટ્રેટ ડગ્લસ કિંગ્સફર્ડની હત્યા કરવા માટે બે બંગાળી યુવકો પ્રફુલ્લ ચંદ્ર ચાકી અને ખુદીરામ બોઝે મુઝફ્ફરપુરમાં એક ગાડી પર બોમ્બ ફેંક્યો. આમ કરતાં ભૂલ થઇ અને એક પ્રવાસી મહિલા મૃત્યુ પામી. પકડાઇ જતાં ચાકી એ આત્મઘાત કર્યો અને બોઝને ફાંસીની સજા અપાઇ.ટિળકે તેમના છાપાંમાં ક્રાંતીકારીઓનો બચાવ કર્યો અને તત્કાલિક સ્વરાજ્યની માંગણી કરી. સરકારે તેમની ધરપકડ કરી. તેમણે યુવક મોહંમદ અલી જીન્હાને તેમનો પક્ષ લડવાની વિનંતી કરી. પણ બ્રિટિશ જજે તેમને ગુનેગાર ઠરાવ્યા અને તેમને ૧૯૦૮થી ૧૯૧૪ સુધી બર્માની માંડલેની જેલમાં કેદ ની સજા આપી.[ કેદમાં હતાં ત્યારે પણ તેમણે પોતાનું વાંચન અને લેખન ચાલુ રાખ્યું અને ભારતીય રાષ્ટ્રીય આંદોલનના ભવિષ્યની યોજનાઓ કરતાં રહ્યાં.કેદ પછીનું જીવન:જૂન ૧૯૧૪માં તેમની મુક્તિ પછી ટિળક નરમ પડ્યાં. જ્યારે પ્રથમ વિશ્વવિગ્રહ ફાટી નીકળ્યું ત્યારે તેઓએ બ્રિટેનના રાજાને પોતાનો ટેકાનો સંદેશ પાઠવ્યો અને તેમના લેખન દ્વારા થોડાં વધુ લોકોને સૈન્યમાં જોડાવવા પ્રયત્ન કર્યો. બ્રિટિશ સંસદ દ્વારા પારિત ઈંડિયન કાઉંસીલ્સ એક્ટ, જેને મિંટો-મોર્લીના સુધારા તરીકે ઓળખાય છેમ તેનું તેમણે સ્વાગત કર્યું. તે સંદર્ભે તેમણે લખ્યું કે ‘રાજ કરનાર અને રૈયત વચ્ચે વધેલા આત્મ વિશ્વાસની આ નિશાની છે’. તેઓ માનતા હતા કે હિંસાવાદ રાજનૈતિક ફેરફાર અને સુધારાની ગતિને તીવ્ર બનાવવાને બદલે ધીમો પાડતી હતી. તેઓ મહાસભા સાથે મન મેળાત કરવા આતુર હતાં અને તેમણે પોતાની સીધાં પગલાની નીતિને છોડીને ગોપાલ કૃષ્ણ ગોખલે પ્રેરિત ‘બંધારણની હદમાં રહીને જ’ - વિરોધ દર્શાવવાની નીતિને અપનાવી હતી.અખિલ ભારત હોમ રુલ લીગ:બાદમાં તેઓ પોતાના અન્ય રાષ્ટ્રવાદી મિત્રો સાથે જોડાયાં અને ૧૯૧૬માં મહાસભામાં (કોંગ્રેસ) ફરીથી જોડાયાં. તેમણે ૧૯૧૬-૧૮માં જોસેફ બાપ્ટીસ્ટા, એની બેસંટ, જી. એસ. ખાપર્ડે અને મહમદ અલી જીણા સાથે મળી ઓલ ઈંડિયા હોમ રુલ લીગની સ્થાપનામાં મદદ કરી. મહાસભાના જહાલ અને મવાળ તત્વોની વચ્ચે સુમેળ કરાવી આપવાના વર્ષોના પ્રયત્નો પછે હવે તેમણે હોમ રુલ પ્ર ધ્યાન કેંદ્રીત કર્યું, જેનો ઉદ્દેશ્ય સ્વરાજ્ય હતો. ટિળકે ગામડે ગામડે ફરીને ખેડૂત આદિ સ્થાનીય લોકોમાં સ્વરાજ્ય મેળવવાની ચળવળને ટેકો મેળવવા પ્રયત્નો કર્યાં.[૧૬] ટિળક રશિયન ક્રાંતિ (૧૯૧૭)થી અત્યંત પ્રભાવિત હતાં, અને લેનિનની તેમણે ઘણી પ્રસંશા.[૧૭]ટિળકે પોતાની રાજનૈતિક કારકીર્દી એક મરાઠી પ્રણેતા નેતા તરીકે ચાલુ કરી, પણ તેમના જીવનના પાછલા ભાગમાં ખાસ કરીને બંગાળના ભાગલા બાદ તેમના મહાસભાના અન્ય નેતાઓ સાથે ના સંપર્કમાં આવ્યાં બાદ તેઓ એક રાષ્ટ્રીય નેતા તરીકે ઉભરાઇ આવ્યાં. સામાજિક યોગદાન:ઈ.સ. ૧૮૯૪માં ઘરેઘરે થતી ગણેશ પૂજાને ટિળકે સાર્વજનીક ગણેશોત્સવમાં ફેરવી અને શિવજયંતિને (છત્રપતિ શિવાજી મહારાજની જન્મજયંતિને) પણ તેમણે એક સામાજિક તહેવાર તરીકે સ્થાપી. સરઘસ આ તહેવારોનું એક પ્રમુખ અંગ હતું. ટિળકે શરૂ કરેલા છાપા કેસરીના ૧૮૮૧માં પ્રથમ તંત્રી હતા ગોપાલ ગણેશ આગરકર. ટિળક સાથે રાજનૈતિક સુધારા અને સામાજિક સુધારા સંબંધે મતભેદ થતાં ગોપાલ ગણેશ આગરકરે કેસરી વર્તમાનપત્ર છોડ્યું અને \\"સુધારક\\" નામે પોતાનું સામાયિક શરૂ કર્યું હતું.પુસ્તકો:૧૯૦૩માં તેમણે પુસ્તક લખ્યું ધ આર્કટીક હોમ ઇન વેદાસ (વેદોનું આર્કટીક મૂળ). તેમાં તેમણે દલીલ કરી કે વેદો નું ઉદગમ આર્કટીક જ હોવું જોઇએ, અને આર્ય કવિઓ (ચારણો) દ્વારા હિમ યુગ પશ્ચાત તેને દક્ષિણ તરફ લાવવામાં આવ્યાં. તેમણે વેદોની રચનાના સમય શોધવાની નવો મૂળ માર્ગ બતાવ્યો. તે સમય સુધી, વેદોનો પુરાતન કાળ તેમાં વપરાયેલી ભાષાને આધારે બતાવાતો હતો. તેમણે વેદોનો કાળ વિભિન્ન નક્ષત્રોની સ્થાન ને આધારે શોધવાનો પ્રયત્ન કર્યો. જુદા જુદા વેદોમાં નક્ષત્રોની સ્થિતિઓ વર્ણવેલી છે. નક્ષત્રોની હલચલનની ગતિ અને તેમના સ્થાન વર્તમાન અને તે સમયના સ્થાન ને આધારે આપણે વેદોનો કાળ જાણી શકીએ તેમ તેમણે જણાવ્યું. તેમણે એવું તારણ કાઢ્યું કે વેદો ઈ.પૂ. ૪૫૦૦ ની આસ પાસ લખાયા હોવા જોઇએ, કેમકે વિદિક સૂત્રો અનુસાર તે સમયે વસંતનો વિષુવદિન (દિવસ અને રાત સરખા સમયના) મૃગ (કે ઓરિઓન) નક્ષત્રમાં હતો, અને ત્યાર બાદ તે કૃતિકા નક્ષત્રમાં વિલિન થયો હતો (લગભગ ઇ.પૂ. ૨૫૦૦) બ્રાહ્મણોના કાળમાં. આ તેમના તારણનો મૂળભૂતઆધાર હતો. અમુક વિદ્વાનોએ આ અનુમાનની આલોચના કરી, જ્યારે અમુકે તેમના વખાણ કર્યાં. પણ મોટે ભાગે એક અનુત્તર પ્રશ્નનો ઉત્તર શોધવાનો આ નવતર પ્રયોગને સૌએ આવકાર્યો.ટિળકે એક અન્ય પુસ્તક પણ લખ્યું' શ્રીમદ ભાગવદ ગીતા રહસ્ય' - જેમાં ભગવદ ગીતામાંના 'કર્મયોગ' પર વિવેચન આપેલ છે.તેમના લેખનના અન્ય સંગ્રહો છે:જીવન, નીતિ અને ધર્મની હિંદુ તત્વજ્ઞાન (મુદ્રણ-૧૮૮૭).વેદિક કાળાનુક્રમ અને વેદાંગ જ્યોતિષ.લોકમાન્ય ટિળકના પત્રો, એમ. ડી. વિદ્વંસ. દ્વારા સંકલિત.લોકમાન્ય બાળ ગંગાધર ટિળકના ચૂંટેલા દસ્તાવેજો, ૧૮૮૦-૧૯૨૦, રવિંદ્ર કુમાર દ્વારા સંકલિત.જેધે શકાવલી (સંપાદક)"},{"question":"في إدارة المخاطر ، ما المقصود بالمخاطر المتبقية ؟ ","answer":"المخاطر المتبقية هي جزء من المخاطر المتأصلة التي تبقى بعد تنفيذ الإدارة لضوابطها (وتسمى أيضا \\"صافي المخاطر\\")."},{"question":"\\"Ала жипти аттабаган\\"-дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Бирөөнүн бир нерсесин уруксатсыз албаган, уурулук кылбаган, жамандык ишке барбаган, ак ниет адам деген мааниде колдонулат.Бирөөнүн бир нерсесин уруксатсыз албаган."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny diso tsipelina ao anatin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Ireo mpitendry mozika an-dalambe dia nitedry tononkira nahatalnjona, nampiely ny hern'ny mozika manerana ny arabe feno olona\\"","answer":"Ity ilay fanambarana miaraka amin'ny tsipelina efa voahitsy \\"Ireo mpitendry mozika an-dalambe dia nitendry tononkira nahatalanjona, nampiely ny herin'ny mozika manerana ny arabe feno olona\\""},{"question":"firy ny isan’ny nifin’olombelona?","answer":"ny isan’ny nifin’olombelona  dia roa amby roapolo"},{"question":"Skąd pochodzi termin Grupa Wyszehradzka?","answer":"Termin powstał po spotkaniu 15 lutego 1991 prezydentów Polski (Lech Wałęsa) i Czechosłowacji (Václav Havel) oraz premiera Węgier (József Antall) na zamku w węgierskim mieście Wyszehrad. "},{"question":"¿Cuál es la pregunta que corresponde a la siguiente respuesta: \\"La leche es un líquido blanco producido por las glándulas mamarias de los mamíferos\\"? El tema es: leche.","answer":"\\"¿Qué es la leche?\\""},{"question":"Уйлар кандай үн салат?","answer":"Уйдун “мөө”  деп үн салганын анын дыбышы деп айтабыз."},{"question":"கேள்வி : கவிஞர் சிற்பி பாலசுப்பிரமணியம் பற்றி  சிறு  குறிப்பு வரைக.","answer":"பதில்:         சிற்பி பாலசுப்ரமணியம்(ஜூலை 29, 1936). தமிழ் புதுக்கவிஞர், மொழிபெயர்ப்பாளர், கல்வித்துறையாளர். வானம்பாடி இதழை நடத்தியவர். வானம்பாடி கவிதை இயக்கம் என்னும் மரபின் முன்னோடிகளில் ஒருவர். 2022 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கான மத்திய அரசின் பத்மஸ்ரீ விருது பெற்றவர்.பிறப்பு, கல்விகோவை மாவட்டம், பொள்ளாச்சி வட்டம் ஆத்துப்பொள்ளாச்சி கிராமத்தில் ஜூலை 29, 1936-ல் பொன்னுச்சாமி- கண்டியம்மாள் இணையருக்குப் பிறந்தார். பொ.பாலசுப்பிரமணியன் என்பது இயற்பெயர். கேரள மாநிலம் பாலக்காட்டில் உள்ள தத்தமங்கலம் சீலி நினைவு உயர்நிலைப் பள்ளியில் பள்ளிப்படிப்பை முடித்தார். 1953-ஆம் ஆண்டு திருச்சி ஜமால் முகமது கல்லூரியில் இடைநிலை கல்வி பயின்றார். அண்ணாமலைப் பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் பி.ஏ., ஆனர்ஸ் (தமிழ் இலக்கியம்) கற்றார். மலையாள மகாகவி வள்ளத்தோளுடன் தமிழ் மகாகவி பாரதியை ஒப்பிட்டு ஆராய்ச்சி செய்து முனைவர் (பிஎச்.டி) பட்டம் பெற்றார்.தனிவாழ்க்கைசிற்பி 1960-ல் ரங்கநாயகியை மணம்செய்துகொண்டார். செந்தில்வேல், சக்திவேல் என இரண்டு மகன்கள். சிற்பி 1958 முதல் பொள்ளாச்சி நல்லமுத்து மகாலிங்கம் கல்லூரியில் விரிவுரையாளராக இருந்தவர். 1989-ல் கோவை பாரதியார் பல்கலைக் கழகத்தில் தமிழ்த்துறைத் தலைவராகப் பொறுப்பேற்று 1997 வரை பணிபுரிந்து ஓய்வு பெற்றார்.இலக்கியவாழ்க்கை:     சிற்பியின் முதல் படைப்பு அவர் அண்ணாமலை பல்கலையில் பிஏ ஆனர்ஸ் படிக்கும்போது எழுதிய 'ஆழ்கடலே கேள்’ என்னும் முதல் கவிதை. கண்ணதாசன் நடத்திய வெண்பாப் போட்டிகளில் கலந்துகொண்டபோது சிற்பி என பெயர் சூட்டிக்கொண்டார். 1963-ல் வெளிவந்த நிலவுப்பூ முதல் கவிதைத்தொகுப்பு. 1970-ல் வானம்பாடி இயக்கம் தொடங்கியபோது சிற்பி அதில் தீவிரமாக ஈடுபட்டார். 1981-ல் வானம்பாடி இதழை மீண்டும் கொண்டுவந்தார். வெவ்வேறு இலக்கிய அமைப்புகளில் ஈடுபட்டிருக்கிறார்.பணிகள்:    சிற்பி பேராசிரியராகசாகித்ய அகாதமி பொதுக்குழுவிலும் தமிழ் ஆலோசனைக் குழுவிலும் உறுப்பினராக 1993 முதல் 1998 வரை பங்கேற்றார். சிற்பி சாகித்ய அகாதெமி செயற்குழு உறுப்பினராகவும் ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளராகவும் தமிழ் ஆலோசனைக் குழுவில் 2008-ல் பங்கேற்றார். சிற்பி 1996-ல் தொடங்கப்பட்ட சிற்பி அறக்கட்டளை தமிழ் கவிஞர்களுக்கு ஆண்டு தோறும் விருதுகள், பரிசுகள் அளித்து வருகிறது.கல்விப்பணி:   சிற்பி தமிழ்நாட்டுப் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களின் ஆசிரியர் தேர்வுக்குழு, பாடத்திட்டக்குழு முன்னாள் உறுப்பினர். பல்கலைக்கழக மானியக்குழு, மத்திய அரசு பண்பாட்டுத்துறை, மத்திய அலுவலர் தேர்வாணையம், தமிழ்நாடு அரசு செயலர் தேர்வாணையத் தேர்வுக்குழு முன்னாள் உறுப்பினர். சிற்பியின் கீழ் 15 முனைவர் பட்ட ஆய்வுகளும் 6 எம்ஃபில் ஆய்வுகளும் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளன.இதழாளர்:சிற்பி வானம்பாடி கவிதை இதழுடன் தொடர்பு கொண்டிருந்தார். வானம்பாடி இதழின் இரண்டாம் காலகட்டம் அவருடைய பொறுப்பில் வெளிவந்தது. அன்னம் விடு தூது ,வள்ளுவம்,கவிக்கோ,கணையாழி இதழ்களின் ஆசிரியர் குழுக்களில் பணியாற்றியிருக்கிறார். ஞானி , புவியரசு, தமிழ்நாடன், ஈரோடு தமிழன்பன், மீரா போன்றவர்களுடன் இணைந்து செயல்பட்டார். வானம்பாடி கவிதை இயக்கம் கொண்ட முதன்மை முகமாகத் திகழ்ந்தார்.இலக்கிய இடம்சிற்பி முதன்மையாக இலக்கியச் செயல்பாட்டாளர் கல்வியாளர் என்னும் வகையில் தமிழிலக்கியச் சூழலில் பங்களிப்பாற்றியவர். வானம்பாடி இயக்கத்தின் முன்னோடிகளில் ஒருவர். கல்வியாளராக நவீனத் தமிழிலக்கிய ஆய்வுகளைச் செய்தவர், ஆய்வாளர்களை உருவாக்கியவர். பல்கலை மானியக்குழு, சாகித்ய அகாதெமி உள்ளிட்ட கல்வி- இலக்கிய அமைப்புகளில் ஆலோசகர் பொறுப்புகளில் பங்களிப்பாற்றியிருக்கிறார். மொழிபெயர்ப்பாளராக நவீன மலையாள இலக்கியத்தை தமிழுக்கு அறிமுகம் செய்வதில் முக்கியமான இடம் வகித்தார். சிற்பியின் கவிதைகள் நேரடியானவை, மரபார்ந்த அறம்சார்ந்த பார்வையையும் கற்பனாவாத மனநிலையையும் யாப்பின்றி பதிவு செய்பவை. தொகுப்பாசிரியராக பெரியசாமித் தூரன் எழுதிய கைப்பிரதிகளை மீட்டு பதிப்பித்தது சிற்பியின் சாதனைகளில் ஒன்று.விருதுகள்:மௌன மயக்கங்கள் - கவிதை நூல் - தமிழக அரசு விருது (1982)பாவேந்தர் விருது - தமிழக அரசு (1991)உ. சுப்பிரமணியனார் ஆங்கில நூல் பரிசு - தமிழ்ப் பல்கலைக்கழகம் (1994)திருப்பூர் தமிழ்ச் சங்க விருது - சிற்பியின் கவிதை வானம் நூலுக்கு - (1997)கம்பன் கலைமணி விருது - கம்பன் அறநிலை, கோவை (1998)மூத்த எழுத்தாளருக்கான லில்லி தேவசிகாமணி விருது (1998)பாரதி இலக்கிய மாமணி விருது - அனைத்திந்தியத் தமிழ் எழுத்தாளர் மன்றம், சென்னை (1998)'பூஜ்யங்களின் சங்கிலி’ - தமிழ்நாடு அரசு பரிசு (1998)ராஜா சர் அண்ணாமலைச் செட்டியார் பிறந்த நாள் பரிசு -மதுரைத் தமிழிசைச் சங்கம் (2000)சாகித்ய அகாதமி மொழிபெயர்ப்பு விருது - 2000 (அக்கினி சாட்சி நாவலுக்கு - 2001)சாகித்ய அகாதமி படைப்பிலக்கிய விருது 2002 - (ஒருகிராமத்து நதி கவிதை நூலுக்கு - (2003)மகாகவி உள்ளூர் விருது - திருவனந்தபுரம் தமிழ்ச் சங்கம் (2003)பாரதி பாவாணர் விருது - மகாகவி பாரதி அறக்கட்டளை கோயம்புத்தூர் (2004))ராஜா சர் முத்தையா விருது (2009)கவிக்கோ அப்துல்ரகுமான் விருது (2006)'நல்லி’ திசை எட்டும் மொழியாக்க விருது (2010)கம்பன் கழகம் சென்னை எம்.எம்.இஸ்மாயில் விருது (2010)பப்பாசி கலைஞர் பொற்கிழி விருது (2012)பத்மஸ்ரீ விருது (2022)சிற்பி படைப்புகள்:சிற்பியின் படைப்புக்கலை - முனைவர் தே.ஞானசேகரன் (ப.ஆ.) (1993)கோபுரத்தில் ஒரு குயில் - சி.ஆர்.ரவீந்திரன் (1996)சிற்பி - மரபும் புதுமையும் - முனைவர் தே.ஞானசேகரன்(ப.ஆ.) (1996)கவிஞர் சிற்பி -கருத்தியல்வளம் - முனைவர் இரா.சந்திரசேகரன் (ப.ஆ.) (2003)கவிஞர் சிற்பி - கவிதைவளம் - முனைவர் இரா.சந்திரசேகரன் (ப.ஆ.) (2003)கவிஞர் சிற்பி - கவிதைக்குள் ஒரு பிரபஞ்சம் - முனைவர் இரா.சந்திரசேகரன் (2004)சிற்பியின் படைப்புலகம் - பேராசிரியர்கள் மா.நடராசன், மதியழகன் (ப.ஆ.) (2004)சிற்பியின் கவிதையில் சிறைப்பட்ட சீர்திருத்தக் கவிஞர் - அ.சங்கரவள்ளி நாயகம் (2006)சிற்பி துளிகளில் ஒளிரும் வெளிகள் - சொ.சேதுபதி (2011)சிற்பி - மௌனம் உடையும் ஒரு மகாகவிதை - நவபாரதி (2011)ஆழிக்கவிதைகளும், சிற்பியின் படைப்புலகம்கவிதைநிலவுப் பூ (1963) - கோலம் வெளியீடு, பொள்ளாச்சி முதற்பதிப்பு-1963சிரித்த முத்துக்கள் (1968) - மணிவாசகா் பதிப்பகம், சென்னை, முதற்பதிப்பு-1968ஒளிப்பறவை (1971) - அன்னம் வெளியீடு, சிவகங்கை, முதற்பதிப்பு-1971சர்ப்ப யாகம் (1976) - கோலம் வெளியீடு, பொள்ளாச்சி, முதற்பதிப்பு-1976புன்னகை பூக்கும் பூனைகள் (1982) - அன்னம் வெளியீடு, சிவகங்கை, முதற்பதிப்பு-1982மௌன மயக்கங்கள் (1982) (தமிழக அரசு பரிசு பெற்றது)சூரிய நிழல் (1990) - கோலம் வெளியீடு, பொள்ளாச்சி, முதற்பதிப்பு-1990, இரண்டாம் பதிப்பு-1995இறகு (1996) - கோலம் வெளியீடு, பொள்ளாச்சிசிற்பியின் கவிதை வானம் (1996) - (திருப்பூர் தமிழ்ச்சங்க விருது பெற்றது) மணிவாசகா் பதிப்பகம் சென்னை, முதற்பதிப்பு-1996ஒரு கிராமத்து நதி (1998) (சாகித்ய அகாதெமி விருது பெற்றது)பூஜ்யங்களின் சங்கிலி (1999) (தமிழக அரசு பரிசு பெற்றது) - கோலம் வெளியீடு, பொள்ளாச்சிபெருமூச்சுகளின் பள்ளத்தாக்கு (2001)பாரதி - கைதி எண்: 253 (2002)மூடுபனி (2003)சிற்பி: கவிதைப் பயணங்கள் (2005)தேவயானி (2006)மகாத்மா (2006)சிற்பி கவிதைகள் தொகுதி-2 (2011)நீலக்குருவி (2012)கவிதை வானம் (சிற்பியின் கவிதைத் தொகுப்பு)கவிதை நாடகம்ஆதிரை (1992)சிறுவர் நூல்கள்சிற்பி தரும் ஆத்திசூடி (1993)வண்ணப்பூக்கள் (1994)கட்டுரைகள்இலக்கியச் சிந்தனைகள் (1989)மலையாளக் கவிதை (1990)இல்லறமே நல்லறம் (1992)அலையும் சுவடும் (1994)மின்னல் கீற்று (1996)சிற்பியின் கட்டுரைகள் (1996)படைப்பும் பார்வையும் (2001)கவிதை நேரங்கள் (2003)மகாகவி (2003)நேற்றுப் பெய்த மழை (2003)காற்று வரைந்த ஓவியம் (2005)புதிர் எதிர் காலம் (2011)மனம் புகும் சொற்கள் (2011)வாழ்க்கை வரலாற்று நூல்கள்இராமானுஜர் வரலாறு (1999)ம.ப.பெரியசாமித் தூரன் (1999)பாரத ரத்னம் சி.சுப்பிரமணியம் (1999)ஆர்.சண்முகசுந்தரம் (2000)சே.ப. நரசிம்மலு நாயுடு (2003)மகாகவி பாரதியார் (2008)நம்மாழ்வார் (2008)தொண்டில் கனிந்த தூரன் (2008)கட்டுரைகள்தேனீக்களும் மக்களும் (1982)சாதனைகள் எப்போதும் சாத்தியந்தான் (கிரண்பேடி) (2006)வெள்ளிப்பனி மலையின்மீது (எம்.பி.வீரேந்திரகுமார்) (2009)இலக்கிய வரலாறுதமிழ் இலக்கிய வரலாறு (2010)மொழிபெயர்ப்பு நூல்கள்கவிதைகள்சச்சிதானந்தன் கவிதைகள் (1998)உஜ்ஜயினி (ஓ.என்.வி.குரூப்) (2001)கவிதை மீண்டும் வரும் (சச்சிதானந்தன்) (2001)காலத்தை உறங்க விடமாட்டேன் (என்.கோபி) (2010)கே.ஜி. சங்கரப்பிள்ளை கவிதைகள் (2012)நாவல்கள்அக்கினி சாட்சி (லலிதாம்பிகா அந்தர்ஜனம்) (1996) (சாகித்ய அகாதெமி விருது பெற்றது)ஒரு சங்கீதம் போல (பெரும்படவம் ஸ்ரீதரன்) (1999)வாராணசி (எம்.டி.வாசுதேவன் நாயர்) (2005)அறக்கட்டளை சொற்பொழிவு நூல்கள்கம்பனில் மானுடம் (2002)இருபதாம் நூற்றாண்டுத் தமிழ்க் கவிதை (2006)பாரதிதாசனுக்குள் பாரதி (2011)உரை நூல்கள்:திருப்பாவை: உரை (1999)திருக்குறள்: சிற்பி உரை (2001)மார்கழிப்பாவை (2009) (திருப்பாவை, திருவெம்பாவை, திருப்பள்ளியெழுச்சி உரை)தொகுப்பு நூல்கள்நதிக்கரைச் சிற்பங்கள் (2012)பதிப்பித்த நூல்கள்மகாகவி பாரதி சில மதிப்பீடுகள் (1982)பாரதி - பாரதிதாசன் படைப்புக்கலை (1992)தமிழ் உலா I & II (1993)பாரதி என்றொரு மானுடன் (1997)மருதவரை உலா (1998)நாவரசு (1998)அருட்பா அமுதம் (2001)பாரதியார் கட்டுரைகள் (2002)மண்ணில் தெரியுது வானம் (2006)கொங்கு களஞ்சியம் (2006)வளமார் கொங்கு (2010)ஆய்வுகள்தமிழ் இலக்கியத்தில் விடுதலை இயக்கத் தாக்கம் (1989 - 1991)இடைக்காலக் கொங்கு நாட்டின் சமூக - பொருளாதார அமைப்புகள் (1993 - 1997)கொங்கு களஞ்சியம் - இரு தொகுதிகளின் பதிப்பாசிரியர்மதிப்புறு பொறுப்புகள்:காந்திகிராம் பல்கலைக்கழகம், மதுரைக் காமராசர் பல்கலைக்கழகம், தமிழ்ப் பல்கலைக்கழகம், துணைவேந்தர் தேர்வுக்குழு உறுப்பினர்.சாகித்ய அகாதமி செயற்குழு உறுப்பினர் / ஒருங்கிணைப்பாளர் தமிழ் ஆலோசனைக் குழு (2008)சாகித்ய அகாதமி பொதுக்குழு / தமிழ் ஆலோசனைக் குழு உறுப்பினர் (1993 - 1998)எஸ்.ஆர்.எம். பல்கலைக்கழகம் தமிழ்ப்பேராயம் செயற்குழு, விருதுக்குழு உறுப்பினர்.தலைவர், இந்தியப் பல்கலைக்கழகத் தமிழாசிரியர் மன்றம் (2000 - 2005)தலைவர், ஞாலத் தமிழ்ப் பண்பாட்டு மன்றம் (2009)தலைவர், பி.எம்.எஸ்., அறக்கட்டளைசெயலர், பொள்ளாச்சி இலக்கியக் கழகம்உறுப்பினர், பாரதிய வித்யா பவன் நிர்வாகக் குழு, கோவைஉறுப்பினர், டாக்டர் NGP கல்லூரிக் குழு, கோவை.தமிழ்நாட்டுப் பல்கலைக்கழகங்களின் ஆசிரியர் தேர்வுக்குழு, பாடத்திட்டக்குழு முன்னாள் உறுப்பினர்பல்கலைக்கழக மானியக்குழு, மத்திய அரசு பண்பாட்டுத்துறை, மத்திய அலுவலர் தேர்வாணையம், தமிழ்நாடு அரசு செயலர் தேர்வாணையத் தேர்வுக்குழு முன்னாள் உறுப்பினர்உறுப்பினர், நிர்வாகக்குழு, பாரதியவித்யா பவன், கோவைபப்பாசி, புதியதலைமுறை, இளையராஜா அமைத்த பாவலர் வரதராஜன் நினைவு விருதுக்கான தேர்வுக்குழு உறுப்பினர்."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'mati dicatuk katak'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang berkuasa dikalahkan (dihina) oleh orang yang lemah"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\"  Bingo manao matso ka ...................................... \\" ","answer":"\\"  Bingo manao matso ka misalovana ny anjaran' ny sasany. \\" "},{"question":"ọdún wo ni a dá ìpínlẹ̀ Rivers sílẹ̀?","answer":"Ọdún 1967"},{"question":"दिए गए प्रश्न का उत्तर दीजिए।प्रश्न:  कोरोना वायरस 2019 का पहला केस कहां सामने आया ?","answer":"उत्तर: चीन में वुहान में"},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:ભાવિનો વિચાર પ્રથમથી કરી શકે તે","answer":"દૂરંદેશી "},{"question":"من أول من قاتل بالسيف ؟","answer":"\\tابراهيم عليه السلام"},{"question":"Kín ni orúkọ gómínà ìpínlẹ̀ Násáráwá?","answer":"Abdullahi Sule ni."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي شروط وجوب الزكاة؟","answer":"الإجابة: الإسلام، الحرية، بلوغ النصاب، تمام الملك، مضي الحول إلا في خارج الأرض"},{"question":"السؤال: كم عدد العظام في الجسم ؟","answer":"الإجابة: 206"},{"question":"வினா: எந்த விலங்குக்கு வயிற்றில் பற்கள் உள்ளன?","answer":"விடை: நண்டுகள்"},{"question":"من الخليفة الأموي الذي لقب بصقر قريش؟","answer":"عبد الرحمن الداخل"},{"question":"May nakita akong tatlong bisikleta at limang kotse sa parke kanina. Ilang gulong ang nakita ko?","answer":"May dalawang gulong ang bawat bisikleta, habang may apat na gulong naman ang bawat kotse. Sa kabuuan, may nakita kang (2 x 3) + (5 x 4) = 26 o dalawampu't anim na gulong."},{"question":"Sta je \\"Sveto Rimsko Carstvo\\" (Holy Roman Empire)? ","answer":"Sveto Rimsko Carstvo (na nemačkom: Heiliges Römisches Reich) bilo je složena politička struktura koja je postojala u srednjovekovnoj Evropi od sredine 10. veka pa sve do 1806. godine. Ovo carstvo se smatra naslednikom Zapadnog Rimskog Carstva, iako nije imalo direktne teritorijalne veze sa starim Rimom.Carstvo je počelo da se formira tokom 10. veka pod vladavinom nemačkih kraljeva koji su postali poznati kao carevi Svetog Rimskog Carstva. Ovi vladari su težili da ožive ideju univerzalnog hrišćanskog carstva koje bi bilo središte hrišćanskog sveta, pod duhovnim vodstvom pape.Međutim, uprkos nazivu, Sveto Rimsko Carstvo nije bilo ni sveto, ni rimsko, ni carstvo u pravom smislu reči. Bilo je to više labava federacija stotina manjih i većih teritorijalnih jedinica koje su uključivale kraljevine, vojvodstva, grofovije, slobodne gradove i biskupska kneževstva. Moć carstva često je bila ograničena, a autoritet cara varirao od regiona do regiona.Tokom svoje istorije, Sveto Rimsko Carstvo bilo je centar brojnih političkih, verskih i kulturnih događaja. Bilo je ključno u razvoju srednjovekovne Evrope, posebno u kontekstu feudalnog sistema, crkvene politike, i razvoja ranih oblika državnosti.Carstvo je prestalo da postoji 1806. godine, kada je poslednji car, Franja II, abdicirao pod pritiskom Napoleona Bonaparte. Njegov kraj označio je značajnu prekretnicu u evropskoj istoriji i dao put za formiranje modernih evropskih država."},{"question":"متحد المال څه شی دی؟","answer":"ځواب: توحید المال له هغو مکتوبونو او لارښوونو څخه عبارت دی چې د صالحو چارواکو له خوا د یو لړ خاصو موضوعاتو په اړه د تابعدارۍ ادارې ته ورکول کیږي."},{"question":"Kan moo fent NOKIA? ","answer":"Fredrik Idestam et Leo Mechelin moo fent Nokia."},{"question":"එක්දින ජාත්‍යන්තර තරඟවලදී වැඩිම දවාගැනීම් සංඛ්‍යාවක් සඳහා දායක වූ ක්‍රීඩකයා කවුද?","answer":"මාක් බවුච(ර්)"},{"question":"Peters is nachtwaker in een groot bedrijf. Op een zekere ochtend als Peters naar huis wil gaan zegt zijn baas tegen hem: \\"Ik ga op zakenreis naar Noorwegen. Morgen vertrek ik vanaf Schiphol.\\" Peters raadt hem echter dringend aan om de boot te nemen. \\"Hoe dat zo?\\" vraagt de directeur. \\"Wel,\\" is het antwoord, \\"ik droomde vannacht dat het vliegtuig naar Noorwegen vlak voor de landing neerstortte.\\" De directeur lacht er eerst om, maar bijgelovig als hij is, hij gaat toch met de boot. In Noorwegen aangekomen hoort hij dat het vliegtuig waarvoor hij in eerste instantie gekozen had inderdaad een ongeluk heeft gehad. Terug in Nederland laat hij bij Peters een grote bos bloemen bezorgen, geeft hem een grote beloning en ontslaat hem op staande voet! Kunt u dit volgen??? ","answer":" Een nachtwaker hoort niet te dromen als hij aan het werk is. "},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 総務省によると、去年、東京都に引っ越してきた人は43万9787人でした。東京都からほかの所に出ていった人は40万1764人でした。引っ越してきた人のほうが約3万8000人多くなりました。","answer":"東京都の23区では、おととし初めて、出ていった人のほうが多くなりました。しかし、去年はまた、引っ越してきた人のほうが約2万1400人多くなりました。 総務省は「新型コロナウイルスの問題で、東京に来るのをやめていた人が引っ越してきたのだと思います。東京にまた人がたくさん集まってくるのか、注目しています」と言っています。"},{"question":"હેરી પોટર શ્રેણીમાં રમત તરીકે ક્વિડિચની ભૂમિકાનું શું મહત્વ છે?","answer":"ક્વિડિચ, હાઇ-ફ્લાઇંગ વિઝાર્ડિંગ સ્પોર્ટ, હોગવર્ટ્સમાં એકીકૃત બળ તરીકે સેવા આપે છે, ટીમ વર્ક, સ્પર્ધાત્મકતા અને વિદ્યાર્થીઓમાં વહેંચાયેલ જુસ્સોને પ્રોત્સાહન આપે છે."},{"question":"Ọwọ tẹ Tọpẹ nibi to ti n fọle onile l’Ondo","answer":"Diẹ lo ku ki wọn dana sun afurasi adigunjale kan, Tọpẹ Owolabi, tọwọ tẹ nibi to ti n fọ ile onile niluu Ondo laaarọ ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ọsẹ to kọja.Ọkunrin ẹni ọgbọn ọdun ọhun ni wọn ba nibi to ti n jale ninu ile kan ti wọn n kọ lọwọ lagbegbe Elewuro, Sunbreaker, lọjọ naa.Ẹni to nile ọhun, Oloye Justinah Ogunsusi Ọlabanji, ṣalaye pe oun ti n palẹmọ lati ko wa sinu ile naa loṣu to n bọ yii. O ni diẹ lara agbado ti wọn gbin sinu ọgba ile tuntun naa toun atawọn eeyan kan fẹẹ waa kore lo tu Tọpẹ lasiiri.Mama yii ni lẹyin tawọn ya  agbado tan loun sọ fun ọkan ninu awọn tawọn jọ lọ pe ko ṣilẹkun ki wọn le wo ibi ti wọn ba iṣẹ ile ọhun de.Gbogbo igbiyanju wọn lati ri ilẹkun ṣi lo ja si pabo,nitori ẹnikan wa ninu ile lọhun-un to ti tilẹkun lẹyin. Nibi ti wọn ti n pe wẹda ti wọn ra ilẹkun lọwọ rẹ lori aago ni ọkan ninu wọn ti kofiri afurasi naa lati oju ferese.Lẹyin bii bii ọgbọn isẹju tí wọn ti n pariwo ni afurasi adigunjale yii too ṣilẹkun, lo ba doju ija nla kọ awọn gende mẹtẹẹta to tẹle mama oloye ọhun lọjọ naa.Meji ninu wọn lo sa ladaa, to si tun ba awọn dukia mi-ín jẹ nibi to ti n wa gbogbo ọna lati sa mọ wọn lọwọ.Pẹlu iranlọwọ awọn araadugbo ni wọn fi pada ri afurasi ọdaran yii mu. Bi wọn ṣe de e lokun tan lawọn ọdọ kan ti fẹẹ dana sun un, awọn agbaagba to wa nitosi ni wọn bẹ wọn, lẹyin eyi ni wọn ranṣẹ sawọn ọlọpaa to wa ni teṣan Yaba, niluu Ondo, lati waa gbe e.Oriṣiiriṣii kọkọrọ ile, waya ina atawọn ohun eelo mi-ín ni wọn ba loke aja ti afurasi naa ko wọn pamọ si.Afurasi ọdaran ọhun ṣalaye fun akọroyin wa pe ọmọ bibi ipinlẹ Ọsun loun, o ni iṣẹ kapẹnta loun n ṣe lagbegbe Ifẹ Garage, niluu Ondo. O ni ọrẹ oun kan to n jẹ Kunle lo gbe oun wa sinu ile naa, bawọn si ṣe wọle tan lo tilẹkun, to si pada lọ ni tirẹ.Ọkan ninu awọn to wa nibi iṣẹlẹ yii ni Kunle wa lara awọn oṣiṣẹ to ba iya onile ọhun fa ina sinu ile rẹ,  o ṣee ṣe ko jẹ asiko naa lo raaye rọ awọn ẹda kọkọrọ toun ati ọrẹ rẹ fi wọle laaarọ ọjọ naa lati ji awọn ẹru ẹlẹru ko."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Hugh Lane. ","answer":"Ba dhéileálaí ealaíne Éireannach é Sir Hugh Percy Lane (9 Samhain 1875 – 7 Bealtaine 1915). An cháil is mó atá atá air ná gur bhunaigh sé an chéad dánlann nua-ealaíne sa domhan in Éirinn. Is é seo Dánlann Hugh Lane, atá suite ar Chearnóg Pharnell i mBaile Átha Cliath. Rugadh Hugh Lane do James William Lane agus Frances Adelaide Persse. Ba as Corcaigh muintir Lane agus as Gaillimh muintir Persse agus bhí Lady Gregory ina aintín leis. Tógadh Hugh Lane i gCorn na Breataine i Sasana, cé gur rugadh é in Éirinn, i gContae Chorcaí. Bhí sé ina dhéileálaí ealaíne i Londain faoin mbliain 1901.Tar éis dó cuairt a thabhairt ar a aintín, Lady Gregory, in Éirinn agus taispeántas péintéireachta comhaimseartha a fheiceáil ansin, shamhlaigh Lane go bhféadfaí dánlann a bhunú ina bhféadfaí an chuid is fearr d'ealaín nua-aimseartha na hÉireann agus an domhain mhór a chur ar taispeáint, taobh le taobh. Ón am sin ar aghaidh, dhírigh Lane a chuir iarrachtaí go léir ar bhailiú na healaíne nua-aimseartha ó Éirinn, Sasana agus ón Mór-Roinn, don dánlann nua. Osclaíodh an dánlann nua seo ar 20 Eanáir 1908 i dTeach Clonmell ar Shráid Fhearcair, i mBaile Átha Cliath. Ach bhí deacrachtaí le hionad buan a fháil don bhailiúchán agus bhí Lane féin imithe ar shlí na fírinne sular lonnaíodh an bailiúchán i ndánlann bhuan, i dTeach Charlemont ar Chearnóg Pharnell.Fuair Lane bás mar phaisinéir ar an RMS Lusitania, nuair a cuireadh an long sin go tóin poill le toirpéad ó fhomhuireán Gearmánach le linn an Chéad Chogaidh Dhomhanda."},{"question":"கேள்வி: சிற்பி பாலசுப்பிரமணியம் எத்தனை முறை சாகித்திய அகாதெமி விருதைப் பெற்றுள்ளார்?","answer":"பதில்: சாகித்திய அகாதெமி விருதைப் சிற்பி பாலசுப்பிரமணியன் இரு முறை பெற்றுள்ளார் . 1.மொழிபெயர்ப்புக்காகவும், 2.‘ஒரு கிராமத்து நதி’ என்னும் கவிதை நூலிற்காகவும் சாகித்திய அகாதெமி விருதைப் சிற்பி பாலசுப்பிரமணியம் பெற்றுள்ளார்."},{"question":"Mfenge-mfenge","answer":"Weak person"},{"question":"चांद्रयान-३ चे टोकन जारी करणारी कोणती मेट्रो सेवा देशातील पहिली मेट्रो सेवा ठरली आहे?(A)  नागपूर(B)  कोलकाता(C)  केरळ(D)  चेन्नई","answer":"(B) कोलकाता"},{"question":"Ahoana ny fomba hanombanana tsara ny fahombiazan'ny mpianatra iray?","answer":"Ny fomba fanombanana ny fahombiazan'ny mpianatra dia ahitana ny fampiasany fitaovana isan-karazany toy ny fitsapana, asa an-tsoratra, tetikasa, fifanakalozan-kevitra ao an-dakilasy, ary fandinihana mitohy mba hahazoana sary feno momba ny fahatakarany sy ny fahaizany."},{"question":"Varginha (MG) é famosa por?","answer":"Varginha é famosa por ser a cidade do ET."},{"question":"வினா : முதல் இஸ்லாமிய பெண் பிரதமர் யார்?","answer":"விடை : பெனாசீர் புட்டோ"},{"question":"ભારતીય પરિષદ અધિનિયમ ૧૯૦૯ જણાવો","answer":"આ અધિનિયમ મોર્લે-મિન્ટો સુધારા તરીકે પણ ઓળખવામાં આવે છે. જે અંતર્ગત કાઉન્સિલોનું વિસ્તરણ કરવામાં આવ્યું. ઈન્ડિયન લેજીસ્લેટીવ કાઉન્સિલની સભ્ય સંખ્યા ૧૬ થી વધારીને ૬૦ કરવામાં આવી. આ ધારા હેઠળ સૌ પ્રથમવાર ચૂંટણી વ્યવસ્થાનો પ્રારંભ કરવામાં આવ્યો. જે અંતર્ગત મુસ્લિમો માટે અલગ પ્રતિનિધિત્ત્વની જોગવાઈ કરવામાં આવી."},{"question":"வினா: பூமிக்கு மிக அருகில் உள்ள நட்சத்திரம் எது?","answer":"விடை: சூரியன்"},{"question":"नेपालमा हुने प्राकृतिक गतिविधिहरु के के छन् ?","answer":"चरा अवलोकन, हिमाल अवलोकन, वन अन्वेषण, पुतली अवलोकन, नगरकोट सूर्योदय र सूर्यास्त, सिमसार क्षेत्र आदि नेपालमा सञ्चालन हुने प्राकृतिक गतिविधिहरु हुन्।"},{"question":"ఎముక ముక్కలు, గుండ్లు, మొక్కల అవశేషాలు ఉన్న రాళ్ళు ఎక్కువగా ఉన్నాయి మీ జవాబును ఎంచుకోండిః (ఎ). స్ఫటికాలు; (B). అగ్నియుక్త; (సి). అవక్షేప; (డి) మెటామార్ఫిక్;","answer":"సి).  అవక్షేప"},{"question":"\\"Nahazo fanasana ho amin'ny hetsika fiantrana izay tsy natrehiko nandritra ny taona maro aho:\\"Inona no mety ho fiafaran'ny tantara teo aloha?A. Nahafinaritra ny hetsika, feno fitiavan-tena ary nifandray indray tamin'ny namana taloha.B. Nanjary tsy voalamina tsara ny hetsika, tsy nisy fiantraikany firy, ka nahatonga ahy nanontany tena ny fahombiazany.","answer":"B. no fiafarana mitombona indrindra."},{"question":"🎶 Эл сүйгөн обондордон Элмирбек Иманалиевдин \\"Булбулум\\"-ырынын сөзү кайсы?🎧","answer":"Ар кечте, ар таңда боздоп сайрап,Армандуу сезимди козгоп сайрап.Бир булбул буулугуп келет күндө,Биз жүрчү алма бакты болжоп сайрап.Ал бакта адашып күүгүм калган,Ар шакта алмадай сүйүүм калган.Ал сүйүүм булбулга айланганбы?Ашыгын издеген үрүл таңдан.Кайырма:Булбулум, булбулум, ай,Буулуккан кургурум, ай.Бул кечте үнүң баспай,Буулуктуң неге мынча, ай,Булбулум, булбулум, ай?Жашайсың, жаш булбул, токтобогон,Жашоодо жан жок, эй боздобогон.Жашыймын көп эстеп ал күндөрдү,Жаштыгым жаштыкка, эй, окшобогон.Сайрашың өткөндү эске салып,Санааркайм, ал күндөр четте калып.Буулуккан булбулдай сени жоктойм,Буйруксуз сүйүүмдү эстеп алып.Кайырма:Ар кечте, ар таңда боздоп сайрап,Азгырып сезимди козгоп сайрап.Бир булбул буулугуп келет күндө,Биз жүрчү алма бакты болжоп сайрап.Ал бакта адашып күүгүм калган,Ар шакта алмадай сүйүүм калган.Ал сүйүүм булбулга айланганбы?Ашыгын издеген үрүл таңдан."},{"question":"ਚੀਕਣੀ ਮਿੱਟੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਚੀਕਣੇ ਕਣਾਂ ਦੀ ਮਾਤਰਾ ਦੱਸੋ ।","answer":"ਘੱਟੋ-ਘੱਟ 40 ਪ੍ਰਤੀਸ਼ਤ ਚੀਕਣ ਕਣ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"Ity misy odidina tantara iray : « Satria nihidy moa ny tanàna tamin’izany fotoana izany dia nikatona ny sekoly ary tsy nianatra izahay. Rehefa manati-bary ho azy mivady aho, matetika mijanona maharitra eo aminy eo. Dia mba itantarany lovantsofina eo. Izay no mba hany tsaroako niresahan-dry zareo lava tamiko. »Raha mamorona fanontaniana isika miainga avy amin’io odidina io ka ny valiny dia « lovantsofina » dia inona ?","answer":"Inona no fitantaran’izy mivady amiko rehefa manati-bary azy ireo aho ?"},{"question":"Fenoy ity ohabolana ity: \\"Ny fitiavana maloto toy ny lomotra ambony vato ___\\"","answer":"\\"Ny fitiavana maloto toy ny lomotra ambony vato ka raha diavina mandavo.\\""},{"question":"ਮੁੰਡੇ ਨੇ ਪੈਨਸਿਲ ਨੂੰ ਤਿੱਖਾ ਕੀਤਾ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਇਹ ਸਸਤੀ ਸੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਇਹ ਫਿੱਕੀ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਇਹ ਫਿੱਕੀ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Aon leideanna maidir le conas rud a scríobh tú a athbhreithniú?","answer":"Is é an t-athbhreithniú go bunúsach rud éigin a scríobh tú cheana féin a shocrú agus a fheabhsú, áit nach bhfuil tú ag dul é a athscríobh arís agus arís, agus áit nach bhfuil aon rud nua á chur leis. Bhuel, is smaoineamh maith é an leagan bunaidh a léamh ar ais cúpla uair. Go háirithe má bhraitheann tú go raibh sé deacair é a scríobh, d'fhéadfadh go mbeadh tentation ort go leor eagarthóireachta a dhéanamh, chun rudaí a shláintú. Is féidir leat athruithe a dhéanamh a fheabhsaíonn soiléireacht, nó léitheoireacht. Mar shampla, má d'úsáid tú go leor idioms a d'fhéadfadh daoine a bheith ag trioblóid a thuiscint, ansin is féidir leat iad a aistriú, nó d'fhéadfá iad a dhéanamh níos soiléire."},{"question":" இரண்டாம் உலகப் போரின் போது 1943 வங்காளப் பஞ்சத்தில்","answer":"30 இலட்சம் மக்கள் பட்டினியால் இறந்தனர்."},{"question":"तामाङ समुदायको \\"सोरथी\\" नृत्य र संगीतको सांस्कृतिक महत्व वर्णन गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"सोरठी तामाङ समुदायको परम्परागत नृत्य र संगीत विधा हो, जुन प्रायः चाडपर्व र सामाजिक जमघटहरूमा प्रदर्शन गरिन्छ।"},{"question":"बैंक दर किसके द्वारा तय की जाती है?","answer":"बैंक दर भारतीय रिज़र्व बैंक द्वारा तय की जाती है ।बैंक दर से तात्पर्य उस ब्याज दर से है जिस पर रिज़र्व बैंक भारत में वाणिज्यिक बैंकों को ऋण देता है। इसे 'छूट दर' के रूप में भी जाना जाता है। बैंक दर घरेलू बैंकों की वित्तीय आवश्यकताओं को पूरा करती है जब वे घाटे में होते हैं।RBI द्विमासिक मौद्रिक नीति समीक्षा में बैंक दर निर्धारित करता है। दीर्घकालिक प्रकृति के कारण यह रेपो दर से अधिक है।जब आरबीआई बैंक दर बढ़ाता है, तो घरेलू बैंकों से उधार लेने की लागत बढ़ जाती है, जिसके परिणामस्वरूप बाजार में धन की आपूर्ति में कमी आती है।बैंक दर वसूलते समय, कोई संपार्श्विक शामिल नहीं होता है।भारतीय रिज़र्व बैंक अधिनियम की धारा 49 बैंक दर निर्धारित करती है।एमएसएफ (मार्जिनल स्टैंडिंग फैसिलिटी), जो आरबीआई द्वारा रातोंरात ऋण देने की सुविधा है, बैंक दर से जुड़ी हुई है।2022 तक, RBI द्वारा बैंक दर 5.15% है"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'dibakar tiada hangus, direndam tiada basah'?","answer":"Ianya bermaksud tidak dapat dikalahkan (kerana degil, berkuasa, dan lain-lain)."},{"question":"Waa maxay tawxiidu-asmaa wa sifaat?","answer":"Tawxiidu al-asmaa wa sifaat (Al-asmaa= magacyada Ilaahay) (Wa sifaa=sifooyinka) waa in la qiro magacyada iyo tilmaamaha Eebbe isu qiray iyadoon leexinayn macnahooda, loogana metaal (metaal=tusaale) qaadanahayn magacyada iyo sifooyinka makhluuqiisa (makhluuq= waa wixiiAlle abuuray). Tusaale ahaan, Alle wax wuu maqlaa waxna wuu arkaa, haddana cid la mid ahi ma jirto."},{"question":"ایرانیان باستان تا چه اندازه با علم نجوم آشنا بودند و با استفاده از این علم چه چیزی را بوجود آوردند؟","answer":"ایرانیان باستان در علم نجوم پیشرفت خوبی داشتند و با سنجش و تعیین زمان به خوبی آشنا بودند و چون برای فعالیت‌های کشاورزی که در فصول خاصی ازسال انجام می‌گرفت به تقویم نیاز داشتند، تقویم خورشیدی را به وجود آوردند و سال را به ۱۲ ماه ۳۰ روزه تقسیم کردند. این تقویم از کم نظیرترین تقویم‌های دنیا است"},{"question":"Эмнеге энергетик суусундуктары зыян?","answer":"Мындай суусундук, реакциянын ылдамдыгын ашырат, бирок, мындай ылдамдыктагы маалыматты кабыл алууга эмес, тескерисинче, аны мээ сактап калууга турушутук бере албайт. Эгер, бир нече бөтөлкөсүн ичкенде, мээ реакциясы көтөрүлбөй эле, төмөндөп кетет.Жана ошондой эле, жүрөк уруусу көтөрүлөт (давление)"},{"question":"درج ذیل جملے کا اردو میں ترجمہ کریں:.Most people think that health and fitness are the same thing but there is a difference","answer":" ترجمہ:اکثر لوگ سوچتے ہیں کہ صحت اور تندرستی ایک ہی چیز ہیں لیکن ان میں فرق ہے۔"},{"question":"Jam’iyyun siyasa nawa ne suka yi rajista a zaben 2019 a Najeriya?","answer":"Jam'iyyu 18."},{"question":"ఈ క్రింది వాక్యాలను పరిశీలించండి.i) కిరణజన్య సంయోగక్రియలో గ్లూకోజ్, నీరు మరియు ఆక్సీజన్లు అంత్య పదార్థాలుగా ఏర్పడతాయి.ii) కిరణజన్య సంయోగక్రియలో నీటి అణువు విచ్ఛిత్తి చెందటం ఒక ముఖ్యమైన సంఘటన.A) (i) – సత్యము, (ii) – సత్యముB) (i) – అసత్యము, (ii) అసత్యముC) (i) – సత్యము, (ii) – అసత్యముD) (i) – అసత్యము, (ii) – సత్యము","answer":"A) (i) – సత్యము, (ii) – సత్యము"},{"question":"Orúkọ Àdúgbò ní Ègbá àti Àwórì, Ìpínlẹ̀ Ògùn, Nàìjíríà","answer":"1. Ìta oseìn: ibi tí àwon ajagun tí màa ń bo soìnmolè tí wón bá fé lò jagun, ni ìgbákìgbá tí wón bá ti boo shin náà wòn maánsègun. 2. Pansekè: igi kan ni tí ó ní èso, tì éso náà bá ti gbe yóò máa dun sékéséké, ibi tí igi na ise ni aso3. Onikólóbo: àdúgbò ti won tí lo kolobo láti gba owó okò ní ayé àtijó4. Aké: àdúgbò orí rún ègbá, ààfin agbogbo ègbá.5. Ìmó: agbolé, tí won tí amò tí ó dára jù légbà6. Àjítàádùn: isé àádùn síse ni emit í ó kókó te àdúgbò náà dó ń se.7. Arule olónì: ní ayé àtijó èni kan wà tí won máa ń sìn ní abúlé yìí8. Ìta Èko: Àdúgbò tí wón tí ń ta èko, ní ìgbà náà ibè nìkan ni wón ti ń ta èko.9. Ìjàyè: Ibi tí àwon ará ìbàdàn tèdó sí ní ìgbà tí won ja ogun àjàyè10. Àgó òwu: Àdúgbò tí ajagun tà kan ní ìlú ìbàdàn tí ó jé akódé tèdó sí.11. Sàpón: Ní ayé àtijó ìyá a kan wà tí ó jé wípé èwà ní ó máa ń tà èyì sì se ànfàń púpò fún àwon àpón tí kòì tí láya, ní ìgbà kígbà tí ó wun àwon àpón yìó ní wón máa ń lo ra èwà tí ó sì jé pé wón á rí ìyá eléwà yìí níbè ìdí éléyìí ni a se ń pè ìyá eléwà yìí ní sàpón lóore.12. Adédòtun: Orúko bale tí ó kókó tèdó sí Àdúgbò yen ní wón fi ń pèé.13. Ìdí Àrà: Igi ńlá kan wàn ní àdúgbò yìí ní ayé àti jó tí ó jé wípé ìgbà túgbà tí àwon àgbè bá ń ti oko bò wón máa ń simi sí abé igi náà nítorí pé ibojì àti atégùn wà ní abé igi náà.14. Ìjógun: Àdúgbò tí àwon àwórì tí ńjagun ní ayé àti jo ìdí ògún ni wón pè ní ìdógun15. Ìmòré: Ní ayé àtijo igi kan wà tí ó ń so èso kan tí à ń pè ni òré, igi yìí pò ní àdúgbò yìí tí ó fi jé pé nígbà tí wón tèdó sí bè ni wón soódi imòòré.16. Ìrobè: Àdúgbò tí awon aborè tí máa ń fi ènìyàn bore, ìdí èyí ni wón fi ń pèé ní ìborè.17. Ojà Àgbó: Agboolé yìí jé ibi tí àwon tí ó kòkòtèdó síbè tí ń sé isé òsìn eran, wón dó ojà sílè tí won ti ńta àgbò, ní torú ìdí èyí ni wón se so ibè ní òjà àgbò.18. Ìlú Gùn: Àdúgbò yìí jé àdúgbò tí ó gùn jù ní gbogbo ègbá.19. Ìjejà: Ní ìgbà kan Oba kan náà ní àdúgbò yìí tí o burú tí ó sì jé wí pé àsé tí ó bá pa ní abé gé. Ó so fún àwon ará ìlú rè ní ojó kan wí pé tí won bá náa ojà sùgbón wok o, Oba pàsè kí wón lo je ojà náà run.20. Láfénwá: Orúko eni tí ó kókó àdúgbò yìí ni oláféniwá ìdí èyí ni wón fi so àdúgbò yìí ni orúko eni tí ó kókó tebè dó.21. Mókóla: Ní ayé ojo un ní ìgbà tí àwon ajagunlà ti ń jagun, wón jagun wón kérú wón kérù, ibi tí wón dé simi tí wón kó àwon erù won sí ni wón sinmi sí ibè tí wón pè ní omokólá.22. Asérò: Abúlé yìí ni àwon kan kókó tèdó sí tí ogun fí léewá, nígbà tí wón dé ibè, bí tí n sì bò ní ibi tí wón lo gégé bí àwon èrò se pò tó ní wón ti sì dé ibi tí wón tèdó sí, ibi tí wón sit i sí kúrò ní wón ń pè ní Asérò23. Ìgbésa: Àdúgbò yìí jé ibi kan tí ó jé pé igbó ni ó pò níbè télè sùgbón ìgbà tí àwon ènìyàn tèdó síbè ní ó di ìlú èyí ni wón se ń pè ní igbésà.24. Ìkujà: Jé abúlé kan tí akínkanjú kan ti kòyá fún àwon ará abúlé lówó àwon adigun jalè Akinkanjú yìí máa ń jà, ìdí èyí ni wón fi ń pè é ní ìkijà.25. Kútò: Ikútòmíwá ni àpè sale orúko yìí ní ìgbà kan okùnrin kan wà ní abúlé kan tí ó jé ohun nìkàn ni ó ń gbé ibè, ní ojó tí eranko búburu kan wá bá ní ibi tí ó ń gbé ni eran kò náà paá je kí ó tó kú ni ó ké tí enìkan fi gbó ohùn rè tí ó si sàlà yé fún ìdí èyí ni wón fi so abúlé ní kútò.26. Olósun: Ení tí ó ti bè dó jé abo òsun tí wón sì ń pèé ni eni tí ó òsun tí ó di Olósun báyìí.27. Ológùn-ún: Ìse Òde ni eni tí ó kókó dé bè n se tí ó sì máa ń bo ògún nígbà tí ó bá ti oko ode dé tí owó si de tí wón sì ń pèé ní ilé eni tí ó ń bo ògún, tí won ń dàpè ni ilé Ológùn-ún báyìí.28. Ìbèrè kòdó: Okùnrin tí won fi ń be àpèjúwe ibí yìí kò dó sí ilé yìí, eni tí ó jé àbúrò rè ni ó wá padà dó sí ilè yìí. Béèrè ni won máa ń pe ègbón ni tiwon gégé bí ó se wà ní àwon ìlú tàbí agbègbè kòòkàn lode òní, tí okùnrin náà sì máa ń so fún òpòlopò ènìyàn pe ibí yìí ló ye kí béérè òun dó sí, sùgbón tí kò dó síbè, òun yóò wá máa pe ibí yìí ni “ìbi tí béérè kò dó sí” tí won ń dà pè ní Ìbèrèkòdó báyìí.29. Ìgbórè: Bàbá kan àti ìyàwó rè ni wón ń rìn kiri tí wón fid é ibi tí àdúgbò yìí wa báyìí, wón gbé erèé lówó wón sì gbo ó ni ibè wón sì fi din àkàrà je, Báyìí ni wón ń se àpèjúwe ibe ni “Ibi tí àwon ti gbo erèé” tí o di Ìgbórè báyìí30. Ìbàsà: Ibí yìí jé ibì kan tí wón tí ń bo àwon àsà ilè Yorùbá ní ayé ìgbà náà, wón sì so ibè ní ilé “ibo àsà tí ó di Ibasa lónìí."},{"question":"ما هو الشئ الذي يمكن كسره دون ان نلمسه؟\\t","answer":"الوعد"},{"question":"Content: ఇప్పటివరకూ భారత్ ఆస్ట్రేలియాతో ఆ దేశంలో ఆడిన ఏ టెస్ట్ సిరీస్‌లోనూ మొదటి మ్యాచ్ గెలవలేదు. ఇప్పుడు అడిలైడ్ టెస్టులో విజయంతో భారత్ ఆ రికార్డు  కూడా బద్దలు కొట్టింది.భారత్ ఈ విజయంతో ఆస్ట్రేలియా గడ్డపై జరిగిన సిరీస్ తొలి టెస్టులో ఆ దేశాన్ని ఓడించిన రెండో ఆసియా దేశంగా నిలిచింది.ఇంతకు ముందు పాకిస్తాన్‌కు ఇలాంటి విజయమే దక్కింది. ఇప్పుడు టీమిండియా అరుదైన విజయంపై బీసీసీఐ సంతోషం వ్యక్తం చేసింది.పోస్ట్ of Twitter ముగిసింది, 1\\"అడిలైడ్‌తో 'లవ్ అఫైర్‌'లో టీమిండియా మరో అద్భుత అద్యాయం జోడించిందని\\" బీసీసీఐ ట్విటర్‌లో పోస్ట్ చేసింది.ఈ విజయంతో కెప్టెన్ కోహ్లీ దక్షిణాఫ్రికా, ఇంగ్లండ్, ఆస్ట్రేలియాలో టెస్ట్ మ్యాచ్ గెలిచిన మొట్టమొదటి ఆసియా కెప్టెన్‌గా అరుదైన ఘనత సాధించాడు. అశ్విన్ మొత్తం ఈ మ్యాచ్‌లో ఆరు వికెట్లు తీశాడు. ఆస్ట్రేలియాలో ఇది అతడి అత్యుత్తమ ప్రదర్శన ఇది బౌలర్ల విజయంఈ మ్యాచ్‌లో భారత బౌలర్లు కట్టుదిట్టంగా బౌలింగ్ చేశారు. ఆస్ట్రేలియా బ్యాట్స్‌మెన్లను ఏ దశలోనూ కోలుకోకుండా చేశారు.అందుకే, విజయం తర్వాత తన బౌలర్లను కెప్టెన్ విరాట్ కోహ్లీ ఆకాశానికెత్తేశాడు. బౌలర్లు తమకు వచ్చిన ప్రతి అవకాశాన్ని సమర్థంగా ఉపయోగించుకున్నారని చెప్పాడు. పుజారా, రహానే బ్యాటింగ్‌పై కూడా ప్రశంసించాడు. ఇద్దరూ ఈ విజయానికి పునాదులు వేశారన్నాడు. మిడిల్ ఆర్డర్ తర్వాత అందరూ వరసగా పెవిలియన్ చేరడంపై ఆందోళన వ్యక్తం చేశాడు.ఈ విజయం తర్వాత సునీల్ గావస్కర్ \\"భారత్ మొదటి ఇన్నింగ్స్‌లో 15 పరుగుల లీడ్ వచ్చినా ఆత్మవిశ్వాసంతో కనిపించిందని\\" అన్నారు. \\"ఈ ఓటమితో  ఆస్ట్రేలియాపై కచ్చితంగా ఒత్తిడి పెరుగుతుంది\\" అని అన్నారు.పదేళ్ల క్రితం ఇదే అద్భుతం2008 తర్వాత భారత్ ఆస్ట్రేలియాపై మళ్లీ టెస్టుల్లో విజయం సాధించింది.2008లో జనవరి 16-20 మధ్య జరిగిన టెస్ట్‌ మ్యాచ్‌లో భారత్ విజయం తర్వాత మళ్లీ ఆ జట్టు ఆస్ట్రేలియా గడ్డపై ఆస్ట్రేలియాను ఓడించడం ఇప్పుడే జరిగింది.పెర్త్, డబ్ల్యుఏసీఏ గ్రౌండ్‌లో భారత్ 72 పరుగుల తేడాతో గెలిచిన ఆ మ్యాచ్‌లో ఇర్ఫాన్ పఠాన్ మ్యాన్ ఆఫ్ ద మ్యాచ్‌గా నిలిచాడు.ఉత్కంఠగా సాగిన పెర్త్ టెస్ట్ ఆ మ్యాచ్‌ కూడా అడిలైడ్ టెస్ట్‌లాగే పోటాపోటీగా జరిగింది. భారత్ తొలి ఇన్నింగ్స్‌లో 330 పరుగులు చేసింది. రాహుల్ ద్రావిడ్ 93 పరుగులు చేశాడు.తర్వాత బ్యాటింగ్ చేసిన ఆస్ట్రేలియా తొలి ఇన్నింగ్స్‌లో 212 పరుగులకు ఆలౌట్ అయ్యింది. 2008లో టెస్ట్ ","answer":"ఆస్ట్రేలియాలో ఆతిథ్య దేశంపై తొలి టెస్టులోనే విజయం సాధించిన భారత్ ఎన్నో రికార్డులు అందుకుంది."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : భారతదేశంలో అంతరిక్షంలోకి ఉపగ్రహాలను ప్రవేశపెట్టే సంస్థ ఏది? కొన్ని భారతీయ ఉపగ్రహాల పేర్లు తెల్పండి.","answer":"భారత అంతరిక్ష పరిశోధనా సంస్థ (ISRO) శ్రీహరికోటలోని తన ప్రయోగ కేంద్రం నుండి ఉపగ్రహాలను అంతరిక్షంలోకి ప్రవేశపెడుతుంది. ఇస్రో మాజీ చైర్మన్ సతీశ్ ధావన్ జ్ఞాపకార్థం దీనికి “సతీష్ ధావన్ స్పేస్ సెంటర్ (SDSC) శ్రీహరికోట హై ఆల్టిట్యూడ్ రేంజ్ (SHAR)” అని పేరు పెట్టారు.కొన్ని భారతీయ ఉపగ్రహాలు : ఇన్సాట్ (INSAT), ఐ ఆర్ ఎస్ (IRS), ఎడ్యుశాట్ (EDUSAT) మొదలైనవి."},{"question":"Sumasali ka sa swimming finals sa Olympics. Sa huling ilang segundo ng karera ay makitid mong nalampasan ang manlalangoy na nasa ikatlong puwesto. Anong lugar ang nakuha mo?","answer":"Ikatlo."},{"question":"இந்தியாவில் முதன் முதலில் மக்கள் நல அரசை உருவாக்கிய சிறப்பினை பெற்றவர்  யார் ?1. அஜாதசத்ரு2. செலூகஸ் நிகோடர்3. அசோகர்4. கனிஷ்கர்","answer":"அசோகர்அசோகர் என்பவர் இந்தியத் துணைக் கண்டத்தை ஆண்ட மௌரியப் பேரரசின் மூன்றாவது பேரரசர் ஆவார். இவர் பொதுவாக பேரரசர் அசோகர் என்று அறியப்படுகிறார். இவர் அண். பொ. ஊ. மு. 268 முதல் அண். பொ. ஊ. மு. 232 வரை ஆட்சி புரிந்தார். இவரது பேரரசானது இந்தியத் துணைக்கண்டத்தின் ஒரு பெரும் பகுதியை உள்ளடக்கியிருந்தது. அது மேற்கில் தற்போதைய ஆப்கானித்தான் முதல் கிழக்கில் தற்போதைய வங்காளதேசம் வரை பரவியிருந்தது. இவரது பேரரசின் தலைநகரம் பாடலிபுத்திரம் ஆகும். இவர் பௌத்தத்தின் புரவலராக விளங்கினார். பண்டைக் கால ஆசியா முழுவதும் பௌத்தத்தைப் பரப்பியத்தில் ஒரு முக்கியப் பங்காற்றியுள்ளார்.அசோகர் குறித்த பெரும்பாலான தகவல்கள் இவரது பிராமி கல்வெட்டுகளிலிருந்தும், இவரது இறப்பிற்குப் பிறகு நூற்றாண்டுகள் கழித்து எழுதப்பட்ட பௌத்த புராணங்களிலிருந்தும் வருகின்றன. பண்டைக்கால இந்தியாவில் ஆரம்பத்தில் உருவாக்கப்பட்ட நீண்ட கல்வெட்டுகளில் இவையும் ஒன்றாகும். அசோகர் பிந்துசாரரின் மகனும், மௌரிய அரசமரபைத் தோற்றுவித்த சந்திரகுப்த மௌரியரின் பேரனும் ஆவார். இவரது தந்தையின் ஆட்சியின் போது நடு இந்தியாவின் உஜ்ஜைனின் ஆளுநராக இவர் சேவையாற்றினார். சில பௌத்த புராணங்களின் படி, ஓர் இளவரசராக தக்சசீலத்தில் ஒரு கிளர்ச்சியையும் இவர் அடக்கினார்.அசோகரின் கல்வெட்டுகள் இவரது ஆட்சியின் எட்டாவது ஆண்டின் (அண். பொ. ஊ. மு. 260) போது இவர் கலிங்கத்தை ஒரு மிருகத்தனமான போருக்குப் பின் வென்றார் என்று குறிப்பிடுகின்றன. போரால் ஏற்பட்ட அழிவானது இவர் வன்முறையைக் கைவிடக் காரணமானது. கலிங்கப் பகுதியில் கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்ட இவரது கல்வெட்டுகளில் இத்தகவல் சேர்க்காது விடப்பட்டுள்ளது. கலிங்க மக்களுக்கு முன்னாள் தான் வருந்துவது அரசியல் ரீதியாகத் தேவையற்றது என்றோ அல்லது இவரது கல்வெட்டுகளில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள தகவல்கள் முழுத் துல்லியமற்றவை என்பதாலோ மற்றும் மற்ற பகுதிகளின் மக்களின் நன் மதிப்பைப் பெறுவதற்காகவோ இவ்வாறு குறிப்பிடப்பட்டிருக்கலாம் என்று கருதப்படுகிறது. அசோகர் இறுதியாகத் தர்மம் அல்லது நன்னடத்தையை பரப்புவதை மிகுதியாக நேசித்தார். இவருடைய கல்வெட்டுகளின் முக்கியக் கருத்தாக இது உள்ளது.அசோகரின் கல்வெட்டுகள் கலிங்கப் போருக்கு ஒரு சில ஆண்டுகள் கழித்து, பௌத்தத்தை நோக்கி இவர் படிப்படியாக இழுக்கப்பட்டார் என்பதைப் பரிந்துரைக்கின்றன. கலிங்கப் போரை பௌத்த புராணங்கள் குறிப்பிடவில்லை. மற்ற சமய நம்பிக்கைகளின் தலைவர்களிடத்தில் மன நிறைவு கொள்ளாததற்குப் பிறகு அல்லது பௌத்தத் தலைவர்களால் நடத்தப்பட்ட அதிசயங்களைக் கண்டதற்குப் பிறகு அசோகர் பௌத்தத்திற்கு மதம் மாறினார் என்று பலவாறாகக் குறிப்பிடுகின்றன. ஒரு பெரும் எண்ணிக்கையிலான தூபிக்களை நிறுவியதற்காகவும், மூன்றாம் பௌத்த சங்கத்திற்குப் புரவலராக விளங்கியதற்காகவும், பௌத்தத் தூதுவர்களுக்கு ஆதரவளித்ததற்காகவும், பௌத்த சங்கத்திற்கு ஈகைக் குணத்துடன் நன்கொடை அளித்ததற்காகவும் மற்றும் பௌத்தர் அல்லாதவர்களை இடர்ப்படுத்தியதற்காகவும் கூட அசோகரை இப்புராணங்கள் குறிப்பிடுகின்றன. நவீன வரலாற்றாளர்கள் மத்தியில் இந்தப் புராணங்களில் வரலாற்றுத் தன்மையானது விவாதிக்கப்படுகிறது. இப்புராணங்கள் கல்வெட்டுக்களுடன் ஒத்துப் போவதில்லை மற்றும் சில நேரங்களில் ஒரு புராணம் மற்றொரு புராணத்துடன் ஒத்துப் போவதில்லை. இவை ஏராளமான புராண மரபியலைக் கொண்டுள்ளன. பௌத்தத்திற்கு மாறுவதற்கு முன் அசோகரின் மோசமான தன்மையையும், பௌத்தத்திற்கு மாறியதற்குப் பின் அவரது பக்தியையும் மிகைப்படுத்திக் கூறுகின்றன. அசோகரின் சொந்தக் கல்வெட்டுகள் இவர் பௌத்ததிற்கு ஆதரவு அளித்தார் என்பதைப் பரிந்துரைக்கின்றன. ஆனால், மேலும் பிராமணியம், சமணம் மற்றும் ஆசீவகம் உள்ளிட்ட பிற முதன்மையான சமகால நம்பிக்கைகளுக்கும் புரவலராக விளங்கினார் என்பதையும் குறிப்பிடுகின்றன.ஒரு வரலாற்று ரீதியான மன்னனாக அசோகரின் வாழ்வானது கிட்டத்தட்ட மறக்கப்பட்டுவிட்டது. ஆனால், 19ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் பிராமி எழுத்துமுறை புரிந்தறியப்பட்டதற்குப் பிறகு இந்நிலை மாறியது. அசோகரின் கல்வெட்டுகளில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ள பிரியதர்சி மற்றும் தேவனாம்பிரியர் ஆகிய பட்டங்களைப் பௌத்த புராணங்களுடன் வரலாற்றாளர்கள் தொடர்புபடுத்தியுள்ளனர். இந்தியப் பேரரசர்களில் மிகச் சிறந்தவர்களில் ஒருவராக அசோகரின் மதிப்பை நிறுவினர். நவீன இந்தியாவின் சின்னமாக அசோகரின் சிங்கத் தூபி பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது.அசோகரின் கல்வெட்டுகள் தவிர இவரது வாழ்வைப் பற்றி அறிந்து கொள்ள இவரது இறப்பிற்குப் பிறகு நூற்றாண்டுகள் கழித்து எழுதப்பட்ட புனைவுகளே நமக்கு உதவுகின்றன. பொ.ஊ. 2ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் அசோகவதனம் (திவ்வியவதனத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியாகிய \\"அசோகரின் கதை\\") மற்றும் இலங்கை நூலாகிய மகாவம்சம் ஆகிய புனைவுகள் நமக்கு உதவுகின்றன. \\"அசோக மரத்துடன்\\" தனது பெயர் கொண்டிருந்த தொடர்பைப் பற்றிய இவரது நேசமும் அசோகவதனத்தில் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"Tilda Swinton","answer":"Tilda Swinton je óṣèrè lobinrin ti ilẹ British osere to gba Ebun Akademi bi Obinrin Osere Keji Didarajulo.Katherine Matilda Swinton ni a bi ni ọjọ kàrun óṣu November ọdun 1960 si ilu london fun Judith Balfour (1929-2012) ati Sir John Swinton (1925-2018). Baba óṣère lobinrin naa jẹ óṣisẹ fẹyinti major-general ti ólógun ilẹ ati ọga lieutenant ti Berwickshire (1989-2000), Iya rẹ si jẹ ọmọ ilẹ Australia.Ni ọdun 1997, Tilda bi ibeji Honor ati Xavier Swinton Byrne fun John Byrne ti o si gbe scotland fun ogun ọdun. Óṣèrè lobinrin naa bẹrẹ èrè oritage lati igba ti o ti wa ni ilè iwe. Swinton ló ọdun meji gẹgẹbi ẹni jọwọ ara rẹ silẹ lati ṣè iranlọwọ ofẹ ni ilẹ South Africa ati Kenya ki o to lọ si ile iwe giga ti Cambridge.Swinton lọsi Ilè ẹkọ Queen's Gate, Ilè ẹkọ Awọn ọdọmọbinrin ètó ilèra west ati Fettes College fun igba diẹ. Ni ọdun 1983, Swinton kawe yege ni Ilè iwè giga ti Cambridge lori imọ social ati science ti óṣẹlu.Tilda gba ami ẹyẹ Akademi, ami ẹyẹ BAFTA ati ami ẹyẹ Independent spirit. Ni ọdun 2020, New York Times ka óṣere lobinrin naa kun gẹgẹbi ọkan lara awọn óṣere to pegede julọ ni 21st century.Swinton gba Cup ti Volpi gẹgẹbi óṣèrè lobinrin to darajulọ ninu ere Edward II nibi ti ó ti ṣèrè gẹgẹbi Isabella ti ilẹ france. Óṣèrè lobinrin naa gba award ti Richard Harris lati ọdọ ere agbelewo independent award ti ilẹ British fun ipa rẹ ninu ere igbelewo industry ti ilẹ British. Ni ọdun 2020, Swinton gba ami idanilọla ti fellowship Institute ere igbelewo ti ilẹ́ British fun ipa ribi ribi ti oun ko lati gbè àṣa filmu larugẹ ati itọrẹ́ anu"},{"question":"问题：护手霜可以每天使用吗？","answer":"回答：是的，可以根据需要每天使用护手霜，特别是在洗手后或皮肤感到干燥时使用。"},{"question":"azavao ny hoe \\"nitanjozotra\\".","answer":"Ny hoe \\"nitanjozotra\\" dia nandeha nanao ranolava, nizotra toa nilahatra"},{"question":"Baba Ijẹṣa ki i ṣe ọmọ ẹgbẹ wa o- Mr LATIN","answer":"Nigba ti ọrọ Baba Ijẹṣa yii ko yee tan kiri, to ti di ohun ti wọn n sọ pe o yẹ ki wọn yọ ọ lẹgbẹ ni, ki wọn ma jẹ ko ṣe tiata mọ, ki wọn da sẹria fun un ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ, Ọtunba Bọlaji Amuṣan tawọn eeyan mọ si Mista Latin, iyẹn Aarẹ ẹgbẹ TAMPAN ni Naijiria, jade lati ṣalaye ohun tawọn eeyan ko mọ. Eyi lohun ti Latin sọ ninu fidio to ju sori ẹrọ ayelujara.‘‘Nigba ti ọrọ yii kọkọ ṣẹlẹ, mo paṣẹ fun ẹni to n ṣe akọsilẹ ninu ẹgbẹ TAMPAN pe ko fi atẹjade sita pe a ko fara mọ iwa ti Ijẹṣa hu, a si koro oju si i. Bi wọn ṣe gbe e jade lori atẹ ẹgbẹ wa lemi naa gbe e soju opo mi ki gbogbo aye le ri i.‘‘Ṣugbọn awọn eeyan tun n pariwo pe o yẹ ka le Baba Ijẹsa kuro ninu ẹgbẹ TAMPAN. Mo fẹẹ fi asiko yii sọ fun yin pe mi o lagbra la ti le Ijẹṣa kuro ninu ẹgbẹ, nitori Ijẹṣa ki i ṣe ọmọ ẹgbẹ TAMPAN. Ẹni ti ki i ṣe ọmọ ẹgbẹ mi, agbara wo ni mo ni lati ni ko kuro nibẹ. Oṣere bii temi ni, a jọ n ṣiṣẹ ni. Aimọye ẹgbẹ lo dẹ wa, ki i ṣe ọmọ ẹgbẹ TAMPAN’Mista Latin sọ pe ohun ti ẹgbẹ awọn le ṣe naa lawọn ti ṣe yẹn, iyẹn ni gbigbe atẹjade sita pe awọn ko fara mọ iwa to hu, awọn ko si lọwọ si i. O lawọn ko si nidii ki wọn ma fiya jẹ Ijẹṣa, ṣugbọn nigba ti ki i ṣe ọmọ ẹgbẹ oun, ko si kinni kan toun le ṣe si i.To ba jẹ ọmọ TAMPAN  ni, o ni niṣe lawọn maa kọkọ yọ ọ lẹgbẹ na, ti yoo jiya to tun tọ si i labẹ ofin pẹlu. Ṣugbọn ni ti Ijẹṣa yii, Aarẹ TAMPAN ni ko si kinni kan toun le ṣe si i."},{"question":"لاندې پوښتنې ته د ځواب لپاره استدلال وکاروئ: دا د جمعې شپه ده او ایلیس ویده کیږي ځکه چې هغه د شنبې په ورځ څه کولو پلان لري؟ انتخاب: - نفرت - خوب - آرام - مینه - بې خوبۍ. د استدلال پروسه:","answer":"خلک عموما د اونۍ په پای کې د شپې ناوخته پاتې کیږي او په بله ورځ ناوخته راپاڅي. د جمعې شپه د اونۍ د پای نه مخکې شپه ده. د شنبې ورځ د اونۍ پای دی. بستر ته د تللو ځنډول د دې مانا لري چې تر ناوخته پورې پاتې شئ. ناوخته ویښیدل د خوب کولو معنی لري. له همدې امله، وروستی ځواب په خوب کې دی."},{"question":"Apakah faedah menabung dan memupuk amalan berjimat-cermat? ","answer":"1. Membentuk disiplin diri 2. Memenuhi keperluan kewangan diri dan keluarga 3. Untuk kegunaan ketika kecemasan 4. Dapat membina dan mengembangkan kekayaan 5. Simpanan untuk masa hadapan 6. Menjadi tauladan kepada orang lain"},{"question":"గమన సిద్ధబీజం, సంయుక్త బీజంల మధ్య తేడాను తెలపండి.","answer":"గమనసిద్ధబీజం 1) చలనసహిత, అలైంగిక సిద్ధబీజము. 2) కశాభాలు ఉంటాయి. ఉదా : శైవలాలు, శిలీంధ్రాలు. సంయుక్త బీజం 1) చలనరహిత, లైంగిక ప్రక్రియవల్ల ఏర్పడును. 2) కశాభాలు ఉండవు. ఉదా : లైంగిక ప్రత్యుత్పత్తి జరిపే మొక్కలు."},{"question":"2face Idibia","answer":"Innocent Ujah Idibia (tí a bí sí ìlú Jos, ìpínlẹ̀ Plateau State, orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà tí orúkọ ìnagijẹ rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ 2Baba, jẹ́ olórin orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà, akọrin sílẹ̀, agbọ́rin jáde àti onísẹ́ àdáni. Ní oṣù keje Odun 2014, ó yan 2face Idibia gẹ́gẹ́ bí orúkọ ìtàgé rẹ̀. Ó jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn olórin ilẹ̀ Áfíríkà tó ń kọ orin Afro pop tí ó lọ́lá jùlọ tí ó sì gbayì. Ó ti lé lógún ọdún tí 2Baba tí ń kọrin tí ó sì ń dánilárayá ó sì jẹ́ ògbóǹtarìgì síbẹ̀.A bí Innocent Idibia sí ìlú Jos, orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn ọmọ Idoma ní apá gúúsù ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà. Ó lọ sí Mount Saint Gabriel's Secondary School ní ìlú Makurdi, ìpínlẹ̀ Benue. Ó tún lọ sí Institute of Management & Technology (IMT) ní ìpínlẹ̀ Enugu níbi tí ó ti gboyè National Diploma nínú Business administration and management. Nígbà tí ó wà ní IMT, ó máa ń kọrin níbi ayẹyẹ àti àwọn ilé-ìwé gíga bíi University of Nigeria Enugu State University of Science & Technology. Kò parí ẹ̀kọ́ rẹ̀, ó kúrò nilé-ìwé ó sì gbájúmọ́ orin kíkọ. Ní ọdún 1996, ó yan \\"2face\\" gẹ́gẹ́ bíi orúkọ ìtàgé rẹ̀.Ní ọdún 2016, ó yí orúkọ ìtàgé rẹ̀ sí 2Baba."},{"question":"சரியான விடையைத் தெரிவு செய்வோமா?பூலோகமெல்லாம் இச்சொல்லைப் பிரித்து எழுதக் கிடைப்பது ……………………….பூலோக + மெல்லாம்பூலோகம் + மெல்லாம்பூலோகம் + எல்லாம்பூலோக + எல்லாம்","answer":"விடை : பூலோகம் + எல்லாம்"},{"question":"Kedu mgbe agbara ụlo Igwe Oliver Nnaji ọkụ? ","answer":"A gbara ụlọ Igwe Oliver Nnaji nke Ogwu Aniocha Anambra steeti ọkụ n'abalị iri na isii nke ọnwa Nọvemba  nke afọ 2021."},{"question":"Напиши продолжение: Как считалось, опьяняющий эффект пива длился дольше чем винный, но, в отличие от вина, пиво не вызывало ощущения \\"ложной жажды\\" (псевдодипсии). Хоть и меньше, чем на севере, пиво также употреблялось на севере Франции и на материковой Италии. Возможно, в ходе","answer":"нормандского завоевания и культурного обмена между Францией и Англией, один из вариантов встречающихся в поваренной книге \\"Le Ménagier de Paris\\" был назван как \\"godale\\" (похоже на прямое заимствование от английского — \\"Хорошее пиво\\") и готовился из ячменя и полбы, но без хмеля. В Англии готовили также несколько вариантов \\"поссета\\" из горячего молока и холодного эля, а также \\"бреккета\\" — приправленного эля, готовящегося во многом как гипокрас."},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Guinée nékk","answer":"Réwum Guinée mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Afrique"},{"question":"ธาตุ O มีชื่อเรียกในภาษาไทยว่าธาตุใด","answer":"ธาตุออกซิเจน"},{"question":"வினா:இயற்கை மருத்துவத்தில் கருவேப்பிலையின் பயன்கள் யாவை?","answer":"விடை :இயற்கை மருத்துவத்தில் கருவேப்பிலையின் பயன்கள்கறிவேம்பு , கறிவேப்பிலை அல்லது கருவேப்பிலை என்று அழைக்கப்படும் இது, பலமருத்துவ குணங்கள் கொண்டதாகும். இந்தியா, இலங்கை போன்ற நாடுகளில் சமைக்கப்படுகின்ற பலவிதமான உணவுப் பதார்த்தங்களில் சுவைகூட்டும் பொருளாகவும், மணத்திற்காகவும் பிரசித்தி பெற்றவையாகும்உணவின் வாசனையை அதிகரிக்கத்தான் கறிவேப்பிலை பயன்படுகிறது என்று பலர் கருதுகின்றனர். இதனால் தான் சாப்பிடும்போது உணவில் கிடக்கும் கறிவேப்பிலையை எடுத்து கீழே போட்டு விடுகிறார்கள். ஆனால் இனிமேல் இப்படிச் செய்யாதீர்கள். ஏனெனில் கறிவேப்பிலையில் பல்வேறு மருத்துவ குணங்கள் இருப்பதாக சமீபத்திய ஆய்வுகள் மூலம் தெரிய வந்துள்ளது. கறிவேப்பிலையின் தாவரப்பெயர் முரையா கோய்னிஜா. இது ருட்டேசி என்ற தாவரக் குடும்பத்தை சேர்ந்தது. கறிவேப்பிலையில் வைட்டமின் ஏ, பி, சி, கால்சியம் போன்றவைகள் உள்ளன. மேலும் கறிவேப்பிலையில் கோயினிஜாக், குளுகோசைட், ஒலியோரெசின், ஆஸ்பர்ஜான் சொரின், ஆஸ்பார்டிக் அமிலம், அயாமைன், புரோலைன் போன்ற அமினோ அமிலங்கள் உள்ளது. இவைகள் தான் கறிவேப்பிலைக்கு இனிய மணத்தை தருகிறது. பல மருத்துவ குணங்களையும் வெளிப்படுத்துகிறது.1. ​ரத்த சோகை பிரச்சினையை குறைக்கஉதவுகிறது.2. கறிவேப்பிலையில் உள்ள பலவிதமான நன்மைகள், சர்க்கரையின் அளவை ரத்தத்தில் சீராக வைத்திருக்க உதவுகிறது.3. ​செரிமானத்தை சீராக்குகிறது.4. ​கொலஸ்ட்ராலைக் கட்டுப்படுத்துகிறது.இந்திய சமையலில் வாசனைக்கு சேர்க்கப்படும் மசாலா பொருள் கறிவேப்பிலை புற்றுநோயை ஆரம்பித்திலேயே கொல்லும் ஆற்றல் உடையது என்பதை அண்மையில் ஆஸ்திரேலிய உணவியல் அறிஞர்கள் கண்டறிந்துள்ளனர். இந்நிறுவன தலைமை ஆராய்ச்சியாளர் லனேகோபியாக் கறிவேப்பிலை சிறந்த ஆண்டி ஆக்ஸிடென்டாக இயங்குகிறது என்கிறார். இது புற்றுநோய், இதய நோய்களை குறைக்கும் ஆற்றல் கொண்டது. மேலும் கறிவேப்பிலையால் ஞாபக சக்தி எளிதில் கிடைக்கிறது என்கிறார் இவர். கறிவேப்பிலையிலிருந்து எண்ணை எடுத்து அதை நுரையீரல், இருதயம், கண்நோய்களுக்கு தலைக்கு தேய்க்கும் எண்ணையாக பயன்படுத்தலாம் என இங்கிலாந்தில் உள்ள வேளாண் மருத்துவ ஆராய்ச்சி நிலையம் தெரிவித்துள்ளது.சாதாரணமாக 100 கிராம் கறிவேப்பிலையை அரைத்து சாற்றை எடுத்து 100 கிராம் தேங்காய் எண்ணையில் கலந்து இதமான சூட்டில் ஈரப்பதம் நீங்கும் வரை காய்ச்சி தினசரி தலைக்கு தேய்த்து வந்தால் உடல் உஷ்ணம் மங்கும். பரம்பரை நரை வராது. கண்பார்வை குறைவு ஏற்படாது. கறிவேப்பிலையை அரைத்து சாப்பிட்டால் நுரையீரல், இருதய சம்பந்தப்பட்ட ரத்த சம்பந்தப்பட்ட நோய்கள் வருவது குறையும் என்கிறது இந்நிறுவனம்.திருவனந்தபுரத்திலுள்ள கேரளா பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில்  கறிவேப்பிலையையும், கடுகையும் தாளிக்க பயன்படுத்தினால் அதனால் நன்மை உண்டா? என்பது பற்றி ஆராய்ந்தார்கள் மருத்துவ குழுவினர். அதில் கறிவேப்பிலையும், கடுகும் சேர்ந்து நமது திசுக்களை அழிவிலிருந்து பாதுகாக்கிறது என்பது தெரிய வந்தது. மேலும் பிரிரேடிக்கல்ஸ் உருவாவதையும் தடுக்கிறது. பிரிரேடிக்கல்ஸ் உருவாவதால்தான் டி.என்.ஏ. பாதிக்கிறது. செல்களிலுள்ள புரோட்டின் அழிகிறது. விளைவு கேன்சர், வாதநோய்கள் தோன்றுகின்றன. தாளிதம் செய்யும்போது நாம் பயன்படுத்தும் கறிவேப்பிலையும், கடுகும் பிரிரேடிக்கல்ஸ் உருவாவதை தடுப்பதாக ஆய்வில் கண்டறிந்துள்ளனர்.இதுதவிர நீரிழிவு நோயாளிகள் காலையில் 10 கறிவேப்பிலை இலையையும், மாலையில் 10 இலையையும் பறித்த உடனேயே வாயில் போட்டு மென்று சாற்றை விழுங்கி வந்தால் மாத்திரை சாப்பிடும் அளவை பாதியாக குறைத்து விடலாம் என்கிறார்கள் மருத்துவர்கள். தினசரி வெறும் வயிற்றில் கறிவேப்பிலை இலையை 3 மாதங்கள் சாப்பிட்டு வந்தால் நீரிழிவால் உடல் கனமாவது குறைக்கப்படும். சிறுநீரில் சர்க்கரை வெளியேறுவதும் முற்றிலும் தடை செய்யப்படும். கறிவேப்பிலை ரத்தத்தில் இருக்கும் கொழுப்பை குறைக்கவும், அறிவை பெருக்கவும் உதவுகிறது. கறிவேப்பிலையை பச்சையாகவே மென்று தின்றால் குரல் இனிமையாகும். சளியும் குறையும் என்கிறார்கள் மருத்துவர்கள்.இந்தியன் கவுன்சில் ஆப் மெடிகல் தினமும் 170 கிராம் காய்கறிகளை சாப்பிட சிபாரிசு செய்கிறது. 75 - 125 கிராம் கீரைகளையும் சாப்பிட சிபாரிசு செய்கிறது. 170 கிராம் காய்கறிகளை சாப்பிட முக்கியமான 10 காய்கறிகளையும் குறிப்பிடுகிறது. அதில் ஒன்று கறிவேப்பிலை என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது."},{"question":"Жүрөгүн ачуу деген сөз эмнени түшүндүрөт?","answer":"Жүрөгүн ачуу деген сөз төмөндөгүдөй маанини билдирет:Абдан берилип, чын ыкласы менен жадырап-жайноо, өтө мээримдүү кабылдоо.«Келиңиз, Теңирберди аке, келиңиз!» - деп жүрөгүн ачып, меймандарын төшөккө чыгарып, калдастады. (Касымбеков)"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'orang dalam'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang dikenali kita bekerja dalam satu-satu jabatan. Contoh ayat: Jika ada orang dalam, senanglah kita berurusan dengan pejabat itu."},{"question":"Gaweo telung contoh pitakonan kuis trivia Basa Jawa gawe dhasar kategori lan konteks ing ngisor iki.Kategori: Buku.Judul buku: Harry Potter dan Tawanan Azkaban.Jawaban:","answer":"1. Q: Sapa penciptae Peta Perampok?   A: Papat mantan siswa Hogwarts sing nduweni julukan jeneng: Moony, Padfoot, Wormtail, dan Prongs.2. Q: Sapa jenengi kucinge Hermione lan tikuse Ron?    A: Kucinge Hermione jenenge Crookshanks, yen tikuse Ron jenenge Scabbers.3. Q: Apa jenenge mantra sihir gawe ngusir Dementor?    A: Mantra Patronus."},{"question":"பருத்தியை முதன் முதலில் உற்பத்தி செய்தவர்கள் யார் ?","answer":"பருத்தி முதன்முதலில் இந்தியாவில் குறைந்தது 7,000 ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன்பு சிந்து சமவெளி நாகரிகத்தில் விளைந்தது. பருத்திச் செடியானது இந்தியத் துணைக்கண்டத்தைச் சேர்ந்ததாக இருக்கலாம்."},{"question":"Шараат бул ...","answer":"Шараат, шарыят - ислам дининдеги мыйзамдардын топтому жыйнагы."},{"question":"다음 맥락에서 중요한 사건에 대해 말하시오:1940년 4월 9일, 베저위붕 작전, 독일의 스칸디나비아 공격 이후, 핀란드는 서부 전통 무역 시장과 물리적으로 격리되었다. 핀란드를 오가는 항로는 이제 전쟁해군에 의해 통제되었다. 발트해의 출구가 막히고 핀란드의 북쪽으로가는 경로는 로바니에미에서 무르만스크 주의 얼음이없는 항구까지 북극 비포장 도로였다. 페창가에서 배는 북극해 때문에 독일이 점령한 노르웨이 해안을 길게 통과해야했다. 스웨덴과 같이 핀란드는 점령을 포기했지만 나치 독일과 소련에 둘러싸였다. 칼 구스타브 에밀 만네르헤임 남작의 직접적인 지원으로 자원 봉사단이 구성되어 나치 군대와의 전쟁을 돕기 위해 노르웨이로 파견되었다. 구급차 부대는 독일군이 복무하던 지역을 정복 할 때까지 전쟁에 참여했다. 지원자들은 핀란드로 돌아 왔다.","answer":"베저위붕 작전과 독일의 스칸디나비아 공격"},{"question":"السؤال: من أول من عمل الأوزان ؟","answer":"الإجابة :  الحجاج بن يوسف ."},{"question":"(ekhomba uMaShezi) We MaShezi! Musa ukudlala ngoMbadlwa.Angangena kanjani esikoleni eselugodo oludala kangaka? (ahleke)Udlala ngami ngempela uMaShezi.(ehleka) Hhayi-bo! Nami ngiyazincokolela nje. Angihambe ngiyobonaizimbiza zami. (asukume aphume)Mbandlwa mfowethu, emhlanganweni ngizokwethula uhlelolokudonsa amanzi ngamapayipi umuzi nomuzi. Engethemba ukuthilokho kuyisidingo esibaluleke kakhulu esizweni.Kuyosiza nokuthi nalaba bantu abathi uzenza inkosi babone ukuthiubalulekile kubo. Futhi ngiyakutshela bayophenduka balifelengamathe elenkosi izwi.Mina angifuni balifele ngamathe elenkosi kodwa yiyo inkosieyokwenza ukuthi abantu balifele ngamathe elayo izwi. Kodwa umakusekhona abantu abanjengoDlamini, sengathi akukezulungangempela.(achithe izandla) Hhayi, khohlwa yilowo. Naye uzoyibona intuthukomaqede abone ngokunye. Okwakobani ukukha amanzi empompiningezansana kwendlu?Wowu! Umuntu ongukhandaqinile akakuboni ubuhle obenziwangumuntu amzondayo. Phela uyangizonda uDlamini. AsimyekeuDlamini okwamanje. Indlela obeka ngayo inginika ithemba.Mbandlwa, ngicela usho uma ngabe unenkinga nge-air time futhiungajwayeli ukuwuvala umakhalekhukhwini wakho.Cha, okwamanje ngisenayo. Phela kuseyiyo lena owanginika yona.Uzame-ke ukucupha isisoka enkulumweni yakho ngosukulomhlangano. Angifuni ukubona umholi wami ebhibhidla phambikwabantu.1. Ngokwalesi siqeshana wayenzani uMaShezi ngesikhathi uMbandlwa noDumabeqhubeka nengxoxo yabo?","answer":"Wayepheka/Wayebheke izimbiza zakhe. "},{"question":"what important event is this text about: 일본의 전쟁 범죄()는 19세기 말에서 20세기 중반 일본 제국에 의해 자행된 일련의 전쟁 범죄를 지칭한다. 일본 내에서는 우익정권의 영향으로 극동 국제 군사 재판(IMTFE)만을 한정하여 의미를 축소해석하기도 한다. 영미권을 비롯한 서구권에서는 아시안 홀로코스트란 표현을 사용한다. 몇 몇 전쟁 범죄는 19세기 말 일본 제국의 군 인사들에 의해 자행됐으며, 대부분이 쇼와 시대 초에 일어났고, 1945년 일본의 항복까지 계속되었다.","answer":"일본의 전쟁 범죄"},{"question":"¿ Qué canción se toca mientras se levanta la bandera americana?","answer":"La canción que generalmente se toca mientras se levanta la bandera estadounidense es el himno nacional de Estados Unidos, conocido como \\"The Star-Spangled Banner\\"."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਲੋਕ ਮਃ ੪ ॥ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਵਿਚਿ ਵਡੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਜੋ ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਵੈ ॥ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਰਮਤ ਸੁਚ ਸੰਜਮੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੇ ਹੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤਾਵੈ ॥ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਤਾਣੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਦੀਬਾਣੁ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੋ ਰਖ ਕਰਾਵੈ ॥ਜੋ ਚਿਤੁ ਲਾਇ ਪੂਜੇ ਗੁਰ ਮੂਰਤਿ ਸੋ ਮਨ ਇਛੇ ਫਲ ਪਾਵੈ ॥ ਜੋ ਨਿੰਦਾ ਕਰੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਪੂਰੇ ਕੀ ਤਿਸੁ ਕਰਤਾ ਮਾਰ ਦਿਵਾਵੈ ॥ ਫੇਰਿ ਓਹ ਵੇਲਾ ਓਸੁ ਹਥਿ ਨ ਆਵੈ ਓਹੁ ਆਪਣਾ ਬੀਜਿਆ ਆਪੇ ਖਾਵੈ ॥ ਨਰਕਿ ਘੋਰਿ ਮੁਹਿ ਕਾਲੈ ਖੜਿਆ ਜਿਉ ਤਸਕਰੁ ਪਾਇ ਗਲਾਵੈ ॥ ਫਿਰਿ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਕੀ ਸਰਣੀ ਪਵੈ ਤਾ ਉਬਰੈ ਜਾ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਵੈ ॥ ਹਰਿ ਬਾਤਾ ਆਖਿ ਸੁਣਾਏ ਨਾਨਕੁ ਹਰਿ ਕਰਤੇ ਏਵੈ ਭਾਵੈ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 303 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਵਿਚ ਇਹ ਭਾਰਾ ਗੁਣ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਹਰ ਰੋਜ਼ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸੁੱਚ ਤੇ ਸੰਜਮ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਜਾਪ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਉਹ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹਹਰਿ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਆਸਰਾ ਤੇ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਲਈ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਇਸ ਗੁਰ-ਮੂਰਤੀ ਦਾ ਪੂਜਨ ਚਿੱਤ ਲਾ ਕੇ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਜੋ ਜੀਵ ਗਹੁ ਨਾਲ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਉਪਰ-ਲਿਖੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਧਾਰਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ) ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਉਹੀ ਫਲ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਇੱਛਾ ਕਰੇ। ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪੂਰੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਨਿੰਦਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮਾਰ ਪਵਾਉਂਦਾ ਹਆਪਣੀ ਹੱਥੀਂ ਨਿੰਦਾ ਦਾ ਬੀਜ ਬੀਜੇ ਦਾ ਫਲ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਭੋਗਣਾ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤਦੋਂ ਪਛਤਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ) ਫੇਰ ਜੋ ਵੇਲਾ (ਨਿੰਦਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਿਚ ਬੀਤ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ) ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ,ਤੇ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਚੋਰ ਨੂੰ ਗਲ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਸੀ ਪਾ ਕੇ ਲੈ ਜਾਈਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਿਵੇਂ ਕਾਲਾ ਮੂੰਹ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਮਾਨੋ) ਡਰਾਉਣੇ ਨਰਕ ਵਿਚ (ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਭੀ) ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਫੇਰ ਇਸ (ਨਿੰਦਾ-ਰੂਪ ਘੋਰ ਨਰਕ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਤਾਂ ਹੀ ਬਚਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨੀ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਜਪੇ ਨਾਨਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੇ ਦਰ) ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਆਖ ਕੇ ਸੁਣਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ; ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੂੰ ਇਉਂ ਹੀ ਭਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਕਿ ਨਿੰਦਕ ਈਰਖਾ ਦੇ ਨਰਕ ਵਿਚ ਆਪੇ ਹੀ ਪਿਆ ਸੜੇ) ।੧।\\""},{"question":"ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਬਦਾਵਲੀ ਦੇ ਵਰਗ ਹਨ?","answer":"ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਵਰਨਮਾਲਾ ਵਿਚ ਕੁੱਲ 35 ਅੱਖਰ ਹਨ। ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ (ੳ, ਅ ਅਤੇ ੲ) ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਤਿੰਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਵਰ ਧੁਨੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਗਿਿਣਆਂ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਕੀ ਦੀਆਂ 32 ਧੁਨੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਅੰਜਨ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਪਰਤੂੰ ਆਧੁਨਿਕ ਵਰਨਮਾਲਾ ਵਿਚ ਛੇ ਨਵੇਂ ਅੱਖਰ ਸ਼ਾਮਿਲ ਕੀਤੀਆਂ ਗਈਆਂ ਹਨ।ਸ਼, ਖ਼, ਗ਼, ਜ਼, ਫ਼, ਲ਼ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਅੱਖਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਾਮਿਲ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿਅੰਜਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਖਿਆਂ 38 ਹੋ ਗਈ ਹੈ।ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ 3 ਸਵਰ ਅਤੇ 32 ਵਿਅੰਜਨ ਹਨ।ਵਰਗੀਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਇਹ ਵੇਖਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਧੁਨੀ ਮੂੰਹ ਵਿਚਲੇ ਕਿਹੜੇ ਅੰਗ ਦੀ ਸਹਾਇਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਥਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਪਰਸ਼ ਨਾਲ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਸਾਡੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਵਿਚ ਹੋਂਠ, ਦੰਦ, ਤਾਲੂ, ਸੰਘ, ਕਾਂ, ਕੰਠ ਪਿਟਾਰੀ, ਨਾਸਾਂ, ਅਜੇਹੇ ਅੰਗ ਹਨ ਜਿਹੜੇ ਧੁਨੀ ਉਚਾਰਨ ਵਿਚ ਮਦਦ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ।ੳ ਅ ੲ ਸ ਹਕ ਖ ਗ ਘ ਙਚ ਛ ਜ ਝ ਞਟ ਠ ਡ ਢ ਣਤ ਥ ਦ ਧ ਨਪ ਫ ਬ ਭ ਮਯ ਰ ਲ ਵ ੜਸ਼ ਖ਼ ਗ਼ ਜ਼ ਫ਼ਲ਼ਇਸ ਲਈ ਅਸੀਂ ਇਹ ਸਿੱਟਾ ਕੱਢ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਭਾਸ਼ਾ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਬਦਾਵਲੀ ਦੇ ਅੱਠ ਵਰਗ ਹਨI"},{"question":"ஆன்றோர் இச்சொல்லின் பொருள் …………………………பெற்றோர்உற்றோர்சுற்றோர்பெரியோர்","answer":"விடை : ஆன்றோர் இச்சொல்லின் பொருள் ………………பெரியோர்"},{"question":"ਗਾਜ਼ੀਆਬਾਦ, 1 ਮਾਰਚਕੇਂਦਰੀ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਤੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਥਲ ਸੈਨਾ ਮੁਖੀ ਵੀ.ਕੇ.ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਅੱਜ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਗੱਲ ਦੀ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਨੇ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਪਾਇਲਟ ਵਿੰਗ ਕਮਾਂਡਰ ਅਭਿਨੰਦਨ ਵਰਤਮਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਰਿਹਾਅ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਗੁਆਂਢੀ ਮੁਲਕ ਨੂੰ ਅਜੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਕੁਝ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਹੈ।ਇਥੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੰਸਦੀ ਹਲਕੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਮਾਗਮ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਪੱਤਰਕਾਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ ਰਾਜ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਕੇਂਦਰ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਨਾਲ ਰਿਸ਼ਤਿਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਈ ਤਲਖੀ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਕੇ ‘ਢੁੱਕਵੇਂ ਕਦਮ’ ਚੁੱਕ ਰਹੀ, ਪਰ ਇਸ ਪੇਸ਼ਕਦਮੀ ਦਾ ਖੁਲਾਸਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ,‘ਸਾਨੂੰ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪਾਇਲਟ ਅਭਿਨੰਦਨ ਵਰਤਮਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਰਿਹਾਅ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਪਰ ਜੇਕਰ ਉਹ ਇਸ ਰਿਹਾਈ ਨੂੰ ‘ਅਮਨ ਦਾ ਸੁਨੇਹਾ’ ਦੱਸਦੇ ਹਨ ਤਾਂ ਅਸੀਂ ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਵੀ ਖੁਸ਼ ਹਾਂ, ਪਰ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ (ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ) ਨੂੰ ਅਜੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਕੁਝ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਹੈ।ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਸ਼ਾਹ ਮਹਿਮੂਦ ਕੁਰੈਸ਼ੀ ਦੀ ਯੂਏਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਓਆਈਸੀ (ਇਸਲਾਮਿਕ ਸਹਿਯੋਗ ਬਾਰੇ ਜਥੇਬੰਦੀ) ਦੀ ਮੀਟਿੰਗ ’ਚੋਂ ਗ਼ੈਰਹਾਜ਼ਰੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਪੁੱਛੇ ਜਾਣ ’ਤੇ ਸਿੰਘ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, ‘ਇਹ ਕੁਰੈਸ਼ੀ ਦੀ ਸਮਝ ਹੈ, ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਉਹ ਕੁਝ ਕਰਨ ਦੇਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਉਹ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ।’ ਕੁਰੈਸ਼ੀ ਨੇ ਲੰਘੇ ਦਿਨ ਐਲਾਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਹਮਰੁਤਬਾ ਸੁਸ਼ਮਾ ਸਵਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਓਆਈਸੀ ਦੀ ਮੀਟਿੰਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਮੁੱਖ ਮਹਿਮਾਨ ਵਜੋਂ ਸੱਦੇ ਜਾਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਹ ਮੀਟਿੰਗ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਣਗੇ।ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਅਭਿਨੰਦਨ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦ ਨੂੰ ਰਿਹਾਅ ਕਰਨ ਨਾਲ ਕੌਣ ਖੁਸ਼ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਅਭਿਨੰਦਨ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦ ਨੂੰ ਰਿਹਾਅ ਕਰਨ ਨਾਲ ਕੇਂਦਰੀ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਤੇ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਥਲ ਸੈਨਾ ਮੁਖੀ ਵੀ.ਕੇ.ਸਿੰਘ ਖੁਸ਼ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"சுற்றுச்சூழல் பற்றி இருநூறு வார்த்தைகளில் கட்டுரை எழுதுக.  ","answer":"குறிப்பு சட்டகம்முன்னுரைசுற்றுச்சூழல் அறிமுகம்சூழல் மாசடைதல்சூழல் மாசடைவதால் ஏற்படும் பாதிப்புக்கள்சூழலைப் பாதுகாப்போம்சூழல் பாதுகாக்க மாணவர் எடுக்க வேண்டிய நடவடிக்கைகள்சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு நடைமுறைகள்முடிவுரைமுன்னுரைநாம் வாழும் சுற்றுப்புற சூழலானது தற்போது பல காரணிகளால் மாசடைந்து வருகின்றது. “நோயற்ற வாழ்வே குறைவற்ற செல்வம்” எனும் போது எம்மை மட்டுமல்ல எமது சுற்றுப்புறச் சூழலையும் பாதுகாப்பாக வைத்துக் கொள்ள வேண்டும்.அப்பொழுதே தூய நீர், தூய காற்று, தூய நிலம் என்பவற்றை மனிதன் பெற்று சுகமான வாழ்வை வாழ்வான். எனவே நாம் வாழும் சூழலை பாதுக்காக்க நாம் ஒவ்வொருவரும் கடமைப்பட்டுள்ளோம்.சுற்றுச்சூழல் அறிமுகம்சுற்றுச்சூழல் என்பது எம்மைச் சுற்றியுள்ள நிலம், நீர், காற்று என்பவற்றை உள்ளடக்கிய இயற்கை பரப்பாகும். இதில் காடுகள், கடல்கள் என பல்வேறு நிலபரப்புக்கள் உள்ளடங்கும்.இவை மட்டுமல்ல புதுப்பிக்க முடியாத வளங்களாகிய கனிமங்கள், எரிபொருட்கள் போன்றவற்றையும் சுற்றுப்புற சூழலானது உள்ளடக்கி காணப்படுகின்றது.இவ்வாறான இயற்கை சூழலில் பல்வேறுபட்ட உயிரினங்கள் அதாவது மனிதர்கள் உட்பட பல்லாயிரக்கணக்கான உயிர்களும் நுண்ணுயிர்களும் இணைந்து வாழ்கின்றன.இவ்வாறான உயிரினங்கள் வாழும் சூழலை பேணிப்பாதுகாத்தால் மட்டுமே பல ஆண்டுகளுக்கு இவ்வாறான உயிர்களின் பல்வகைமையை பாதுகாக்க முடியும். ஆகையால் பூமியில் வாழும் உயிரினங்களுக்காக நாம் சூழலை பாதுகாக்க கடமைப்பட்டுள்ளோம்.சூழல் மாசடைதல்இயற்கை அன்னையின் கொடையால் நிறைந்த சுற்றுப்புறச் சூழலானது இன்று பல்வேறு காரணங்களினால் மாசுபட்டு வருகின்றது. நிலம், நீர், காற்று போன்றவை அதிக மாசடைதலுக்கு உள்ளாகியுள்ளன. இதன் காரணமாக சுற்றுப்புற சூழலில் காணப்படும் உயிர்ப்பல்வகைமையும் பாதிக்கப்படுகின்றது.சுற்றுப்புறச்சூழலின் ஒரு பகுதியான நீரை எடுத்துக்கொண்டோமானால் பூமியானது 71% நீரால் சூழப்பட்டு உள்ளது. இவை இன்று மானிட நடவடிக்கைகள் காரணமாக பாதிப்படைந்த நிலையில் காணப்படுகின்றது.உதாரணமாக இந்தியாவில் பாயும் நதிகளில் 70 சதவீத நதிகள் கழிவுகள் சேர்ந்து கலப்பட நீராக காணப்படுகின்றது. இவ்வாறான நீர் மாசானது கழிவுகளை நீர்நிலைகளில் கொட்டுவதனாலும் கிருமி நாசினிகளை விவசாயத்தில் பயன்படுத்துவதாலும் நீர் மாசடைகின்றது.மேலும் உக்கலடையாத பொலித்தீன் மற்றும் பிளாஸ்டிக் பாவனையினாலும் சட்ட விரோத மண் அகழ்வுகளை மேற்கொள்வதனாலும் நிலமானது அதிகம் பாதிப்படைகின்றது.அனைத்து உயிர்களின் சுவாசத்தற்கு இன்றியமையாத வளியானது வாகனப்புகையின் காரணமாகவும் பொலித்தீன் பிளாஸ்டிக் போன்றவற்றை எரிப்பதன் காரணமாகவும் தொழிற்சாலைகளில் இருந்து வெளியேறும் புகையின் காரணமாகவும் அதிகம் மாசடைகின்றது.இவ்வாறு உயிர் அங்கிளின் வாழிடமான சுற்றுப்புற சூழலானது மனிதனின் பல்வேறு செயற்பாடுகளின் காரணமாக மாசடைகின்றது.சூழல் மாசடைவதால் ஏற்படும் பாதிப்புகள்சூழல் மாசடைவு என்பது நிலம், நீர், வாயு என மூன்று வகையாக மாசடைகின்றது. இவை மாசடைவதால் இவற்றில் தங்கி வாழும் உயிரிகள் பெரிதும் பாதிக்கப்படுகின்றன. இதன் காரணமாக உயிர்ப்பல்வகைமைத் தலம்பல் ஏற்படுகின்றது.இவ்வாறு சூழல் மாசடைவதால் பல பாதிப்புகள் ஏற்படுகின்றன. உதாரணமாக நீர் மாசடைவதால் நீரில் வாழும் உயிரினங்கள் பாதிப்படைகின்றது. மேலும் நீர் மாசடைவதால் பலரும் நல்ல குடிநீர் இன்றி தவிக்கின்றனர். இந்நிலை இந்திய நாட்டில் அதிகமாக காணப்படுகின்றது.மேலும் வாயு மாசடைதல் காரணமாக சுவாசப் பிரச்சினைகள் ஏற்படுகின்றன. சுவாசம் சார்ந்த புற்று நோய்களும் ஏற்படுகின்றன.நிலமானது மாசடைவதன் காரணமாக விவசாயம் பாதிப்படைவதோடு மேலும் பல பிரச்சனைகள் உண்டாகின்றன.“வினை விதைத்தவன் வினை அறுப்பான்” என்ற வாக்கிற்கு இணங்க நாம் வாழும் சூழலை மாசுபடுத்திய நாமே அதன் பாதிப்பையும் அனுபவிக்கின்றோம். எனவே சூழலை பாதுகாத்தால் இப்பிரச்சினையில் இருந்து விடுபட முடியும்.சூழலை பாதுகாப்போம்சூழல் என்பது நிலம், நீர், வளி மட்டும் அல்ல எம்மைச் சுற்றியுள்ள உயிருள்ள உயிரற்ற கூறுகள் அனைத்துமே சூழலில் உள்ளடங்கும். இன்றைய காலகட்டத்தில் அதிகரித்து வரும் சூழல் மாசடைவின் காரணமாக உயிர்களின் பல்வகைத்தன்மையும் மனித இனத்தின் வாழ்க்கைத் தகமையும் கேள்விக்குறியாக மாறியுள்ளது.இந்நிலையை மாற்றியமைக்க வேண்டுமாயின் சூழலானது அதன் உயிர்த்தன்மை மாற்றமடையாது பாதுகாக்கப்படல் வேண்டும். சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு என்பது நீர், நிலம், வளி என்பவற்றை பாதுகாப்பதோடு புதுப்பிக்க்கூடிய வளங்களை புதுப்பித்தல் ஆகும்.அவ்வகையில் இன்று சூழலானது பொலித்தீன் மற்றும் பிளாஸ்டிக் பாவனையினாலையே அதிகம் மாசடைகின்றன.மேலும் விவசாயத்தில் இரசாயன உரப்பாவனைக்குப் பதிலாக இயற்கை உரப்பாவனையை அதிகம் பயன்படுத்த வேண்டும்.இவ்வாறு நாம் சூழலை பாதுகாத்து வருங்கால சந்ததியினருக்கு சூழலை மாசடையாமல் கையளிக்க வேண்டியது எமது கடமையாகும். ஆதலால் நாம் சூழலை பாதுகாக்க வேண்டும்.சூழலை பாதுகாக்க மாணவர்கள் எடுக்க வேண்டிய நடவடிக்கைகள்இன்றைய சிறார்கள் நாளைய தலைவர்கள் என்ற வகையில் மாணவர்களும் சூழலை பாதுகாக்க பல நடவடிக்கைகளை எடுக்க வேண்டும். மாணவர்கள் சூழல் மாசடைதனால் ஏற்படும் பாதிப்புக்களை மக்களுக்கு எடுத்துக்கூறி அதன் மூலம் சூழலை பாதுகாக்க முடியும்.மேலும் சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு தொடர்பான சிறு நாடகங்களை வானொலி மற்றும் தொலைகாட்சியில் ஒளிபரப்பு செய்வதன் மூலம் சூழலை பாதுகாக்க முடியும். இவ்வாறு நாம் மேற்கொள்ளும்சிறு சிறு நடவடிக்கையின் மூலம் சூழலை பெரிய அளவில் பாதுகாக்க முடியும்.சூழல் பாதுகாப்பு நடவடிக்கைகள்சூழலை பாதுகாக்க தனிப்பட்ட ரீதியில் மட்டுமல்ல நாடுகள் ரீதியிலும், சர்வதேச ரீதியிலும் பல்வேறு நடவடிக்கைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்படுகின்றன.சர்வதேசம் என்ற நிதியில் பல மாநாடுகள் நடாத்தப்பட்டு சூழல் பாதுகாக்கப்படுகின்றது. உதாராணமாக வியன்னா மாநாடானது சூழல் பாதுகாப்புக்காக மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்ட மாநாடாகும்.நாடுகளின் நடவடிக்கைகள் என்று நோக்கும் போது அமெரிக்கா மற்றும் நோர்வே போன்ற நாடுகளில் சூழலிற்கு பாதிப்பை ஏற்படுத்தும் குளேரோ புளேரோ காபன் போன்றவற்றின் பயன்பாட்டில் கடுமையான சட்டதிட்டங்களை ஏற்படுத்தி உள்ளது.மேலும் இந்திய நாட்டை பொருத்தமட்டில் எக்ஸ்னோரோ இன்டர்நேஷனல், சிறுதுளி, சூழல் கழகம், தேசிய பசுமைப்படை போன்ற அமைப்புக்களால் மரம் நடுதல், தரிசு நிலங்களை மேம்படுத்தல் போன்ற செயற்பாடுகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றன.இவ்வாறு நாடுகள் ரீதியிலும் சர்வதேச ரீதியிலும் பல நடவடிக்கைகள் மேற்கொள்ளப்பட்டு சூழல் பாதுகாக்கப்படுகின்றது.முடிவுரைபல்லாயிரக்கணக்கான உயிர்கள் வாழும் சூழலை பாதுகாக்க வேண்டியது எமது கடமையாகும். நம் எதிர்கால சந்ததியினருக்கு நாம் வாழும் சூழலை பாதுகாப்பான முறையில் கையளிக்க வேண்டியது எமது கடமையாகும்.“வீடு வளம் பெறின் நாடு வளம் பெறும் நாடு வளம் பெறின் இவ்வுலகம் வளம் பெறும்”அகவே அனைவரும் ஒன்றினைந்து சுற்றுச் சூழலைப் பாதுகாப்போம்.பசுமை எங்கோ! வளமை அங்கே!"},{"question":"கிராம்பு என்பது தாவரத்தின் எப்பகுதி?\\tஅ. இலைஆ. வேர்இ. கனிஈ. மலர்மொட்டு","answer":"விடை: ஈ. மலர்மொட்டு. கிராம்பு (இலவங்கம்) ஒரு மருத்துவ மூலிகை ஆகும். இது சமையலில் நறுமணப் பொருளாகப் பயன்படுத்தப்படுகிறது. இது இந்தோனேசியாவில் தோன்றிய தாவரமாகும். இது இந்தோனேசியாவில் பெரும்பான்மையாகப் பயிரிடப்பட்டாலும் இந்தியாவிலும் இலங்கையிலும் பயிரிடப்படுகிறது. கிராம்பில் கார்போ ஹைட்ரேட், ஈரப்பதம், புரதம், வாலடைல் எண்ணெய், கொழுப்பு, நார்ப்பொருள் , மினரல், ஹைட்ரோகுளோரிக் அமிலச் சாம்பல்கள், கால்சியம், பாஸ்பரஸ், தயமின், ரிபோ பிளேவின், நயாசின், வைட்டமின் சி மற்றும் ஏ போன்றவை உள்ளன. கிராம்பின் மொட்டு, இலை, தண்டு போன்றவற்றிலிருந்து எண்ணெய் எடுக்கப்படுகிறது. அன்றாடம் பயன்படுத்தும் பற்பசைகளில் கிராம்பு சேர்க்கப்படுகிறது. இதிலிருக்கும் சுறுசுறு தன்மையானது வாய்க்கு புத்துணர்வைக் கொடுக்கிறது. இதற்கு அஞ்சுகம், உற்கடம், கருவாய்க்கிராம்பு, சோசம், திரளி, வராங்கம் என்ற பல பெயர்களும் உண்டு."},{"question":"ලාඩම \\" යන්නෙහි ඉංග්‍රීසි වදනක් වෙත් නම් දක්වනු මැනැවි.","answer":"පොදුවේ කියන්නේ Hoof shoe"},{"question":"ब्रम्हचर्माश्रम, गृहस्थाश्रम, वानप्रस्थाश्रम व संन्यासाश्रम हे प्राचीन भारतातील कोणत्या व्यवस्थेचे प्रकार होते ?","answer":"ब्रम्हचर्माश्रम, गृहस्थाश्रम, वानप्रस्थाश्रम व संन्यासाश्रम हे प्राचीन भारतातील आश्रमव्यवस्थेचे प्रकार होते."},{"question":"Витаминология деген эмне?","answer":"Витаминология - бул биохимия, тамак-аш гигиенасы, фармакология жана башка кээ бир биомедициналык илимдердин кесилишиндеги илим, ал витаминдердин структурасын жана таасир этүү механизмдерин, ошондой эле аларды терапиялык жана профилактикалык максаттарда колдонууну изилдейт."},{"question":"ഇറാന്റെ തലസ്ഥാനം ഏതാണ്?","answer":"ഇറാന്റെ തലസ്ഥാനവും ഏറ്റവും വലിയ നഗരവുമാണ് ടെഹ്‌റാൻ അല്ലെങ്കിൽ ടെഹ്‌റാൻ. ഇറാന്റെ ഭരണ, സാമ്പത്തിക, സാംസ്കാരിക കേന്ദ്രവും മേഖലയിലെ പ്രധാന വ്യാവസായിക, ഗതാഗത കേന്ദ്രവുമാണ് ടെഹ്‌റാൻ."},{"question":"Ответьте на этот сложный вопрос: на какой улице в Санкт-Петербурге находится музей Эрмитаж?","answer":"Музей Эрмитаж находится на Дворцовой Набережной, вдоль реки Невы, в центре Санкт-Петербурга."},{"question":"အောက်ပါပြက်လုံးကို ရှင်းပြပါဦး။ ဘီးလေးဘီးနဲ့ ပျံသန်းနေတဲ့ အရာက ဘာလဲ။ ဖြေ- အမှိုက်တင်ကား။","answer":"သင်ဟာ ၄ဘီးနဲ့fliesဆိုတဲ့စကားလုံးကိုကြားရင် flies ဆိုတာကလေယျာဉ်ပျံ ဒါမှမဟုတ် Superman လိုလေပေါ်မှာပျံသန်းတာကိုတွေးမိမှာပါ။ Flies ဆိုတာက ယင်ကောင်တွေကိုဆိုလိုတာမှန်းတွေးမိမှာမဟုတ်ပါဘူး။ အမှိုက်ကားကဘီးလေးဘီးရှိပြီးယင်ကောင်တွေလဲအများကြီးရှိမှာပါ။ ဘာလို့လဲဆိုတော့ယင်ကောင်တွေကအမှိုက်ကိုကြိုက်တယ်လေ။ နောက်ပြီး ပျော်ရွှင်မှုအတွက် ဒီမှာ မြင်ရတာက ပျံသန်းနေတဲ့ အမှိုက်ကားတစ်စီးပါ။ ဗီဒီယို"},{"question":"Kíni ìjì ní ède Gẹ̀ẹ́sì?","answer":"Wind."},{"question":"Patarosan: Saha nu jadi Diréktur Éksekutif Bank of America?","answer":"Jawaban: Diréktur Éksekutif Bank of America nyaéta Brian Thomas Moynihan ti taun 2010 tepi ka kiwari. "},{"question":"Nitori owo ọmọ onilẹ, ọlọpaa atawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun kọju ija sira wọn l’Oṣogbo","answer":"Ere asapajude lawọn eeyan agbegbe Gbaẹmu, niluu Oṣogbo, sa nirọlẹ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, nigba ti awọn ikọ ọlọpaa Puff Adder atawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun kọju ija sira wọn nibẹ.Ile kan ti wọn n kọ lọwọ lagbegbe naa la gbọ pe awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun ọhun ti wọn to ogun ya lọ, wọn si sọ fun awọn oṣiṣẹ ibẹ pe dandan ni ki wọn sanwọ ọmọ onilẹ.Awada lawọn oṣiṣẹ ti wọn n kọle ọhun pe ọrọ yii, afigba tawọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun naa sọ pe wọn ko ni i ṣiṣẹ kankan lai sanwo ti wọn n beere lọwọ wọn.Ẹnikan ti ọrọ naa ṣoju rẹ ṣalaye fun akọroyin wa pe lasiko ti idunaadura n lọ lọwọ ni mọto awọn ọlọpaa naa kọja, awọn agbofinro mẹta pere ni wọn si wa nibẹ.Nigba ti wọn gbọ nnkan to ṣẹlẹ, wọn paṣẹ pe ki awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun naa kuro nibẹ, ṣugbọn bii igba ti awọn ọlọpaa naa ṣẹso iya ni, ṣe lawọn eeyan yii kọ lu wọn, ti wọn si ṣe wọn leṣe.Bayii lawọn ọlọpaa yii ranṣẹ si agọ wọn, awọn ẹgbẹ wọn ba wa sibẹ lati ran wọn lọwọ pẹlu ibọn to n dun lakọlakọ nibẹ, ọwọ si tẹ meji lara wọn.A gbọ pe ṣe lawọn ti wọn ni ile ati ṣọọbu lagbegbe naa n sa kijokijo kiri, ti wọn si n bẹru ki aṣita ibọn ma lọọ ba awọn.Koda, alubami ni awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun yii lu ẹnikan to n ṣiṣẹ POS lagbegbe naa nigba ti wọn fura si i pe o n fi foonu rẹ ka nnkan to n lọ silẹ, bẹẹ ni wọn si tun ko owo ti wọn ba ninu ṣọọbu rẹ.Gbogbo igbiyanju akọroyin wa lati gbọ alaye nipa iṣẹlẹ naa latọdọ Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, Yẹmisi Ọpalọla, lo ja si pabo, nitori ko gbe ẹrọ ibanisọrọ rẹ."},{"question":"Мындан 15 жыл мурун анда Манас 15 жашта эле, түш көргөм аны м-н 13 жаш-тагы жолдошу ойноп жүрүптүр, Теңир жалгаптыр, уулумдун жолдошу туулуптур деген ким?а) Акбалта б) Кошойв) Бакай г) Жакып","answer":"Мындан 15 жыл мурун анда Манас 15 жашта эле, түш көргөм аны м-н 13 жаш-тагы жолдошу ойноп жүрүптүр, Теңир жалгаптыр, уулумдун жолдошу туулуптур деген Жакып. Туура варианты г) болот."},{"question":"स्वातंत्र्यवीर सावरकरांचे जन्मस्थान कोणते आहे?","answer":" भगूर जि. नाशिक."},{"question":"Iza no tendrombohitra ambony indrindra eto Madagasikara?","answer":" Ny Tendrombohitra Maromokotro no tendrombohitra avo indrindra eto Madagasikara"},{"question":"ஆண்டுதோறும் திருமந்திரம் மாநாடு நடத்தும் மடம் எது?","answer":"ஆண்டுதோறும் திருமந்திரம் மாநாடு நடத்தும் மடம் திருவாவடுதுறை ஆதினம் ஆகும்."},{"question":"Wọn ma fọlọpaa mu ọmọ mi o","answer":"Emi o le fi taratara da si ọrọ awọn Sẹki yẹn, ọrọ lọkọ-laya ni, nigba tẹni to si ni oun fẹẹ waa fẹjọ ọmọ mi sun ko ti wi kinni kan, mo mọ pe ko ti i ka a lara niyẹn, bo ba ka a lara, yoo sọrọ soke. N oo ṣa ni i sọ fun un pe iyawo ẹ waa ba mi pe o ni oun fẹẹ bimọ si i. Bo ba waa sọ fun mi, n oo mọ ẹjọ ti n oo da, ṣugbọn ti ko ba ti fẹnu ara ẹ sọ fun mi, Sẹki ni n oo ba sọrọ to ba ya.  Bi Akinfẹnwa ba waa ba mi, n oo ni ko fọgbọn tan iyawo ẹ ni, ko ṣe nnkan gidi mi-in fun un, ko tu u loju, bo ba ṣe daadaa, Sẹki le bimọ kan si i.  Owo kuku wa lọwọ wọn ti wọn yoo fi tọ wọn.Beeyan o ba lowo lọwọ ni yoo ni ọmọ meji loun fẹẹ bi, bi owo ba wa, ko si ohun to buru ninu ọmọ mẹrin, nitori a ko mọ ọmọ ti yoo duro sin ni, ẹni ti ọmọ ba sin nikan naa lo bimọ. Iṣẹ ti emi o ṣe nibẹ ni pe n ko ni i jẹ ko lo oogun feto-sọmọ-bibi kan lasiko yii, ko ma ko piisi jẹ, ko si ma lọọ ki waya bọ ara ẹ loju ara, n oo ṣalaye fun un pe awọn iroyin ti mo maa n gbọ nipa kinni naa ko daa. Emi ṣaa ree, emi iya ẹ, mi o lo oogun kan ri. Oṣu ati taimu lemi n ka, ko si ja mi kulẹ ri, nitori ẹ ni n o ṣe lo piisi, n ko si ni i jẹ ki Sẹki naa lo o. Ṣugbọn ọkọ ẹ gbọdọ ṣe e daadaa.Ọrọ Sẹki o le to gbogbo iyẹn, bi ọkọ ẹ ba ti ṣe e daadaa, to gbe nnkan tuntun kan le e lọwọ, yoo maa pariwo Dele kiri ni: ‘Dele ni o, Dele ni o!’ Ṣebi bo ṣe maa n ṣe tẹlẹ niyẹn. Ọrọ wọn yẹn o le loju emi rara. Eyi to tiẹ le, eyi to jọ pe o fẹẹ le, Ọlọrun ti ba mi yanju ẹ. Ọrọ ọmọ ti mo n sọ pe o loyun fun Akin yẹn ni.Ọrọ naa ma fẹẹ le kọja ọrọ oloyun de, ti wọn si fẹẹ sọ ọrọ di nnkan mi-in mọ mi lọwọ. Ọlọrun lo ni ki oluwa ẹ naa jẹ eeyan, ki iṣẹ rere ati orukọ rere oluwa ẹ naa si ṣaaju. Ẹ wo o, onisọnu lawọn ọmọ ti a n bi yii jare. Isọnu wọn pọ paapaa!Akin fun ọmọ loyun, ọmọ pasitọ! Ohun to di wahala niyẹn o. Eewọ ni nile awọn ọmọ yii lati lọọ fẹ Musulumi, wọn ni baba wọn buru debii pe o ti kọ akọbi ẹ lọmọ nitori iyẹn, pe wọn ko ti i yanju iyẹn lati ọjọ ti tọhun ti taku pe ọmọkunrin kan ti baba ati iya ẹ jẹ Musulumi loun fẹẹ fẹ. Wọn wa lẹnu iyẹn ki ọrọ awọn Akin too wọ ọ. Ohun ti Akin fi waa ba ọrọ naa jẹ ni pe ko sọ fẹnikan, koda ko sọ fun aunti ẹ ti wọn jọ n rira ni gbogbo igba, ka tiẹ ni ki i ṣe gbogbo igba lemi ati ẹ n rira. Titi ti ọrọ fi di gbẹgẹdẹ mọ ọn lọwọ, ko wi fẹnikan o. Wọn ti ti i mọle ka too gbọ o.Ọmọ naa fẹran Akin. Tinukẹ ni Sẹki ni oun mọ ọn si, koda, Safu naa mọ ọn, nitori Akin ti mu un wa si ṣọọbu ri lọjọ kan ti emi o si nibẹ, Safu ni iwa ọmọ naa daa debii pe nigba to n lọ, ẹgbẹrun marun-un loun fun un lapo ara oun. Bẹẹ, emi o gbọ nnkan kan. Bawo ni ki n tiẹ ṣe gbọ, ṣe Akin ti ki i ba mi sọrọ. Bo o ba si ti beere ọrọ pe lọjọ wo ni yoo mu iyawo wale bayii, bii ẹni pe o kan an leewo ni. Yoo sa lọ kuro niwaju ẹ loju ẹsẹ ni. Ohun ti emi o ṣe mọ pe o ni Tinukẹ kan nibi kan niyẹn. Ṣugbọn Elizabeth ni wọn mọ ọn si ninu ile wọn.Bi Akin si ṣe wa yẹn, kinni kan wa ti ki i fi ṣere, iyẹn ni pe ki i fẹ ki awọn eeyan ma mọ pe Musulumi loun. Ki i kirun taara o, ṣugbọn bii ko maa sọrọ ko sare sọ pe Walai, tabi ko ni Alau Akbaru, tabi ko ni Subuhanala, gbogbo iyẹn lawọn ọrẹ rẹ fi mọ ọn ni Musulumi o. Awọn mi-in tiẹ maa n fẹẹ pe e lorukọ ẹ, awọn ti wọn mọ ọn dele ni o, inu ẹ maa n dun ti wọn ba pe e ni Aloma, awọn ọrẹ ẹ ni o. Awọn ti wọn si n pe e ni Aloma ko mọ pe nitori orukọ ẹ ni. Idris. Wọn ni ọkunrin olowo ati alagbara kan ti wa nibi kan nigba kan to n jẹ Idiris Aloma.Boya oun lo sọ ara ẹ bẹẹ ni o, boya awọn ọrẹ ni o, ṣugbọn nigba to ti wa ni ileewe girama ni wọn ti n pe e bẹẹ. Emi o waa mọ bo ṣe jẹ ọmọ pasitọ lo lọọ ba yii o. Wọn ni ọjọ ọrẹ wọn ti pẹ, awọn ti wọn mọ wọn naa ni nileewe girama ni wọn ti pade, nigba naa ni wọn si ti n ba ọrẹ wọn bọ. Ọrẹ ti wọn ti n ṣe lati bii ọdun mẹẹẹdogun sẹyin. Ṣugbọn wọn sọ pe latigba ti baba yẹn ti mọ pe ọrẹ wọn n le lo ti n kilọ fun ọmọ rẹ, iyẹn lẹẹkọọkan to ba wa sile wọn. Nigba to si ya, Akin o dele wọn mọ, nigba to jẹ ojoojumọ niyẹn n lọọ ba Akin nile ẹ.Kẹ ẹ maa wo awọn ọmọ yii o, o ni oun ko gbe ile wa, ile merẹnti loun n lọọ gbe, to tun jade nibẹ, to ko wa sile mi nibi to fi ṣe ọọfiisi, aṣe ọrọ ọmọ Tinukẹ yẹn wa nibẹ. Emi o kuku mọ. Gbogbo bi ọrọ si ti n di wahala nile awọn ọmọ yii, ti pasitọ n kilọ fun un lojoojumọ pe ko ma fẹ Musulumi, ko gbọdọ mu Musulumi waa ba oun, gbogbo ẹ ni ọmọ yẹn n sọ fun Akin temi o. Kaka ko si sọ nile ka le mọ ohun ti a oo ṣe, niṣe ni wọn n fi ọrọ naa rẹrin-in laarin ara wọn, pe ko si wahala. Ṣe bi emi ba gbọ, n ko ti ni i le e nidii ẹ. Abi ọran ni wọn fi n fẹẹyan ni.Loootọ o maa wu mi ki ọmọ mi fẹ Musulumi, ṣugbọn to ba jẹ Kristiẹni naa lo fẹ, ko si ohun to buru ninu ẹ lọdọ temi, ohun ti n ko kan fẹ naa ni ki ẹnikan maa wa fi ọrọ ẹsin tiẹ yọ emi naa lẹnu, onikaluku lo lẹsin tiẹ. Ohun to dun mi ju ninu ọrọ yẹn niyẹn. Sẹki ni Tinukẹ funra ẹ lo ni afi ki oun loyun, Akin kọ fun un. Nigba ti ko si fi i lọrun silẹ lo fi loyun yii. Wọn lo ni ohun to le yi baba oun lọkan pada niyẹn. N lọmọ ba loyun, lo di wahala, ni wọn ni baba ẹ ba yari, lo ni ti oun ba ri Akin, oun maa bẹ ẹ lori. Lo ni ki ọmọ ko jade nile oun o.Nigba ti ọmọ o si ni ibi meji ti yoo ko lọ, ọdọ Akin naa lo ko wa. Wọn waa ni aburo ẹ kan to ti maa n ba a wa sọdọ Akin naa lo lọọ ṣofofo pe ibẹ lo ma wa. Ni pasitọ ba lọọ fi ọlọpaa mu ọmọ temi o, lo ni o ji ọmọ gbe. Ẹ gbọ, nibi ti aye le de bayii, keeyan ni ki ọlọpaa lọọ mu ẹnikan pe o ji ọmọ gbe! Eyi ti mo ri niyẹn o!"},{"question":"ጥያቄ:- የትኛው ኩባንያ ቡጋቲ፣ ላምቦርግኒ፣ ኦዲ፣ ፖርሽ እና ዱካቲ ባለቤት ነው? መልስ፦","answer":"ቮልስዋገን"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Cô sinh viên giấu tên đến từ tỉnh Sơn Đông nói rằng liên tục bị người khách nữ mắng nhiếc khi đặt một tô mì bò 2,5 USD. Khi đến tòa nhà, cô mới phát hiện cần có thẻ an ninh mới có thể dùng thang máy đến căn hộ của khách hàng. Nhưng khi cô gọi điện để nhờ hướng dẫn, người khách nói rằng: \\"Cô không xứng đáng để dùng thang máy, leo thang bộ không được à?\\". Sinh viên giao hàng đã phải dùng thang bộ và đặt đồ ăn trước cửa người khách và rời đi, nhưng sau đó nguời này lại gọi và nói rằng có vấn đề với món mì bò và yêu cầu cô quay lại. Người khách này sau đó nói","answer":"có lỗi bao bì và đã ném món mì xuống sàn, khiến nước súp nóng bắn hết lên người nhân viên giao hàng. \\"Tôi cho cô 5 phút để mua phần mì mới, nếu không tôi sẽ khiếu nại lên công ty\\", người khách nói. Nhân viên giao hàng phải trấn an người khách và chạy đi mua phần mì mới. \\"Người đó vẫn rất thô lỗ khi tôi mang đơn mì mới trở lại, nói rằng tôi học tập lẫn làm việc đều không tốt\\", cô nói. Nhiều người nghe câu chuyện đã bày tỏ sự bất bình với thái độ của người khách. Nhiều người yêu cầu công ty phải có hệ thống đánh giá cho cả nhân viên và khách hàng. \\"Một số khách hàng ứng xử rất tệ, khiến những nhân viên giao hàng bối rối\\", một bình luận cho hay. "},{"question":"Cột mốc cuối cùng của biên giới Việt – Trung nằm ở tỉnh nào?","answer":"Nếu cột mốc số 0 A Pa Chải là khởi đầu của đường biên giới Việt – Trung thì 1378 là cột mốc cuối cùng. Cột mốc này có vị trí đặc biệt khi nằm ở cửa sông Bắc Luân trên hòn Dậu Gót, trong cụm đảo nhỏ thuộc mũi Sa Vĩ, phường Trà Cổ, thành phố Móng Cái, tỉnh Quảng Ninh.Xung quanh là nước, cột mốc được xây thành hình trụ khá cao để không bị chìm khi thủy triều lên. Trên đỉnh của mốc trụ là một cột mốc đá hoa cương theo đúng hình mẫu của các cột mốc khác trên đất liền, cũng có hai mặt, mỗi bên đánh số và tên quốc gia. "},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Corée du Sud?","answer":"Péeyum gëblag Corée du Sud mu ngi tudd Séoul."},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Giá heo bất ngờ quay đầu giảm","answer":"Ngày 30-7, thông tin với PLO, ông Nguyễn Kim Đoán, Phó chủ tịch Hiệp hội Chăn nuôi Đồng Nai cho biết giá heo hơi tại thủ phủ chăn nuôi lớn nhất cả nước, sau một tuần tăng lên mức giá 68.000 - 70.000 đồng/kg thì nay đã quay đầu giảm xuống quanh mức giá 65.000 đồng/kg. Hai nguyên nhân khiến giá heo hơi giảm, theo ông Đoán là do giá heo hơi Trung Quốc giảm, và Chính phủ yêu cầu bình ổn giá thịt heo. \\"Hiện nay, nếu người nuôi phải mua heo giống thì giá thành nuôi heo rơi vào khoảng 62.000 -65.000 đồng/kg, với giá heo hơi bán tại chuồng thì coi như người nuôi huề vốn, tiết giảm được chi phí thì mới có chút lời. Còn những người nuôi heo nào chủ động được con giống, chủ yếu là các doanh nghiệp chăn nuôi thì giá thành chăn nuôi sẽ thấp hơn khoảng 60.000 đồng/kg, có lợi nhuận khi giá bán 65.000 đồng/kg heo hơi xuất chuồng\\" - ông Đoán nói. "},{"question":"问：什么是真爱？","answer":"答：真爱是一种深深的情感和情感的承诺，涵盖了理解、尊重、忍耐和无私。"},{"question":"Quân tốt trong cờ vua không thể phong cấp thành quân nào?","answer":"Tốt. Thông thường tốt được phong cấp thành hậu bởi đó là quân mạnh nhất. Tuy nhiên cũng có những thế cờ, phong hậu không phải phương án tối ưu nhất, thường để tránh việc đối thủ được rơi vào thế hòa vì hết nước đi. Tốt khi xuống đến hàng 8 với Trắng, hoặc hàng 1 với Đen, buộc phải phong cấp thành một trong bốn quân gồm hậu, xe, tượng hoặc mã ở vị trí đó. Do không giới hạn số quân trên bàn cờ, mỗi bên có thể có tối đa 9 hậu hoặc 10 xe, 10 tượng hay 10 mã. Tốt không được phong thành vua, cũng không thể giữ nguyên là tốt."},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 熊が町の近くに来る季節　外にごみを置いたままにしないで","answer":"環境省によると、毎年6月になると、熊が人の住んでいる町の近くに来ることが多くなります。熊はこの季節に、パートナーをさがすために、いろいろな所に行くからです。今年は5月から、北海道や岩手県などで熊を見た人が増えています。環境省は、熊が町に来ないようにするために、次のことに気をつけてほしいと言っています。熊が食べに来ないように、食べ物が入ったごみを家の外に置いたままにしないでください。木についている果物にも気をつけてください。山に山菜などをとりに行く場合は、1人で行かないでください。そして、すずなど音が出る物を持って歩いてください。熊を見つけた場合は、熊を見ながらゆっくり後ろに下がって、静かに離れてください。"},{"question":"චන්ද්‍රබිංදුව කියන්නේ සඤ්ඤක පිල්ලමද?අලුත් සිංහල යුනිකේත වල සිංහල චන්ද්‍රබින්දුවකුත් තියෙනවා.","answer":"චන්ද්‍ර බින්ඳිය,,, දේවනාගරී අක්ෂර වල යෙදුමක් නේ,,,, මම දන්න තරමට හින්දි භාෂාවේ නම් භාවිතා වෙනවා,, සිංහලය තුළ චන්ද්‍ර බි්‍න්ඳිය භාවිත වන්නේ නෑනේ"},{"question":"WASAN KWAIKWAYO‘‘Yanzu tun abin nan Geda, me kike jira ba ki mayar da yarinyar nan ɗakinta ba?’’Wa ya faɗi wannan magana a wasan ‘Bari Ba Shegiya Ba Ce’ na Zaman Duniya Iyawa Ne na Y. Ladan ?A)BawaB)Baban TaguduC)KofurD)Alhaji Mai Rokoki","answer":"B)Baban Tagudu"},{"question":"જન્મદિવસ નું બાળગીત જણાવો.","answer":"આજે મોજ મજાનો દિવસ, આજે તારો  જન્મ  દિવસતંદુરસ્ત  રહો   તુજ  તનઢગલાબંધ  કમાઓ   ધનઆનંદમાં    રહો     મનખૂબ જીવો   સુખ ભોગવોનામ      કરો      રોશનઆજે મોજ મજાનો દિવસ. આજે તારો  જન્મ  દિવસ"},{"question":"কোয়ান্টাম তত্ত্ব বিশ শতকে পদার্থবিদ্যা চর্চায় যুগান্তকারী পরিবর্তন আনতে সক্ষম হয় যখন","answer":"বিজ্ঞানী ম্যাক্স প্লাংক এবং আলবার্ট আইনস্টাইন মত প্রকাশ করেন যে আলোক শক্তি একটি নির্দিষ্ট পরিমানে শোষিত বা উদগিরিত হয় যা কোয়ান্টাম (একবচনে কোয়ান্টা) নামে পরিচিত। ১৯১৩ সালে নীলস বোর পরমাণুর বোর মডেলের সঙ্গে এই তত্ব একীভূত করেন। বোর মডেল অনুসারে ইলেক্ট্রন নিউক্লিয়াসকে কেন্দ্র করে নির্দিষ্ট কক্ষপথে নির্দিষ্ট কৌণিক ভরবেগ সহ আবর্তিত হয় এবং নিউক্লিয়াস থেকে ইলেকট্রনের দূরত্ব এর শক্তির সমানুপাতিক। এই মডেলানুসারে ইলেকট্রণ অবিরত শক্তি বিকিরণ করে না। এরা সহসা শক্তি বিকিরণ বা গ্রহণ করে এক কক্ষপথ থেকে অন্য কক্ষপথে লাফ দেয় যা কোয়ান্টাম লাফ (কোয়ান্টাম লিপ) নামে পরিচিত। শক্তি শোষন বা বিচ্ছুরণের ফলে স্পেকট্রাম বা বর্ণালী উৎপন্ন হয়।"},{"question":"Mene ne \\"Lokacin da Ake Ciki na II\\" a Hausa?","answer":"Lokaci ne da ya ke nuni zuwa ga aikin da ke tsaka da faruwa, ba a riga an kammala shi ba a lokacin da ake maganar. Kalmar ke, ita take bayyana shi. Misali:1. Bala ne yake kaɗa ganga.2. Ni nake magana da kai."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి నానార్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి: కల్యాణం","answer":"శుభము, బంగారం, పెండ్లి, అక్షయం "},{"question":"දේදුන්න වර්ණ කීයකින් සමන්විතද?","answer":"දේදුන්න වර්ණ වර්ණ 7 කින් සමන්විතයි."},{"question":"Ит куйругун түйүштүрүү дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Бирин-бирине каршылаштыруу, араздаштыруу, бузуу.Ит куйругун түйүштүрбөй тынч жүрсөңчү!"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"berapa berat mata memandang, berat lagi bahu memikul\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud hanya orang yang mengalami tahu kesusahan sebenar."},{"question":"Dukia to to miliọnu meje naira jona raurau nibi ijamba ina to ṣẹle niluu Iwo","answer":"Dukia to to miliọnu meje naira lo jona ninu ijamba ina to ṣẹlẹ lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, nileeṣẹ Rabsih Imec Nigeria Limited, to wa niluu Iwo, nipinlẹ Ọṣun.Agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ panapana nipinlẹ Ọṣun, Ibrahim Adekunle, sọ fun ALAROYE pe ni nnkan bii aago mọkanla aarọ ni ijamba ina naa ṣẹlẹ.Abala kan nileeṣẹ naa, nibi ti tanki meji to kun fun epo (oil) wa nijamba naa ti bẹrẹ, ati pe lọgan ti awọn gbọ nipa iṣẹlẹ naa lawọn kọja sibẹ.O ni epo to wa ninu awọn tanki mejeeji naa ti wọn fẹẹ fi ṣiṣẹ nileeṣẹ naa to ẹgbẹrun lọna marundinlọgọta lita.O fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe lojiji ni ina ṣẹ yọ ninu awọn tanki naa, ti gbogbo rẹ si bu gbamu, o si to wakati meji ki ileeṣẹ panapana too lanfaani lati pa ina naa.Adekunle sọ siwaju pe awọn dukia to to miliọnu meje lo ba iṣẹlẹ ina naa lọ, nigba ti awọn ajọ panapana lanfaani lati daabo bo dukia to to biliọnu meji naira nileeṣẹ ọhun lọwọ iṣẹlẹ ina naa."},{"question":"Baba mi lo nifẹẹ si iṣẹ ṣọja, nitori tiwọn ni mo ṣe wa nileewe naa bayii – Lọọya Kunle","answer":"Ọdọmọde ni, nitori ọjọ ori rẹ ko ju mẹẹẹdọgbọn(25), lọ. Ṣugbọn iṣẹ adẹrin-in-poṣonu to n ṣe a maa mu awọn agbalagba ti wọn ju u lọ daadaa rẹrin-in arintakiti, bẹẹ naa lo si jẹ aayo awọn ọdọ iwoyi naa lori awọn ikanni bii Fesibuuku, Instagraamu ati Tuita(Twitter).Eeyan to n tẹle e lẹyin gẹgẹ bii ololufẹ lori Instagraamu le ni miliọnu kan(1.1 million followers), bo si ṣe n ṣẹfẹ naa lo tun jẹ ṣọja to n kọṣẹ ologun lọwọ.Lọọya Kunle la n sọ nipa ẹ, oun naa ni wọn n pe ni ‘Ankara Gucci, awọn mi-in a si maa pe e ni ‘The Cute Abiola. Eyi ni ifọrọwerọ to waye laarin oun ati ADEFUNKẸ ADEBIYI lọsẹ to kọja, ẹ jẹ gbadun ẹ.AKEDE AGBAYE: Lọọya Kunle, Ankara Gucci ati The Cute Abiola lawọn eeyan n mọ yin si, ki lorukọ yin gan, ọmọ ilu wo si ni yin?LỌỌYA KUNLE: Orukọ mi ni Abdulgafar Ahmed Abiọla. Ọmọ Ilọrin ni mi, nipinlẹ Kwara.AKEDE AGBAYE: Awọn ileewe wo lẹ lọ?LỌỌYA KUNLE: Mo lọ si Iqra Nursery and Primary School. Mo lọ si Iqra College, mo tun lọ si Model Secondary School naa. Mo lọ si Kwara Poli. Ilọrin ni gbogbo ileewe yii wa.AKEDE AGBAYE:Ẹ wa lẹnu ẹkọṣẹ iṣẹ ṣọja lọwọ, ẹ tun n ṣe ẹfẹ lori ẹka ayelujara. Awọn ṣọja ko raye ẹfẹ, bawo lẹ ṣe n mu un pọ ti ko pa ara wọn lara?LỌỌYA KUNLE: Ọlọun naa lo n jẹ ko maa yiisi. Ninu gbogbo ohun teeyan ba n ṣe laye yii, ko maa fi eto si i.Mo n ṣe gbogbo ẹ mọra wọn naa ni, loootọ, o n pa ara wọn lara o,ṣugbọn ko han saye bi mo ṣe n ṣe e. AKEDE AGBAYE:Nigba tẹ ẹ ṣọjọọbi lọjọ kejidinlọgbọn oṣu kẹrin ọdun yii, ẹ faṣọ ṣọja yin ya fọto, awọn ṣọja si binu, wọn gbe e yin lọ fun ibawi. Alaye wo lẹ le ṣe lori eyi?LỌỌYA KUNLE:Ma a fẹ kẹ ẹ jẹ ka fi idahun yẹn silẹ, mi o ti i le sọrọ nipa ẹ lasiko yii ti mo ṣi wa lẹnu ẹkọṣẹ naa lọwọ. To ba di lọjọ iwaju ti mo ba pari, ti mo di ologun, ma a sọ ọ.Looya Kunle ninu aso soja ori-omiAKEDE AGBAYE: Ẹ tiẹ sọ pe ẹkọṣẹ ologun yẹn ko rọrun nigba kan, ẹ ni ẹ fẹẹ kuro nibẹ, bawo ni bayii?LỌỌYA KUNLE:  Ẹkọṣẹ ologun(Training) ki i ṣe nnkan to rọrun rara, loootọ ni mo kọ ọ sita nigba yẹn pe mo fẹẹ kuro, nitori ko rọrun ni. Ṣugbọn iṣẹ yẹn naa jẹ iṣẹ ti baba mi nifẹẹ si, eeyan ko dẹ mọ nnkan teeyan fi n ṣẹ obi ẹ, nitori tiwọn ni mo ṣe n ṣe e lọ. Ati pe mo gba pe teeyan ba ti kara bọ nnkan kan, afi ko gba bo ba ṣe ri. Mo ṣi wa lẹnu ẹ, mi o kuro mọ.AKEDE AGBAYE: Ẹnikan fun yin ni mọto lọjọ ayẹyẹ ọjọọbi naa, ta ni tọhun?LỌỌYA KUNLE: Ootọ ni.Ẹni yẹn jẹ ẹnikan to maa n gba mi niyanju lati ma jẹ ko su mi nigba ti mo ṣẹṣẹ bẹrẹ kọmẹdi. Alatilẹyin mi ni latilẹ,ẹni yẹn n ta mọto niluu oyinbo ati ni Naijiria naa. Mi o tiẹ fọkan si i, asiko igbele ni,ile ni mo wa ti wọn fi gbe e wa, inu mi dun gan-an lọjọ naa.AKEDE AGBAYE:Bawo lẹ sẹ bẹrẹ Kọmẹdi ọhun gan-an?LỌỌYA KUNLE: Kọmẹdi gan-an kọ ni mo fẹẹ ṣe tẹlẹ, iṣẹ lọọya lo wu dadi mi pe ki n ṣe. Igba ti mi o waa lanfaani lati wọ yunifasiti,mo lọ si poli. Ṣugbọn kọmẹdi yẹn ti wa lara mi tipẹ, lati ileewe girama ni mo ti nifẹẹ si ka maa ṣere tabi ẹfẹ. Bi mo ṣe kuku tẹra mọ ọn niyẹn.Ipari 2010 ni mo bẹrẹ si i ṣe adari eto lode inawo titi wọ 2011 ti mo tun mu skit ṣiṣe mọ ọn. Ko yiisi nigba yẹn, mo kan n fori ti i ni. 2017 ni Ọlọun gbadua.AKEDE AGBAYE:Awọn nnkan daadaa wo ni skit ṣiṣe yii ti mu ba yin bayii?Skit ṣiṣe ti mu mi mọ ọpọlọpọ eeyan, mo mọ awọn olori ilu, mo mawọn eeyan pataki lawujọ. Ko sibi ti mo fẹẹ wọ ti wọn yoo fọwọ rọ mi da sẹyin, ọpọlọpọ ilẹkun anfaani lo ti ṣi fun mi.Mo fi n ran awọn obi mi lọwọ, mo fi n ṣaanu fawọn eeyan, emi naa dẹ n na an funra mi, nitori igbesi aye gbajumọ(celebrity) ko rọrun.AKEDE AGBAYE: Ẹyin ọmọde ẹlẹfẹ asiko yii ni aṣa kan, aṣọ kan ṣoṣo lẹ n wọ ṣiṣe lọpọ igba.A mọ LizzyJay(Ọmọọbadan) mọ lesi iro ati buba, agbada ati fila ni ti Mista Macaroni, ṣẹẹti kan bayii ni ti Lọọya Kunle, ṣe nitori idanimọ naa ni?LỌỌYA KUNLE: Nitori idanimọ, ati nitori pe awọn ẹfẹ wa yẹn maa n tẹsiwaju nigba mi-in. Pataki ibẹ waa ni pe bawọn eeyan ba ti ri aṣọ yẹn lọrun wa, awọn ẹlomi-in aa ti maa rẹrin-in silẹ ki wọn tiẹ too gbọ ohun ti skit naa da le lori. Nitori ẹ la ṣe n wọṣọ kan ṣoṣo, ki i ṣe pe ko daa keeyan paarọ aṣọ.AKEDE AGBAYE: Njẹ ẹ ranti ‘skit’ tẹ ẹ kọkọ ṣe mọ?LỌỌYA KUNLE: Bẹẹ ni, mo ranti.O yatọ si eyi to jẹ kawọn eeyan mọ mi. Oun ni eyi ti mo ti n bu awọn nẹtwọọki pe wọn ja kaadi mi, pe ki wọn da a pada abi ki n fun wọn lepe. Eyi tawọn eeyan fi waa mọ mi ni ‘Ankara Gucci’, nibi ti mo ti ni a fẹẹ ṣenawo, Ankara Gucci la dẹ maa mu.AKEDE AGBAYE: Awọn obinrin ọlọmu nla, oni bakasi rabata maa n wa ninu awọn skit yin,ṣe bẹẹ naa lẹ nifẹẹ wọn loju aye?LỌỌYA KUNLE: Mo kan n fiyẹn ṣere ni, emi o kundun awọn nnkan bẹẹ. Ẹni ti mo n fẹ gan-an ko ri bẹẹ yẹn.Ko dẹ ki i ṣe gbogbo igba naa la maa n ṣe awọn nnkan bẹẹ.Mo n lo awọn obinrin to sanra ki wọn le mọ pe ko si bawọn ṣe ri tawọn ko ni i ri ọkunrin to laiki awọn, ki wọn ma baa maa ro ara wọn pin ni.AKEDE AGBAYE: Ṣe ẹ ti ṣegbeyawo, awọn ọmọ nkọ?LỌỌYA KUNLE:Mi o ti i gbeyawo, ṣugbọn mo ti ni afẹsọna, mi o ti i bimọ.AKEDE AGBAYE:Ounjẹ wo lẹ fẹran ju?LỌỌYA KUNLE:  Okele ni, ko ṣaa ti jẹ okele. Mo maa n jẹun daadaa. AKEDE AGBAYE: Ọna wo lẹ n gba ṣe faaji bi ẹ ko ba si lẹnu iṣẹ?LỌỌYA KUNLE: Mo maa n nifẹẹ lati ṣe faaji pẹlu awọn alaini, ki n fun wọn ni nnkan. Ki i ṣe gbogbo nnkan leeyan n gbe si Fesibuuku. Emi o ki i muti, mi o dẹ ki n lọ si kilọọbu. O tẹ mi lọrun ki n ba awọn ti ko to mi ṣe, inu mi dẹ maa n dun ti wọn ba ṣadua fun mi."},{"question":"ਇਸ ਅਧਿਆਇ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਸੀਂ ਪੜਿਆ ਕਿ ਜਦੋਂ ਜੰਗਲ ਅਤੇ ਜੰਗਲੀ ਜੰਤੂਆਂ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਤਾਂ ਚਾਰ ਮੁੱਖ ਦਾਵੇਦਾਰ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਕਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਜੰਗਲ ਉਤਪਾਦਾਂ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਹਿੱਤ ਨਿਰਣਾ ਲੈਣ ਦੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ ? ਤੁਸੀਂ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਕਿਉਂ ਸੋਚਦੇ ਹੋ ?","answer":"ਜੰਗਲ ਅਤੇ ਜੰਗਲੀ ਜੰਤੂਆਂ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਆਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਚਾਰ ਦਾਵੇਦਾਰ ਹਨ1.ਜੰਗਲ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਅਤੇ ਇਸਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਲੋਕ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ-ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਲੋੜਾਂ ਲਈ ਜੰਗਲ ‘ਤੇ ਨਿਰਭਰ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।2.ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦਾ ਜੰਗਲ ਵਿਭਾਗ ਜੰਗਲਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਨਿਯੰਤਰਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।3.ਕਾਰਖ਼ਾਨੇਦਾਰ ਅਤੇ ਵਪਾਰੀ ਤੇਂਦੂਆ ਪੱਤੀ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਬੀੜੀ ਉਤਪਾਦਕਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਕਾਗ਼ਜ਼ ਮਿੱਲ ਤੱਕ ਜੰਗਲ ਉਤਪਾਦਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ।4ਜੰਗਲੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਅਤੇ ਕੁਦਰਤ ਪ੍ਰੇਮੀ ਕੁਦਰਤ ਦੀ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਇਸਦੀ ਅਸਲ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਜੰਗਲ ਉਤਪਾਦ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧਨ ਲਈ ਫੈਸਲਾ ਲੈਣ ਦੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਜੰਗਲ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਅਤੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਣੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਸਦੀਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਜੰਗਲਾਂ ‘ਤੇ ਨਿਰਭਰ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਪਰੰਤੂ ਕੁੱਝ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਕੋਲ ਹੀ ਹੋਣੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ ਹਨ ਤਾਂਕਿ ਲੋਕ ਜੰਗਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਠੀਕ ਢੰਗ ਨਾਲ ਕਰਨ ਅਤੇ ਇਸਦੀ ਗਲਤ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਨਾ ਕਰਨ । ਜੰਗਲੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਅਤੇ ਕੁਦਰਤੀ ਪ੍ਰੇਮੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਕੁੱਝ ਅਧਿਕਾਰ ਦੇਣੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਹ ਕੁਦਰਤ ਦੀ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਇਸਦੀ ਅਸਲੀ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"Haliç'in Avrupalılar arasındaki ismi ve hikayesi nedir?","answer":"Haliç, Avrupalılar tarafından “Golden Horn” yani “Altın Boynuz” olarak bilinmektedir ve bu ismin çıkış yeri bir Yunan efsanesine dayandırılır. Kocası Zeus’un güzel İo ile aşk yaşadığını öğrenen baş tanrıça Hera’nın, İo’yu boynuzlu bir ineğe çevirmesi ve başına bir sineği musallat etmesiyle başlar efsane. Hatta bu aynı zamanda İstanbul Boğazı’nın oluşmasına da neden olan efsanedir. Sinekten kaçarken başını bir sağa bir sola toslayan İo, toprak parçalarını birbirinden ayırarak derin yarıklar oluşturur. İşte bu yarıklardan biri de Haliç’tir. Sonra İo nihayet kıyıya çıkar… Bir kız çocuğu dünyaya getirir… Keroessa ismini koyduğu kızın adı zamanla “keros” yani “boynuz”a dönüşür. Ve bu isim İo’nun torunu Megara Kralı Byzas tarafından da bizim Haliç adıyla bildiğimiz bölgeye verilir. Taşıdığı verimlilikten dolayı taşı toprağı altın gibi görülen Haliç’in adına Batılılar tarafından bir de “Altın” eklenir ki “Altın Boynuz” adı böylece günümüze kadar ulaşır."},{"question":"Rumuskan jawaban untuk pertanyaan rumit ini: Di mana karakter Suami berada dalam buku yang diterbitkan pada tahun 1847 dengan nama penerbit samaran \\"Ellis Bell\\"?","answer":"Thrushcross Grange"},{"question":"வினா:பாகற்காய்- பிரித்தெழுதுக(1) பாகு + அல் + காய்(2) பாகு + அற்காய்(3) பாகற்+ காய்(4) பாகு + கல்+ காய்","answer":"விடை :(1) பாகு + அல் + காய்"},{"question":"තෙරුවන් වන්දනා කළ යුතු අනුපිළිවෙළ වන්නේ කුමක්ද?","answer":"තෙරුවන් වන්දනා කළ යුතු අනුපිළිවෙළ වන්නේ බුද්ධ, ධම්ම, සංඝයි."},{"question":"Wan xob mooy génne wurekat (joueur) ci po mi ?","answer":"xob bu xonq bi"}]`),S={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:T},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:M,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},B={class:"search-container"},C={class:"card-container"},O=["disabled"],K={key:0},L={key:1};function P(e,a,s,k,t,u){const m=b("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",B,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),y(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>t.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[w,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",C,[(i(!0),o(c,null,p(u.filteredPoems,(r,d)=>(i(),f(m,{key:d,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",L,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",K,"See more"))],8,O)):j("",!0)])}const E=g(S,[["render",P],["__scopeId","data-v-6f59b69c"]]),H=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/6.md","filePath":"chatai/6.md"}'),D={name:"chatai/6.md"},W=Object.assign(D,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[v(E)]))}});export{H as __pageData,W as default};
